COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 6/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O 1111TH/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MAY/O 10/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 10/O ,/O 11/O ,/O AND/O 12/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 93012/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION '/O 1952/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/O S/O WOOD/O ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O FRANCIS/PERSON E/PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION HAROLD/PERSON H/PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION MORGAN/O M/O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Missouri/O BERNARD/PERSON W/PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B/PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O Ja/O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E/PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S/LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr/O ,/O Couont/PERSON LoUis/PERSON J/PERSON Ri/PERSON oSrLL/O ./O 
Senior/O In/O rtrqator/O JOHN/PERSON W/PERSON CnnRRIvGTN/PERSON ,/O Cl/O </O rk/O of/O Committee/ORGANIZATION SPECIAL/ORGANIZATION SUBCOMMITTEE/ORGANIZATION ,/O MAY/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O JOHN/PERSON S/PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION SPECIAL/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 10-12/O ,/O 1951/O DONALD/PERSON L/PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION II/O CONTENTS/O May/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Arthur/ORGANIZATION Strawn/ORGANIZATION ------/O September/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O Eugene/PERSON Fleury/PERSON .../O ./O 
.../O --/O ./O 
Statement/O ofAnne/O Ray/PERSON Frank/PERSON -/O -/O _/O __/O -/O ./O 
./O 
_/O Eve/O Ettmger/O .../O ./O 
---------------------/O September/O 11/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofRobert/O Shayne/PERSON -LRB-/O Robert/PERSON Shaen/PERSON Dawe/PERSON -RRB-/O --/O ./O 
Mendell/PERSON Morton/PERSON Krieger/PERSON .../O --/O _/O -/O .../O September/O 12/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofProkop/O Jack/PERSON Prokop/PERSON --------------------/O Helen/PERSON Schwartz/PERSON Donath/PERSON ./O 
--/O ./O 
------/O _/O ./O 
./O 
Bella/PERSON Lewitzky/PERSON Reynolds/PERSON ---------------/O ./O 
Page/O --/O .../O --/O ./O 
./O 
-/O .../O 2053/O --/O ./O 
./O 
-------/O 2061/O ./O 
-----------/O 2071/O .../O ./O 
./O 
----------/O ./O 
./O 
2076/O _/O 2091/O .../O ./O 
---------/O 2098/O --------/O 2117/O ----------/O 2120/O .../O ----------/O ./O 
2122/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 6/O THURSDAY/O ,/O MAY/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O INITEDI/O S1VIES/O ll/O ,/O lE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVE/O ./O 
SUBCOM3II/O `/O iTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECI/O THE/O l/O ON/O A/O spe/O ial/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Conmmittee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 10/O a./O in./O ,/O in/O room/O 603/O ,/O Drake/O Hotel/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O member/O present/O :/O Representative/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ./O 
Mr./O Woo/PERSON ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O ,/O composed/O of/O myself/O ,/O is/O now/O in/O order/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O e/O Mr./O WHVIEELER/PERSON ./O 
YeN/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Strawn/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O rise/O and/O be/O sworn/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
You/O ./O 
Mr/O STREWN/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ARTHUR/PERSON STRAWN/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROBERT/PERSON W./PERSON KENNY/PERSON AND/O BEN/PERSON MARGOLIS/PERSON m1/O tate/O your/O full/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WilHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O Mr./O Saiixw/PERSON ,/O ./O 
Arthur/PERSON Strawn/PERSON ,/O S-t-r-a-w-n/O ./O 
Mr./O WHIEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O ale/O repiesented/O by/O counsel/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O :/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/PERSON Noui/PERSON identify/O yourselves/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr/O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
I/O ami/PERSON Roblert/PERSON W./PERSON Kenny/PERSON ,/O from/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
M.Rlnu/O is/O ./O 
I/O am/O Ben/PERSON Miiialsh/PERSON ,/O also/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
VWHEELER/O -LRB-/O addre-ing/O witness/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O reside/O 7270/O Woodi/PERSON ow/O Wilson/PERSON Drive/PERSON ./O 
STRAWs/O ./O 
WHti/O :/O ELER/O ./O 
What/O is/O VOlr/O '/O OCCUlpation/O iMr.STxRAWx/O ./O 
I/O am/O :/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O WVI1EE/O ./O 
LER/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O STR/O \/O n/O x./O I/O xxas/O born/O in/O Ness/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O September/O 29/O ,/O 1900/O ./O 
Mi/O ./O 
Will/O ELER/O ./O 
Will/O yot/O give/O ui/O ,/O a/O brief/O r16sumn/O of/O your/O educational/O background/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O nind/O if/O I/O refer/O to/O a/O couple/O of/O notes/O that/O I/O have/O brought/O ,/O do/O you/O ?/O 
2/O -RRB-/O 53/O 2054/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O will/O be/O perfectly/O all/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O brought/O this/O with/O me/O in/O the/O interest/O of/O accuracy/O ./O 
I/O was/O graduated/O from/O high/O school/O in/O St./LOCATION Louis/LOCATION in/O 1918/O ./O 
After/O volunteering/O for/O service/O in/O the/O First/O World/O War/O ,/O and/O the/O war/O ending/O before/O I/O could/O serve/O ,/O although/O I/O had/O been/O accepted/O ,/O I/O then/O went/O on/O and/O attended/O Washington/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION St./ORGANIZATION Louis/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O which/O I/O was/O graduated/O ./O 
First/O ,/O I/O should/O say/O ,/O I/O did/O a/O year/O at/O Stanford/LOCATION and/O then/O I/O got/O my/O bachelor/O of/O arts/O degree/O from/O Washington/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O 1925/O or/O 1926/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O that/O conclude/O your/O formal/O education/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAIN/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupational/O background/O after/O leaving/O school/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O began/O writing/O while/O I/O was/O still/O going/O to/O college/O ./O 
I/O did/O newspaper/O work/O and/O then/O when/O I/O left/O the/O university/O I/O continued/O on/O with/O that/O ./O 
I/O worked/O on/O the/O St/O Louis/PERSON Post-Dispatch/PERSON ,/O and/O from/O there/O I/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O became/O ,/O for/O a/O number/O of/O years/O ,/O their/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION correspondent/O and/O began/O to/O write/O for/O magazines/O and/O had/O books/O published/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O associated/O with/O the/O motionpicture/O industry/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O while/O I/O was/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O and/O still/O while/O I/O was/O doing/O newspaper/O work/O and/O contributing/O to/O magazines/O ,/O I/O did/O work/O on/O several/O pictures/O by/O an/O independent/O outfit/O ./O 
I/O also/O wrote/O plays/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O say/O that/O my/O first/O formal/O connection/O with/O motion/O pictures/O was/O around/O 1935/O or/O 1936/O ,/O when/O I/O came/O out/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O stories/O or/O scripts/O have/O you/O written/O that/O were/O made/O into/O motion/O pictures/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O them/O all/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O you/O have/O had/O ,/O probably/O ,/O more/O impressive/O lists/O than/O mine/O ./O 
I/O did/O the/O original/O story/O and/O joint/O screen/O play/O on/O The/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION Room/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Columbia/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O did/O a/O joint/O screen/O play/O for/O The/O Man/O Who/O Lived/O Twice/O ./O 
I/O also/O worked/O on/O a/O joint/O screen/O play/O called/O Lady/O in/O Distress/O ./O 
I/O also/O did/O added/O scenes/O for/O Do/O n't/O Gamble/O with/O Love/O ./O 
I/O did/O the/O original/O story/O Here/O Comes/O the/O Girls/O ./O 
I/O also/O worked/O on/O a/O joint/O screen/O play/O entitled/O ``/O Road/O Agent/O ./O ''/O 
Another/O joint/O screen/O play/O entitled/O ``/O The/O Enemy/O Meets/O Ellery/PERSON Queen/PERSON ./O ''/O 
I/O did/O another/O joint/O screen/O play/O called/O Eyes/O of/O the/O Underworld/O ./O 
That/O brought/O me/O up/O to/O the/O war/O and/O I/O was/O sick/O ,/O recovering/O from/O a/O minor/O operation/O ,/O when/O the/O Japs/O hit/O us/O at/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ,/O but/O I/O immediately/O began/O to/O correspond/O to/O see/O if/O there/O was/O any/O way/O I/O could/O get/O into/O the/O service/O ./O 
By/O the/O time/O I/O had/O recovered/O from/O the/O operation/O ,/O and/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O knew/O of/O my/O desire/O to/O serve/O ,/O I/O was/O notified/O that/O there/O was/O a/O representative/O out/O here/O from/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Force/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O went/O to/O see/O him/O ./O 
I/O was/O interviewed/O by/O him/O and/O he/O thought/O that/O he/O could/O use/O me/O and/O could/O get/O me/O a/O commission/O ,/O but/O he/O asked/O me/O if/O I/O could/O n't/O get/O a/O commission/O whether/O I/O would/O be/O willing/O to/O serve/O in/O a/O civilian/O capacity/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2055/O I/O said/O that/O I/O would/O be/O willing/O to/O serve/O in/O any/O capacity/O ./O 
So/O he/O wired/O me/O later/O and/O said/O that/O there/O was/O no/O commission/O for/O me/O ,/O but/O would/O I/O come/O on/O anyway/O ./O 
I/O wired/O back/O ,/O ``/O Name/O the/O date/O and/O I/O will/O come/O on/O ,/O ''/O and/O I/O did/O ./O 
So/O I/O went/O back/O to/O Wright/LOCATION Field/LOCATION and/O worked/O in/O a/O civilian/O capacity/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O your/O work/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O wrote/O ,/O directed/O ,/O and/O produced/O motion/O pictures/O for/O the/O war/O effort/O ,/O and/O for/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Force/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Someone/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O going/O over/O the/O work/O in/O that/O unit/O ,/O singled/O my/O work/O out/O as/O the/O most/O professional/O work/O and/O wanted/O to/O know/O why/O I/O was/O n't/O commissioned/O and/O came/O back/O and/O said/O that/O they/O had/O better/O commission/O me/O before/O they/O lose/O me/O ,/O because/O as/O a/O civilian/O I/O was/O n't/O obliged/O to/O stay/O there/O ,/O so/O they/O promptly/O put/O through/O a/O commission/O to/O keep/O me/O with/O the/O unit/O ./O 
I/O served/O for/O several/O years/O ,/O until/O I/O was/O disabled/O and/O discharged/O from/O the/O service/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O rank/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O captain/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O were/O you/O discharged/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O discharged/O out/O of/O the/O Birmingham/LOCATION Hospital/LOCATION here/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O around/O August/O of/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O what/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O a/O civilian/O employee/O of/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O in/O around/O June/O ,/O following/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ,/O and/O they/O commissioned/O me/O about/O 4/O months/O later/O ,/O right/O after/O my/O first/O scripts/O were/O seen/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
I/O remained/O until/O my/O discharge/O ,/O which/O was/O ,/O approximately/O ,/O August/O of/O 1944/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O say/O that/O you/O were/O disabled/O while/O you/O were/O in/O the/O service/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O sort/O of/O disability/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O internal/O injuries/O and/O was/O operated/O on/O ./O 
I/O volunteered/O for/O overseas/O duty/O in/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O seeking/O overseas/O duty/O and/O in/O the/O course/O of/O a/O routine/O overseas/O examination/O they/O discovered/O that/O I/O had/O hurt/O myself/O so/O they/O sent/O me/O to/O a/O hospital/O and/O I/O was/O operated/O on/O ./O 
There/O they/O found/O other/O things/O wrong/O and/O discharged/O me/O after/O 4/O or/O 5/O months/O in/O the/O hospital/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O your/O employment/O been/O after/O your/O discharge/O from/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O wrote/O a/O play/O which/O was/O produced/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Let/O me/O refresh/O my/O memory/O for/O just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
Then/O I/O sold/O several/O original/O stories/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O name/O of/O the/O play/O and/O the/O names/O of/O the/O stories/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
The/O play/O was/O called/O Sleep/O No/O More/O which/O was/O subsequently/O bought/O by/O Universal/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O comedy/O ./O 
Then/O I/O sold/O some/O original/O stories/O ./O 
One/O was/O called/O Blossoms/O for/O Effie/PERSON and/O another/O one/O called/O Affairs/O of/O Geraldine/PERSON ,/O and/O for/O Monogram/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION I/O did/O a/O rewrite/O on/O Bad/O Men/O of/O Tombstone/O and/O then/O I/O did/O an/O original/O ,/O sold/O an/O original/O screen/O play/O called/O Hiawatha/PERSON ,/O and/O another/O one/O called/O Flight/O to/O Mars/LOCATION ./O 
That/O just/O about/O brings/O it/O up/O to/O date/O ./O 
Flight/O to/O Mars/LOCATION was/O completed/O last/O December/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ;/O approximately/O that/O time/O ./O 
Previously/O I/O had/O had/O another/O play/O produced/O in/O the/O East/LOCATION ,/O See/O No/O Evil/O ,/O and/O another/O play/O of/O mine/O which/O was/O called/O Anthony/PERSON Nero/PERSON ./O 
That/O 2056/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O was/O twice/O given/O a/O full/O length/O hour/O and/O one-half/O production/O by/O the/O British/ORGANIZATION Broadcasting/ORGANIZATION Corp./ORGANIZATION ,/O on/O television/O ,/O which/O was/O an/O unusual/O distinction/O to/O get/O a/O full-length/O play/O like/O that/O shown/O ./O 
I/O have/O contributed/O articles/O and/O stories/O to/O the/O New/O Yorker/O and/O the/O American/O Mercury/O and/O the/O Herald/ORGANIZATION Tribune/ORGANIZATION magazine/O section/O ./O 
I/O have/O also/O contributed/O stories/O to/O the/O Screen/O Writer/O ,/O the/O Saturday/O Evening/O Post/O ,/O and/O E-quire/O ./O 
Perhaps/O there/O may/O be/O more/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELiER/O ./O 
As/O a/O writer/O ,/O you/O register/O all/O manuscripts/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O original/O manuscripts/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O rule/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O manuscripts/O have/O you/O registered/O during/O the/O year/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRA.WN/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O check/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O records/O on/O that/O ./O 
What/O manuscripts/O have/O I/O registered/O ,/O you/O say/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O in/O the/O year/O 1949/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWX/PERSON ./O 
I/O frankly/O do/O n't/O recall/O at/O the/O moment/O ./O 
I/O could/O check/O their/O records/O and/O find/O out/O for/O you/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WHiEELER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O a/O manuscript/O entitled/O ``/O Twilight/O Street/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O STR/O kw/O -/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O recall/O that/O manuscript/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O registering/O that/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAwx/O ./O 
I/O very/O likely/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O this/O manuscript/O in/O conjunction/O with/O another/O author/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mind/O if/O I/O consult/O with/O my/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O have/O a/O right/O to/O confer/O with/O your/O counsel/O any/O time/O you/O desire/O ./O 
You/O can/O retire/O from/O the/O room/O if/O you/O care/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O these/O gentlemen/O are/O trying/O to/O link/O me/O with/O someone/O else/O ,/O who/O has/O been/O mentioned/O in/O the/O hearings/O ./O 
I/O find/O that/O I/O must/O refuse/O to/O answer/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O my/O answer/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O have/O not/O been/O asked/O to/O identify/O any/O person/O at/O all/O ./O 
You/O were/O asked/O if/O you/O wrote/O it/O in/O connection/O with/O any/O other/O person/O ./O 
No/O one/O has/O been/O named/O as/O yet/O ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O it/O by/O yourself/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
With/O whom/O did/O you/O write/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O claim/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O on/O that/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O J./PERSON Redmond/PERSON Prior/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O a/O J./O R./O Prior/O ,/O P-r-i-o-r/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O a/O document/O here/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O which/O was/O subpenaed/O from/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O It/O is/O a/O registration/O certificate/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O where/O the/O writers/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION register/O articles/O or/O scripts/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
It/O bears/O the/O registration/O guild/O No./O 41938/O ./O 
This/O form/O was/O filled/O out/O on/O 2-25-49/O ./O 
It/O is/O registered/O in/O the/O name/O of/O Arthur/PERSON Strawn/PERSON and/O J./PERSON R./PERSON Prior/PERSON ./O 
The/O registration/O fee/O is/O indicated/O as/O $/O 1/O and/O the/O name/O of/O the/O manuscript/O is/O given/O as/O Twilight/O Street/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2057/O I/O would/O like/O to/O show/O this/O to/O the/O witness/O and/O ask/O him/O if/O he/O can/O identify/O it/O as/O a/O registration/O certificate/O receipt/O ,/O that/O he/O registered/O this/O at/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Again/O I/O will/O have/O to/O claim/O the/O same/O privilege/O in/O not/O answering/O the/O question/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O question/O again/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O if/O you/O recognize/O that/O as/O a/O receipt/O you/O received/O when/O the/O manuscript/O was/O registered/O at/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O only/O recognize/O this/O as/O a/O receipt/O ./O 
I/O had/O better/O claim/O the/O same/O privilege/O on/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
A/O moment/O ago/O ,/O Mr./O Strawn/PERSON ,/O you/O stated/O in/O response/O to/O a/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O did/O register/O this/O particular/O script/O with/O the/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION in/O 1949/O ,/O you/O stated/O that/O you/O could/O investigate/O the/O records/O up/O there/O and/O determine/O the/O answer/O to/O that/O question/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O having/O refreshed/O your/O recollection/O by/O being/O confronted/O with/O this/O record/O ,/O do/O you/O state/O now/O that/O you/O did/O not/O register/O this/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O making/O an/O error/O ,/O I/O am/O afraid/O ./O 
I/O said/O that/O I/O would/O have/O to/O investigate/O ./O 
There/O could/O still/O be/O this/O receipt/O and/O it/O does/O n't/O necessarily/O mean/O that/O I/O registered/O it/O or/O got/O the/O receipt/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O find/O out/O now/O ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O whether/O you/O registered/O that/O or/O not/O ,/O after/O having/O refreshed/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Even/O after/O having/O seen/O this/O receipt/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Was/O it/O ever/O registered/O e/O Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Obviously/O it/O must/O have/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Did/O anyone/O else/O have/O any/O interest/O in/O this/O except/O yourself/O ./O 
in/O this/O registration/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Was/O n't/O that/O question/O asked/O before/O and/O answered/O ?/O 
Mr./O WIHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Not/O the/O same/O question/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O were/O asked/O if/O you/O wrote/O it/O by/O yourself/O and/O you/O said/O you/O did/O n't/O and/O now/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O if/O anyone/O had/O any/O interest/O in/O it/O but/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
If/O someone/O else/O wrote/O it/O with/O me/O ,/O then/O that/O person/O must/O ,/O obviously/O ,/O have/O an/O interest/O in/O registering/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O does/O not/O answer/O my/O question/O ./O 
Did/O anyone/O else/O have/O any/O interest/O in/O registering/O this/O except/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWs/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Could/O it/O have/O been/O possible/O the/O other/O person/O interested/O in/O the/O registration/O of/O it/O actually/O did/O the/O registering/O ,/O or/O did/O you/O do/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWW.It/O could/O have/O been/O done/O by/O the/O other/O person/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O it/O could/O have/O been/O done/O by/O either/O of/O you/O ;/O is/O that/O right/O '/O Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON You/PERSON say/O you/O have/O no/O independent/O recollection/O of/O who/O did/O it/O ;/O is/O that/O right/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
My/O answer/O was/O that/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O having/O registered/O it/O myself/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O anyone/O else/O having/O registered/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O but/O I/O assume/O that/O it/O was/O registered/O by/O someone/O else/O ./O 
93012-52-lit/O 6/O --/O 2/O 2058/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O logical/O person/O to/O register/O this/O would/O have/O been/O J./PERSON R./PERSON Prior/PERSON ,/O he/O having/O an/O interest/O in/O the/O manuscript/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O have/O to/O claim/O the/O same/O privilege/O ,/O because/O I/O think/O this/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O get/O me/O to/O incriminate/O myself/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Isnt/O '/O it/O a/O fact/O that/O J./PERSON Redmond/PERSON Prior/O is/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O he/O has/O been/O rather/O prominently/O labeled/O as/O subversive/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ,/O by/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O will/O have/O to/O claim/O my/O privilege/O for/O the/O reasons/O given/O ,/O because/O I/O think/O it/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O link/O me/O up/O with/O someone/O who/O has/O been/O incriminated/O and/O I/O am/O afraid/O the/O answer/O to/O that/O question/O might/O tend/O fo/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O make/O the/O same/O answer/O to/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mentioned/O previouslyMr/O ./O 
STRAWN/ORGANIZATION ./O 
May/O I/O interrupt/O and/O say/O that/O any/O question/O which/O I/O feel/O is/O in/O any/O way/O an/O attempt/O to/O link/O me/O with/O any/O organization/O or/O any/O individual/O ,/O that/O I/O understand/O to/O have/O been/O listed/O as/O subversive/O by/O this/O committee/O ,/O that/O I/O do/O not/O careMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O me/O set/O you/O straight/O about/O that/O right/O now/O ./O 
This/O committee/O has/O listed/O no/O one/O as/O subversive/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O seen/O printed/O lists/O of/O organizations/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O am/O talking/O about/O individuals/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Individuals/O connected/O with/O those/O organizations/O or/O who/O have/O been/O subpenaed/O or/O cited/O for/O contempt/O ,/O any/O attempt/O to/O link/O me/O with/O any/O of/O those/O people/O I/O am/O going/O to/O ,/O in/O that/O connection/O ,/O claim/O the/O same/O privilege/O because/O I/O feel/O that/O it/O represents/O an/O attempt/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O previously/O stated/O ,/O in/O your/O testimony/O ,/O that/O you/O were/O the/O author/O of/O a/O story/O called/O Bad/O Men/O of/O Tombstone/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O sold/O directly/O to/O Monogram/O or/O do/O you/O still/O have/O a/O percentage/O of/O the/O picture/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O have/O any/O percentage/O of/O the/O picture/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O you/O sold/O it/O outright/O to/O Monogram/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O tell/O us/O the/O mechanics/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
Monogram/PERSON had/O a/O picture/O with/O that/O title/O or/O some/O approximate/O title/O ,/O and/O they/O wanted/O rewriting/O done/O on/O the/O version/O that/O they/O had/O ./O 
I/O was/O engaged/O to/O do/O some/O rewriting/O on/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O do/O the/O rewriting/O yourself/O or/O in/O conjunction/O with/O another/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O it/O in/O conjunction/O with/O another/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O other/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O have/O to/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O already/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O n't/O J./O R./O Prior/O or/O J./O Redmond/O Prior/O also/O engaged/O on/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O make/O the/O same/O answer/O to/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Strawn/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O as/O heretofore/O stated/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2059/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O STRAWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O I/O think/O the/O answer/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O and/O therefore/O I/O stand/O on/O my/O privilege/O not/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O perhaps/O there/O is/O a/O question/O or/O two/O that/O I/O should/O ask/O ./O 
You/O are/O here/O under/O subpena/O ,/O are/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O STRAW/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O introduce/O this/O document/O as/O Strawn/O exhibit/O No./O 1/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
It/O will/O be/O admitted/O as/O Strawn/O exhibit/O No./O 1/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O document/O referred/O to/O was/O marked/O as/O ``/O Strawn/O Exhibit/O No./O 1/O ./O ''/O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Is/O there/O anything/O further/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O further/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
May/O this/O witness/O be/O excused/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O he/O may/O be/O excused/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O witness/O was/O excused/O ./O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 6/O MONDAY/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O AcTivrrlES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O A/O special/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 9:30/O a./O in./O ,/O in/O Conference/O Room/O C/O ,/O at/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Roosevelt/ORGANIZATION Hotel/ORGANIZATION ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O member/O present/O :/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O member/O present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKWIX/PERSON ./O 
The/O chairman/O of/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O has/O appointed/O me/O as/O a/O special/O subcommittee/O to/O conduct/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O hearing/O continued/O with/O testimony/O not/O printed/O in/O this/O volume/O ,/O together/O with/O the/O following/O :-RRB-/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O call/O the/O next/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Eugene/PERSON Fleury/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACK.IN/O ./O 
Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O testimony/O you/O give/O before/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O EUGENE/PERSON FLEURY/PERSON MIr/O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Eugene/PERSON Strong/PERSON Fleury/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
4524/O Coldwater/O Canyon/O ,/O North/LOCATION Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O not/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
IMr/O ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O desire/O to/O be/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
What/O for/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O like/O to/O make/O a/O little/O preliminary/O statement/O here/O ,/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O and/O that/O is/O that/O you/O are/O under/O no/O compulsion/O to/O answer/O any/O of/O the/O questions/O directed/O to/O you/O ./O 
You/O have/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O if/O you/O wish/O to/O claim/O it/O against/O possible/O self-inerimination/O ./O 
However/O ,/O the/O measure/O of/O your/O cooperation/O with/O 2061/O 2062/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O the/O committee/O in/O answering/O its/O questions/O will/O largely/O determine/O the/O future/O course/O of/O the/O committee/O so/O far/O as/O you/O are/O concerned/O ./O 
I/O simply/O make/O that/O statement/O in/O order/O that/O you/O may/O be/O advised/O of/O your/O constitutional/O rights/O ,/O the/O fact/O that/O you/O are/O not/O compelled/O to/O answer/O questions/O in/O the/O absence/O of/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
My/O intent/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O is/O to/O be/O as/O cooperative/O as/O I/O possibly/O can/O ./O 
That/O is/O natural/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O what/O is/O now/O a/O piece/O of/O Glendale/LOCATION ,/O then/O called/O Tropico/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O May/O 29/O ,/O 1913/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O relate/O your/O educational/O background/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
California/LOCATION public/O schools/O through/O Sacramento/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sacramento/ORGANIZATION Junior/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION for/O 21\/2/O years/O ,/O approximately/O 3/O years/O at/O Chouinard/ORGANIZATION Art/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O say/O ``/O approximately/O ''/O because/O I/O worked/O part/O of/O the/O time/O ,/O my/O last/O semester/O that/O I/O was/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O leave/O Chouinard/ORGANIZATION Art/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
This/O must/O have/O been/O 1936/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O 1935/O ,/O 1936/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O are/O you/O now/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O an/O instructor/O at/O Art/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O at/O 5353/O West/O Third/O Street/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O have/O you/O been/O employed/O since/O leaving/O school/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Leaving/O school/O ,/O my/O first/O job/O was/O an/O instructor/O in/O the/O training/O school/O of/O Walt/ORGANIZATION Disney/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O the/O approximate/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O at/O Disney/ORGANIZATION 's/O for/O between/O 41\/2/O to/O 5/O years/O ./O 
Approximately/O the/O last/O year/O of/O this/O was/O on/O production/O on/O Fantasia/LOCATION ./O 
At/O that/O time/O ,/O why/O ,/O we/O can/O call/O it/O I/O was/O canned/O ,/O or/O there/O was/O a/O layoff-it/O started/O as/O a/O lay-off/O and/O I/O quit/O ./O 
I/O drew/O about/O 2/O months/O '/O unemployment/O insurance/O and/O went/O to/O Warner/ORGANIZATION Bros./ORGANIZATION as/O a/O background/O painter/O ./O 
It/O was/O called/O Leon/PERSON Schlesinger/PERSON at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O was/O there/O until/O I/O went/O in/O the/O Army/O in/O April/O 1943/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O were/O you/O discharged/O from/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
February/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O rank/O in/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O finally/O made/O T-5/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O honorably/O discharged/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O your/O employment/O been/O since/O your/O discharge/O from/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O keep/O the/O history/O going/O ./O 
Upon/O my/O return/O to/O California/LOCATION ,/O I/O was/O discharged/O at/O Fort/LOCATION Dix/LOCATION ,/O N./O J./O :/O I/O did/O nothing/O for/O I/O think/O ,/O a/O couple/O of/O months/O and/O then/O my/O wife/O and/O I/O went/O to/O Mexico/LOCATION ,/O more/O to/O kind/O of/O knit/O my/O tattered/O nerves/O after/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION thing/O more/O than/O anything/O else/O ./O 
I/O believe/O we/O were/O there/O approximately/O 5/O to/O 6/O months/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O ./O 
In/O any/O case/O we/O returned/O during/O the/O summer/O and/O was/O then/O offered/O the/O position/O instructing/O at/O Art/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION and/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O started/O my/O work/O there/O in/O the/O fall/O term/O ,/O September/O of/O 1946/O ,/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O that/O bring/O your/O employment/O up/O to/O date/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2063/O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O with/O Art/O Center/O except/O for/O a/O year/O off/O when/O we/O went/O to/O Europe/LOCATION and/O worked/O on/O a/O motion/O picture/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O Adams/PERSON kind/O of/O gave/O us/O a/O leave/O of/O absence/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O at/O the/O time/O that/O I/O suppose/O I/O had/O some/O sort/O of/O association/O with/O it/O ,/O it/O would/O constitute/O membership/O ./O 
It/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O called/O CPA/O then/O ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O this/O would/O be/O previous/O to/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION thing/O ,/O so/O it/O would/O be-actually/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O 1943/O ./O 
These/O times/O and/O dates/O ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O are/O going/O to/O be/O off/O one/O side/O or/O the/O other/O ,/O because/O like/O most/O artists/O I/O am/O dopey/O on/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O the/O CPA/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O actually/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
It/O seemed/O to/O be/O just/O sort/O of/O suddenly/O you/O are/O ,/O that/O 's/O that/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O paid/O dues/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O and/O that/O kind/O of/O thing/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O business/O of/O proselyting/O me/O or/O trying/O to/O get/O me/O in/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O wanted/O to/O be/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O vou/O have/O a/O reason/O for/O wanting/O to/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O ;/O yes/O ;/O I/O think/O I/O did/O have/O a/O reason/O ./O 
Naturally/O ,/O being/O an/O artist/O ,/O why/O ,/O I/O am/O fundamentally/O concerned/O in/O not/O how/O things/O are/O but/O maybe/O how/O things/O could/O be/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O change/O people/O 's/O outlook/O ,/O change/O your/O feelings/O ./O 
And/O this/O seemed/O to/O he/O ./O 
to/O me/O ,/O why/O ,/O the/O one/O concrete/O ,/O what/O I/O would/O call/O liberal/O approach/O ./O 
My/O interest/O still/O was/O fundamentally/O that/O of/O kind/O of/O a/O philosophical/O background/O to/O my/O art/O instead/O of/O my/O political/O background/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O my/O action/O then/O consisted/O mostly/O of/O conversation/O ,/O and/O that/O 's/O about/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WHIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O remain/O with/O this/O group/O until/O you/O went/O in/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O me/O the/O date/O again/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
The/O exact/O date/O would/O be-Mr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O approximate/O date/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O be/O the/O time/O I/O went/O in/O the/O Army/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O in/O April/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
For/O what/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O associated/O with/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O this/O I/O ca/O n't/O even/O pin/O down/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O less/O than/O a/O year/O ,/O or/O approximately/O a/O year/O at/O the/O most/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O prior/O to/O your/O entrance/O to/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O the/O entrance/O in/O the/O Army/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O particular/O group/O or/O unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O received/O what/O you/O might/O call/O no/O orders/O of/O any/O kind/O ./O 
It/O seemed/O to/O be/O very/O casual/O sort/O of/O conversations/O that/O at/O this/O time/O I/O could/O n't/O distinguish/O between/O what/O was/O a/O meeting/O and/O between/O a/O bunch/O of/O people/O sitting/O around/O shooting/O the/O breeze/O about/O the/O problems/O of/O the/O day/O ./O 
Mostly/O it/O was/O directly/O related/O to/O our/O profession/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O meet/O with/O the/O same/O group/O of/O people/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
It/O seemed/O to/O change/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O people/O comprised/O this/O group/O ?/O 
2064/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O like/O an/O average/O evening/O at/O anyone/O 's/O house/O ,/O varying/O anywhere/O from/O 5/O to/O 15/O ./O 
Actually/O as/O far/O as/O a/O stable/O membership/O ,/O I/O was/O never/O very/O conscious/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O at/O whose/O homes/O you/O met/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O one/O was/O at/O our/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
On/O how/O many/O occasions/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Once/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Anybody/O else/O 's/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O although/O offhand/O without/O going/O through/O practically/O a/O list/O of/O acquaintances/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O I/O could/O pin/O it/O down/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O mean/O that/O to/O be/O a/O refusal/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O just/O mushy/O and/O I/O would/O like/O a/O specific/O question/O and/O I/O will/O say/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O specific/O question/O is/O :/O At/O whose/O home/O did/O you/O meet/O during/O the/O course/O of/O these/O discussion/O groups/O ,/O or/O at/O whose/O homes/O in/O addition/O to/O your/O own/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O an/O awful/O tough/O kind/O of/O thing-well/O ./O 
There/O was/O one/O ,/O Bill/PERSON Pomerantz/PERSON '/O home./O ,/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Bill/PERSON Pomerantz/PERSON is/O the/O former/O executive/O secretary/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O lie/O eventually/O became/O that/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
I/O always/O refer/O to/O him/O as/O a/O business/O agent/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Congressman/O Jackson/PERSON advised/O your/O wife/O that/O the/O committee/O undoubtedly/O has/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O information/O concerning/O all/O of/O these/O individuals/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ,/O sir/O ;/O certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O very/O doubtful/O if/O any/O additional/O names/O could/O be/O supplied/O by/O you/O and/O I/O thought/O that/O that/O may/O make/O it/O easier/O giving/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
We/O realize/O the/O circumstances/O you/O are/O under/O and/O would/O like/O to/O make/O it/O as/O easy/O as/O possible/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O why/O I/O made/O my/O little/O statement/O that/O I/O would/O like/O you/O ,/O if/O you/O could/O ,/O to/O ask/O me/O a/O specific/O name/O instead/O of/O having/O me/O go/O over/O a/O whole/O bunch/O of/O things/O ,/O because/O it/O boils/O down/O to/O this/O ,/O that/O specifically/O and/O in/O so/O many/O words/O to/O my/O own/O true/O knowledge/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O who/O was/O or/O who/O was/O not/O a/O party/O member/O when/O I/O was/O ./O 
I/O actually/O do/O not/O know/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSNox/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O that/O there/O is/O not/O necessarily/O a/O connotation/O of/O membership/O in/O the/O Commnunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O in/O the/O CPA/O attached/O to/O the/O names/O that/O you/O may/O mention/O ./O 
However/O ,/O it/O is/O the/O duty/O and/O the/O obligation/O of/O this/O committee/O to/O determine/O the/O extent/O of/O membership/O and/O the/O names/O of/O those/O who/O were/O intimately/O associated/O with/O it/O ./O 
The/O yardstick/O of/O cooperation/O with/O the/O committee/O must/O necessarily/O be/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O any/O given/O individual/O is/O willing/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O committee/O ./O 
The/O future/O actions/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O when/O it/O reaches/O the/O city/O ,/O will/O lie/O largely/O conditioned/O by/O the/O attitude/O and/O the/O extent/O of/O cooperation/O extended/O by/O witnesses/O in/O the/O executive/O hearings/O ./O 
I/O merely/O set/O that/O forth/O in/O order/O that/O you/O may/O know/O that/O we/O are/O not/O concerned/O with/O prosecution/O or/O persecution/O but/O we/O are/O determined/O to/O get/O to/O the/O bottom/O of/O this/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O job/O that/O has/O been/O assigned/O us/O by/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
So/O in/O that/O light/O I/O ask/O your/O full/O measure/O of/O cooperation/O with/O respect/O to/O people/O who/O may/O be/O entirely/O innocent/O in/O your/O eyes/O but/O who/O may/O even/O today/O continue/O in/O their/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION unknown/O to/O you/O and/O represent/O and/O constitute/O a/O continuing/O menace/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2065/O I/O say/O that/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION does/O not/O necessarily/O attach/O to/O those/O whom/O you/O may/O mention/O ./O 
We/O do/O require/O the/O information/O and/O under/O the/O anthoritv/O that/O is/O vested/O in/O the/O committee/O I/O direct/O your/O answer/O to/O the/O questions/O which/O are/O directed/O by/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O ,/O Congressman/O ,/O under/O those/O circumstances/O I/O certainly/O shall/O ./O 
Besides/O Pomerantz/PERSON the/O other/O individuals/O ,/O Mr./O David/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON ,/O at/O his/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O Mr./O Hilberman/PERSON 's/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
At/O present/O I/O have/O no/O idea/O ./O 
He/O is/O no/O longer/O in/O this/O area/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O his/O area/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
He/O was/O in/O the/O animation/O business/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
For/O Walt/PERSON Disney/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O long/O ago/O he/O had/O been/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Mrs./O Hilberman/PERSON present/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O her/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Lib/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O attend/O a/O meeting/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Edward/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O never/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Edward/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O ani/O acquainted/O with/O him/O as/O a/O teacher/O formerly/O with/O Art/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O vou/O recall/O anybody/O else/O 's/O home/O that/O you/O attended/O meetings/O at/O ?/O 
Mr./O FmLi/PERSON iiR/O No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Those/O are/O really/O the/O only/O two/O that/O I/O do/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O WHrIELER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whio/O attended/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEU'RY/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O individuals/O mentioned/O ,/O naturally/O the/O homes/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O they/O are/O the/O stand-outs/O ./O 
I/O simply/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O actually/O in/O so/O many/O words/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Iow/O many/O meetings/O did/O you/O attend/O ,/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Even/O that/O is/O indefinite/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O know/O this/O ,/O that/O I/O certainly/O was/O not/O a/O regular/O attendant/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O to/O call/O it/O that/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O what/O would/O probably/O be/O called/O a/O very/O ill-disciplined/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O leaving/O us/O with/O the/O thought/O that/O out/O of/O the/O meetings/O that/O you/O did/O attend/O that/O you/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O any/O names/O other/O than/O tlme/O two/O or/O three/O that/O you/O have/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Definitely/O and/O specifically-wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
There/O is/O another/O one/O ./O 
A/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O John/PERSON McGrew/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O how/O Mr./O McGrew/PERSON was/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O in/O the/O animation/O business/O ,/O also/O ./O 
Mr./O JAC.KSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O -RRB-/O o/O xou/O know/O where/O lie/O was/O employed/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEIURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O bele/O \/O c/O Warner/PERSON ./O 
Bro./LOCATION ,/O or/O Leon/PERSON Schlesinger/PERSON Productions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O wia/O ,/O the/O procedure/O uied/O in/O calling/O one/O of/O these/O meetings/O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O sometimes/O telephone-usually/O just/O telephone/O or/O you/O bumped/O into/O someone/O who/O said/O ,/O ``/O We/O are/O getting/O together/O on/O ciich/O and/O such/O a/O night/O ./O ''/O 
61/O --/O 93012/O --/O 52-lt/O 2066/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O true/O in/O the/O case/O of/O all/O the/O meetings/O which/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
All/O that/O I/O went/O to/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Someone/O notified/O you/O of/O the/O meeting/O either/O in/O passing/O conversation/O or/O by/O a/O telephone/O call/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WiiEELE/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O take/O the/O meeting/O at/O your/O home/O Did/O you/O notify/O the/O people/O ?/O 
Mr./O Fi/O ar/O '/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O question/O where/O would/O we/O meet/O next/O week/O and/O Bernyce/PERSON and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Let/O 's/O meet/O at/O our/O house/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O reside/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O at/O 1022/O Laguna/LOCATION Avenue/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHIEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O reside/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O goodness/O ,/O let/O 's/O see/O It/O would/O be/O from/O 1940/O until/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O were/O discharged/O from/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION did/O you/O renew/O your/O association/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O saw/O some/O of/O these/O people/O casually/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O have/O any/O contact/O with/O them/O any/O longer/O because/O actually/O when/O I/O met/O them/O any/O more/O my/O interest/O was/O not/O the/O motion-picture/O business/O ,/O I/O was/O fed/O up/O to/O here/O -LSB-/O indicating/O -RSB-/O with/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O meeting/O that/O was/O held/O at/O your/O home/O ,/O I/O assume/O you/O received/O the/O guests/O at/O the/O door/O ,/O ushered/O them/O in/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O actually/O ,/O no/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O busy/O stirring/O up/O a/O piece/O of/O grog/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O who/O were/O present/O at/O the/O meeting/O at/O your/O home/O other/O than/O those/O you/O have/O named/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O am/O still/O trying/O to/O cudgel/O and/O find/O and/O make/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O Communist/O Party/O publications/O have/O you/O subwribed/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O Suppose/O it/O is/O called/O now-I/O guess/O it/O always/O was-People/O 's/O World/O ,/O and/O that/O 's/O all/O ./O 
Years/O and/O years/O ago-I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O a/O subscription/O or/O whether/O I/O just/O bought/O it/O at/O the/O newsstand-I/O used/O to/O buy/O New/O Masses/O and/O New/LOCATION Republic/LOCATION ,/O all/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O completely/O broken/O with/O the/O philosophy/O of/O the/O Communist/O doctrines/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O certainly/O ./O 
In/O the/O circumstances/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O is/O n't/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O as/O it/O might/O sound/O on/O the/O surface/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON There/O are/O a/O great/O number/O of/O people/O iho/O have/O n't/O Broken/O their/O association/O ./O 
,/O \/O IMr/O ./O 
FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Congressman/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O make/O a/O remark/O here/O ?/O 
Mr./O JAClKSOu/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O ./O 
Mr./O FLr/O `/O un/O ./O 
This/O is/O not/O just/O greased-pig/O stuff/O on/O my/O part/O when/O I/O say/O that/O my/O fundamental/O attraction/O to/O the/O party/O was/O not/O as/O a/O political/O party/O at/O all/O ./O 
It/O was/O fundamentally/O an/O endeavor/O at/O that/O time/O by/O many/O of/O us/O who/O were/O for/O the/O first/O time/O artists/O thrown/O into/O industry/O to/O try/O to/O arrive/O at/O some/O soit/O of/O adjustment/O between/O our/O personal/O problems/O brought/O up/O as/O artists/O and/O the/O problems/O of/O these/O fields/O that/O we/O were/O found/O in/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O resolve/O that/O ,/O we/O looked/O anywhere/O and/O every/O -/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2067/O where/O for/O any/O kind/O of/O thing/O that/O would/O help/O us/O out/O ./O 
So/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O certain/O commnion/O examination/O among/O these/O people/O with/O respect/O to/O that/O particular/O problem/O ,/O which/O was/O ,/O I/O remember/O ,/O the/O essence/O of/O all/O meetings/O ,/O and/O my/O sole/O interest/O in/O them/O ./O 
To/O that/O degree/O ,/O wily/O ,/O I/O found/O at/O that/O time/O some/O ,/O what/O I/O felt/O were/O ,/O fairly/O helpful/O and/O valid/O ideas/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O they/O were/O tile/O ideas/O as/O stiel/O or/O simply/O the/O opportunity/O to/O disciiu/O them/O and/O air/O them/O and/O dtll/O ss/O what/O to/O us/O was/O a/O very/O important/O problem/O ./O 
AMrJACKSON/O ./O 
In/O tie/O light/O of/O what/O lias/O ince/O tral/O `/O iilllred/O ,/O do/O you/O feel/O that/O there/O is/O any/O field/O of/O free/O explresion/O and/O self-determination/O for/O the/O arti-t/O ill/O coimmuniim/O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O certainly/O do/O noll/O ./O 
III/O fact/O ,/O I/O found/O that/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O r-aN/O oni/O why/O a/O very/O conscious/O and/O avid/O interest/O never/O developed/O on/O imn/O part/O ill/O following/O this/O thing/O through/O was/O because/O the/O basic/O philosophy/O in/O approaching/O the/O problem/O of/O an/O artist/O and/O his/O role/O in/O society/O wa/O entirely/O counter/O to/O that/O which/O I/O was/O able/O to/O think/O or/O that/O made/O enie/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O steps/O Hwere/O evel/O taken/O by/O anyone/O with/O respect/O to/O your/O work/O in/O the/O discussion/O group/O which/O might/O lead/O you/O to/O believe/O that/O an/O effort/O w/O as/O being/O made/O to/O influence/O your/O work/O ,/O to/O give/O it/O ,/O shall/O we/O say/O ,/O a/O social/O message/O Mr./O FLIA/O Ry/O ./O 
Absolutely/O none/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O J.AKSO-N/O ./O 
There/O ila/O no1/O effort/O on/O the/O part/O of/O anyonell/O MIr/O ./O 
FLI/O URY/O ./O 
No/O ,/O -/O ir/O ./O 
Mr./O J.ACKSON/O '/O A/O ./O 
Fleiy/O i/O as/O stated/O that/O sh/O e/O had/O disagreements/O with/O Bibeiian-Mr/O ./O 
FLEI/ORGANIZATION RY/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O had/O heard/O ailout/O them/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O .1/O X'KSON/O -LRB-/O continulig/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Over/O the/O approach/O of/O the/O artist/O to/O his/O w/O ork/O ./O 
I/O wondered/O \/O \/O hether/O you/O held/O any/O discussion/O with/O Mr./O Biberman/PERSON or/O anyone/O el-c/O in/O which/O that/O philosophy/O ,/O as/O it/O pertains/O to/O the/O artist/O and/O iis/O '/O work/O ,/O wa/O ,/O advanced/O ./O 
Mr./O Fi.LE/O `/O RY/O Yes/O :/O I/O think/O that/O on/O occasion/O the/O orthodox/O view/O ,/O because/O natural/O \/O it/O was/O also/O prominent/O in/O the/O literature/O which-I/O ca/O n't/O i-Plekhanov/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O who/O it/O was/O ;/O lie/O was/O even/O rebel/O ,/O -1/O ppo-ed/O to/O have/O been/O the/O great/O orthodox/O Marxist/O boy/O on/O art/O criticism/O ./O 
And/O thii/O to/O me/O was/O just/O simply/O ,/O if/O you/O will/O pardon/O the/O expression/O ,/O a/O red/O Iag/O ./O 
because/O I/O did/O n't/O believe/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O J./O 1/O \/O K-ON/O ./O 
Did/O lie/O addre-s/O at/O alnl/O tune/O a/O discusi-on/O group/O ?/O 
Oil/O ./O 
no/O ./O 
He/O is/O dead/O long/O ago/O ,/O 1890/O ,/O or/O something/O Mr./O Frviity/PERSON ./O 
like/O thliat/O ./O 
01/O right/O at/O the/O time/O of/O the/O so-called/O Russian/O Revolution/O ./O 
Pardon/O inil/O abysmal/O ignorance/O on/O that/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O J.CKiisiO/O Mr./O Fi/PERSON ,/O :/O m-R/O ./O 
That/O '/O -/O all/O i/O ight/O ./O 
Mr./O J/O \/O -LRB-/O KSiN/O Was/O it/O the/O cutoni/O to/O invite/O people/O in/O to/O talk/O to/O the/O lssion/O gioup/O oni/O o/O -LRB-/O caion/O on/O varioI/O ,/O phases/O of/O art/O ?/O 
dl/O </O l/O Mr./O FiuExRY/O As/O I/O remember/O ,/O no/O ./O 
This/O was/O all/O sort/O of/O a/O selfcontained/O thling/O right/O within/O itself/O ./O 
We/O would/O bounce/O off/O each/O other/O as/O sounding/O boards/O ./O 
isumethat/O ,/O in/O common/O with/O many/O of/O the/O AmeriMr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O a/O can/O people/O ,/O a/O great/O number/O of/O people/O ./O 
you/O followed/O the/O activities/O of/O this/O committee/O o/O -LRB-/O far/O as/O the/O witnesses/O we/O have/O had/O before/O un/O are/O concerned/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Inl/O a/O general/O wayi/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O met/O any/O of/O those/O who/O have/O been/O called/O as/O witnesses/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
2068/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
To/O my/O knowledge/O now/O ,/O no/O ;/O never/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O many/O of/O them/O I/O never/O heard/O of/O before/O until/O during/O the/O history/O of/O this/O thing/O when/O their/O names/O have/O become/O prominent/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O have/O not/O met/O on/O any/O occasion/O any/O of/O the/O witnesses/O we/O have/O had/O before/O us/O ?/O 
John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O met/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O never/O even/O heard/O of/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O meet/O any/O motion-picture/O people/O at/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
I/O am/O not/O talking/O about/O the/O cartoonists/O or/O those/O immediately/O concerned/O with/O animation/O ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O other/O fields/O of/O the/O motion-picture/O arts/O or/O the/O entertainment/O world/O in/O general/O represented/O at/O these/O meetings/O or/O was/O the/O membership/O strictly/O limited/O to/O those/O who/O were/O more/O or/O less/O and/O in/O one/O way/O or/O another/O connected/O with/O animation/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O purely/O animation/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O purely/O animation/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
IIn/O fact/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O we/O were/O probably/O considered/O pretty/O useless/O and/O not/O a/O very-how/O would/O you/O call/O it/O ?/O 
-/O solid/O party/O unit/O by/O any/O manner/O of/O means/O ,/O and/O we/O were/O very/O carefully/O kept/O segregated/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O amount/O of/O dues/O you/O paid/O ,/O and/O how/O were/O they/O paid/O ,/O on/O a/O monthly/O basis/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O remember/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O monthly/O basis/O and/O it/O had/O to/O do/O with/O the/O amount/O of/O your/O earnings/O ./O 
I/O know/O ours/O ,/O at/O least/O mine/O ,/O were/O damn/O small/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O also/O pay/O dues/O for/O Mrs./O Fleury/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
She/O paid/O her/O own/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
To/O whom/O were/O the/O dues/O paid/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O on/O occasion/O ,/O why/O ,/O Pomerantz/PERSON would/O pick/O them/O up/O ,/O or/O someone/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Those/O major/O four/O seemed/O to/O be/O the/O ones/O who/O mainly/O collected/O them/O ./O 
Actually/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O I/O was/O in/O arrears/O for/O most/O of/O the/O time/O that/O I/O was/O there/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O only/O paid/O about/O twice/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O about/O the/O amount/O of/O your/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O remember/O ,/O mine/O was/O under/O $/O 3/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
A/O month/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Very/O slight/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O asked/O at/O any/O time/O to/O introduce/O into/O the/O group/O any/O other/O person/O or/O persons/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O so/O many/O words/O ;/O no/O ./O 
There/O was/O none/O of/O tho/O business/O of/O us/O going/O out/O and/O selling/O ./O 
If/O we/O felt/O that/O anyone/O might/O possibly/O be/O interested/O ,/O why/O ,/O we/O were/O to/O invite/O them/O to/O come/O around/O ./O 
I/O never/O found/O anyone/O ./O 
Mr./O WHIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O given/O any/O assignments/O by/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mi/O '/O ./O 
WrIIELE/O ./O 
Sticlh/PERSON as/O a/O book/O to/O read/O on/O which/O to/O give/O a/O lecture/O ;/O ia/O a/O future/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Francis/PERSON de/PERSON Erdely/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Only/O as/O a/O naie/O I/O read/O in/O the/O newspapers/O and/O as/O an/O artist/O and/O teacher/O here/O in/O town/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
This/O John/PERSON McGrew/PERSON ,/O is/O it/O M-c/O G-r-e-w/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2069/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O at/O one/O time/O an/O instructor/O at/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEeURY/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O for/O a/O few/O weeks/O 1/O went/O over/O to/O the/O life/O class/O for/O about/O 8/O weeks/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O ./O 
Alr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O requested/O that/O you/O assume/O this/O position/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O tlink/O it/O was/O actually/O the/O fellow/O who/O was/O secretary/O ./O 
or/O something/O ,/O of/O the/O school/O ,/O called/O me/O because/O he/O had/O heard/O somehow/O that/O I/O was/O a/O life/O teacher/O and/O the/O actual/O person/O that/O was/O scheduled/O could/O n't/O make/O the/O thing/O and/O I/O was/O agreeable/O to/O the/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Wlho/PERSON was/O the/O individual/O in/O charge/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O a/O name/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
It/O would/O have/O to/O be-in/O fact/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O even/O remember/O the/O dates/O when/O I/O did/O teach/O these/O things/O ./O 
If/O you/O can/O tell/O me/O the/O dates/O ,/O why/O ,/O maybe/O I/O can/O find/O out/O generally/O or/O think/O back/O and/O see/O if/O I/O can/O find/O out/O what/O his/O name/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was-in/O charge/O ?/O 
That/O is/O ,/O who/O was/O in/O direct/O hliarge/O of/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FLEI'RY/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O name/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O secretary/O that/O was/O in/O charge/O of/O the/O school/O ./O 
A/O young/O guy/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O his/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O if/O this/O individual/O was/O Sidney/PERSON Davidson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O subscribe/O to/O the/O People/O 's/O Daily/O World/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O during/O your/O membership/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Before/O the/O war/O ,/O certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O you/O were/O solicited/O to/O subscribe/O for/O this/O paper/O ?/O 
Mr./O F.EURY/O ./O 
Well/O ./O 
actually/O I/O have/O been/O buying/O it/O on/O the/O newsstand/O and/O just/O took/O a/O subscription/O because/O it/O was/O easier/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
At/O these/O meetings/O you/O attended/O did/O they/O sell/O literature/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sure/O ;/O there/O was/O always/O something/O being/O brought/O around/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O nature/O of/O this/O literature/O ?/O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O be/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O ;/O it/O would/O be/O New/O Masses/O magazine-that/O kind/O of/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O make/O the/O recommendation/O that/O either/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON or/O Mrs./O Fleury/PERSON testify/O at/O the/O hearings/O starting/O September/O 17/O ./O 
At/O the/O present/O time/O my/O personal/O reaction/O is/O that/O perhaps/O Mrs./O Fleury/PERSON should/O testify/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O is/O so/O ordered/O ./O 
The/O subpena/O will/O be/O extended/O ,/O and/O you/O will/O notify/O her/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O set/O the/O date/O for/O Mrs./O Fleury/PERSON for/O Thursday/O ,/O September/O 20/O ,/O at/O 2/O p./O m./O Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Congressman/O ,/O is/O n't/O there/O anyone/O else/O in/O southern/O California/LOCATION who/O could/O do/O this/O besides/O my/O wife/O and/O myself/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O very/O frankly-and/O I/O am/O only/O expressing/O my/O own/O opinion-I/O am/O not/O convinced/O that/O the/O measure/O of/O your/O cooperation/O has/O been/O full/O and/O complete/O ./O 
It/O is/O inconceivable/O to/O me/O that/O one/O person/O or/O two/O people/O could/O be/O associated/O over/O the/O period/O of/O a/O year/O ,/O 2070/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O attend/O a/O number/O of/O meetings/O ,/O including/O one/O in/O your/O own/O home/O ,/O and/O be/O unable/O ,/O out/O of/O that/O association/O ,/O to/O remember/O more/O than/O the/O four/O or/O five/O individuals/O whom/O you/O have/O named/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O those/O are/O the/O names/O that/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O and/O I/O can/O do/O no/O more/O about/O that/O ./O 
After/O all/O ,/O this/O was/O how/O long/O ago/O ?/O 
Nine/O years/O ago/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O matter/O within/O your/O own/O mind/O ,/O obviously/O ,/O over/O which/O we/O have/O no/O control/O ./O 
If/O you/O sincerely/O can/O not/O remember/O more/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O that/O is/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O make/O the/O remark/O that/O if/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON and/O Mrs./O Fleury/PERSON discuss/O this/O more/O fully/O in/O the/O next/O couple/O of/O days/O ,/O and/O if/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON wants/O to/O contact/O me/O or/O reappear/O before/O us/O after/O he/O has/O additional/O time/O to/O think/O it/O over/O ,/O perhaps/O he/O could/O testify/O ,/O rather/O than/O his/O wife/O ,/O if/O he/O desires/O to/O do/O that/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O our/O policy/O to/O call/O both/O the/O husband/O and/O the/O wife/O before/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O the/O final/O decision/O must/O rest/O in/O the/O hands/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O purely/O a/O preliminary/O investigation/O ./O 
I/O would/O suggest/O ,/O pending/O a/O discussion/O with/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O upon/O their/O arrival/O ,/O that/O the/O subpena/O be/O held/O open/O until/O such/O time/O as/O the/O matter/O can/O be/O discussed/O at/O greater/O length/O with/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O ./O 
If/O you/O will/O ,/O Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O keep/O in/O touch/O with/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON in/O the/O event/O that/O you/O change/O your/O address/O ,/O or/O in/O order/O that/O he/O may/O be/O able/O to/O contact/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O let/O both/O subpenas/O remain/O open/O until/O a/O decision/O is/O made/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O so/O ordered/O ;/O the/O subpenas/O will/O remain/O open/O ./O 
If/O in/O the/O interim/O ,/O and/O after/O fuller/O discussion/O of/O the/O matter/O ,/O there/O is/O any/O further/O information/O which/O you/O feel/O you/O can/O give/O the/O committee/O ,/O you/O can/O communicate/O with/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON at/O the/O Roosevelt/O Hotel/O ./O 
Mr./O FLERY/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O very/O much/O ,/O instead/O of/O asking/O me/O to/O volunteer/O information/O ,/O to/O at/O least/O have/O specific/O questions/O that/O I/O get/O a/O chance/O to/O answer/O ,/O because/O actually/O this/O is/O so/O remote/O and/O so/O forgotten/O that/O I/O simply/O do/O not/O remember/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fleury/PERSON ,/O the/O matter/O of/O the/O identification/O of/O people/O who/O were/O associated/O with/O you/O in/O this/O activity/O at/O that/O time/O is/O a/O matter/O that/O is/O within/O your/O knowledge/O and/O not/O necessarily/O within/O the/O knowledge/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
I/O say/O that/O much/O of/O the/O information/O which/O has/O already/O been/O given/O is/O information/O which/O is/O already/O in/O the/O possession/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
We/O are/O looking/O for/O additional/O information/O and/O ,/O quite/O frankly/O ,/O information/O which/O may/O not/O be/O in/O the/O possession/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O FLEURY/PERSON ./O 
Naturally/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
So/O far/O as/O the/O identifications/O are/O concerned/O ,/O that/O is/O a/O matter/O which/O is/O entirely/O within/O your/O own/O discretion/O ./O 
I/O would/O hope/O that/O upon/O further/O consideration-and/O I/O realize/O how/O repugnant/O it/O is/O to/O the/O average/O person/O to/O disclose/O names/O ,/O dates/O ,/O and/O places/O ;/O but/O that/O is/O the/O sum/O and/O substance/O of/O the/O things/O we/O must/O have/O if/O we/O are/O to/O carry/O this/O investigation/O through/O to/O a/O successful/O conclusion-again/O I/O would/O hope/O that/O after/O further/O discussion/O both/O of/O you/O can/O refresh/O your/O memories/O to/O the/O extent/O that/O you/O can/O contact/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON and/O give/O us/O some/O additional/O information/O with/O respect/O to/O those/O who/O were/O active/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O 1IOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2071/O in/O the/O CPA/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
In/O the/O meanwhile/O the/O subpenas/O will/O be/O held/O open/O and/O extended/O awaiting/O the/O will/O and/O pleasure/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O until/O tomorrow/O morning/O at/O 9:30/O ./O 
AFTERNOON/O SESSION/O -LRB-/O The/O following/O sworn/O statement/O of/O Anne/PERSON Ray/PERSON Frank/PERSON was/O given/O at/O 2:45/O p./O m./O to/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O committee/O investigator/O ./O -RRB-/O 
STATEMENT/O OF/O ANNE/PERSON RAY/PERSON FRANK/PERSON Will/PERSON you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Anne/PERSON Ray/PERSON Frank/PERSON Mr./PERSON WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
245/O Parkwood/ORGANIZATION Drive/ORGANIZATION ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION 24/O ./O 
Mr./O WHlEELER/O ./O 
You/O tie/O appearing/O before/O the/O committee/O under/O subpena/O ;/O is/O that/O col/O rect/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEEI/PERSON ,/O `/O ER/O ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O WtIIEELEi/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Pittsburgh/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O us/O a/O brief/O r6sume/O of/O your/O educational/O background/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Public/O schools/O in/O Pennsylvauia/LOCATION and/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O and/O Fairfax/LOCATION High/O Sc/O `/O hool/O was/O my/O last/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O your/O educational/O background/O been/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O work/O in/O 1930/O foithe/O Charles/PERSON R./PERSON Hadley/PERSON Co./O ;/O in/O 1935/O I/O went/O to/O work/O for/O the/O Richfield/ORGANIZATION Oil/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O was/O at/O Hadley/PERSON for/O I/O worked/O a/O week/O for/O Sam/PERSON 5/O years/O ,/O Richfield/PERSON from/O 19:35/O to/O 11942/O In/O 1942/O I/O went/O to/O work/O for/O MCA/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O Goldwyn/PERSON as/O a/O secretary/O secretary/O ./O 
In/O 1943/O I/O wiote/O for/O radio/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O know/O wlio/O I/O worked/O foi/O in/O radio/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Please/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
1/O was/O a/O contributing/O writer/O to/O the/O F./O Hugh/PERSON Herbert/PERSON show/O ,/O Meet/O Corliss/PERSON Archei/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O did/O fiee-lance/O radio/O writing/O for/O the/O next/O year/O and/O a/O half/O ./O 
Mr./O WHrLELR/O ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O married/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANKt/O Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WVHEELER/PERSON ./O 
To/O whoun/O ale/O you/O married/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON Melvin/PERSON Frank/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WiIEELER/O ./O 
What/O is/O Mi/O Frank/PERSON 's/O occupationu/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O WHLELER/PERSON ./O 
Wlien/O Mis/O ./O 
FRANK/O ./O 
January/O married/O were/O youi/O to/O Mr./O Frank/PERSON ?/O 
22/O ,/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Ale/O you/O known/O professionally/O as/O Anne/PERSON Ray/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O known/O professionally/O as/O Atne/O Ray/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEEI/PERSON 1R/O ./O 
Miss/O Ray/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O WTHEEILER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O when/O you/O first/O joined/O the/O Communist/O \//O Party/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Thie/O exact/O moth/O I/O ca/O n't/O tell/O you/O ./O 
Somewhere/O in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
2072/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O you/O were/O introduced/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Through/O a/O friend/O of/O mine/O ,/O Mrs./O Meta/PERSON Rosenberg/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O taken/O to/O a/O Commumst/O Party/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
YoU/O subsequently/O joined/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
And/O I/O subsequently/O joined/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O particular/O group/O or/O unit/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O for/O any/O period/O of/O time/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1943/O there/O were/O two/O or/O three/O meetings/O that/O I/O went/O to/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O where/O the/O ,/O -/O meetings/O were/O held/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Somewhere/O north/O of/O Franklin/LOCATION near/O Western/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O at/O whose/O home/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
MIr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O was/O present/O at/O these/O initial/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ,/O simply/O because/O these/O were/O ,/O I/O was/O led/O to/O believe/O ,/O radio/O people/O ./O 
I/O never/O saw/O them/O before/O and/O never/O saw/O them/O afterward/O ./O 
They/O were/O all/O sti/O angers/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O first/O assigned/O to/O a/O radio/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O never/O was/O formally/O assigned/O to/O anything/O ./O 
There/O were/O radio/O writers/O '/O problems/O discussed/O here/O ,/O joining/O the/O guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELE/PERSON ,/O ./O 
R./O For/O what/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O remain/O with/O this/O radio/O writers/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O two/O or/O three/O meetings/O ,/O and/O how/O long/O ,/O over/O what/O period/O of/O time/O I/O really/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O recall/O anyone/O in/O this/O first/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
They/O are/O all/O strangers/O to/O me/O ./O 
I/O was/O working/O in/O MCA/ORGANIZATION from/O 10/O o'clock/O in/O the/O morning/O until/O 7/O in/O the/O evening/O ,/O then/O I/O was/O working/O ,/O I/O was/O writing/O these/O radio/O scripts/O for/O F./O Hugh/PERSON Herbert/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O my/O first/O entrance/O into/O knowing/O anybody/O in/O radio/O at/O all/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O radio/O workers/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O anybody/O who/O was/O working/O for/O radio/O ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O included/O in/O a/O group/O because/O this/O was/O ,/O if/O I/O can/O phrase/O it/O a/O little/O bit/O better-I/O was/O n't/O officially/O in/O radio/O work/O ./O 
My/O relationship/O with/O F./PERSON Hugh/PERSON Herbert/PERSON was/O one/O in/O which/O I/O assisted/O him/O in/O connection/O with/O his/O literary/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O previously/O testified/O that/O you/O attended/O two/O or/O three/O meetings/O comprised/O of/O people/O in/O the/O radio/O industry/O ./O 
Were/O you/O subsequently/O transferred/O to/O another/O group/O or/O did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O of/O another/O group/O at/O any/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Three/O or/O four/O months/O after/O I/O joined/O the/O party/O I/O left/O for/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
While/O I/O was/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION I/O had/O no/O contact/O whatsoever/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O any/O other/O political/O organization/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O November/O 1943/O ,/O where/O I/O resumed/O my/O radio/O work/O ./O 
The/O pressure/O of/O this/O work/O and/O my/O romantic/O involvement/O with/O the/O man/O who/O has/O since/O become/O my/O husband/O precluded/O my/O attending/O party/O meetings/O ./O 
In/O January/O 1944/O I/O was/O married/O ./O 
Shortly/O after/O that/O I/O resumed/O attending/O meetings/O ./O 
It/O was/O then/O that/O I/O first/O told/O my/O husband/O about/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O ./O 
Over/O his/O strenuous/O objections/O to/O my/O membership/O I/O continued/O the/O meetings/O ./O 
My/O attendance/O was/O occasional/O and/O irregular/O ,/O however/O ,/O amounting/O to/O no/O more/O than/O six/O or/O seven/O in/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O where/O these/O meetings/O were/O held/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLT/LOCATION WOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2073/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
They/O were/O held/O ,/O with/O the/O except/O ion/O of/O perhaps/O one/O ,/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Dalton/ORGANIZATION Trumbo/ORGANIZATION in/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELEr/PERSON ./O 
Do/O oMI/O recall/O where/O the/O other/O one/O was/O held/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O other/O one/O was/O held/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Ring/O Lardner/O ,/O Jr./O ,/O in/O Westwood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O the/O individuals/O who/O attended/O these/O meetings/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
But/O since/O at/O about/O this/O time/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O dissolved/O and/O became/O Instead/O an/O organization/O known/O as/O the/O Communist/O Political/O Asciation/O ,/O and/O since/O thie/O meetings/O of/O the/O association/O were/O open/O and/O for/O purposes/O of/O recruiting/O it/O was/O impossible/O then/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O impossible/O now/O ,/O to/O know/O just/O which/O of/O these/O people/O were/O party/O members/O and/O which/O were/O guests/O ./O 
However/O ,/O there/O did/O seem/O to/O le/O a/O small/O group/O wliho/O were/O at/O all/O the/O meetings/O that/O I/O was/O at/O ./O 
I/O assumed/O then/O ,/O and/O I/O assume/O now/O ,/O that/O they/O were/O at/O that/O time/O members/O of/O thie/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O vno/O identify/O these/O individuals/O ?/O 
tMr/O ./O 
Triumbo/PERSON and/O Mr./O Lardner/PERSON I/O Mrs./O FRANK/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O would/O -/O Iaythis/O group/O consisted/O of/O Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON ,/O Paul/PERSON Jarrico/PERSON ,/O Gordon/PERSON Kahn/PERSON ,/O Haiold/PERSON Buchiman/PERSON ,/O and/O Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ./O 
I/O also/O remember/O being/O impressed/O with/O thile/O eloquence/O of/O two/O guest/O speakers/O ,/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON and/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ./O 
lMr.WHEELER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O remlneber/O what/O iMr.Lawson/O and/O Mr./O Maltz/PERSON discussed/O e/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O dues/O to/O this/O group/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O did/O ./O 
MIr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O much/O your/O dues/O were/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O assessed/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O my/O being/O a/O housewife/O and/O miv/O dues/O were/O 2.7/O cent/O ,/O a/O week/O ,/O whether/O I/O attended/O the/O meetings/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O to/O whom/O you/O paid/O the/O money/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O because/O it/O was/O a/O different/O person/O each/O time/O ./O 
There/O would/O be/O a/O period/O of/O time/O when/O someone/O would/O be/O the/O dues/O chairman/O and/O then/O there/O would/O be/O another/O time/O when/O someone/O would/O be/O a/O dues/O chairman/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O youi/O related/O to/O the/O former/O Mrs./O Budd/PERSON Schulberg/PERSON ,/O now/O Virginia/PERSON Veitel/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
She/O is/O my/O sister/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
DI/O -RRB-/O you/O know/O liet/O a/O ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Wienll/PERSON you/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION did/O you/O use/O a/O name/O other/O than/O the/O name/O Anne/PERSON Ray/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr/O '/O ./O 
WIIEELER/O ./O 
According/O to/O tlie/O records/O of/O the/O committee/O you/O were/O registered/O in/O thie/O -LRB-/O Conmnist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION under/O the/O name/O of/O Adelaide/LOCATION C/O -LRB-/O I/O umley/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O kidding/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O your/O knowledge/O you/O have/O never/O used/O the/O name/O Adelaide/PERSON Crumley/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O hear/O it/O before/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Never/O ./O 
93012-52-pt/O --/O 4/O 2074/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Additional/O information/O developed/O by/O the/O committee/O reflects/O that/O in/O 1944/O you/O were/O issued/O CP/O Card/O No./O 36106/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O of/O ever/O having/O been/O issued/O a/O card/O '/O Mrs./O FRANK/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WVIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O registering/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FR/O NXK.No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
I/O got/O a/O card/O and/O I/O tore/O it/O up/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Thle/O card/O was/O in/O your/O real/O name/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
T/O Mr/O W/O HEELER/O ./O 
While/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Commnist/O Party/O do/O you/O recall/O if/O any/O literature/O was/O distributed/O during/O the/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O what/O literature/O \//O Mr/O ,/O ./O 
FRI'NIXK/O ./O 
People/O 's/O World/O ,/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O subscribe/O to/O the/O Daily/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Mrs./ORGANIZATION FR/O \/O NK/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O subscribe/O to/O it/O ./O 
I/O might/O have/O subscribed/O to/O it/O ./O 
I/O lelnmember/O mostly/O buying/O it/O at/O news-tands/O but/O I/O might/O have/O sub-cribed/O to/O it/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O be/O truthful/O ./O 
It/O is/O certainly/O possible/O that/O I/O subscribed/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O Wii.iLELR/O ./O 
Were/O yon/O ever/O given/O an/O assigilnent/O by/O the/O Commuist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O make/O a/O study/O of/O any/O given/O subject/O and/O later/O give/O a/O lecture/O 9/O on/O it/O before/O thl/O group/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O what/O was/O generally/O dicu-esed/O at/O the'e/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O evening/O went/O something/O like/O this/O :/O First/O there/O would/O be/O discussion/O of/O the/O agenda/O ./O 
which/O was/O ended/O and/O then/O there/O would/O be/O a/O discussion/O of/O current/O event/O ./O 
For/O in-tance/O ,/O theie/O would/O be/O an/O analysis/O of/O what/O was/O presently/O happening/O in/O the/O war/O ,/O then/O a/O discussion/O of/O local/O problems/O ./O 
I/O remember/O particularly/O one/O time/O talking/O about/O raising/O money/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O Mexicans/O in/O the/O Sleepy/O Lagoon/O case/O ,/O the/O Sleepy/O Lagoon/O Defense/O Conmminttee/O ./O 
Then/O we/O would/O talk/O about/O the/O elections-this/O was/O an/O election/O year-and/O what/O we/O could/O do/O on/O a/O city/O ,/O State/O ,/O and/O national/O basis/O to/O elect/O candidates/O of/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
9/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Miss/O Ray/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O spring/O of/O 1943/O the/O world/O was/O at/O war/O and/O I/O had/O very/O strong/O feelings/O about/O the/O issues/O involved/O ./O 
I/O was/O strongly/O antiHitler/O ,/O anti-Mussolini/O ./O 
anti-Franco/O and/O pro-Roosevelt/O ./O 
I/O wanted/O then/O what/O I/O want/O now/O ,/O a/O better/O world/O for/O the/O people/O in/O it/O ./O 
I/O believed/O in/O Franklin/LOCATION Delano/LOCATION Roosevelt/LOCATION and/O all/O he/O stood/O for/O ./O 
I/O was/O against/O racial/O discrimination/O and/O for/O social/O security/O ,/O economic/O security/O ./O 
p/O ublic/O health/O ,/O and/O universal/O education/O ./O 
In/O those/O days/O I/O felt/O a/O peculiar/O sense/O of/O frustration/O at/O not/O being/O able/O to/O do/O enough/O to/O bring/O about/O this/O better/O world/O ./O 
I/O was/O led/O to/O believe/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION wanted/O the/O same/O things/O that/O I/O did/O ,/O and/O in/O addition/O were/O doing/O something/O about/O it/O ./O 
That/O is/O why/O I/O joined/O ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O leave/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRxNKi/O ./O 
MVy/O husband/O was/O violently/O opposed/O to/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O paity/O ./O 
We/O argued/O constantly/O the/O first/O few/O months/O of/O our/O marriage/O ./O 
It/O was/O his/O point/O that/O one/O could/O be/O anti-Hitler/O and/O pro-Roosevelt/O ,/O in/O fact/O all/O the/O things/O I/O believed/O in/O ,/O without/O being/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O organization/O which/O I/O began/O to/O realize/O was/O inordinately/O concerned/O with/O the/O welfare/O of/O the/O Soviet/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2075/O Union/O ./O 
I/O found/O that/O I/O had/O no/O answers/O for/O the/O questions/O he/O asked/O ,/O I/O found/O no/O way/O to/O justify/O or/O reconcile/O a/O police/O state/O ,/O a/O controlled/O press/O ,/O one-party/O elections/O and/O secret/O police/O with/O the/O concepts/O of/O freedom/O and/O democracy/O ,/O both/O of/O which/O are/O the/O main/O requirements/O for/O what/O I/O considered/O to/O be/O a/O decent/O society/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O I/O discovered/O that/O tin/O words/O ``/O democracy/O ''/O and/O ``/O freedom/O '/O were/O just/O words/O as/O far/O as/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O concerned/O ./O 
I/O found/O nothing/O democratic/O in/O tthe/O wax/O the/O meetings/O were/O held/O ./O 
Nothing/O was/O ever/O voted/O upon/O hy/O the/O membership/O ,/O we/O were/O merely/O told/O what/O the/O line/O at/O the/O moment/O would/O be/O and/O that/O was/O that/O ./O 
1/O began/O to/O find/O their/O rigidity/O of/O thinking/O intolerable/O ./O 
I/O found/O that/O anyone/O w/O ho/O in/O any/O way/O differed/O with/O whatever/O the/O party/O line/O happened/O to/O b/O e/O at/O tlie/O moment/O `/O as/O immediately/O and/O automatically/O termed/O either/O a/O Trotskvite/O ,/O a/O Fascist/O ,/O a/O reactionary/O ,/O or/O a/O confused/O liberal/O ./O 
As/O 1/O understand/O what/O the/O structure/O of/O the/O party/O was/O ,/O the/O way/O it/O was/O explained/O ti/O ,/O me/O ./O 
was/O that/O the/O mass/O of/O the/O members/O w/O ere/O the/O bottom/O elected/O other/O member/O ./O 
the/O pyramid/O n/O of/O a/O pyramid/O and/O as/O them/O members/O got/O smaller/O and/O theie/O was/O a/O guy/O at/O the/O top/O ,/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON ./O 
But/O it/O never/O walked/O that/O way/O as/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O ./O 
The/O masses/O did/O n't/O and/O then/O the/O guy/O at/O the/O head/O carried/O out/O the/O orders/O vote/O on/O someth/O i/O of/O the/O people/O the/O Nayv/O the/O President/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION does/O ./O 
It/O came/O from/O this/O guy/O at/O the/O top/O and/O trickled/O down/O and/O there/O it/O was/O ./O 
and/O that/O was/O that/O ./O 
You/O got/O the/O feeling/O that/O if/O you/O did/O vote/O on/O somemake/O a/O lot/O of/O difference/O anyway/O ./O 
thing/O it/O would/O n't/O 1/O Mr./O JWI/PERSON EELLR/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O completely/O sever/O your/O relationship/O or/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION Mrs./O FuiANK/O ./O 
Some/O time/O easily/O in/O 1945/O after/O I/O had/O n't/O gone/O to/O meetings/O for/O months/O ,/O Harold/PERSON Buchman/PERSON came/O to/O my/O house/O and/O asked/O me/O why/O I/O had/O stopped/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O did/O you/O tell/O him/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O told/O him/O I/O decided/O to/O quit/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O Buchman/PERSON agreed/O it/O was/O my/O right/O to/O do/O so/O and/O after/O he/O left/O the/O house/O I/O never/O again/O had/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WnHEELER/O ./O 
Miss/O Bay/O ,/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O ./O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WhIEELER/O ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O a/O pupil/O or/O instructor/O at/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O took/O two/O courses/O in/O history/O at/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O instructor/O ?/O 
his/O Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
I/O recall/O what/O he/O looks/O like/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O did/O he/O look/O like/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
He/O had/O an/O English/O accent/O and/O he/O wore/O old-school/O wore/O ties/O and/O he/O was/O a/O very/O round/O guy/O ,/O had/O quite/O a/O potbelly/O and/O peculiar/O vests/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O his/O name/O ./O 
2076/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION AntiFascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O contributed/O to/O any/O of/O the/O organizations/O which/O I/O have/O named/O ?/O 
Mrs./O FRANK/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O searched/O my/O records/O and/O I/O found/O that/O I/O wrote/O thile/O following/O checks/O to/O the/O organizations/O you/O named/O and/O to/O some/O of/O the/O following/O ./O 
The/O entire/O list/O in/O chronological/O order/O is/O as/O follows/O :/O January/O 17/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 10/O to/O the/O Labor/ORGANIZATION Herald/ORGANIZATION ;/O February/O 21/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 8.80/O ,/O Sleepy/ORGANIZATION Lagoon/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ;/O March/O 4/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 8.15/O to/O the/O Rusmsan/O War/O Relief/O :/O March/O 6/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 2.77/O to/O the/O Russian/O War/O Relief/O ;/O April/O 7/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 1U/O ,/O American/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ;/O June/O 5/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 5/O ,/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ;/O June/O 14/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 12/O ,/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ;/O June/O 1.5/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O $/O 5/O ./O 
Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ;/O and/O October/O 5/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O '/O $/O ;/O ,/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O is/O the/O list/O of/O the/O organizations/O to/O which/O I/O contributed/O and/O which/O may/O now/O be/O on/O the/O Attorney/O General/O 's/O list/O of/O subversive/O organizations/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O may/O be/O excused/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O witness/O was/O excused/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O The/O following/O sworn/O statement/O was/O then/O made/O by/O Eve/PERSON Ettinger/PERSON to/O William/PERSON A/PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O committee/O investigator/O ./O -RRB-/O 
STATEMENT/O OF/O EVE/O ETTINGER/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
Eve/O Ettinger/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
New/O York-Manhattan/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O present/O address/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
330/O South/O Almont/O Drive/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION 48/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O here/O pursuant/O to/O subpena/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O are/O you/O presently/O employed/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
At/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O position/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O story/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O relate/O briefly/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O graduated/O from/O public/O school/O and/O high/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O relate/O your/O employment/O record/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION for/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O it/O is/O 15/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O employed/O before/O going/O to/O work/O for/O Columbia/LOCATION ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
For/O a/O short/O while/O I/O was/O at/O Paramount/O as/O a/O secretary/O ,/O then/O I/O came/O to/O Columbia/LOCATION as/O a/O reader/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
For/O a/O period/O of/O time/O you/O were/O employed/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION by/O these/O organizations/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
By/O Columbia/LOCATION ./O 
Up/O until/O May/O 1945/O I/O worked/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O work/O for/O Paramount/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O also/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2077/O Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O just/O got/O out/O of/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Readers/O '/O Guild/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O also/O known/O as/O the/O Screen/O Analysts/O '/O Guild/O ,/O either/O before/O the/O Screen/O Readers/O '/O Guild/O or/O after/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O I/O say/O I/O think/O so/O ./O 
I/O must/O tell/O you/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O a/O reader/O for/O not/O too/O long/O a/O time/O ./O 
I/O never/O thought/O of/O it/O until/O you/O brought/O it/O up/O ./O 
I/O forgot/O that/O there/O was/O a/O Screen/O Readers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Miss/O Ettinger/PERSON ,/O a/O witness/O has/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O has/O given/O testimony/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O the/O witness/O knew/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O to/O affirm/O or/O deny/O that/O statement/O ?/O 
Miss/O ETTINGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
I/O have/O also/O tried/O to/O tell/O Mr./O Gang/PERSON ,/O my/O attorney/O ,/O that/O I/O honestly/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ,/O and/O yet/O I/O must/O have/O had/O a/O party/O card/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O remember/O carrying/O one/O or/O having/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O Wi/PERSON IFELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whlien/O you/O first/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O ETTIN/O -LRB-/O i./O '/O ./O 
