COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 4/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O SEPTEMBER/O 17/O ,/O 18/O ,/O AND/O 19/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 81596/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1951/O fA/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION MORGAN/LOCATION M./LOCATION MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION Tennessee/LOCATION JR./O ,/O JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O FRANK/PERSON S./PERSON TAVENNER/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O LOUIS/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O SPECIAL/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O APPOINTED/O TO/O SIT/O IN/O Los/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O To/O HOLD/O HEARINGS/O ON/O THIS/O SUBJECT/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION 1/O CONTENTS/O September/O 17,1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O :/O Harold/PERSON J./PERSON Ashe/PERSON ---------------------/O ------/O Mildred/PERSON Ashe/PERSON -------------------------------------/O Michael/PERSON Gordon/PERSON ./O 
----------/O Charles/PERSON Daggett/PERSON -----------------------------/O --/O --/O Page/O 1415/O 14C0/O __/O 1480/O 1486/O ---------/O Percy/PERSON Solotoy/PERSON ---------------------/O September/O 18/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O :/O Henry/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ------------------------------/O Howland/PERSON Chamberlin/PERSON ------------------------/O Leo/PERSON Towsend/PERSON -----/O ---------/O 1490/O 1495/O 1503/O -------------/O 1506/O Dr./O Leo/PERSON Bigelman/PERSON --------------------------/O Helen/PERSON Slote/PERSON Levitt/PERSON ----------------------------------/O 1542/O 1549/O Alfred/PERSON Levitt/PERSON ------------------------------/O Bess/PERSON Taffel/PERSON ---------/O _/O -------------/O Herbert/PERSON Arthur/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
./O 
------------------------/O 1552/O 1560/O 1562/O September/O 19,1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O :/O Martin/LOCATION Berkeley/LOCATION ----------/O -/O Philip/PERSON Edward/PERSON Stevenson/PERSON ./O 
./O 
--/O Daniel/PERSON Lewis/PERSON James/PERSON ./O 
------/O --------/O --/O ./O 
--/O .../O -----/O ./O 
-/O ./O 
Lilith/ORGANIZATION James/ORGANIZATION ---------------/O Georgia/ORGANIZATION Backus/ORGANIZATION Alexander/ORGANIZATION -/O ----------------/O 1576/O 1613/O -------/O ------------/O _/O 1622/O 1631/O 1635/O -------/O MM/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 4/O MONDAY/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
A/O Subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 9/O :/O 50/O a./O m./O in/O room/O 518/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ./O 
senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ;/O and/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O wil/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Please/O let/O the/O record/O disclose/O that/O acting/O under/O the/O authority/O vested/O in/O me/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O have/O designated/O a/O subcommittee/O to/O continue/O the/O hearings/O that/O were/O initiated/O in/O March/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
That/O subcommittee/O consists/O of/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON of/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Mr./O Potter/PERSON of/O Michigan/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O present/O of/O that/O subcommittee/O all/O of/O them/O except/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O whose/O presence/O is/O expected/O momentarily/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O take/O advantage/O of/O this/O opportunity/O to/O express/O thanks/O and/O appreciation/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O to/O Mr./O James/PERSON J./PERSON Boyle/PERSON ,/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O for/O the/O southern/O district/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O for/O the/O efficient/O manner/O in/O which/O he/O has/O performed/O the/O duties/O of/O his/O office/O in/O serving/O subpenas/O for/O the/O attendance/O of/O witnesses/O at/O this/O hearing/O ;/O Mr./O E./PERSON F./PERSON Stillwell/PERSON ,/O the/O superintendent/O of/O the/O building/O ,/O for/O his/O splendid/O cooperation/O in/O making/O facilities/O available/O to/O us/O ;/O and/O to/O the/O Signal/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION for/O making/O this/O public-address/O system/O available/O to/O us/O at/O these/O hearings/O ./O 
I/O would/O also/O like/O to/O express/O the/O appreciation/O of/O the/O committee/O for/O the/O splendid/O cooperation/O of/O many/O other/O of/O the/O citizen/O groups/O and/O organizations/O in/O and/O around/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION for/O their/O many/O expressions/O of/O cooperation/O and/O splendid/O assistance/O ,/O including/O the/O press/O ,/O radio/O ,/O television/O ,/O and/O many/O private/O groups/O and/O indvduals/O ./O 
In/O this/O connection/O I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O one/O of/O the/O communications/O which/O is/O typical/O of/O the/O character/O of/O the/O cooperation/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O received/O and/O is/O receiving/O in/O its/O efforts/O here/O to/O make/O an/O investigation/O in/O subversive/O influences/O ,/O particularly/O in/O the/O field/O of/O enter1415/O 1416/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O tainment/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O the/O following/O letter/O directed/O to/O me/O as/O chairman/O under/O date/O of/O today/O which/O has/O just/O been/O handed/O to/O me/O ./O 
-LSB-/O Reading/O :]/O DEAR/O MR./O WOOD/O :/O With/O regard/O to/O the/O hearings/O of/O the/O Un-American/O Activities/O Committee/O which/O start/O September/O 17/O ,/O we/O beg/O to/O call/O your/O attention/O to/O the/O following/O :/O The/O signatories/O to/O this/O letter/O comprise/O the/O representatives/O of/O the/O producers/O ,/O actors/O ,/O writers/O ,/O directors/O ,/O and/O practically/O all/O of/O the/O guilds/O and/O unions/O whose/O members/O are/O engaged/O in/O the/O production/O of/O motion/O pictures/O ,/O and/O which/O ,/O together/O ,/O constitute/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O March/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O this/O organization/O stated/O :/O `/O The/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION reaffirms/O its/O consistent/O opposition/O to/O communism/O ,/O its/O works/O ,/O its/O members/O ,/O its/O methods/O ./O 
It/O wants/O to/O emphasize/O that/O ,/O with/O the/O overwhelming/O majority/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O ,/O it/O believes/O that/O a/O `/O clear/O and/O present/O danger/O '/O to/O our/O Nation/O exists/O ./O 
The/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION offers/O its/O strength/O and/O support/O to/O any/O legally/O constituted/O body/O that/O has/O as/O its/O object/O the/O exposure/O and/O destruction/O of/O the/O international/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION conspiracy/O ./O ''/O 
Our/O position/O is/O no/O different/O today/O than/O it/O was/O earlier/O in/O the/O year/O when/O the/O March/O 21st/O statement/O was/O made/O ./O 
The/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION speaks/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O motion/O picture/O industry/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
We/O wish/O to/O make/O crystal/O clear/O our/O complete/O repudiation/O of/O the/O Arts/O ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION and/O any/O right/O of/O that/O organization/O to/O speak/O for/O any/O branch/O of/O the/O motion/O picture/O industry/O in/O attacking/O the/O purposes/O and/O objectives/O of/O your/O body/O ./O 
Statements/O have/O been/O made/O that/O there/O has/O been/O resistance/O to/O the/O employment/O of/O individuals/O because/O of/O their/O activity/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O communism/O ./O 
We/O declare/O such/O statements/O to/O be/O completely/O untrue/O ./O 
It/O is/O our/O understanding/O that/O a/O number/O of/O witnesses/O have/O been/O subpenaed/O to/O testify/O before/O your/O body/O ./O 
This/O country/O is/O engaged/O in/O a/O war/O with/O communism/O ./O 
Eighty-seven/O thousand/O American/LOCATION casualties/O leave/O little/O room/O for/O witnesses/O to/O stand/O on/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ;/O and/O for/O those/O who/O do/O ,/O we/O have/O no/O sympathy/O ./O 
We/O commend/O and/O encourage/O those/O who/O testify/O to/O their/O complete/O repudiation/O of/O communism/O and/O effectively/O demonstrate/O their/O loyalty/O to/O our/O country/O ./O 
It/O is/O our/O hope/O that/O witnesses/O will/O testify/O honestly/O ,/O freely/O and/O fully/O ,/O in/O cooperation/O with/O your/O committee/O ./O 
In/O this/O time/O of/O crisis/O ,/O we/O believe/O that/O the/O demands/O of/O American/O patriotism/O makes/O necessary/O that/O witnesses/O respond/O to/O the/O call/O of/O their/O country/O ,/O as/O represented/O by/O your/O committee/O ,/O and/O give/O you/O all/O information/O necessary/O to/O the/O success/O of/O your/O objective/O ./O 
We/O are/O hopeful/O that/O through/O and/O as/O a/O result/O of/O the/O hearings/O of/O your/O committee/O ,/O ways/O and/O means/O will/O be/O provided/O which/O will/O enable/O the/O Nation/O to/O fairly/O ,/O legally/O and/O effectively/O deal/O with/O the/O problem/O of/O communism/O or/O subversive/O elements/O ./O 
Very/O truly/O yours/O ,/O THE/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O COUNCIL/O FORASSOCIATION/O OF/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O PRODUCERS/O ,/O ARTISTS/O '/O MANAGERS/O GUILD/O ,/O HOLLYWOOD/O AFL/ORGANIZATION FILM/O COUNCIL/O ,/O INDEPENDENT/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O PRODUCERS/O ASSOCIATION/O ,/O INDEPENDENT/O OFFICE/O WORKERS/O ,/O SCREEN/O ACTORS/O GUILD/O ,/O SCREEN/O DIRECTORS/O GUILD/O ,/O SCREEN/O PRODUCERS/O GUILD/O ,/O SCREEN/O WRITERS/O GUILD/O ,/O SOCIETY/O OF/O INDEPENDENT/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O PRODUCERS/O ,/O SOCIETY/O OF/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O ART/O DIRECTORS/O ,/O UNITED/O PRODUCTION/O MANAGERS/O GUILD/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O further/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O audience/O that/O is/O present/O ,/O this/O committee/O is/O here/O as/O representatives/O of/O the/O American/O Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O and/O is/O charged/O with/O the/O responsi/O -/O bility/O of/O doing/O a/O duty/O imposed/O upon/O it/O by/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O hearing/O room/O has/O been/O made/O available/O to/O this/O committee/O for/O this/O service/O and/O is/O temporarily/O under/O its/O control/O ./O 
This/O audience/O is/O here/O as/O a/O courtesy/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1417/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O captive/O audience/O ./O 
You/O are/O at/O liberty/O to/O depart/O any/O time/O you/O see/O fit/O ,/O but/O while/O you/O are/O here/O this/O committee/O will/O not/O tolerate/O any/O demonstration/O ,/O either.approval/O or/O disapproval/O ,/O of/O anything/O that/O may/O be/O said/O by/O any/O witness/O that/O appears/O before/O this/O committee/O ,/O or/O any/O of/O its/O members/O ,/O or/O of/O anything/O that/O may/O be/O done/O in/O these/O transactions/O ./O 
I/O sincerely/O hope/O that/O in/O the/O course/O of/O these/O hearings/O it/O will/O not/O be/O necessary/O to/O again/O refer/O to/O this/O matter/O ./O 
This/O committee/O ,/O approximately/O 3/O years/O ago/O ,/O adopted/O a/O policy/O which/O it/O has/O uniformly/O adhered/O to/O of/O prohibiting/O moving/O pictures/O or/O television/O reports/O from/O its/O hearing/O rooms/O ./O 
It/O has/O come/O to/O my/O attention/O that/O there/O are/O present/O in/O this/O room/O now/O certain/O small/O moving-picture/O cameras/O ./O 
I/O sincerely/O trust/O that/O this/O rule/O that/O has/O been/O in/O force/O by/O this/O committee/O for/O approximately/O 3/O years/O will/O not/O be/O violated/O in/O the/O course/O of/O these/O hearings/O ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O have/O just/O been/O handed/O some/O other/O communications/O ,/O some/O several/O hundred/O that/O have/O been/O handed/O me/O which/O I/O have/O n't/O had/O an/O opportunity/O to/O read/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O into/O the/O record/O this/O letter/O or/O at/O least/O ,/O to/O refer/O to/O the/O letter/O as/O being/O sent/O to/O this/O committee/O endorsing/O its/O work/O ,/O its/O objectives/O by/O the/O Grand/O Parlor/O of/O the/O Native/O Sons/O of/O the/O Golden/O West/O ,/O signed/O by/O Eldred/PERSON L./PERSON Meyer/PERSON and/O by/O Mr./O Ray/PERSON Schultz/PERSON ,/O financial/O secretary/O of/O Local/O 80/O ,/O Studio/LOCATION Grip/LOCATION of/LOCATION Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O as/O the/O first/O wit/O -/O ness/O this/O morning/O Mr./O Harold/PERSON J./PERSON Ashe/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Is/O Mr./O Ashe/PERSON in/O the/O courtroom/O ?/O 
Are/O you/O Mr./O Ashe/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Ashe/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O lift/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Reporter/O ,/O would/O you/O let/O the/O record/O disclose/O that/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O the/O other/O member/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O now/O present/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O HAROLD/PERSON J./PERSON ASHE/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Ashe/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O move/O into/O the/O chair/O closest/O to/O the/O committee/O so/O I/O will/O be/O able/O to/O see/O you/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
YOU/O are/O Mr./O Harold/PERSON J./PERSON Ashe/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Ashe/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Irvington/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ,/O February/O 18/O ,/O 1901/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O or/O calling/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O free-lance/O magazine/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O at/O one/O time/O a/O functionary/O in/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O position/O did/O you/O hold/O in/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION !/O 
1418/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
State/O secretary/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O State/O secretary/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O 10/O months/O ,/O approximately/O a/O little/O longer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Over/O what/O period/O of/O time/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O from/O about/O February/O or/O March/O of/O 1933/O until/O possibly/O December/O or/O January/O of/O 1933/O or/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O period/O when/O you/O held/O that/O position/O where/O did/O you/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION headquarters/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O know/O as/O Commonwealth/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O at/O the/O outset/O ,/O except/O by/O hearsay/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O your/O learning/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O learned/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION directly/O on/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O September/O of/O 1933/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O if/O I/O understand/O you/O correctly/O ,/O that/O while/O you/O were/O State/ORGANIZATION secretary/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION you/O were/O also/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O a/O later/O date/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
I/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O instant/O I/O joined/O the/O party/O I/O was/O assigned/O back/O to/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O work/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O to/O help/O capture/O it/O and/O channel/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O I/O did/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O spoke/O of/O the/O effort/O made/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O capture/O membership/O from/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O that/O effort/O was/O and/O how/O it/O materialized/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O my/O actually/O coming/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION --/O or/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION through/O Sam/PERSON Darcy/PERSON ,/O the/O district/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O issued/O a/O call/O to/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O meet/O with/O the/O Communists/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O certain/O minimum/O demands/O and/O for/O purposes/O of/O establishing/O a/O united/O front/O ./O 
I/O believe/O the/O issue/O at/O the/O time/O was/O the/O threat/O of/O fascism/O ,/O in/O which/O I/O was/O greatly/O interested/O and/O in/O which/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION showed/O very/O little/O real/O interest/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O effort/O to/O bring/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O as/O a/O part/O of/O the/O united/O front/O successful/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
TO/O some/O extent/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
The/O State/O executive/O committee/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION resisted/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O the/O only/O member/O of/O the/O State/O executive/O committee/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O that/O voted/O in/O favor/O of/O the/O united/O front/O ./O 
Subsequently/O I/O was/O expelled/O ,/O or/O rather/O removed/O as/O State/ORGANIZATION secretary/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O I/O was/O n't/O expelled/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Upon/O the/O failure/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O obtain/O an/O approval/O by/O a/O majority/O of/O the/O executive/O committee/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O the/O Communist/O front-I/O mean/O to/O the/O united/O front/O plan/O ,/O what/O plan/O did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION adopt/O to/O capture/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O at/O first/O they/O tried/O to/O establish/O a/O united/O front/O from/O above/O through/O the/O leadership/O ./O 
This/O failing/O ,/O they/O then/O resorted/O to/O what/O was/O called/O the/O united/O front/O from/O below/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O they/O reached/O out/O and/O appealed/O to/O the/O individual/O rank-and-file/O Socialists/O who/O were/O discouraged/O with/O the/O lack/O of/O initiative/O on/O the/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1419/O part/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O who/O ,/O like/O myself/O ,/O were/O preoccupied/O with/O the/O danger/O of/O communism/O ./O 
This/O was/O quite/O successful/O ./O 
I/O might/O add/O that/O at/O the/O February/O 1934/O convention/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION a/O very/O large/O part/O of/O the/O delegates/O walked/O out/O and/O reorganized/O themselves/O into/O a/O rump/O convention/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O that/O possibly/O 50/O of/O these/O delegates/O were/O in/O this/O rump/O convention/O ./O 
It/O was/O almost/O as/O large/O as/O the/O remaining/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION convention/O ./O 
Ultimately/O ,/O according/O to/O Sam/PERSON Darcy/PERSON ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION recruited/O approximately/O 600/O dues-paying/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O which/O point/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION had/O succeeded/O in/O doubling/O its/O membership/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O in/O that/O campaign/O ,/O in/O that/O effort/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O you/O became/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O joined/O in/O September/O of/O 1933/O ./O 
I/O broke/O off/O all/O organizational/O connection/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O February/O 14/O ./O 
1939/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O relate/O more/O in/O detail/O to/O the/O committee/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O that/O is/O ,/O who/O recruited/O you/O into/O the/O party/O and/O what/O initial/O steps/O were/O taken/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O too/O clear/O a/O recollection/O now/O of/O all/O of/O the/O initial/O steps/O that/O were/O taken/O to/O get/O in/O touch/O with/O or/O put/O me/O in/O touch/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O distinctly/O that/O the/O organizational/O secretary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON ,/O was/O one/O of/O the/O signers/O of/O my/O application/O card/O ,/O and/O subsequently/O I/O met/O with/O Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON two/O or/O three/O evenings/O a/O week/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O first/O became/O a/O member/O and/O had/O these/O conferences/O with/O Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON ,/O what/O instructions/O were/O given/O you/O as/O to/O your/O activity/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O which/O you/O were/O then/O the/O State/O secretary/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O only/O remember/O in/O a/O general/O sort/O of/O way/O ./O 
It/O was/O simply/O to/O retain/O my/O position/O in/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O not/O to/O expose/O myself/O as/O a/O Communist/O but/O to/O infiltrate/O as/O much/O as/O I/O could/O in/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O recruit/O wherever/O possible/O ./O 
I/O did/O do/O a/O nominal/O amount/O of/O recruiting/O ,/O and/O I/O understand/O this/O same/O recruiting/O was/O going/O on/O in/O other/O parts/O of/O the/O State/O where/O the/O Communists/O also/O had/O party/O members/O in/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
There/O were/O at/O that/O time/O some/O ,/O oh/O ./O 
30/O or/O 40/O or/O 50/O locals/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION scattered/O around/O the/O State/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O first/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O meet/O an/O individual/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O met/O Mr./O Lawrence/PERSON later/O ./O 
Mr./O Lawrence/PERSON came/O along/O in/O about/O 1935/O ./O 
He/O was/O misrepresented/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O being/O an/O expert/O in/O underground/O work/O and/O that/O he/O was/O a/O liaison/O man/O in/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O Hungary/LOCATION or/O Austria/LOCATION for/O important/O Communist/O members/O there/O ./O 
Later/O independent/O investigation/O of/O mine/O revealed/O that/O he/O had/O been/O a/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION taxicab/O driver/O ./O 
Just/O a/O little/O deceit/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O a/O device/O used/O by/O the/O leadership/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O build/O up/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
They/O undertook/O to/O use/O him/O to/O educate/O the/O party/O leadership/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION on/O underground/O work/O and/O things/O of/O that/O 1420/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O nature/O ./O 
I/O might/O add/O that/O he/O knows/O less/O about/O underground/O work/O than/O my/O 6-year-old/O girl/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O to/O the/O committee/O just/O what/O the/O activities/O of/O Lawrence/PERSON were/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O a/O later/O date/O he/O was/O put/O in/O charge/O of/O Hollywood/LOCATION ac/O -/O tivity/O ,/O organizing/O the/O party/O in/O studios/O ,/O with/O particular/O emphasis/O on/O professionals/O in/O the/O studios-the/O writers/O ,/O the/O actors/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
This/O took/O the/O form/O originally/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O of/O studio/O study/O clubs/O ./O 
I/O know/O Mr./O Lawrence/PERSON used/O to/O come/O down/O to/O the/O headquarters/O of/O the/O party/O and/O depart/O with/O two/O or/O three/O hundred/O dollars/O '/O worth/O of/O books/O ,/O cloth-bound/O books/O ,/O every/O week/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O investigation/O conducted/O by/O the/O committee/O dis/O -/O closes/O that/O V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON came/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION at/O the/O time/O that/O St.anley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON was/O still/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O it/O ,/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON made/O a/O very/O observing/O remark/O which/O ,/O however/O ,/O the/O comrades/O resented/O very/O much/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O said-in/O the/O presence/O of/O some/O of/O the/O studio/O comrades/O ,/O I/O think/O he/O made/O the/O observation/O that/O the/O people/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O including/O the/O comrades/O ,/O were/O ``/O only/O fat/O cows/O to/O be/O milked/O ./O ''/O 
Of/O course/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O the/O party/O had/O quite/O a/O few/O good-looking/O milkmaids/O ./O 
This/O resulted/O in/O his/O ultimate/O removal/O ,/O and/O Mr./O Jerome/PERSON succeeded/O to/O that/O position/O ./O 
I/O first/O met/O Mr./O Jerome/PERSON in/O about/O ,/O oh/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O June/O or/O July/O of/O 1936/O ./O 
He/O was/O here/O coincidental/O with/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O come/O with/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON but/O he/O arrived/O while/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON was/O here/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O the/O first/O person/O that/O Jerome/PERSON contacted/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Before/O proceeding/O further/O with/O the/O development/O of/O Communist/O activities/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION proper/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O for/O you/O to/O state/O what/O your/O first/O assignment/O was/O after/O joining/O the/O party/O ,/O other/O than/O having/O to/O do/O with/O the/O work/O of/O recruiting/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
After/O I/O came/O back/O from/O the/O national/O convention/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Cleveland/LOCATION ,/O which/O was/O early/O in/O 1934/O ,/O my/O first/O assignment/O was/O to/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O ./O 
This/O assignment/O was/O given/O to/O me/O by/O Elmer/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ,/O the/O county/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O did/O not/O solicit/O the/O assignment/O from/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O ./O 
I/O want/O that/O to/O be/O explicitly/O understood/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O I/O went/O in/O there/O on/O the/O instructions/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O was/O accepted/O by/O the/O IWO/O as/O their/O organizer/O on/O the/O representation/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O I/O was/O suitable/O for/O the/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O this/O was/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O work/O of/O the/O -/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
The/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O was/O already/O well/O organized/O when/O I/O went/O into/O it/O ./O 
They/O had/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O 12/O or/O 15/O lodges/O ,/O and/O most/O of/O them-in/O fact/O ,/O all/O of/O them/O save/O one-were/O foreign/O -/O language/O lodges/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O you/O received/O your/O appointment/O and/O directions/O through/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O it/O your/O opinion/O and/O conclusion/O at/O that/O time/O that/O it/O was/O an/O organization/O dominated/O and/O controlled/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O AsHE/PERSON ./O 
The/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O was/O controlled/O lock/O ,/O stock/O ,/O and/O barrel/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O was/O so/O known/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O consider/O it/O a/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/O move/O -/O ment/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1421/O Mr./O AsTrE/O ./O 
Definitely/O ./O 
I/O have/O received/O many/O donations/O from/O the/O various/O lodges/O of/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O given/O directly/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O knowingly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O particular/O cell/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION when/O you/O first/O joined/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O first/O assigned/O to/O a/O street/O unit/O in/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION street/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O was/O early/O in/O 1934/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O was/O traveling/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O the/O time/O for/O the/O party/O as/O a/O speaker/O ,/O and/O I/O daresay/O I/O did/O n't/O attend/O more/O than/O a/O dozen/O meetings/O all/O during/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O by/O ``/O street/O section/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O use/O that/O term/O to/O differentiate/O from/O the/O section/O that/O later/O was/O developed/O there/O which/O was/O known/O as/O the/O studio/O section/O ./O 
There/O has/O been/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O confusion/O about/O this/O in/O the/O minds/O of/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O ./O 
They/O are/O two/O entirely/O separate/O and/O distinct/O sections/O ./O 
The/O street/O section/O was/O then/O organized/O along/O strictly/O territorial/O or/O geographical/O lines/O ./O 
The/O studio/O section/O did/O not/O recognize/O any/O geographical/O limitations/O but/O was/O determined/O by/O whether/O a/O person/O worked/O in/O the/O studios/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O at/O this/O particular/O time/O to/O which/O you/O now/O refer/O ,/O if/O a/O person/O from/O the/O studio/O happened/O to/O live/O within/O the/O geographical/O section/O ,/O he/O likely/O would/O have/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O particular/O cell/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O section/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O except/O ,/O back/O in/O 1934/O ,/O I/O question/O very/O much/O whether/O there/O were/O very/O many/O important/O studio/O people/O that/O were/O members/O of/O any/O unit/O of/O the/O party/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
They/O may/O have/O been/O members/O at/O large/O ,/O or/O there/O may/O have/O been/O some/O other/O dispensation/O to/O take/O care/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O street/O section/O also/O commonly/O known/O as/O the/O downtown/O section/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O the/O downtown/O section/O was/O a/O different/O section/O ,/O entirely/O ./O 
The/O downtown/O section/O composed/O roughly/O the/O forty-fourth/O ,/O forty-fifth/O ,/O and/O fifty-fourth/O assembly/O districts/O ./O 
It/O included/O all/O of/O the/O assembly/O districts/O from/O the/O Fourteenth/O Congressional/O District/O except/O the/O sixty-second/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O when/O did/O you/O become/O exposed/O publicly/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Immediately/O upon/O my/O return/O from/O the/O Cleveland/LOCATION convention/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O I/O was/O one/O of/O the/O speakers/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in/O 1934/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
1934/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O exposed/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O your/O exposure/O ,/O what/O unit/O or/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION were/O you/O assigned/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O at/O that/O time/O that/O I/O went/O into/O this/O Hollywood/O unit/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O I/O see/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
And/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O I/O was/O there/O probably/O until/O late/O fall/O ,/O 1934/O ./O 
I/O was/O running/O for/O State/O oice/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O attend/O very/O many/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O State/O office/O were/O you/O running/O for/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Secretary/O of/O state/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O AHE/O ./O 
Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
1422/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O served/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION street/O section/O or/O group/O ,/O were/O you/O transferred/O to/O another/O section/O ?/O 
\/O Ir/O ./O 
ASHE/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O was/O transferred/O to/O the/O downtown/O section/O ,/O and/O because/O of/O certain/O difficulties/O I/O was/O experiencing/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION with/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Tashjian/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O ,/O apparently/O ,/O out/O to/O give/O me/O a/O very/O bad/O time/O ./O 
Bob/PERSON Minor/PERSON intervened/O and/O ,/O I/O understand/O ,/O gave/O Mr./O Tashjian/PERSON a/O bad/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O ask/O you/O :/O Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON ?/O 
`/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O position/O did/O he/O hold/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O was/O unable/O to/O find/O out/O whether/O he/O held/O any/O position/O or/O not/O ,/O but/O he/O exerted/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O influence/O ./O 
He/O had/O a/O considerable/O gift/O for/O intrigue/O and/O also/O for/O stirring/O up/O factional/O disputes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O describe/O the/O doctor/O a/O little/O more/O fully/O ./O 
What/O type/O of/O doctor/O was/O he/O ?/O 
Was/O he/O a/O medical/O doctor/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O what/O Bob/PERSON Minor/PERSON referred/O to/O contemptuously/O as/O a/O ``/O proletarian/O dentist/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O result-he/O is/O not/O living/O at/O this/O time/O ;/O is/O he/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O he/O died/O sometime/O ago/O after/O leaving/O a/O Communist/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O effort/O to/O discipline/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O the/O result/O of/O the/O complaint/O or/O dispute/O which/O the/O doctor/O had/O aroused/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON was/O a/O rigid/O little/O disciplinarian/O ;/O and/O ,/O not/O having/O understood/O clearly/O how/O I/O had/O come/O into/O the/O party/O ,/O which/O involved/O a/O considerable/O period/O of/O training/O and/O study/O under/O Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON and/O under/O Elmer/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ,/O the/O organization/O secretary/O and/O organizer/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O respectively/O ,/O which/O involved/O meetings/O sometimes/O two/O and/O three/O times/O a/O week/O with/O them/O ,/O Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON decided/O that/O I/O had/O not/O gone/O to/O a/O beginner/O 's/O class/O and/O that/O I/O should/O go/O to/O a/O beginner/O 's/O class/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O had/O been/O to/O about/O the/O equivalent/O of/O three/O beginner/O 's/O classes/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O been/O speaking/O officially/O in/O the/O name/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION throughout/O the/O State/O at/O mass/O meetings/O and/O had/O been/O meeting/O in/O closed/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O help/O them/O straighten/O out/O matters/O ;/O so/O ,/O I/O thought/O this/O was/O going/O a/O little/O bit/O too/O far/O ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O did/O enforce/O his/O point/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O obliged/O to/O go/O to/O one/O beginners/O '/O class/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O the/O only/O time/O I/O attended/O ./O 
The/O next/O day/O ,/O when/O the/O county/O leadership/O found/O out/O what/O happened/O and/O when/O Bob/PERSON Minor/PERSON found/O out/O what/O happened/O ,/O they/O went/O into/O a/O huddle/O and/O gave/O Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON ,/O I/O understand/O ,/O a/O very/O ,/O very/O bad/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O was/O the/O doctor/O known/O as/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O disciplinary/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Not/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
He/O later/O succeeded/O to/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O have/O stated/O that/O you/O were/O assigned/O to/O the/O downtown/O section/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1423/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O in/O that/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
itMr/O ./O 
AsIE/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O downtown/O section/O ,/O or/O the/O successors/O to/O my/O they/O changed/O the/O terminology/O some-until/O the/O day/O I/O terminated1939/O ./O 
membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O in/O February/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O go/O back/O to/O the/O first/O group/O that/O you/O were/O assigned/O to/O ,/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION street/O group/O ,/O and/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O can/O identify/O the/O names/O of/O the/O members/O of/O that/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O try/O ./O 
Bill/PERSON and/O Clara/PERSON Ward/PERSON were/O members/O ;/O my/O wife/O and/O I/O were/O members/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O 's/O not/O go/O quite/O so/O fast/O there/O ./O 
Bill/O Mr./O ASHS/O ./O 
Bill/PERSON and/O Clara/PERSON Ward/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O will/O you/O ,/O in/O identifying/O them/O ,/O give/O us/O such/O further/O information/O relating/O to/O them/O as/O you/O can/O from/O your/O recollection/O as/O to/O their/O participation/O and/O their/O position/O and/O vocation/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O never/O did-well/O ,/O I/O 'll/O take/O that/O back/O ./O 
I/O do/O now/O know/O what/O Bill/PERSON Ward/PERSON 's/O vocation/O was/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O police/O officer/O in/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION Police/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Bill/PERSON and/O Clara/PERSON Ward/PERSON at/O various/O times/O were/O on-or/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O at/O one/O time/O she/O was/O membership/O director/O ./O 
At/O another/O time-this/O is/O for/O the/O county/O ./O 
At/O another/O time/O I/O believe/O she/O was/O dues/O secretary/O ,/O and/O for/O a/O considerable/O length/O of/O time/O she/O served/O on/O the/O disciplinary/O committee/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O on/O the/O disciplinary/O committee/O for/O a/O while/O with/O her/O ./O 
Bill/PERSON ,/O to/O my/O knowledge-I/O do/O n't/O believe/O ever/O held/O any/O position/O of/O responsibility/O ,/O but/O merely/O went/O along/O with/O his/O wife/O and/O sat/O in/O on/O many/O of/O these/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Will/O you/O continue/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Morton/PERSON Beeman/PERSON ./O 
1/O I/O believe/O he/O is/O now/O deceased/O ./O 
It/O is/O my/O recollection/O that/O he/O was/O organizer/O at/O least/O part/O of/O the/O time/O while/O I/O was/O in/O ;/O his/O wife/O ,/O Ruth/PERSON ,/O whose/O first/O name/O I/O ca/O n't/O now/O recall/O ./O 
There/O were/O two/O Japanese/O whom/O I/O ca/O n't/O further/O identify/O ./O 
One/O or/O two/O other/O people/O whom/O I/O ca/O n't/O bring/O into/O focus/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O and/O in/O addition/O ,/O there/O was/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O his/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O that/O time/O he/O was/O trying/O to/O get/O work/O in/O the/O studios/O ./O 
Probably/O did/O occasional/O bit/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON ,/O an/O actor/O ,/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O Washington/LOCATION and/O refused/O to/O answer/O questions/O that/O were/O propounded/O to/O him/O regarding/O his/O alleged/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION affiliations/O and/O activities/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O the/O same/O individual/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O is/O only/O an/O assumption/O on/O my/O part/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O a/O fair/O assumption/O ,/O because/O I/O followed/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON 's/O professional/O career/O for/O some/O years/O ./O 
I/O know/O that/O the/O same/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON that/O I/O knew/O in/O 1934/O was/O the/O Will/O Geer/PERSON who/O appeared/O in/O two/O outstanding/O theatrical/O productions/O in/O 1937/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O appearing/O in/O two/O simultaneously/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O it/O ./O 
I/O believe/O one/O was/O called/O Pins/O and/O Needles/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O at/O the/O moment/O recall/O the/O other/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O there/O was/O any/O change/O in/O the/O spelling/O of/O his/O name/O ?/O 
SAn/O individual/O was/O named/O by/O Mrs./O Mildred/PERSON Ashe/PERSON as/O Morton/PERSON Beaman/PERSON ./O 
1424/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O noticed/O lately/O that/O he/O spells/O it/O differently/O than/O when/O I/O knew/O him/O ./O 
When/O I/O knew/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON he/O spelled/O it/O G-h-e-r-e/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O has/O since/O simplified/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whether/O he/O played/O in/O a/O picture/O called/O the/O Tall/O Target/O or/O the/O Man/O on/O the/O Train/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whether/O he/O played/O in/O a/O picture/O called/O Lights/O Out/O ,/O at/O Universal/O Studio/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O meet/O at/O that/O time/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Rose/PERSON Elfman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O since/O tried/O to/O refresh/O my/O memory/O on/O her/O ,/O and/O at/O this/O time/O I/O would/O n't/O want/O to/O say/O under/O oath/O whether/O she/O is/O or/O is/O not/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
I/O know/O the/O woman/O ./O 
I/O have/O seen/O her/O around/O meetings/O ./O 
1/O can/O visualize/O her/O at/O a/O Hollywood/LOCATION street/O demonstration/O that/O we/O had/O ,/O but/O at/O this/O time/O I/O can/O not/O positively/O place/O the/O woman/O as/O to/O party/O affiliation/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O spoke/O of/O having/O met/O several/O Japanese/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O their/O names/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASIIE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O can/O not/O ./O 
I/O might/O say/O ,/O however/O ,/O there/O were/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ,/O about/O 40/O Japanese/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O party/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
This/O was/O their/O principal/O concentration/O point/O ,/O and/O they/O had/O a/O nationality/O commission/O that/O was/O located/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION contrary/O to/O the/O procedure/O of/O other/O nationality/O commissions/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O testimony/O of/O General/O Willoughby/PERSON before/O the/O committee/O several/O weeks/O ago/O relating/O to/O the/O Sorge/PERSON spy/O trial/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O it/O developed/O there/O was/O a/O Japanese/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Miyagi/PERSON who/O was/O executed/O as/O one/O of/O the/O spies/O in/O that/O spy/O ring/O ,/O came/O from/O Japan/LOCATION and/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O the/O interrogation/O of/O Miyagi/PERSON in/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O he/O referred/O to/O certain/O activities/O of/O the/O party/O in/O California/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O want/O to/O call/O to/O your/O attention/O ./O 
In/O describing/O the/O activities/O in/O 1930/O ,/O which/O I/O understand/O was/O earlier/O than/O your/O connection/O with/O the/O partyMr/O ./O 
ASHE/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O stated/O that/O it/O fostered-meaning/O by/O ``/O it/O ''/O the/O Communist/O Party-fostered/O strikes/O in/O the/O Imperial/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION against/O such/O large/O capital/O concerns/O as/O the/O Girard/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Sun/ORGANIZATION Fruit/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION and/O agitated/O among/O the/O fishermen/O and/O fishing-industry/O workers/O in/O San/LOCATION Pedro/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O your/O activities/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O did/O you/O obtain/O any/O information/O relating/O to/O those/O incidents/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O about/O them/O only/O from/O having/O been/O told/O about/O them/O by/O other/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ./O 
I/O know/O that/O at/O a/O later/O date/O another/O effort/O was/O made/O to/O organize/O the/O unorganized/O field/O workers/O in/O Imperial/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O believe/O also/O in/O the/O San/LOCATION Joaquin/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION ./O 
I/O believe/O these/O strikes/O were/O broken/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O too/O clear/O now/O as/O to/O the/O outcome/O of/O them/O ./O 
They/O were/O Communist-led/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O while/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O downtown/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O the/O task/O of/O organizing/O units/O or/O sections/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O cells/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1425/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time/O I/O was/O ./O 
I/O held/O possibly/O 20/O positions/O at/O one/O time/O or/O another/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O this/O would/O be/O a/O good/O time/O for/O you/O to/O state/O just/O what/O positions/O you/O have/O held/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O State/O chairman/O of/O the/O State/O central/O committee/O of/O the/O party/O in/O 1936/O ./O 
I/O was/O downtown-section/O organizer/O for/O about/O a/O year/O ,/O year/O and/O a/O half/O ;/O Western/ORGANIZATION Worker/ORGANIZATION correspondent/O for/O approximately/O a/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O right/O there/O for/O just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
What/O publication/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Western/O Worker/O ,/O official/O publication/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O succeeded/O by/O another/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O succeeded/O by/O the/O People/O 's/O Daily/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O was/O county/O chairman/O at/O one/O time/O of/O the/O Relief/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Protective/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O composed/O of/O unemployed/O workers/O and/O which/O was/O a/O very/O fine/O source/O for/O recruiting/O party/O members/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O was/O chairman/O of/O various/O united-front/O groups/O ./O 
I/O was/O official/O speaker/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION for/O a/O considerable/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
I/O toured/O the/O State/O ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O edited/O a/O paper/O called/O the/O Hunger/O Fighter/O ,/O official/O organ/O of/O the/O Relief/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Protective/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O probably/O held/O a/O good/O many/O other/O jobs/O ./O 
I/O taught/O briefly/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION Workers/O '/O School/O ,/O taught/O what/O was/O known/O as/O labor/O journalism/O ./O 
Actually/O it/O was/O teaching/O them/O basic/O English/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O think/O of/O any/O more/O offhand/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O served/O for/O a/O while/O on/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION disciplinary/O committee/O and/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O executive/O committee/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION here/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O connected/O at/O any/O time/O with/O the/O Workers/O '/O Alliance/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHiE/O ./O 
Workers/O '/O Alliance/O succeeded/O the/O Relief/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Protec/ORGANIZATION -/O tive/O Union/O and/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O I/O was/O not/O in/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O was/O deeply/O involved/O in/O State/O organizational/O work/O for/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O telling/O the/O committee/O of/O the/O assignment/O you/O had/O in/O organizational/O work/O in/O the/O establishment/O of/O certain/O cells/O or/O units/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Will/O you/O continue/O with/O that/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O downtown-section/O organizer/O ,/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O called/O subsection/O for/O a/O while/O ,/O and/O later/O section/O ,/O I/O had/O charge/O of/O all/O of/O the/O units/O in/O the/O section/O ,/O which/O incidentally/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O the/O largest/O section/O in/O the/O city/O ,/O numerically/O ./O 
I/O believe/O in/O 1936/O at/O our/O section/O convention/O we/O reported/O somewhere/O between/O 300/O and/O 350/O members/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O recall/O this/O is/O because/O there/O was/O considerable/O argument/O among/O the/O delegates/O ,/O who/O accused/O me/O of/O padding/O the/O membership/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O unenviable/O position/O of/O not/O being/O able/O to/O reveal/O to/O them/O that/O the/O membership/O was/O so/O large/O because/O I/O had/O attached/O to/O the/O street/O section/O ,/O several/O professional/O sections/O that/O could/O not/O be/O exposed/O and/O could/O n't/O even/O be/O identified/O by/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O instrumental/O in/O the/O formation/O of/O these/O professional/O sections/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
The/O professional/O units/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O was/O it/O that/O the/O membership/O in/O the/O units/O was/O to/O be/O kept/O secret/O 1426/O CO1MMIUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ASIn/PERSON ./O 
Because/O of/O the/O character/O of/O their/O employment/O ./O 
Some/O were/O attorneys/O ,/O some/O --/O I/O believe/O one/O was/O a/O dentist/O ;/O two/O or/O three/O of/O them/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O were/O writers/O ,/O newspapermen/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
They/O could/O only/O be/O recruited/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O not/O being/O exposed/O ./O 
I/O know/O ,/O again/O ./O 
I/O ran/O into/O Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON ,/O who/O insisted/O on/O forcing/O these/O people/O into/O street/O units/O where/O they/O would/O immediately/O be/O exposed/O instead/O of/O being/O exposed/O here/O 15/O years/O later/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O these/O individuals/O wanted/O to/O reap/O whatever/O profits/O or/O advantage/O they/O could/O from/O their/O activities/O and/O yet/O have/O their/O names/O concealed/O because/O they/O knew/O it/O was/O an/O unlawful/O enterprise/O in/O which/O they/O were/O engaged/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
They/O did/O n't/O have/O any/O guts/O ./O 
They/O do/O n't/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O name/O or/O designation/O for/O those/O professional/O units/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
It/O started/O out/O very/O small/O ./O 
After/O the/O EPIC/O convention/O in/O 1935/O ,/O which/O I/O covered/O for/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O and/O the/O Western/O Worker/O ,/O I/O met/O two/O or/O three/O individuals/O who/O were/O sympathetic/O ./O 
I/O took/O them/O over/O to/O the/O Western/O Worker/O office/O and/O high-pressured/O them/O into/O the/O party/O ./O 
Those/O individuals/O were/O Morgan/PERSON Hull-I/PERSON now/O understand/O he/O is/O dead-another/O one/O was/O John/PERSON Jack/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ,/O better/O known/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O John/PERSON Broman/PERSON ;/O and/O a/O third/O person/O whose/O name/O escapes/O me/O at/O the/O moment/O ./O 
But/O I/O recruited/O three/O that/O night/O and/O in/O the/O next/O 2/O or/O 3/O weeks/O was/O able/O to/O convince/O the/O party/O that/O a/O professional/O unit/O should/O be/O permitted/O ./O 
Over/O Dr./O Tasjian/PERSON 's/O objection/O we/O set/O up/O a/O unit/O known/O as/O Z-100/O ./O 
Z-100/O immediately/O started/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O usually/O met/O with/O them/O because/O there/O were/O no/O old/O party/O members/O to/O guide/O them/O ./O 
It/O recruited/O very/O rapidly/O and/O I/O would/O say/O within/O about/O 5/O months/O it/O had/O become/O so/O large/O we/O had/O to/O split/O the/O unit/O and/O make/O another/O unit/O called/O Z-150/O ./O 
The/O last/O I/O knew/O of/O these/O two/O units/O the/O combined/O membership/O totaled/O about/O 23/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O give/O to/O the/O committee/O the/O names/O of/O the/O members/O of/O these/O professional/O units/O whose/O membership/O was/O to/O be/O kept/O secret/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON was/O one/O ./O 
Later/O onMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
In/O giving/O the/O names/O of/O these/O in/O -/O dividuals/O I/O wish/O you/O would/O identify/O them/O as/O fully/O as/O you/O can/O so/O that/O there/O will/O be/O no/O misunderstanding/O as/O to/O the/O individual/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ,/O was/O unemployed/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O his/O background/O was/O ./O 
He/O was/O fairly/O young/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O 25/O or/O 30/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O he/O is/O doing/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
He/O is/O with/O a/O fishermen/O 's/O union/O down/O at/O San/LOCATION Pedro/LOCATION ,/O ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O a/O branch/O of/O Harry/PERSON Bridges/PERSON '/O union/O ,/O I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O union/O organizer/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
He/O had/O had/O no/O union/O experience/O at/O the/O time/O he/O came/O into/O the/O party/O ;/O that/O ,/O I/O am/O reasonably/O certain/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O unaware/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O had/O gained/O such/O experience/O later/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O presume/O he/O did/O through/O the/O guidance/O of/O the/O Commu/LOCATION -/O nist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O his/O wife/O a/O member/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1427/O Mr./O ASIIE/PERSON ./O 
His/O wife/O was/O later/O recruited/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O over/O his/O vigorous/O objections/O ./O 
I/O never/O did/O find/O out/O why/O he/O objected/O to/O his/O wife/O being/O in/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O distinctly/O recall/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O already/O spoken/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O of/O Jack/PERSON Wilon/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Jack/PERSON Broman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O also/O quite/O young/O ./O 
I/O believe/O he/O had/O had/O some/O slight/O amount/O of/O newspaper/O experience/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O not/O sure/O now/O ,/O but/O I/O believe/O he/O worked/O for/O an/O organization/O at/O that/O time/O known/O as/O the/O City/ORGANIZATION News/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O believe/O they/O had/O headquarters/O in/O the/O old/O L./ORGANIZATION A./ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION Building/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O his/O later/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activity/O consisted/O of/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Jack/PERSON later/O came/O into/O the/O downtown/O street/O unit/O ,/O did/O expose/O himself/O ,/O showed/O considerably/O more/O courage/O than/O a/O lot/O of/O others/O that/O he/O had/O been/O with/O ./O 
He-I/O believe/O I/O proposed/O his/O name/O as/O Western/O Worker/O correspondent/O after/O I/O was/O no/O longer/O holding/O that/O position/O ./O 
He/O still/O went/O to/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O worked/O on/O the/O Western/O Worker/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O there/O ,/O and/O still/O later/O on/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O ./O 
At/O a/O later/O date/O I/O believe/O he/O became/O an/O editor/O of/O a/O newspaper/O put/O out/O by/O the/O fishermen/O 's/O union/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ;/O proceed/O with/O the/O naming/O of/O any/O others/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Spencer/O Austrian/O ,/O a/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION attorney/O ;/O Joe/PERSON Aidlin/PERSON ,/O a/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION attorney/O ;/O Percy/PERSON Solotoy/PERSON ,/O a/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION attorney/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O Percy/PERSON Solotoy/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O give/O us/O any/O additional/O information/O relating/O to/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O very/O little/O about/O him/O except/O I/O met/O with/O him/O possibly/O 20/O or/O 30/O times/O in/O closed/O party/O units/O ,/O Z-100/O or/O Z-150/O ,/O or/O both/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O he/O was/O an/O attorney/O ,/O a/O practicing/O lawyer/O ,/O here/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
I/O lost/O track/O of/O him/O after/O I/O got/O out/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O he/O is/O employed/O or/O in/O what/O business/O he/O is/O now/O engaged/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O he/O is/O now/O the/O head/O of/O Brown-Saltman/ORGANIZATION Furniture/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION and/O also/O an/O official/O in/O the/O Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION Furniture/ORGANIZATION Manufacturers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O his/O wife/O was/O also/O a/O member/O of/O this/O unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O by/O recollection/O ,/O she/O was/O ./O 
I/O have/O the/O distinct/O impression/O that/O she/O was/O transferred/O out/O of/O that-I/O have/O a/O distinct/O impression/O that/O she/O was/O transferred/O out/O of/O the/O professional/O section/O and/O into/O the/O social/O workers/O ,/O or/O professional/O unit/O ,/O I/O should/O say/O ,/O into/O the/O social/O workers/O unit/O ,/O which/O was/O also/O attached/O to/O downtown/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O spoke/O of/O Spencer/O Austrian/O ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O the/O last/O name/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
A-u-s-t-r-i-a-n/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
DO/O you/O know/O anything/O about/O his/O present/O whereabouts/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASH-IE/O ./O 
I/O understand/O lie/O is/O still/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O you/O will/O continue/O ,/O please/O ,/O with/O the/O names/O ,/O if/O you/O can/O recall/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Joe/PERSON Aidlin/PERSON I/O mentioned/O without/O further/O identifying/O him/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O young/O attorney/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
He/O was/O married/O to/O 81595-51-pt/O ./O 
4/O --/O 2/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O a/O woman/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Mary/PERSON Raden/PERSON ./O 
Mary/PERSON Raden/PERSON at/O that/O time/O was/O office/O secretary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
She/O was/O not/O an/O official/O :/O she/O was/O an/O office/O secretary/O ./O 
I/O might/O add/O that/O Joe/PERSON Aidlin/PERSON and/O Mary/PERSON Raden/PERSON later/O moved/O into/O my/O home/O which/O I/O had/O had/O at/O 1124/O North/O Randall/PERSON Court/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O that/O Mary/PERSON Raden/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O she/O was/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
She/O was/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
She/O was/O a/O member/O of/O a/O street/O unit/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION at/O tlat/O time/O ./O 
She/O was/O an/O exposed/O party/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O she/O was/O a/O member/O of/O another/O cell/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Were/O there/O others/O whose/O names/O you/O can/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Charlie/PERSON Daggett/PERSON ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION newspaperman/O ,/O was/O a/O member/O of/O that/O professional/O unit/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O additional/O descriptive/O information/O you/O could/O give/O regarding/O Daggett/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O not/O particularly/O ,/O except/O that/O he/O was/O rather/O a/O vacillating/O sort/O of/O character/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O mean/O for/O you/O to/O describe/O personal/O traits/O particularly/O ,/O unless/O it/O is/O necessary/O in/O order/O to/O identify/O the/O individual/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O man/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O I/O 'd/O say/O ,/O about/O 35/O years/O old/O ,/O rather/O inclined/O to/O flesh/O ,/O had/O many/O years/O '/O experience/O as/O a/O newspaperman/O ./O 
I/O believe/O he/O worked/O on/O the/O Seattle/ORGANIZATION Star/ORGANIZATION as/O city/O editor/O while/O that/O paper/O was/O still/O going/O ./O 
I/O understand/O he/O worked/O on/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION News/O around/O about/O 1934/O or/O 1935/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O close/O friend/O of/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O assume/O that/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON may/O have/O even/O recruited/O him/O ./O 
I/O remember/O at/O one/O time/O that/O Charlie/PERSON Daggett/PERSON undertook/O to/O write/O for/O a/O magazine/O called/O New/O Theatre/O ./O 
New/O Theatre/O was/O a/O left-wing/O Communist-controlled/O publication/O put/O out/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O believe/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Herb/PERSON Klein/PERSON was/O its/O editor/O ./O 
He/O wrote/O two/O or/O three/O articles/O in/O there/O in/O which/O he/O blackguarded/O several/O personalities/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O know/O that/O the/O magazine/O was/O a/O sell-out/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O was/O even/O selling/O at/O a/O premium/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O considerable/O speculation/O as/O to/O who/O had/O written/O the/O article/O ./O 
I/O think/O at/O one/O time/O somebody/O rather/O shrewdly/O guessed/O that/O he/O did/O ,/O and/O about/O that/O time/O they/O concluded/O that/O somebody/O else/O did/O ./O 
So/O they/O never/O did/O pin/O it/O down/O to/O him/O ./O 
But/O Charlie/PERSON Daggett/PERSON has/O admitted/O to/O me/O several/O times/O ,/O with/O considerable/O pride/O ,/O that/O he/O wrote/O these/O articles/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O his/O present/O employment/O is/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O identify/O him/O as/O to/O the/O meetings/O that/O he/O attended/O ./O 
How/O frequently/O did/O you/O see/O him/O at/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O almost/O every/O week/O for/O a/O period/O of/O time/O when/O we/O were/O trying/O to/O get/O these/O professional/O units/O going/O and/O trying/O to/O work/O out/O some/O formula/O by/O which/O the/O professionals/O could/O participate/O in/O Communist/O work/O without/O exposing/O themselves/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ,/O sir/O ;/O now/O if/O you/O will/O proceed/O to/O name/O others/O ,/O if/O you/O recall/O them/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O AsHE/PERSON ./O 
Herb/PERSON and/O Minna/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
1429/O This/O Herb/PERSON Klein/PERSON ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O is/O not/O to/O be/O confused/O with/O the/O editor/O of/O the/O New/O Theatre/O magazine/O ./O 
This/O is/O Herb/PERSON and/O Minna/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O Herb/PERSON Klein/PERSON had/O been/O a/O correspondent/O for/O UP/O over/O in/O Germany/LOCATION before/O Hitler/PERSON 's/O rise/O to/O power/O ./O 
I/O believe/O his/O immediate/O interest/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION when/O he/O came/O in/O was/O his/O fear/O of/O the/O threat/O of/O fascism/O ./O 
Minna/PERSON Klein/PERSON came/O in/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
I/O understand/O later/O that/O he/O taught/O out/O at/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION City/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION as/O an/O instructor/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O journalism/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O on/O that/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O the/O spelling/O of/O his/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
K-l-e-i-n/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O did/O he/O and/O his/O wife/O attend/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O they/O attended/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O every/O meeting/O that/O I/O attended/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O at/O that/O time/O I/O was/O attending/O at/O least/O half/O of/O these/O meetings/O because/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O leadership/O in/O there/O that/O had/O had/O any/O experience/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O for/O that/O reason/O I/O was/O devoting/O a/O considerable/O amount/O of/O my/O time/O to/O them/O ,/O including/O meeting/O with/O them/O after/O their/O meetings/O were/O over/O ,/O in/O my/O home/O ./O 
I/O might/O add/O that/O most/O of/O these/O meetings/O were/O held/O in/O my/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
DO/O you/O know/O in/O what/O business/O Mr./O Klein/PERSON is/O engaged/O now/O ,/O or/O how/O he/O is/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O AsHE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O name/O of/O others/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Lucy/PERSON Stander/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O at/O that/O time/O the/O wife/O of/O J./PERSON Stander/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Lionel/PERSON Stander/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O character/O actor/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
He/O ,/O however/O ,/O was/O not/O in/O the/O unit/O for/O any/O great/O length/O of/O time/O ./O 
I/O recall/O distinctly/O that/O he/O was/O brought/O in/O and/O a/O very/O short/O time/O later/O was/O transferred/O out/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O reason/O for/O the/O transfer/O ./O 
1/O think/O it/O was/O arranged/O directly/O between/O Stander/PERSON and/O the/O county/O office/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
However/O ,/O his/O wife/O remained/O in/O one/O of/O these/O professional/O units/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O definite/O in/O your/O statement/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O Lionel/PERSON Stander/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Lionel/PERSON Stander/PERSON was/O definitely/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ./O 
He/O was/O transferred/O in/O ,/O and/O I/O handled/O the/O transfer/O ./O 
Of/O that/O I/O am/O positive/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O from/O what/O place/O he/O was/O transferred/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O referred/O to/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Hull/PERSON a/O few/O moments/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O Hull/PERSON or/O Hall/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Hull/PERSON ,/O H-u-l-1/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O that/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
I/O recruited/O him/O ./O 
He/O was/O one/O of/O the/O first/O members/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O his/O employment/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O the/O time/O I/O recruited/O him/O he/O was/O a/O reporter/O for/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION Times/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O think/O he/O shortly/O afterward/O lost/O his/O job/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O too/O clear/O about/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O his/O wife/O a/O member/O ,/O also/O ,/O or/O not/O ?/O 
1430/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Charlotte/PERSON Hull/PERSON was/O also/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O cominil/O in/O at/O the/O same/O time/O he/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAV.N/O XER/O ./O 
Are/O there/O others/O whose/O names/O you/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O Asiu/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O mentioned/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Lou/PERSON Harris/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O Vera/PERSON Harris/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O T./PERSON \/PERSON VENER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O Lou/PERSON Harris/PERSON '/O position/O at/O the/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O AsiE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O holding/O some/O minor/O position/O with/O Paramount/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O if/O I/O am/O not/O mistaken/O ,/O he/O came/O out/O here/O to/O work/O in/O the/O trade/O department/O of/O the/O publicity/O end/O of/O the/O studios/O ,/O writing/O publicitv/O for/O motion-picture/O trade/O magazines/O and/O also/O laying/O out/O ads/O for/O tlie/O same/O trade/O magazines/O ./O 
Mr./O T.AENNER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O the/O name/O Lou/PERSON is/O an/O abbrevi/O -/O ation/O of/O a/O name/O or/O whether/O that/O is/O his/O full/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O would/O n't/O know/O as/O to/O that/O ./O 
I/O never/O knew/O him/O as/O anything/O else/O except/O Lou/PERSON Harris/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
L-o-u/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
L-o-u/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O other/O persons/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O mention/O Jane/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O you/O have/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Jane/PERSON Wilson/PERSON is/O the/O sister/O of/O Jack/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ./O 
She/O is/O better/O known/O in/O the/O party/O as/O Jane/PERSON Wallace/PERSON ./O 
I/O helped/O recruit/O her/O ./O 
Her/O brother/O signed/O the/O card/O ,/O and/O I/O countersigned/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O spoke/O earlier/O of/O a/O dentist/O ,/O but/O you/O did/O not/O give/O a/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Dr./O Albert/PERSON Hickox/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Dr./O Albert/PERSON Hickox/PERSON ,/O H-i-c-k-o-x/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O was/O he/O from/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
A/O practicing/O dentist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O giving/O us/O the/O name/O of/O Jane/PERSON Wilson/PERSON you/O did/O not/O state/O what/O her/O connection/O was/O ,/O what/O her/O affiliation/O was/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O other/O than/O being/O a/O member/O ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O us/O anything/O more/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O she/O was/O in/O this/O unit/O she/O was/O only/O a/O rank-andfile/O member/O ./O 
At/O a/O later/O time/O I/O ran/O into/O her/O working/O in/O the/O Interna/LOCATION -/O tional/O Workers/O '/O office/O as/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O a/O paid/O worker/O in/O there/O ,/O some/O secretarial/O capacity/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
That/O is/O when/O they/O were/O located/O in/O the/O Douglas/O Building/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Syd/PERSON Birk/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O very/O well/O ./O 
Syd/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O is/O the/O third/O person/O that/O I/O recruited/O the/O night/O I/O recruited/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON and/O Jack/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O how/O he/O was/O later/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O too/O much/O about/O Syd/PERSON 's/O early/O employment/O ./O 
At/O the/O outset/O he/O certainly/O was/O n't/O employed/O by/O the/O party/O ./O 
He/O was/O unemployed/O for/O a/O considerable/O length/O of/O time/O ./O 
He/O had/O employment/O at/O one/O time/O with/O the/O Mayer/ORGANIZATION Advertising/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION on/O South/O Main/O Street/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O direct-mail/O advertising/O company/O ./O 
I/O lost/O track/O of/O Syd/PERSON ./O 
The/O last/O I/O knew/O of/O him/O he/O was/O working/O for/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O ./O 
I/O had/O dinner/O with/O him/O one/O night/O m/O about/O 1946/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O so/O obtuse/O that/O I/O was/O unable/O to/O convey/O to/O him/O my/O sentiments/O ,/O and/O we/O parted/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1431/O friends/O ./O 
The/O next/O time/O I/O saw/O him/O on/O the/O street/O he/O would/O n't/O speak/O to/O me/O ,/O or/O did/O n't/O speak/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O Syd/PERSON Birk/PERSON spell/O his/O name/O S-y-d/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
B-u-r-k-e/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
B-i-r-k/O is/O a/O party/O name/O ./O 
His/O real/O name/O is/O Berkowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O does/O he/O spell/O his/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O AsHE/PERSON ./O 
B-e-r-k-o-w-i-t-z/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O ,/O for/O his/O father/O ,/O that/O his/O father/O has/O no/O sympathy/O whatsoever/O for/O Syd/PERSON 's/O politics/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O last/O time/O that/O you/O saw/O Charles/PERSON Daggett/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O saw/O Charley/PERSON Daggett/PERSON in/O about/O 1939/O up/O in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ./O 
A/O rather/O amusing/O incident/O impressed/O it/O on/O me/O ./O 
Charley/PERSON had/O just/O rented/O an/O apartment/O up/O there/O that/O was/O unfurnished/O ,/O and/O he/O had/O undertaken/O to/O make/O some/O furniture/O to/O get/O out/O of/O buying/O any/O ./O 
I/O recall/O distinctly/O that/O he/O had/O a/O chair/O that/O he/O was/O very/O proud/O of/O and/O was/O showing/O me/O the/O construction/O of/O it/O ./O 
It/O was/O simply/O four/O upright/O legs/O and/O a/O piece/O to/O go/O across/O for/O the/O seat/O ,/O and/O I/O remember/O that/O I/O sat/O down/O on/O it/O and/O the/O thing/O collapsed/O ./O 
It/O developed/O that/O all/O he/O had/O done/O was/O to/O drive/O one/O nail/O through/O each/O leg/O of/O the/O chair/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O he/O was/O very/O much/O distressed/O that/O his/O craftsmanship/O had/O been/O exposed/O ./O 
I/O really/O think/O he/O ought/O to/O get/O himself/O a/O job/O as/O an/O apprentice/O with/O Percy/PERSON Solotoy/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O at/O that/O time/O or/O any/O other/O time/O deliver/O to/O you/O any/O document/O or/O book/O relating/O to/O communism/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
He/O gave/O me/O a/O book/O ,/O the/O 1938/O Report/O of/O the/O Un/O -/O American/ORGANIZATION Activities/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O I/O have/O in/O my/O possession/O now/O with/O his/O name/O on/O it/O ./O 
I/O understand/O Mr./O Daggett/PERSON does/O n't/O remember/O me/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O a/O book/O I/O borrowed/O from/O him/O in/O his/O home/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O it/O to/O this/O day/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O it/O with/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ,/O unfortunately/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O book/O that/O he/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O received/O from/O Congressman/O Havenner/PERSON ,/O of/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Containing/O reports/O of/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ,/O for/O the/O year/O 1938/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O his/O giving/O you/O a/O report/O prepared/O by/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O he/O was/O amused/O at/O some/O of/O the/O testimony/O and/O thought/O it/O might/O be/O enlightening/O to/O me/O ./O 
It/O was/O ,/O very/O ,/O because/O at/O that/O time/O I/O was/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O during/O the/O period/O of/O time/O that/O you/O were/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O you/O must/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O have/O become/O well/O acquainted/O with/O other/O functionaries/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O the/O func/O -/O tionaries/O in/O southern/O California/LOCATION who/O were/O active/O in/O the/O work/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O came/O into/O the/O party/O ,/O the/O bureau/O was/O composed/O of/O Elmer/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ,/O organizer-this/O is/O the/O county/O ;/O Elmer/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ,/O organizer/O ;/O Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON ,/O organization/O secretary/O ,/O and/O Jimmy/PERSON Allen/PERSON ./O 
I/O never/O did/O figure/O out/O what/O Jimmy/PERSON Allen/PERSON 's/O function/O was/O ./O 
A/O short/O time/O later/O Hanoff/PERSON was/O removed/O as/O organizer/O ./O 
Lawrence/PERSON Ross/PERSON became/O acting/O organizer/O ,/O and/O Louise/PERSON Todd/PERSON came/O down/O at/O about/O that/O time/O and/O she/O became/O organizer/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O considerable/O shuffle/O there/O ./O 
It/O was/O quite/O a/O scandal/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O which/O they/O hushed/O up/O ./O 
Then/O Ross/PERSON went/O to/O 1432/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION as/O editor/O of/O the/O Western/O Worker/O ./O 
John/PERSON Leech/PERSON became/O organization/O secretary/O under/O Louise/PERSON Todd/PERSON until/O she/O went/O to/O Tehachapi/LOCATION some/O time/O in/O 1935/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O State/O women/O 's/O -/O yes/O ,/O prison/O for/O women/O ./O 
Then/O Leech/PERSON became/O organizer/O ,/O and/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O James/PERSON Thorm/PERSON ,/O whose/O real/O name/O 1/O believe/O is/O Tourney/PERSON ,/O was/O made/O organizational/O secretary/O ./O 
There/O were/O two/O other/O people/O around/O about/O that/O time/O ./O 
One/O was/O Eva/PERSON Shafran/PERSON whom/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O was/O educational/O director/O ,/O and/O Betty/PERSON Gannett/PERSON was/O somewhere/O in/O the/O picture/O ./O 
I/O know/O she/O was/O on/O the/O county/O bureau/O ./O 
She/O exerted/O a/O very/O great/O deal/O of/O influence/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O 1936/O ,/O Leech/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O was/O removed/O ./O 
There/O was/O another/O complete/O reshuffle/O ,/O and/O Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON was/O brought/O out/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O from/O the/O East/O to/O be/O organizer/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O lapse/O of/O several/O months/O there/O when/O there/O were/O acting/O functionaries/O holding/O down/O the/O job/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O does/O Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON spell/O his/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
C-l-i-n-e/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O person/O ,/O Elmer/PERSON HarnoffMr/PERSON ./O 
ASHE/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Hanoff/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
-/O Hanoff/O to/O whom/O you/O referred/O also/O known/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Pop/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Pop/PERSON Hanoff/PERSON ,/O that/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O are/O there/O any/O other/O functionaries/O of/O the/O party/O whose/O names/O you/O can/O now/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O county/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
County/O leadership/O ./O 
Not/O offhand/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Tom/PERSON Patterson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O his/O affiliation/O with/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time/O he/O was/O Western/O Worker/O correspondent/O ./O 
I/O believe/O for/O a/O time/O he/O was/O organizer/O in/O the/O Firestone/O subsection/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
At/O a/O later/O date/O he/O went/O up/O to/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O worked/O on/O the/O Western/O Worker/O and/O eventually/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O became/O some/O kind/O of/O a/O functionary/O in/O the/O East/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O includes/O Oakland/ORGANIZATION and/O Berkeley/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Miriam/PERSON Bonner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Miriam/PERSON Bonner/PERSON was/O codirector/O of/O the/O Worker/O 's/O School/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION during/O the/O period/O of/O 1934/O ,/O 1935/O ,/O 1936/O with/O Lillian/PERSON Jones/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O Pat/PERSON Callahan/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Pat/PERSON Callahan/PERSON was/O an/O unemployed/O leader/O here/O about/O 1935-36/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Definitely/O ;/O member/O of/O the/O downtown/O section/O with/O his/O wife/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Clyde/O Champion/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Clyde/PERSON Champion/PERSON was/O section/O organizer/O for/O the/O party/O in/O Belvedere/O subsection/O ,/O 1935/O ,/O 1936/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
James/PERSON Tracy/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
James/PERSON Tracy/PERSON was/O in/O charge/O of/O railroad/O work/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O penetration/O into/O the/O railroad/O unions/O and/O brotherhoods/O working/O out/O of/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O a/O delegate/O to/O the/O national/O convention/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
James/PERSON I-n-g-h-a-m/PERSON ?/O 
Tracy/PERSON ,/O T-r-a-c-y/O ./O 
William/PERSON Ingham/PERSON ,/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1433/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
William/PERSON Ingham/PERSON functioned/O out/O in/O the/O San/LOCATION Fernando/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O for/O a/O long/O time/O was/O a/O member/O ,/O and/O ,/O for/O some/O time/O ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O disciplinary/O committee/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Loretta/PERSON Adam/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Loretta/PERSON Adams/PERSON is/O one/O of/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O in/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ,/O about/O 1934/O ,/O 1935/O ,/O and/O about/O 1936/O she/O transferred/O to/O Bakersfield/LOCATION where/O she/O was/O the/O Bakersfield-the/O Kern/LOCATION County/LOCATION section/O organizer/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O time/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON entered/O the/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O again/O the/O last/O name/O of/O that/O in/O -/O dividual/O ?/O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O the/O last/O name/O I/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Loretta/PERSON Adams/PERSON ,/O A-d-a-m-s/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
S./PERSON Adams/PERSON ./O 
E./O 0/O ./O 
Cope/O ,/O C-o-p-e/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Cope/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O his/O initials/O ./O 
He/O was/O active/O in/O the/O milk/O strike/O in/O 1932/O and/O 1933/O was/O a/O Communist/O Party/O member/O ./O 
To/O my/O certain/O knowledge/O in/O 1934/O ,/O when/O I/O had/O to/O go/O out/O to/O San/LOCATION Fernando/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION representing/O the/O county/O in/O an/O effort/O to/O straighten/O him/O out/O on/O some/O disruptive/O tactics/O that/O he/O was/O indulging/O in/O in/O the/O party/O out/O there/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O straighten/O him/O outMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
YOU/O are/O uncertain/O about/O his/O initials/O ./O 
Can/O you/O give/O us/O any/O further/O descriptive/O information/O which/O would/O definitely/O identify/O the/O individual/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Short/O ,/O stocky/O man/O ,/O short/O tempered/O ;/O unpredictable/O ./O 
believe/O he/O now/O works/O as/O a/O bartender/O ./O 
I/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Julia/PERSON Walsh/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Julia/PERSON Walsh/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O downtown/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O also/O was/O a/O functionary/O in/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Cliff/O Lechrome/O ,/O L-e-c-h-r-o-m-e/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Cliff/PERSON Lechrome/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O one/O of/O the/O units/O of/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION Street/LOCATION subsection/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O much/O else/O about/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Charles/PERSON McClaughlan/PERSON ,/O M-c-C-l-a-u-g-h-l-a-n/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Charlie/PERSON McClaughlan/PERSON was/O Communist/O Party/O organizer/O for/O Orange/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
This/O was/O a/O separate/O section/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O under/O the/O guidance/O of/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION section/O because/O of/O weakness/O of/O leadership/O in/O Orange/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
M./PERSON E./PERSON Freeman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O AsHE/PERSON ./O 
M./PERSON E./PERSON Freeman/PERSON was/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O down/O town/O ,/O I/O believe/O ;/O also/O active/O in/O the/O old/O Relief/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Protective/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Tom/PERSON Miller/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Tom/PERSON Miller/PERSON ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O understanding/O ,/O is/O a/O cousin/O of/O Emil/PERSON Freed/PERSON ./O 
Tom/PERSON Miller/PERSON was/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O a/O mass/O organization/O functionary/O and/O was/O a/O Communist/O Party/O member/O ./O 
He/O held/O membership/O in/O a/O street/O unit/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Emil/PERSON Freed/PERSON ,/O to/O whom/O you/O just/O referred/O -/O Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Emil/O Freed/O wasMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
The/O spelling/O is/O E-m-i-1/O F-r-e-e-d/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Emil/PERSON Freed/PERSON has/O ,/O so/O far/O back/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O been/O a/O function/O -/O ary/O of/O one/O kind/O or/O another/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O one/O time/O he/O was/O Hollywood/O subsection/O organizer/O ./O 
I/O distinctly/O recall/O him/O being/O in/O county/O organizational/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O recall/O one/O instance/O where/O he/O kept/O asking/O something/O to/O be/O explained/O over/O and/O over/O again/O on/O the/O basis/O 1434/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O that/O he/O was/O afraid/O some/O of/O the/O comrades/O did/O n't/O understand/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O finally/O got/O disgusted/O and/O told/O him/O to/O speak/O for/O himself/O ,/O and/O let/O 's/O get/O on/O with/O the/O agenda/O ./O 
He/O has/O held/O any/O number/O of/O functionary/O jobs/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O at/O this/O time/O what/O they/O are/O ./O 
I/O remember/O distinctly/O at/O a/O free-speech/O meeting/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O 1934/O where/O he/O was/O keenly/O disappointed/O because/O the/O police/O would/O n't/O arrest/O him/O ,/O and/O he/O pushed/O his/O way/O over/O to/O a/O squad/O car/O and/O they/O finally/O obliged/O him/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O first/O time/O he/O made/O a/O martyr/O of/O himself/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Melvyn/PERSON Letzman/PERSON ,/O L-e-t-z-m-a-n/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Letzman/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O later/O transferred/O to/O San/LOCATION Pedro/LOCATION and/O was/O an/O assistant/O to/O whoever/O was/O then/O the/O section/O organizer/O down/O there/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O just/O who/O that/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O you/O one/O or/O two/O other/O questions/O about/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
What/O was/O your/O connection/O with/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Artists/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
In/O about/O 1937/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Artists/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION conceived/O the/O idea/O of/O touring/O the/O country/O in/O their/O name/O with/O a/O motionpicture/O short/O ,/O about/O a/O 30-minute/O sound/O film/O ,/O called/O Heart/O of/O Spain/LOCATION ./O 
There/O was/O no/O one/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION that/O they/O could/O use/O ,/O so/O they/O apparently/O appealed/O to/O the/O downtown/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party-that/O is/O ,/O the/O county/O -LSB-/O branch/O -RSB-/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O supply/O a/O suitable/O manager/O and/O speaker/O for/O this/O tour/O ./O 
Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON recommended/O me/O ,/O and/O after/O considerable/O consultation/O with/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O they/O fin/O -/O ally/O decided/O that/O it/O would/O be/O all/O right/O for/O me/O to/O go/O representing/O the/O committee/O ,/O even/O though/O I/O was/O fairly/O widely/O known/O as/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O ./O 
They/O bought/O a/O couple/O of/O old/O broken-down/O laundry/O trucks/O which/O they/O painted/O up/O to/O look/O like/O ambulances/O ,/O and/O I/O and/O several/O other/O people/O made/O the/O tour/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O ending/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION about/O the/O 14th/O of/O December/O 1937/O ./O 
The/O purpose/O of/O the/O trip/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O was/O to/O raise/O money/O for-or/O the/O ostensible/O purpose/O was/O to/O raise/O money/O for/O the/O North/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION To/ORGANIZATION Aid/ORGANIZATION Spanish/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O that/O was/O another/O device/O to/O raise/O money/O for/O the/O Loyalist/O Spain/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEXNER/PERSON ./O 
Which/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O and/O project/O at/O that/O particular/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O want/O to/O testify/O as/O to/O how/O much/O of/O the/O money/O ever/O got/O to/O Spain/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O T.AENNER/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O direct/O information/O of/O your/O own/O as/O to/O the/O misuse/O of/O any/O of/O that/O money/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O just/O got/O a/O very/O strong/O feeling/O that/O it/O did/O n't/O all/O get/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O at/O this/O point/O to/O go/O back/O in/O your/O testimony/O to/O the/O organizational/O work/O done/O by/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON and/O later/O by/O V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON in/O the/O motion/O picture/O industry/O ,/O generally/O ./O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O too/O familiar/O with/O that/O aspect/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activity/O except/O insofar/O as/O I/O had/O some/O knowledge/O of/O it/O as/O a/O result/O of/O reports/O made/O in/O the/O county/O executive/O committee/O meeting/O in/O informal/O discussions/O with/O various/O functionaries/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O including/O discussions/O with/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON over/O coffee/O sometimes/O ./O 
I/O do/O know/O that/O they/O raised/O a/O considerable/O sum/O of/O money/O out/O there/O during/O that/O period-I/O believe/O considerably/O more/O than/O they/O anticipated/O at/O the/O outset/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O they/O quite/O knew/O the/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1435/O gold/O mine/O they/O were/O opening/O up/O when/O they/O did/O set/O up/O these/O study/O groups/O ./O 
I/O know/O on/O one/O occasion/O Stanley-the/O election/O campaign/O committee/O ,/O I/O should/O say/O ,/O of/O which/O I/O was/O the/O head-needed/O some/O quick/O money/O to/O finance/O the/O preliminary/O arrangements/O for/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON to/O speak/O at/O a/O big/O stadium/O on/O the/O East/LOCATION Side/LOCATION ./O 
We/O needed/O this/O money/O to/O lay/O on/O the/O line/O right/O now/O ./O 
Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON raised/O ,/O within/O a/O matter/O of/O a/O few/O hours/O ,/O a/O thousand/O dollars/O ,/O brought/O it/O down/O in/O cash/O ,/O and/O gave/O ./O 
it/O to/O me/O ./O 
We/O later/O paid/O this/O back/O ./O 
I/O remember/O another/O occasion/O when/O I/O had/O to/O go/O out/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION with/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON to/O make/O a/O movie/O short-I/O believe/O it/O was/O a/O talkie-which/O was/O to/O be/O used/O for/O campaign/O purposes/O ./O 
It/O never/O was/O used/O ,/O but/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O made/O ./O 
The/O last/O thing/O before/O I/O left/O the/O downtown/O office/O with/O Browder/PERSON was/O to/O receive/O from/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON several/O hundred/O dollars/O to/O turn/O over/O to/O Tania/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O charge/O of/O making/O this/O film/O ,/O and/O which/O I/O did/O turn/O over/O to/O her/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O who/O was/O her/O husband/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O the/O director/O ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
From/O your/O observation/O and/O your/O knowledge/O as/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O what/O would/O you/O say/O was/O the/O principal/O objective/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O how/O did/O it/O go/O about/O the/O accomplishment/O of/O it/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ASHE/PERSON ./O 
In/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
