COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 3/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MAY/O 22/O ,/O 23/O ,/O 24/O ,/O 25/O ;/O JUNE/O 25/O AND/O 26/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 81595/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1951/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD./PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION MORGAN/LOCATION M./LOCATION MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/O of/O Cormmittee/PERSON RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O Page/O May/O 22/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Jose/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ----------/O ------------------/O ---------/O May/O 23/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Budd/PERSON Schulberg/PERSON -/O ,/O ----------------/O ./O 
---------------/O May/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Frank/PERSON Wright/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ------------/O -----/O 533/O 581/O -/O 625/O ----------/O May/O 25/O ,/O 1951/O :/O 647/O Testimony/O of/O Jos6/O Ferrer/O -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -------------------------/O ./O 
June/O 25/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ---------------------------------/O 671/O June/O 26/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O J./PERSON Edward/PERSON Bromberg/PERSON ./O 
./O 
----------------------------/O ./O 
719/O Ia/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 3/O TUESDAY/O ,/O MAY/O 22/O ,/O 1951/O UNrfED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O adjournment/O at/O 10:30/O a./O m./O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON -LRB-/O appearance/O as/O noted/O in/O transcript/O -RRB-/O ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON -LRB-/O appearance/O as/O noted/O in/O transcript/O -RRB-/O ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O :/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O there/O are/O present/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O Messrs./PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O Velde/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/PERSON ,/O a/O quorum/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Whom/O do/O you/O have/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jose/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O stand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ./O 
?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O JOSE/PERSON FERRER/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ABE/O FORTAS/O AND/O EDWARD/PERSON REISKIND/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Jose/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O here/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O themselves/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O FORTAS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O Abe/PERSON Fortas/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O firm/O of/O Arnold/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Fortas/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Porter/ORGANIZATION ,/O Ring/O Building/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON ,/O representing/O Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O REISKIND/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O Edwin/PERSON Reiskind/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O attorney/O for/O Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ./O 
533/O 534/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O office/O address/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O REISKIND/PERSON ./O 
1270/O Sixth/O Avenue/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O state/O briefly/O for/O the/O committee/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Most/O of/O my/O education/O took/O place/O ,/O through/O high/O school/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O to/O various/O schools/O ,/O and/O I/O only/O went/O to/O school/O in/O Puerto/LOCATION Rico/LOCATION 2/O years/O ,/O first/O and/O second/O years/O of/O high/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O that/O you/O speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ?/O 
hear/O you/O up/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Righto/O ./O 
We/O ca/O n't/O Most/O of/O my/O education/O up/O to/O college/O ,/O that/O is/O through/O high/O school/O ,/O took/O place/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
The/O first/O and/O second/O years/O of/O high/O school/O ,/O I/O went/O to/O school/O in/O Puerto/LOCATION Rico/LOCATION ./O 
When/O I/O graduated/O from/O high/O school/O I/O spent/O a/O year/O preparing/O for/O my/O college-entrance/O examination/O ./O 
I/O went/O abroad/O ,/O to/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O for/O a/O year/O ,/O then/O entered/O Princeton/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O fall/O of/O 1928/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O class/O of/O 1932/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O graduate/O in/O 1932/O ,/O but/O did/O graduate/O in/O 1933/O ./O 
I/O majored/O in/O architecture/O ./O 
In/O 1933/O I/O decided/O to/O change/O my/O profession/O ,/O and/O did/O an/O additional/O year/O 's/O work/O at/O Princeton/LOCATION in/O modern/O languages/O ./O 
Then/O from/O 1934/O to/O 1935/O I/O studied/O at/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION with/O the/O intention/O of/O getting/O a/O master/O 's/O degree/O in/O modern/O languages/O ./O 
I/O completed/O all/O the/O requirements/O for/O this/O degree/O except/O that/O of/O writing/O my/O thesis/O ,/O the/O reason/O for/O not/O writing/O my/O thesis/O being/O that/O in/O June/O 1935/O I/O decided/O to/O go/O into/O the/O theater/O professionally/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O outline/O briefly/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O your/O experience/O has/O been/O after/O entering/O the/O profession/O of/O acting/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON entered/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O to/O make/O it/O brief/O ,/O from/O 1935/O to/O the/O present/O time/O I/O have/O been/O connected/O with/O 24/O Broadway/O productions/O ;/O I/O have/O done/O about/O 70/O weeks/O of/O stock/O ;/O and/O I/O have/O been/O in/O 4/O motion/O pictures/O ./O 
Would/O you/O care/O for/O any/O names/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Suppose/O you/O name/O three/O or/O four/O of/O the/O principal/O Broadway/O productions/O with/O which/O you/O have/O been/O associated/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
The/O ones/O that/O might/O be/O best/O known/O to/O the/O general/O public/O ,/O sir/O ,/O would/O be/O Brother/PERSON Rat/PERSON ,/O Charlie/PERSON 's/O Aunt/O -/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Both/O of/O those/O were/O also/O adapted/O to/O the/O movies/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O they/O were/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O take/O part/O in/O the/O movie/O productions/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ;/O I/O did/O not/O ./O 
The/O Theatre/O Guild/O 's/O production/O of/O Othello/O ;/O Cyrano/O de/O Bergerac/O on/O the/O stage/O ;/O The/O Silver/O Whistle/O ;/O and/O now/O Twentieth/O Century/O with/O Miss/PERSON Swanson/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON entered/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O if/O you/O will/O state/O the/O main/O screen/O productions/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
There/O were/O four/O ./O 
The/O first/O was/O Joan/PERSON of/O Arc/O ,/O starring/O Ingrid/PERSON Bergman/PERSON ./O 
The/O second/O was/O Whirlpool/ORGANIZATION ,/O starring/O Gene/PERSON Tierney/PERSON ./O 
The/O third/O was/O Crisis/O ,/O starring/O Cary/PERSON Grant/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O fourth/O was/O Cyrano/O de/O Bergerac/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O about/O the/O picture/O Strange/O Fruit/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O has/O never/O been/O made/O on/O film/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O stage/O production/O ?/O 
Mr./O FmRRER/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O produced/O and/O directed/O it/O but/O did/O not/O play/O in/O it/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O mention/O it/O because/O it/O was/O not/O very/O much/O of/O a/O success/O ./O 
It/O only/O ran/O a/O few/O weeks/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTrRY/O 535/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O the/O period/O of/O time/O during/O which/O you/O were/O engaged/O as/O an/O actor/O in/O screen/O productions/O ?/O 
What/O was/O the/O date/O of/O your/O first/O engagement/O as/O an/O actor/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O remember/O if/O it/O was/O 1947/O or/O 1948/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O 1947/O ,/O September/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
I/O was/O engaged/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 3/O weeks/O in/O Joan/PERSON of/O Arc/O ./O 
Whirlpool/ORGANIZATION was/O in/O 1949/O ,/O the/O months/O of/O June/O and/O July/O ./O 
Crisis/O was/O in/O 1950/O ,/O the/O months/O of/O January/O and/O February/O ./O 
And/O Cyrano/PERSON was/O in/O 1950/O ,/O the/O month/O of/O July/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION on/O each/O of/O the/O occasions/O you/O have/O listed/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Generally/O speaking/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O it/O has/O been/O my/O practice/O to/O leave/O Hollywood/LOCATION as/O soon/O as/O the/O picture/O is/O terminated/O ./O 
There/O are/O two/O exceptions/O ./O 
In/O every/O case/O I/O arrived/O just/O in/O time/O to/O start/O work/O ./O 
After/O Joan/PERSON of/O Arc/O I/O remained/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION for/O approximately/O 4/O weeks/O beyond/O the/O term/O of/O by/O contract/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O not/O have/O to/O be/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION for/O a/O period/O of/O time/O prior/O to/O the/O actual/O production/O of/O the/O picture/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O when/O I/O arrived/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION for/O Joan/PERSON of/O Arc/O they/O had/O already/O begun/O shooting/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O vast/O production/O ,/O 4/O months/O ,/O and/O I/O only/O worked/O 3/O weeks/O ./O 
For/O Whirlpool/O I/O arrived/O just/O before/O they/O began/O shooting/O and/O left/O right/O after/O ./O 
risis/O ,/O I/O stayed/O afterward/O because/O we/O began/O preparatory/O work/O for/O Cyrano/O de/O Bergerac/O ./O 
I/O worked/O on/O Cyrano/O for/O 3/O or/O 4/O months/O before/O the'actual/O shooting/O began/O ,/O because/O having/O produced/O as/O well/O as/O played/O in/O the/O Broadway/O production/O ,/O they/O felt/O I/O could/O be/O useful/O to/O them/O in/O the/O capacity/O of/O a/O technical/O adviser/O on/O the/O film/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O periods/O did/O you/O spend/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O addi/O -/O tion/O to/O those/O you/O have/O described/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
1/O was/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O living/O in/O downtown/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O for/O 3/O weeks/O when/O Othello/O played/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in/O 1943/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
1945/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O in/O January/O 1945/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION for/O 4/O weeks/O during/O the/O summer/O of/O 1939/O under/O contract/O to/O RKO/O ,/O a/O contract/O which/O resulted/O in/O no/O work/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O 4/O weeks/O we/O called/O it/O off/O by/O mutual/O consent/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION on/O several/O occasions/O `/O during/O 1950/O for/O a/O day/O or/O two/O or/O a/O week/O at/O a/O time/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O doing/O a/O national/O publicity/O junket/O for/O Cyrano/O ./O 
I/O traveled/O all/O over/O the/O country/O and/O appeared/O in/O about/O a/O dozen/O cities/O ,/O spoke/O on/O Cyrano/O ,/O and/O during/O the/O course/O of/O this/O junket/O had/O occasion/O to/O return/O to/O California/LOCATION on/O several/O occasions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Again/O may/O I/O suggest/O that/O you/O talk/O a/O little/O louder/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O thought/O this/O -LSB-/O indicating/O loud/O -/O speaker/O -RSB-/O was/O serving/O some/O purpose/O ./O 
Apparently/O it/O is/O n't/O ./O 
I/O will/O speak/O louder/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Had/O you/O completed/O your/O answer/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O just/O going/O to/O say/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O which/O may/O be/O a/O gratuitous/O remark/O on/O my/O part/O ,/O that/O my/O stay/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION has/O always/O been/O as/O a/O transient/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O lived/O there/O or/O considered/O it/O my/O residence/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O after/O the/O service/O of/O a/O subpena/O on/O you/O ,/O the/O committee/O reecived/O a/O letter/O from/O you/O ,/O through/O counsel/O ,/O in/O which/O you/O stated/O :/O 536/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O I/O attest/O and/O will/O so/O swear/O under/O oath/O that/O I/O am/O not/O ,/O have/O never/O been/O ,/O could/O not/O be/O ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O nor/O ,/O specifically/O ,/O am/O I/O a/O sympathizer/O with/O any/O Communist/O aim/O ,/O a/O fellow/O traveler/O ,/O or/O in/O any/O way/O an/O encourager/O of/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION concept/O or/O objective/O ./O 
Is/O that/O substantially/O your/O statement/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O assume/O it/O is/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
In/O any/O event/O ,/O that/O defi/O -/O nitely/O reflects/O my/O views/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O read/O it/O to/O you/O is/O it/O appeared/O in/O the/O letter/O as/O a/O quotation/O ,/O and/O therefore/O I/O assumed/O it/O was/O your/O statement/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O now/O have/O a/O copy/O of/O the/O letter/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O it/O is/O accurate/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O or/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O now/O nor/O have/O I/O ever/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O or/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O sympathizer/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Paraphrasing/O the/O language/O of/O your/O statement/O ,/O have/O you/O been/O a/O sympathizer/O with/O any/O Communist/O aim/O ,/O or/O have/O you/O been/O a/O fellow/O traveler/O ,/O or/O in/O any/O way/O an/O encourager/O of/O any/O Communist/O Party/O concept/O or/O objective/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O time/O I/O could/O even/O remotely/O be/O said/O to/O have/O been/O in/O sympathy/O with/O any/O Communist/O aim/O was/O when/O it/O coincided/O with/O the/O aim/O of/O our/O Government/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O when/O they/O wanted/O us/O to/O win/O the/O last/O war/O ,/O I/O certainly/O was/O '/O in/O sympathy/O with/O that/O ;/O but/O in/O the/O sense/O you/O indicate/O ,/O I/O never/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O indicating/O your/O affiliation/O or/O connection/O with/O quite/O a/O number/O of/O organizations/O which/O have/O from/O time/O to/O time/O been/O cited/O by/O various/O governmental/O agencies/O as/O Communist-front/O organizations/O ./O 
You/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O ./O 
are/O aware/O that/O affiliations/O with/O or/O activities/O in/O Communist-front/O organizations/O ,/O if/O true/O and/O unexplained/O ,/O leave/O the/O implication/O that/O one/O is/O in/O fact/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O has/O been/O ,/O or/O that/O he/O is/O in/O fact/O a/O sympathizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O an/O encourager/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION concepts/O and/O objectives/O ./O 
You/O agree/O with/O that/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
This/O has/O been/O made/O dramatically/O clear/O to/O me/O recently/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O `/O committee/O is/O quite/O concerned/O about/O the/O use/O of/O Communist/O fronts/O in/O exploiting/O the/O objectives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O that/O is/O particularly/O true/O with/O regard/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O only/O one/O phase/O of/O the/O entertainment/O field/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O witness/O who/O appeared/O here/O before/O this/O committee/O last/O week/O ,/O Mr./O Roy/PERSON M./PERSON Brewer/PERSON ,/O whose/O position/O with/O a/O labor/O union/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION over/O a/O long/O period/O of/O time/O has/O put/O him/O in/O a/O position/O of/O having/O special/O knowledge/O on/O this/O subject/O ,/O states/O that/O the/O real/O power/O that/O they/O -LSB-/O the/O Communists/O -RSB-/O had/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION was/O through/O their/O front/O organizations/O ./O 
He/O also/O testified/O at/O some/O length/O regarding/O the/O Communist/O fronts/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
This/O may/O in/O one/O way/O or/O another/O be/O true/O as/O to/O all/O the/O entertainment/O fields/O ./O 
At/O least/O ,/O it/O applies/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 537/O Mr./O Brewer/PERSON testified/O as/O follows/O ,/O on/O page/O 131/O of/O the/O transcript/O :/O \*/O \*/O \*/O The/O Communist/O fronts/O played/O a/O very/O important/O part/O in/O publicizing/O the/O class/O struggle/O and/O publicizing/O their/O efforts/O to/O infiltrate/O and/O take/O control/O of/O all/O trade-union/O activities/O which/O they/O felt/O would/O promote/O the/O philosophy/O of/O their/O party/O ./O 
But/O in/O this/O Hollywood/O situation/O the/O fronts/O played/O an/O even/O more/O important/O part/O in/O this/O control/O of/O the/O thought/O of/O the/O community/O ,/O which/O certainly/O followed/O over/O into/O the/O unions/O and/O made/O it/O very/O difficult/O for/O those/O of/O us/O who/O were/O trying/O to/O expose/O the/O Communist/O nature/O of/O this/O thing/O to/O get/O that/O idea/O across/O ./O 
During/O this/O period/O the/O fronts/O played/O a/O very/O important/O part/O in/O controlling/O the/O thought/O of/O the/O community/O ,/O which/O I/O testified/O to/O yesterday/O ./O 
This/O was/O really/O the/O instrument/O by/O which/O they/O got/O all/O these/O people/O ,/O most/O of/O whom/O were/O honest/O ,/O sincere/O people/O who/O wanted/O to/O do/O the/O right/O thing/O ,/O who/O wanted/O to/O serve/O humanity/O in/O a/O practical/O way/O ,/O and/O wound/O up/O finding/O themselves/O in/O an/O organization/O that/O had/O been/O manipulated/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION day/O after/O day/O ,/O week/O after/O week/O ,/O and/O month/O after/O month/O ./O 
That/O illustrates/O what/O has/O been/O testified/O to/O here/O as/O to/O the/O importance/O of/O Communist-front/O activities/O in/O the/O entertainment/O field/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O committee/O desires/O to/O ask/O you/O a/O number/O of/O questions/O relating/O to/O your/O own/O special/O knowledge/O of/O Communist/O fronts/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O not/O only/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O finding/O what/O your/O own/O connection/O with/O those/O organizations/O was/O ,/O but/O to/O ascertain/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O your/O assistance/O was/O secured/O ,/O if/O that/O be/O true/O ,/O and/O the/O method/O by/O which/O these/O organizations/O function/O ./O 
So/O ,/O I/O will/O start/O off/O asking/O you/O about/O various/O Communist-front/O organizations/O with/O which/O we/O have/O information/O that/O you/O have/O at/O one/O time/O or/O another/O been/O connected/O ./O 
First/O of/O all/O ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O comment/O to/O make/O upon/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Brewer/PERSON `/O that/O I/O have/O just/O read/O to/O you/O about/O the/O importance/O of/O Communist-front/O activities/O in/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O ,/O the/O broader/O field/O of/O entertainment/O ,/O unless/O you/O desire/O to/O confine/O it/O to/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION area/O particularly/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O my/O comment/O would/O have/O to/O be/O in/O the/O broader/O field/O ,/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O enough/O about/O any/O organized/O activity/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
I/O have/O never/O belonged/O to/O any/O committee/O or/O group/O in/O Hollywood/O of/O any/O sort/O whatever/O except/O the/O Screen/O Actors/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Regarding/O the/O broader/O phases/O of/O the/O entertainment/O field/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O undoubtedly/O what/O Mr./O Brewer/PERSON says/O probably/O is/O very/O perceptive/O and/O very/O accurate/O ,/O not/O only/O as/O regards/O Communist-front/O activities/O ,/O but/O also/O ,/O very/O importantly/O from/O my/O personal/O point/O of/O view/O ,/O the/O way/O innocent/O and/O well-intentioned/O people/O have/O been/O deceived/O and/O lured/O into/O participation/O in/O causes/O which/O at/O one/O time/O seemed/O worthy/O and/O later/O on/O appeared/O unworthy/O ./O 
Any/O comment/O ,/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O would/O have/O to/O make/O on/O Mr./O Brewer/PERSON 's/O testimony/O ,/O would/O have/O to/O apply/O to/O the/O broader/O field/O and/O not/O to/O Hollywood/O specifically/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O have/O anything/O else/O you/O desired/O to/O say/O ?/O 
Mr./O FFRRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O before/O me/O ./O 
a/O pamphlet/O entitled/O ``/O Artists/O '/O Front/O to/O Win/O the/O War/O ,/O ''/O published/O by/O that/O organization/O October/O 16/O ,/O 1942/O ./O 
It/O reflects/O that/O you/O are/O one/O of/O the/O sponsors/O of/O the/O theater/O section/O of/O that/O organization/O ./O 
Were/O you/O affiliated/O with/O it/O in/O any/O way/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O see/O the/O pamphlet/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
1/O See/O pp./O 518/O and/O 519/O ,/O pt/O ./O 
2/O ,/O of/O hearings/O printed/O under/O this/O title/O ./O 
538/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
And/O to/O explain/O my/O request/O to/O see/O it/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O tell/O you/O that/O my/O memory/O in/O these/O matters/O is/O controlled/O largely/O by/O association/O ./O 
If/O I/O can/O see/O where/O a/O function/O took/O place/O and/O who/O was/O there/O ,/O then/O I/O am/O able/O to/O tell/O you/O accurately/O my/O participation/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O as/O far/O as/O we/O can/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
-LSB-/O After/O examining/O document/O :]/O I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O this/O whatever/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O entirely/O possible/O ,/O and/O even/O probable/O ,/O that/O the/O listing/O of/O my/O name/O is/O legitimate/O ./O 
and/O that/O I/O did/O authorize/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O have/O any/O recollection/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O pamphlet/O ,/O under/O date/O October/O 16/O ,/O 1942/O ,/O has/O a/O heading/O ,/O as/O you/O noticed/O ,/O in/O the/O center/O of/O the/O pamphlet/O ,/O For/O a/O Second/O Front/O This/O Year/O ./O 
You/O do/O recall/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O ,/O that/O that/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O during/O that/O period/O in/O 1942/O ,/O to/O urge/O the/O establishment/O of/O a/O second/O front/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION went/O all/O out/O to/O establish/O that/O line/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O recall/O that/O in/O the/O light/O of/O later/O knowledge/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O know/O at/O the/O time/O that/O it/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
A/O second/O front/O in/O what/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O World/O War/O II/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O is/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O that/O is/O the/O only/O purpose/O shown/O for/O the/O establishment/O of/O this/O organization/O ,/O Artists/O '/O Front/O to/O Win/O the/O War/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O me/O to/O explain/O why/O I/O probably/O allowed/O my/O name/O to/O be/O used/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Looking/O over/O the/O names/O of/O the/O sponsors/O ,/O the/O general/O technique/O is/O to/O come/O to/O someone/O ,/O by/O letter/O or/O otherwise/O ,/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O You/O realize/O that/O a/O second/O front/O must/O be/O established/O ./O ''/O 
And/O to/O make/O yourself/O appear/O to/O be/O a/O person/O of/O some/O sagacity/O ,/O you/O say/O ,/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
Then/O they/O say/O ,/O ``/O Important/O people/O are/O ready/O to/O move/O in/O that/O direction/O ,/O ''/O and/O they/O show/O you/O a/O list/O of/O distinguished/O names/O ,/O leaders/O in/O cultural/O and/O various/O fields/O ,/O names/O you/O associate/O with/O integrity/O and/O authority/O ,/O and/O if/O it/O seems/O a/O worth-while/O cause-and/O I/O am/O speaking/O only/O for/O myself-you/O say/O ,/O ``/O Certainly/O ,/O use/O my/O name/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O were/O one/O of/O the/O distinguished/O persons/O in/O the/O field/O of/O actors/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O was/O very/O distinguished/O in/O 1942/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O a/O question/O whether/O I/O am/O distinguished/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O solicited/O your/O affiliation/O with/O this/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O this/O organization/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O recall/O that/O sometime/O later/O this/O organization/O was/O cited/O as/O a/O Communist/O front/O by/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O and/O the/O California/LOCATION committee/O ;/O do/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O recall/O it/O in/O the/O light/O of/O the/O work/O and/O the/O research/O that/O I/O have/O done/O recently/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O a/O committee/O known/O as/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Protection/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Born/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O committee/O possesses/O information/O indicating/O that/O your/O name/O was/O listed/O as/O the/O sponsor/O of/O a/O dinner/O given/O by/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Protection/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Born/ORGANIZATION held/O April/O 17/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O at/O the/O Hotel/O Biltmore/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O sponsoring/O that/O dinner/O and/O attending/O it/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 539/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O pretty/O sure/O I/O did/O not/O attend/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O will/O say/O I/O think/O I/O remember/O sponsoring/O it/O simply/O because/O it/O has/O been/O proven/O to/O me/O time/O and/O again/O ,/O especially/O in/O the/O last/O few/O weeks/O ,/O that/O one/O 's/O memory/O can/O be/O treacherous/O ,/O especially/O about/O things/O which/O ,/O although/O undoubtedly/O important/O ,/O are/O peripheral/O to/O one/O 's/O activities/O ./O 
Were/O you/O to/O ask/O me/O about/O the/O theater/O ,/O I/O would/O recall/O even/O if/O it/O was/O a/O long/O time/O ago/O ,/O but/O this/O kind/O of/O thing/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O devote/O most/O of/O my/O thought/O to/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O ca/O n't/O say/O I/O remember/O or/O do/O n't/O because/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O what/O I/O do/O remember/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O my/O name/O was/O used/O legitimately/O in/O this/O connection/O ./O 
I/O am/O reasonably/O certain/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O people/O connected/O with/O this/O dinner/O ,/O that/O I/O authorized/O the/O use/O of/O my/O name/O ,/O but/O I/O must/O be/O tentative/O in/O my/O answer/O if/O I/O am/O to/O be/O entirely/O truthful/O ,/O which/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O be/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O association/O did/O you/O have/O with/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Protection/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Foreign/ORGANIZATION Born/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O any/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O any/O connection/O whatever/O ./O 
What/O probably/O happened/O ,/O again/O ,/O is/O that/O I/O received/O a/O letter/O saying/O :/O ``/O We/O are/O having/O this/O dinner/O ;/O will/O you/O lend/O us/O your/O name/O ?/O ''/O 
Then/O they/O cited/O some/O distinguished/O names/O connected/O with/O the/O dinner/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O who/O they/O were/O ,/O but/O was/O n't/O Mrs./O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O name/O and/O other/O names/O used/O in/O soliciting/O sponsors/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
There/O were/O the/O names/O of/O a/O number/O of/O people/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O see/O the/O name/O you/O mentioned/O ./O 
sponsors/O ./O 
I/O am/O handing/O you/O the/O list/O of/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON -LRB-/O examining/O list/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Dorothy/PERSON Thompson/PERSON ,/O William/PERSON Allen/PERSON White/PERSON ,/O and/O Edward/PERSON G./PERSON Robinson/PERSON were/O among/O the/O people/O who/O spoke/O at/O that/O dinner/O ./O 
In/O connection/O with/O the/O foreign-born/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O I/O would/O probably/O be/O predisposed/O emotionally/O to/O help/O the/O foreignborn/O in/O any/O legitimate/O cause/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O am/O a/O Puerto/O Rican/O ,/O that/O I/O was/O born/O in/O Puerto/LOCATION Rico/LOCATION ,/O that/O I/O was/O born/O an/O American/LOCATION citizen/O in/O Puerto/LOCATION Rico/LOCATION ,/O as/O all/O Puerto/O Ricans/O are/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O deeply/O aware/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O although/O I/O myself/O have/O always/O been/O treated/O admirably/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O I/O have/O many/O Puerto/O Rican/O friends/O ,/O and/O there/O are/O many/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O who/O are/O treated/O as/O foreigners/O in/O this/O country/O and/O as/O people/O who/O are/O unwanted/O ./O 
I/O am/O extremely/O sympathetic/O to/O their/O problems/O and/O do/O all/O I/O can/O to/O alleviate/O them/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O an/O organization/O to/O help/O the/O foreign-born/O would/O have/O an/O immediate/O appeal/O to/O my/O emotions/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O are/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O endeavored/O to/O infiltrate/O organizations/O that/O may/O be/O interested/O in/O that/O cause/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Unfortunately/O ,/O I/O have/O become/O aware/O only/O in/O recent/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O that/O this/O organization/O has/O been/O cited/O as/O subversive/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O that/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O this/O committee/O and/O also/O by/O the/O California/LOCATION com/O -/O mittee/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O you/O questions/O now/O concerning/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION AntiFascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O December/O 21/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O issue/O of/O New/O Masses/O ,/O at/O page/O 31/O ,/O contains/O an/O advertisement/O indicating/O that/O Jos6/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ,/O among/O others/O ,/O was/O to/O be/O an/O entertainer/O at/O an/O all-star/O show/O to/O be/O held/O on/O January/O 26/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O at/O the/O Imperial/O Theater/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION 540/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O appear/O as/O an/O entertainer/O on/O that/O occasion/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O explain/O to/O the/O committee/O how/O your/O name/O happened/O to/O appear/O in/O the/O advertisement/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O what/O probably/O happened/O is/O that/O they/O came/O to/O me/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Will/O you/O appear/O ?/O ''/O 
and/O I/O agreed/O to/O appear/O because/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O ,/O Jimmy/PERSON Durante/PERSON ,/O Milton/PERSON Berle/PERSON ,/O and/O other/O people/O prominent/O in/O show/O business/O were/O going/O to/O appear/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O did/O n't/O appear/O is/O probably/O because/O an/O actor/O such/O as/O I/O am/O as/O not/O qualified/O to/O entertain/O at/O this/O kind/O of/O a/O benefit/O ./O 
When/O a/O man/O can/O sing/O a/O song/O or/O tell/O stories/O or/O make/O jokes/O or/O tap/O dance/O ,/O he/O is/O qualified/O to/O go/O out/O and/O entertain/O 2/O ,/O 3/O ,/O 4/O ,/O 5/O ,/O or/O 10/O minutes/O with/O an/O act/O ./O 
An/O actor/O is/O ,/O as/O a/O rule/O ,/O in/O a/O play/O which/O begins/O about/O 8/O :/O 30/O or/O 8/O :/O 45/O and/O ends/O at/O 11/O ,/O and/O he/O works/O with/O other/O actors/O in/O a/O carefully/O designed/O entertainment/O program/O ./O 
What/O we/O usually/O do/O when/O called/O upon/O to/O appear/O at/O benefits/O is/O either/O to/O introduce/O entertainers/O or/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O very/O happy/O to/O be/O here/O ,/O greetings/O ,/O and/O good/O night/O ,/O ''/O and/O get/O away/O as/O gracefully/O as/O possible/O until/O Ray/PERSON Bolger/PERSON comes/O ./O 
What/O probably/O happened/O is/O that/O I/O got/O cold/O feet/O and/O ducked/O ,/O because/O I/O knew/O if/O I/O appeared/O I/O would/O be/O somewhat/O of/O a/O lull/O in/O the/O program/O ./O 
But/O I/O did/O agree/O to/O appear/O and/O just/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O more/O or/O less/O active/O ,/O were/O you/O not/O ,/O with/O this/O organization/O ,/O the/O Joint/O Anti-Fascist/O Refugee/O Committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O contributions/O to/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O so/O ./O 
If/O I/O may/O ask/O counsel/O ,/O they/O would/O be/O able/O to/O tell/O you/O better/O than/O I/O can/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON -LRB-/O continuing/O -RRB-/O ./O 
They/O are/O of/O the/O opinion/O I/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O FORTAS/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O a/O list/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O of/O all/O contributions/O Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON made/O to/O any/O cause/O so/O far/O as/O they/O can/O be/O ascertained/O from/O his/O own/O records/O ,/O and/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O supply/O that/O if/O you/O want/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O take/O a/O hurried/O glance/O at/O the/O list/O and/O see/O if/O you/O have/O made/O contributions/O to/O this/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O suspect/O they/O will/O take/O careful/O glances/O ./O 
Mr./O FORTAS/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O to/O have/O a/O copy/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
-LRB-/O Copy/O of/O document/O was/O handed/O to/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
May/O 1/O inquire/O if/O there/O are/O extra/O copies/O of/O the/O list/O avail/O -/O able/O for/O the/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O FORTAS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O -LSB-/O handing/O copies/O to/O members/O of/O committee/O -RSB-/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O looked/O at/O the/O list/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O not/O see/O any/O con/O -/O tributions/O to/O this/O organization/O ./O 
Does/O that/O mean/O that/O you/O did/O not/O make/O any/O contributions/O as/O far/O as/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
As/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Any/O contribution/O I/O would/O have/O made/O I/O would/O have/O made/O by/O check/O ,/O and/O this/O list/O is/O made/O from/O a/O thorough/O search/O of/O my/O check/O books/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O engage/O in/O other/O activities/O with/O regard/O to/O the/O raising/O of/O money/O or/O benefits/O for/O what/O was/O known/O as/O the/O Spanish/O Refugee/O Appeal/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON :/O I/O think/O I/O probably/O did/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O acquainted/O with/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O Spanish/O Refugee/O Appeal/O was/O one/O of/O the/O projects/O of/O the/O organization/O with/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 541/O which/O you/O -/O ay/O you/O were/O connected/O ,/O the/O Joint/O Anti-Fascist/O Refugee/O Committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O aware/O now/O ./O 
Whether/O I/O was/O then/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O linked/O them/O together/O in/O my/O mind/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O trying/O to/O evade/O your/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O in/O -/O dicating/O you/O were/O the/O guest/O of/O honor/O at/O a/O meeting/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION on/O March/O 10/O ,/O 1945/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O is/O the/O one/O at/O which/O Walter/PERSON Huston/PERSON spoke/O ,/O then/O I/O do/O recall/O it/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Tell/O us/O about/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
My/O memory/O is/O vague/O on/O that/O subject/O ./O 
I/O suspect/O the/O purpose/O was/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O I/O knew/O and/O so/O far/O as/O Mr./O Huston/PERSON 's/O speech/O indicated/O ,/O which/O is/O what/O I/O remember/O about/O the/O meeting/O ,/O action/O against/O Franco/PERSON ./O 
We/O who/O ./O 
called/O ourselves/O liberal/O Democrats/O considered/O France/LOCATION a/O dictator/O ,/O a/O man/O who/O was/O against/O the/O democratic/O processes/O ,/O as/O Hitler/PERSON had/O been/O and/O as/O Stalin/PERSON is/O today/O ,/O and/O anytime/O there/O was/O an/O occasion/O to/O oppose/O him/O I/O ,/O for/O one/O ,/O rather/O unquestioningly/O did/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O that/O you/O spoke/O at/O a/O Spanish/O Refugee/O Appealbenefit/O held/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O raising/O funds/O on/O May/O 5/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Wisconsin/ORGANIZATION ,/O Madison/LOCATION ,/O Wis./LOCATION ,/O which/O was/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O do/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O spoke/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Tell/O us/O what/O the/O arrangements/O were/O by/O which/O you/O were/O to/O appear/O at/O these/O various/O meetings/O ,/O and/O whether/O it/O was/O a/O series/O of/O meetings/O that/O you/O attended/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
During/O the/O season/O 1944/O to/O 1945/O I/O was/O on/O tour/O with/O Othello/O ,/O and/O what/O would/O happen/O ,/O as/O in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION or/O Madison/LOCATION ,/O would/O be/O that/O we/O would/O be/O playing/O in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O and/O in/O the/O case/O of/O Madison/LOCATION we/O were/O playing/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION ,/O and/O Madison/PERSON is/O only/O 3/O hours/O away/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O asked/O would/O I/O appear/O and/O speak/O ,/O and/O I/O agreed/O to/O ,/O my/O sole/O thought/O being/O anti-Franco/O activity/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O arrangement/O made/O prior/O to/O your/O leaving/O on/O this/O tour/O with/O Othello/O for/O you/O to/O appear/O in/O behalf/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION at/O various/O places/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O any/O definite/O arrangements/O were/O made/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O seem/O to/O recall/O having/O been/O told/O that/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O if/O the/O schedule/O coincided/O ,/O they/O might/O contact/O me/O and/O that/O I/O would/O be/O asked/O to/O speak/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O I/O would/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O guided/O and/O directed/O that/O course/O of/O procedure/O ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O who/O made/O the/O suggestion/O to/O you/O and/O the/O arrangements/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Gosh/O ,/O I/O wish/O I/O could/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Very/O often/O these/O things/O came/O in/O a/O phone/O call/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O specifically/O any/O persons/O or/O name/O because/O ,/O strange/O as/O it/O seems/O ,/O I/O would/O get/O a/O letter/O or/O phone/O call/O and/O be/O asked/O to/O appear/O and/O I/O would/O say/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O ''/O and/O I/O would/O appear/O and/O that/O would/O be/O the/O end/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O rather/O active/O ,/O I/O take/O it/O ,/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O over/O a/O considerable/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
542/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Active/O only/O in/O appearing/O at/O public/O functions/O ./O 
I/O never/O appeared/O at/O private/O meetings/O or/O anything/O of/O that/O sort/O ./O 
My/O only/O activities/O were/O in/O connection/O with/O public/O functions/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O find/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O in/O the/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O of/O September/O 25/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O an/O article/O listing/O you/O as/O a/O speaker/O before/O a/O group/O of/O 17,000/O persons/O at/O Madison/O Square/O Garden/O on/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O as/O a/O function/O held/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O Spanish/O Refugee/O Appeal/O ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O speaker/O on/O that/O occasion/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O introduced/O Paula/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON ,/O Josh/PERSON White/PERSON ,/O and/O the/O CIO/O chorus/O ./O 
That/O was/O my/O function/O during/O the/O evening/O I/O acted/O as/O master/O of/O ceremonies/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O the/O occasion/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O article/O mentions/O that/O ,/O so/O I/O guess/O that/O is/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O the/O night/O Mr./O Laski/PERSON spoke/O from/O Eng/O -/O land/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
He/O is/O chairman/O of/O the/O English/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
And/O made/O remarks/O supposed/O to/O be/O derogatory/O to/O the/O Caltholic/ORGANIZATION Church/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Frank/PERSON FayMr/PERSON ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
This/O is/O another/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O the/O meeting/O which/O provoked/O Frank/PERSON Pay/PERSON ,/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O at/O that/O same/O meeting/O Dr./O Edward/PERSON K./PERSON Barsky/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O spoke/O and/O made/O a/O special/O appeal/O for/O funds/O for/O the/O Spanish/O cause/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O at/O the/O same/O meeting/O Mr./O Nikolai/PERSON Novikov/PERSON ,/O acting/O head/O of/O the/O Russian/O Embassy/O ,/O was/O a/O speaker/O and/O called/O for/O the/O prosecution/O of/O Franco/PERSON as/O a/O war/O criminal/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O you/O have/O ever/O attended/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O at/O the/O Garden/O ,/O but/O I/O can/O give/O you/O my/O view/O of/O what/O happened/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O explanation/O you/O wish/O to/O make/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Say/O a/O meeting/O is/O scheduled/O for/O 7:30/O ./O 
They/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O We/O want/O you/O to/O introduce/O some/O of/O the/O speakers/O ./O ''/O 
I/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O engaged/O in/O a/O production/O on/O Broadway/O ,/O ''/O which/O I/O was/O at/O that/O time-I/O was/O working/O on/O Strange/O Fruit-and/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O If/O you/O will/O submit/O the/O material/O you/O want/O me/O to/O use/O ,/O and/O write/O the/O introductions/O ,/O I/O will/O be/O there/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O as/O soon/O as/O I/O am/O through/O I/O will/O leave/O ./O ''/O 
If/O they/O say/O ,/O ``/O We/O want/O you/O at/O 9:30/O ,/O ''/O I/O arrive/O at/O 9:30/O ./O 
The/O activity/O i/O -/O taking/O place/O on/O an/O elevated/O platform/O ,/O something/O like/O a/O prize/O fighting/O ring/O ./O 
Around/O the/O bottom/O of/O this/O arena/O is/O a/O tremendous/O hustle/O and/O bustle/O of/O newspaper/O people/O ,/O photographers/O ,/O people/O coming/O and/O going/O ,/O and/O one/O very/O seldom/O listens/O to/O what/O is/O happening/O on/O the/O stage/O ,/O because/O one/O is/O busy/O preparing/O one/O 's/O own/O material/O ,/O and/O when/O he/O is/O through/O ,/O he/O leaves/O ./O 
I/O remember/O a/O Spanish/O lady/O ,/O Isabel/PERSON de/PERSON Palencia/PERSON ,/O was/O there/O ./O 
I/O was/O introduced/O to/O her/O ./O 
I/O remember/O Paula/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON and/O Josh/PERSON White/PERSON ,/O and/O that/O is/O all/O I/O remember/O of/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O made/O mention/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O there/O was/O a/O later/O meeting/O held/O criticizing/O this/O particular/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O charged/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ,/O that/O this/O meeting/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O Communistinspired/O program/O that/O was/O being/O conducted/O there/O ;/O you/O recall/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 543/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O any/O investigation/O to/O determine/O ,/O for/O yourself/O whether/O there/O was/O any/O substance/O to/O that/O charge/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O this/O organization/O ,/O of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member/O and/O in/O which/O you/O had/O been/O very/O active/O ,/O was/O tainted/O with/O communism/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
1945/O ,/O September/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O Is/O that/O right/O ,/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O regret/O to/O say/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O ,/O and/O one/O reason/O I/O may/O not/O have/O was/O that/O the/O charges/O of/O communism/O against/O his/O meeting/O and/O against/O this/O organization/O at/O that/O time/O were/O made/O by/O Frank/PERSON Fay/PERSON ,/O who/O ,/O although/O he/O turns/O out/O to/O have/O been/O factually/O right/O in/O regard/O to/O this/O meeting/O ,/O behaved/O in/O such/O a/O scandalous/O and/O ill-advised/O manner/O throughout/O that/O charges/O were/O brought/O against/O him/O by/O his/O own/O union/O ./O 
I/O was/O then/O on/O the/O council/O at/O Equity/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O Fay/PERSON to/O be/O a/O man/O of/O excessive/O conduct/O ,/O a/O man/O who/O automatically/O ,/O if/O you/O are/O a/O decent/O and/O fair-mined/O person/O ,/O throws/O you/O into/O an/O opposite/O point/O of/O view/O ./O 
I/O mean/O this/O very/O sincerely/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O n't/O it/O have/O been/O a/O warning/O ?/O 
Was/O n't/O it/O a/O flag/O in/O your/O face/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O admit/O I/O was/O wrong/O ,/O and/O take/O all/O the/O blame/O for/O not/O listening/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O like/O to/O explain/O that/O listening/O to/O Mr./O Frank/PERSON Fay/PERSON is/O something/O that/O does/O n't/O come/O easily/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O become/O connected/O with/O this/O organi/O -/O zation/O ,/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O my/O connection/O with/O the/O organization/O was/O that/O they/O would/O call/O me/O up/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O Will/O you/O appear/O ?/O ''/O 
and/O I/O would/O say/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
I/O never/O was/O in/O any/O way/O connected/O with/O them/O in/O the/O sense/O that/O I/O worked/O with/O them/O ,/O except/O to/O agree/O to/O appear/O at/O rallies/O and/O meetings/O ,/O and/O on/O those/O occasions/O either/O I/O would/O be/O approached/O by/O phone/O or/O by/O letter/O ,/O depending/O on/O the/O importance/O of/O the/O occasion/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O any/O of/O the/O names/O of/O persons/O who/O called/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON asked/O me/O a/O while/O ago/O if/O I/O remembered/O ,/O and/O I/O tried/O to/O think/O of/O some/O names/O ,/O but/O you/O must/O believe/O me/O when/O I/O say/O I/O am/O not/O trying/O to/O avoid/O the/O question/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O or/O think/O of/O a/O name/O or/O a/O face/O in/O connection/O with/O this/O matter/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O meeting/O to/O which/O we/O referred/O was/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O as/O to/O which/O we/O spoke/O of/O the/O flag/O which/O should/O have/O notified/O you/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION purposes/O of/O this/O organization/O ./O 
The/O ./O 
Special/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O cited/O this/O organization/O on/O March/O 29/O ,/O ,1944/O ,/O more/O than/O a/O year/O prior/O to/O that/O ./O 
Were/O n't/O you/O aware/O of/O the/O fact/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O in/O September/O 1945/O ,/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION infiltration/O into/O that/O organization/O was/O a/O publicly/O known/O charge/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O was/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O like/O to/O explain/O something/O else/O about/O appearing/O at/O this/O sort/O of/O meeting/O ./O 
Before/O any/O member/O of/O an/O actors/O '/O or/O entertainment/O union/O is/O allowed/O to/O appear/O at/O any/O function/O and/O lend/O his/O services/O ,/O he/O has/O to/O check/O with/O an/O organization/O known/O as/O Theater/O Authority/O ,/O the/O chairman/O of/O which/O was/O Alan/PERSON Corelli/PERSON ./O 
If/O they/O say/O ,/O ``/O Do/O not/O appear/O ,/O ''/O you/O do/O not/O appear/O ,/O because/O if/O you/O do/O appear/O against/O their/O instructions/O ,/O Equity/O ,/O my/O union/O ,/O takes/O a/O very/O ,/O very/O serious/O view/O of/O it/O ./O 
544/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Theater/O Authority/O was/O established/O by/O Equity/O ,/O Screen/O Actors/O '/O Guild/O ,/O and/O other/O unions/O ./O 
I/O can/O only/O say/O ,/O to/O explain/O my/O answer/O ,/O that/O there/O were/O people/O in/O the/O organization/O whom/O I/O considered/O not/O subversive/O ,/O including/O the/O CIO/O chorus/O ,/O and/O because/O of/O that/O fact/O ,/O plus/O the/O fact/O Theater/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION gave/O me/O permission/O to/O go/O ahead/O ,/O I/O did/O appear/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O secure/O authority/O on/O that/O occasion/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O in/O charge/O of/O Theater/O Authority/O in/O September/O 1945/O ?/O 
\/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Alan/PERSON Corelli/PERSON has/O been/O in/O charge/O for/O many/O ,/O many/O years/O until/O just/O recently/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O brought/O to/O your/O attention/O through/O any/O source/O that/O this/O committee/O had/O cited/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O it/O was/O or/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O first/O learn/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O suspect/O that/O I/O first/O learned/O it/O recently/O ,/O when/O I/O had/O to/O do/O a/O lot/O of/O studying/O that/O I/O probably/O should/O have/O done/O long/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Is/O that/O your/O best/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O my/O best/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O are/O n't/O artists/O such/O as/O you/O required/O to/O make/O certain/O appearances/O other/O than/O theatrical/O appearances/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
We/O are/O not/O required/O to/O do/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
A/O witness/O testified/O before/O the/O committee/O sometime/O ago/O that/O ,/O under/O a/O contract/O she/O had/O ,/O she/O was/O required/O to/O make/O public/O appearances/O wherever/O her/O manager/O said/O she/O was/O to/O appear/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
-/O That/O is/O a/O special/O arrangement/O she/O had/O with/O her/O manager/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O not/O a/O typical/O arrangement/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O we/O do/O have/O the/O habit/O of/O appearing/O whenever/O we/O can/O for/O what/O appear/O to/O be/O worthy/O causes/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O no/O obligation/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O that/O you/O have/O no/O choice/O about/O where/O you/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ./O 
You/O misunderstood/O me/O ./O 
I/O have/O the/O choice/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O was/O telling/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O not/O be/O forced/O to/O appear/O but/O I/O can/O be/O prevented/O from/O appearing/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Are/O the/O organizations/O or/O meetings/O at/O which/O you/O do/O appear/O selected/O for/O you/O ,/O or/O do/O you/O exercise/O some/O choice/O about/O it/O yourself/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
This/O body/O ,/O Theater/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION ,/O when/O you/O are/O asked/O to/O appear/O at/O a/O function/O ,/O if/O you/O decide/O that/O you/O want/O to/O appearMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Then/O you/O have/O to/O clear/O it/O with/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O if/O they/O turn/O thumbs/O down/O you/O ca/O n't/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
You/O can/O not/O appear/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Can/O they/O require/O you/O to/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
So/O your/O appearance/O is/O voluntary/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O it/O was/O in/O this/O instance/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O compulsory/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O not/O compulsory/O ./O 
I/O take/O full/O blame/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O 545/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O you/O have/O the/O privilege/O of/O making/O a/O full/O investiga/O -/O tion/O of/O the/O organizations/O that/O ask/O you/O to/O appear/O ,/O before/O you/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O you/O had/O that/O privilege/O in/O this/O instance/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O in/O this/O instance/O you/O did/O not/O make/O such/O investiga/O -/O tion/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O make/O the/O investigation/O I/O should/O have/O ./O 
I/O can/O only/O say/O that/O in/O the/O future/O I/O will/O ./O 
Mr./O DoyiE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYlE/PERSON ./O 
Is/O it/O one/O of/O the/O functions/O of/O Theater/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION to/O be/O a/O clearing-house/O as/O to/O whether/O the/O event/O is/O a/O proper/O event/O ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O if/O they/O would/O have/O knowledge/O that/O it/O was/O Communist/O infiltrated/O ,/O should/O they/O have/O told/O you/O to/O stay/O away/O from/O that/O event/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O answer/O to/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O that/O I/O was/O told/O ,/O when/O I/O joined/O Actors/O '/O Equity/O Association/O ,/O that/O during/O the/O period/O of/O years/O when/O excesses/O occurred/O and/O actors/O were/O requested/O to/O appear/O for/O anything/O and/O everything/O ,/O Theater/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION was/O established/O to/O protect/O them/O ./O 
What/O screening/O they/O do/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYE/O ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O their/O rules/O or/O bylaws/O are/O ,/O or/O what/O investigation/O they/O make/O of/O events/O ,/O or/O knowledge/O they/O have/O of/O events/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Is/O Theater/O Authority/O still/O in/O existence/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Does/O it/O still/O screen/O the/O organizations/O at/O which/O actors/O are/O asked/O to/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O does/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O still/O belong/O to/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Theater/O Authority/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
People/O do/O n't/O belong/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O still/O under/O its/O jurisdiction/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O as/O long/O as/O I/O am/O a/O member/O of/O Actors/O '/O Equity/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O am/O under/O its/O jurisdiction/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Who/O is/O head/O of/O Theater/O Authority/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O who/O is/O now/O ./O 
Alan/PERSON Corelli/PERSON was/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
He/O no/O longer/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O they/O have/O offices/O in/O different/O parts/O of/O the/O country/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O only/O know/O of/O the/O office/O they/O used/O to/O have/O on/O Fifth/O Avenue/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O ever/O tell/O you/O in/O writing/O whether/O you/O should/O appear/O ?/O 
Did/O they/O ever/O send/O you/O a/O written/O letter/O telling/O you/O not/O to/O appear/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ;/O I/O was/O never/O told/O not/O to/O appear/O ./O 
Every/O function/O I/O was/O asked/O to/O appear/O at/O ,/O they/O 0/O ./O 
K./O 'd/O ./O 
However/O ,/O time/O after/O time/O I/O have/O seen/O Mr./O Corelli/PERSON at/O the/O functions/O ./O 
He/O was/O extremely/O busy/O ,/O but/O was/O almost/O always/O there/O whenever/O I/O was/O at/O these/O functions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
These/O occasions/O at/O which/O you/O spoke/O or/O introduced/O persons/O who/O spoke/O ,/O I/O take/O it/O were/O money-raising/O events/O ,/O most/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O a/O great/O proportion/O were/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O I/O would/O infer/O that/O part/O of/O the/O reason/O for/O the/O existence/O of/O Theater/ORGANIZATION Authority/ORGANIZATION would/O be/O to/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O they/O could/O ,/O 81595-51-pt/O ./O 
3-2/O 546/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O protect/O you/O actors/O from/O being/O imposed/O upon/O by/O being/O asked/O to/O appear/O at/O events/O which/O in/O fact/O were/O not/O charitable/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O have/O that/O understanding/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O that/O that/O was/O the/O function/O of/O Theater/O Authority/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O it/O is/O one/O of/O the/O functions/O ,/O but/O I/O can/O not/O answer/O your/O other/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O their/O authority/O extended/O beyond/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O occasion/O on/O which/O Theater/O Au/O -/O thority/O denied/O you/O permission/O to/O appear/O at/O a/O function/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O it/O was/O under/O Communist/ORGANIZATION influence/O and/O control/O ,/O or/O was/O a/O Communist/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON Not/O that/O I/O remember/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
These/O various/O instances/O when/O you/O participated/O in/O activities/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O were/O you/O always/O called/O by/O the/O same/O individual/O or/O by/O different/O individuals/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O because/O ,/O as/O I/O told/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O an/O individual/O ./O 
Sometimes/O I/O was/O approached/O by/O phone/O ;/O sometimes/O I/O was/O approached/O by/O letter/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O an/O individual/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O occasions/O when/O you/O recall/O that/O you/O were/O called/O by/O persons/O who/O were/O members/O of/O organizations/O other/O than/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O asking/O that/O you/O participate/O in/O one/O of/O these/O affairs/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O someone/O who/O was/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O but/O who/O might/O be/O interested/O from/O an/O entirely/O different/O angle/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O know/O of/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ;/O not/O that/O I/O know/O of/O ./O 
May/O I/O say/O one/O more/O thing/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O scratching/O around/O the/O back/O of/O my/O head/O trying/O to/O discover/O why/O these/O requests/O for/O my/O appearance/O are/O so/O anonymous/O in/O my/O memory/O ,/O and/O one/O reason/O I/O may/O submit/O is/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O go/O to/O my/O office/O very/O often/O ./O 
My/O office/O where/O I/O produce/O from/O receives/O my/O mail/O ,/O my/O secretary/O opens/O my/O mail/O ,/O and/O messages/O are/O often/O transmitted/O to/O me/O by/O phone/O ,/O and/O sometimes/O I/O may/O have/O gotten/O invitations/O to/O appear/O second/O or/O third-hand/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O say/O ``/O Call/O and/O say/O `/O yes/O '/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O organization/O known/O as/O Theater/O Authority/O screened/O and/O passed/O upon/O the/O public/O appearances/O you/O could/O make/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O also/O screen/O and/O pass/O upon/O the/O organizations/O you/O were/O permitted/O to/O sponsor/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O organizations/O you/O sponsored/O were/O entirely/O upon/O your/O own/O initiative/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O voluntary/O act/O without/O any/O restrictions/O of/O any/O sort/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O you/O now/O about/O -/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 547/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Excuse/O me/O ./O 
Their/O jurisdiction/O extends/O to/O a/O professional/O appearance/O ./O 
When/O I/O act/O as/O an/O individual/O ,/O they/O have/O nothing/O to/O say/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O consider/O that/O your/O appearance/O at/O this/O meeting/O of/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O was/O a/O professional/O appearance/O or/O a/O personal/O appearance/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O professional/O in/O the/O sense/O that/O they/O published/O my/O name/O ,/O and/O my/O name/O was/O linked/O with/O others/O who/O were/O going/O to/O perform/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O had/O been/O advertised/O without/O the/O word/O ``/O actor/O ''/O after/O your/O name/O ,/O would/O that/O mean/O you/O were/O appearing/O in/O a/O personal/O and/O not/O a/O professional/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
If/O they/O promise/O you/O a/O show/O ,/O and/O your/O name/O is/O listed/O as/O an/O individual/O appearing/O for/O many/O people/O to/O look/O at/O and/O listen/O to/O ,/O then/O that/O is/O a/O professional/O appearance/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O if/O you/O were/O to/O take/O part/O in/O a/O public/O meeting/O to/O argue/O a/O question/O in/O which/O the/O meeting/O was/O interested/O ,/O that/O would/O be/O a/O personal/O appearance/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O distinguished/O from/O a/O professional/O appearance/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O my/O understanding/O that/O is/O the/O fact/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Spanish/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION was/O an/O organization/O formed/O after/O the/O civil/O war/O in/O Spain/LOCATION ./O 
According/O to/O a/O letterhead/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Spanish/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION bearing/O date/O January/O 21/O ,/O 1946/O ,/O you/O are/O named/O as/O one/O of/O the/O sponsors/O of/O this/O organization/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O explain/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O motivated/O you/O in/O becoming/O a/O sponsor/O of/O that/O organization/O ,/O if/O you/O did/O ,/O :/O and/O how/O your/O sponsorship/O was/O obtained/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O remember/O this/O specific/O organization/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O once/O more/O I/O must/O plead/O guilty/O to/O the/O charge/O of/O carelessness/O ./O 
If/O I/O was/O approached/O on/O an/O anti-Franco/O question/O ,/O the/O chance/O is/O I/O would/O agree/O to/O sponsor/O it/O ./O 
Without/O knowing/O ,/O I/O suspect/O that/O probably/O the/O same/O people/O sponsored/O it/O ,/O the/O same/O set/O of/O people/O ,/O as/O sponsored/O the/O Joint/ORGANIZATION Anti-Fascist/ORGANIZATION Refugee/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O that/O there/O was/O a/O community/O of/O activity/O which/O I/O accepted/O without/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O an/O interlocking/O membership/O of/O these/O organizations/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O in/O my/O mind/O ./O 
In/O January/O 1946/O Strange/O `/O Fruit/O was/O on/O its/O last/O leg/O ,/O a/O financial/O crisis/O for/O me/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O preparing/O for/O Cyrano/O ,/O and/O my/O feeling/O is/O that/O I/O would/O be/O very/O cursory/O in/O ./O 
my/O examination/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O was/O asked/O to/O appear/O and/O it/O was/O something/O ./O 
at/O which/O I/O wanted/O to/O appear/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ``/O yes/O ''/O and/O forget/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
January/O 1946/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O preparing/O Cyrano/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O an/O earlier/O date/O ,/O in/O May/O 1945/O ,/O you/O were/O listed/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Arts/O and/O Sciences/O Division/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Spanish/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O more/O formal/O sponsorship/O in/O that/O it/O is/O of/O a/O special/O division/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
In/O May/O 1945/O we/O were/O completing/O our/O tour/O of/O Othello/O ,/O which/O had/O taken/O us/O out/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION for/O 10/O months/O ./O 
I/O probably/O allowed/O them/O to/O use/O my/O name/O ./O 
548/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O organization/O was/O cited/O also/O by/O this/O commit/O -/O tee/O ,/O but/O at/O a/O later/O date/O ,/O 1948/O ,/O and/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O in/O 1949/O ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O informtion/O indicating/O that/O on/O June/O 22/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O you/O were/O introduced/O as/O a/O guest/O speaker/O at/O a/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION Rally/ORGANIZATION sponsored/O by/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Victory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION at/O Madison/O Square/O Garden/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O you/O were/O one/O of/O the/O entertainers/O at/O this/O function/O ./O 
Did/O you/O take/O part/O in/O that/O meeting/O '/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O document/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O that/O I/O could/O examine/O to/O refresh/O my/O memory/O as/O to/O who/O else/O participated/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Does/O that/O mean/O you/O do/O not/O have/O any/O independent/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
My/O memory/O in/O most/O of/O these/O cases/O is/O by/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O having/O attended/O that/O meeting/O spon/O -/O sored/O by/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Victory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O I/O probably/O did/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O rerhember/O ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O could/O be/O very/O specific/O if/O I/O saw/O a/O document/O on/O the/O subject/O ./O 
But/O the/O chances/O are/O I/O did/O ./O 
I/O worked/O with/O a/O great/O number/O of/O Negro/O artists/O in/O the/O theater/O ./O 
I/O have/O seen/O them/O suffer/O injustices/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O extremely/O sympathetic/O to/O their/O situation/O ./O 
I/O have/O here/O a/O note/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O this/O June/O 26/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O rally/O of/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Victory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION which/O you/O mentioned/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O speakers/O at/O that/O rally/O was/O Mayor/O LaGuardia/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O you/O took/O part/O in/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Even/O the/O name/O of/O Mayor/O LaGuardia/PERSON does/O not/O make/O me/O remember/O being/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O know/O that/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Victory/ORGANIZATION Com/ORGANIZATION -/O mittee/O has/O been/O cited/O as/O a/O Communist-front/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O that/O now/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Both/O by/O this/O committee/O and/O twice/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O ,/O by/O Attorney/O General/O Tom/PERSON Clark/PERSON in/O his/O letters/O to/O the/O Loyalty/ORGANIZATION Review/ORGANIZATION Board/ORGANIZATION released/O June/O 1/O ,/O 1948/O ,/O and/O September/O 21/O ,/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
TO/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O I/O think/O that/O is/O my/O only/O connection/O with/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Victory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Is/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O anything/O about/O that/O meeting/O at/O all/O ?/O 
You/O made/O mention/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O Mayor/PERSON LaGuardia/PERSON was/O there/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whether/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON spoke/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O anything/O about/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O do/O remember/O that/O in/O some/O of/O the/O research/O I/O made/O in/O connection/O with/O this/O appearance/O ,/O I/O read/O that/O Mayor/PERSON LaGuardia/PERSON did/O not/O appear/O because/O of/O illness/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O this/O occasion/O ./O 
I/O remember/O meeting/O Mr./O Davis/PERSON on/O another/O occasion/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O other/O occasion/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON left/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
The/O other/O occasion/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O April/O 1944/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O birthday/O celebration/O in/O honor/O of/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON at/O one/O of/O the/O armories/O ,/O I/O believe/O the/O armory/O on/O Park/O Avenue/O in/O the/O thirties/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Thirty-fourth/O Street/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O be/O the/O one/O ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O meeting/O Mr./O Davis/PERSON then/O because/O he/O was/O a/O speaker/O that/O night/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O official/O position/O did/O he/O hold/O at/O that/O time/O in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 549/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O whether/O he/O already/O was/O councilman/O of/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION or/O running/O for/O councilman/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O one/O or/O the/O other/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in/O April/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
When/O he/O did/O run/O for/O reelection/O you/O lent/O your/O name/O in/O support/O of/O his/O candidacy/O ,/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O that/O I/O did/O ,/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ,/O but/O if/O I/O did/O it/O was/O because/O ,/O in/O my/O mind/O ,/O he/O was/O being/O presented/O to/O me/O as/O being/O endorsed/O by/O ./O 
the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O endorsement/O subsequently/O withdrawn/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O he/O ran/O ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O contribute/O anything/O toward/O Mr./O Davis/PERSON '/O reelection/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
According/O to/O the/O September/O 25/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O you/O became/O one/O of/O the/O group/O of/O sponsors/O for/O the/O elec/O -/O tion/O of/O Mr./O Davis/PERSON ./O 
The/O heading/O is/O ,/O ``/O Thousand/O artist/O ,/O writers/O back/O Davis/PERSON ./O 
Formation/O of/O an/O artists/O '/O ,/O writers/O '/O ,/O and/O professionals/O '/O group/O for/O reelection/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON was-announced/O yesterday/O by/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O new/O group/O ./O ''/O 
Then/O the/O article/O gives/O the/O names/O of/O sponsors/O ,/O among/O whom/O your/O name/O Jose/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ,/O appears/O ./O 
Does/O that/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O ever/O authorizing/O my/O name/O to/O be/O used/O ./O 
I/O repeat/O ,/O I/O may/O have/O authorized/O it/O to/O be/O used/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
,/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O hand/O you/O the/O article/O to/O see/O if/O your/O memory/O is/O fully/O refreshed/O ,/O if/O it/O can/O be/O ,/O on/O that/O point/O -LSB-/O handing/O article/O to/O the/O witness/O -RSB-/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON -LRB-/O after/O examining/O article/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
There/O are/O a/O great/O many/O names/O listed/O whom/O I/O remember/O among/O my/O acquaintances/O and/O friends/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O name/O does/O appear/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
My/O name/O does/O appear/O there/O ;/O yes/O ;/O and/O I/O probably/O au/O -/O thorized/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O say/O you/O probably/O authorized/O it/O ./O 
Have/O you/O any/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recollection/O ,/O but/O there/O are/O so/O many/O names/O of/O people/O I/O know/O and/O whom/O I/O have/O associated/O with/O that/O I/O would/O accept/O this/O as/O evidence/O against/O myself/O if/O it/O should/O be/O submitted/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O was/O what/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
September/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Davis/PERSON was/O serving/O at/O that/O time/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O council/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O had/O met/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O met/O him/O a/O few/O months/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON asked/O what/O was/O his/O position/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O he/O was/O either/O serving/O as/O councilman/O or/O was/O elected/O later/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O n't/O you/O know/O that/O at/O that/O time/O he/O was/O serving/O as/O councilman/O ,/O and/O that/O he/O had/O been/O elected/O on/O the/O Communist/O ticket/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O did/O n't/O know/O that/O ?/O 
550/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O at/O the/O time/O you/O say/O you/O probably/O sponsored/O his/O reelection/O ,/O did/O n't/O you/O know/O he/O was/O being/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ./O 
If/O I/O had/O ,/O I/O would/O not/O have/O authorized/O the/O use/O of/O my/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Would/O you/O sponsor/O the/O reelection/O of/O a/O man/O without/O ascertaining/O on/O what/O party/O ticket/O he/O was/O running/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O linked/O him/O in/O my/O mind/O as/O being/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O is/O only/O an/O evidence/O of/O how/O careless/O I/O can/O get/O ./O 
But/O I/O did/O not/O know/O he/O was/O running/O on/O the/O Communist/O ticket/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O had/O no/O knowledge/O or/O information/O about/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O find/O it/O out/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Recently/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O doing/O research/O on/O the/O things/O listed/O against/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
When/O was/O the/O last/O time/O you/O saw/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O seeing/O him/O after/O that/O birthday/O party/O ./O 
The/O next/O time/O his/O name/O was/O brought/O to/O my/O attention/O was/O when/O heand/O a/O number/O of/O others/O were/O brought/O up/O on/O trial/O as/O being-Mr/O ./O 
KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
One/O of/O the/O 11/O defendants/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O next/O time/O I/O thought/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON ,/O when/O his/O name/O became/O prominent/O in/O connection/O with/O that/O trial/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O at/O that/O time/O were/O living/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
A/O registered/O voter/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O on/O tour/O much/O of/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O did/O vote/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O voted/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O have/O always/O been/O on/O tour/O when/O the/O elections/O :/O have/O been/O held/O ./O 
Actors/O usually/O go/O on/O tour/O September/O and/O October/O when/O everyone/O has/O to/O register/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O you/O never/O even/O registered/O ,/O then/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O because/O by/O the/O time/O I/O got/O my/O absentee/O ballot/O in/O Ossining/LOCATION ,/O generally/O I/O was/O on/O tour/O ./O 
If/O I/O had/O voted/O for/O him/O I/O certainly/O would/O have/O known/O what/O party/O he/O was/O running/O on/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O have/O misunderstood/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O you/O are/O in/O doubt/O as/O to/O whether/O you/O permitted/O your/O nameto/O be/O used/O in/O support/O of/O the/O candidacy/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON for/O councilman/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O I/O did/O not/O recollect/O giving/O permission/O to/O use/O my/O name/O ,/O but/O after/O seeing/O the/O document/O submitted/O ,/O with/O the/O list/O of/O names/O on/O it/O ,/O I/O told/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O told/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ,/O that/O the/O chances/O were/O I/O probably/O had/O authorized/O the/O use/O of/O my/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O use/O the/O word/O ``/O probably/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O refer/O to/O a/O letter/O you/O addressed/O yesterday/O to/O the/O chairman/O '/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O and/O I/O quote/O from/O that/O letter/O :/O I/O have/O long/O supported/O the/O National/O Urban/O League/O and/O the/O Negro/ORGANIZATION Actors/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION ,/O neither/O of/O which/O has/O any/O Communist/O connection/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O I/O can/O find/O :/O but/O I/O also/O permitted/O my/O name/O to/O be/O used/O in/O support/O of/O the/O candidacy/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON as/O councilman/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 551/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O does/O n't/O indicate/O any/O uncertainty/O about/O au/O -/O thorization/O of/O use/O of/O your/O name/O for/O that/O purpose/O ./O 
tive/O statement/O that/O you/O did/O do/O that/O ?/O 
It/O is/O a/O plain/O ,/O posi/O -/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O n't/O that/O correct/O ;/O that/O you/O did/O permit/O the/O use/O of/O your/O name/O for/O that/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O the/O reason/O I/O wrote/O this/O in/O the/O way/O I/O did/O is/O as/O follows/O :/O I/O assume/O that/O most/O of/O these/O charges/O that/O are/O leveled/O against/O me/O are/O true/O ;/O most/O of/O them/O ./O 
If/O you/O ask/O me/O under/O oath/O ,/O ``/O Do/O you/O remember/O endorsing/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON ?/O ''/O 
,/O I/O say/O ,/O ``/O No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O ''/O but/O I/O say/O I/O probably/O did/O when/O I/O see/O the/O list/O of/O names/O associated/O with/O me/O ./O 
I/O wrote/O this/O carelessly/O ,/O again/O ,/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O simplicity/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O get/O the/O facts/O ./O 
If/O you/O are/O uncertain/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O know/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O uncertain/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O want/O the/O facts/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O my/O position/O clear/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O were/O reading/O from/O a/O letter/O addressed/O to/O me/O as/O chair/O -/O man/O of/O the/O committee/O on/O the/O 21st/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O letter/O was/O released/O by/O you/O to/O the/O press/O on/O yesterday/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O asked/O you/O a/O question/O about/O the/O meeting/O of/O September/O 24th/O which/O announced/O the/O organization/O of/O a/O group/O with/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON as/O chairman/O to/O back/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON in/O the/O campaign/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
What/O question/O did/O you/O ask/O me/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O referred/O to/O that/O ./O 
Now/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O as/O to/O what/O comment/O you/O have/O to/O make/O regarding/O an/O article/O which/O appeared/O in/O the/O Worker/O ,/O issue/O of/O September/O 30/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O entitled/O ``/O Ben/PERSON Davis/PERSON Backed/O by/O 1,000/O Leaders/O in/O the/O Arts/O ./O ''/O 
This/O is/O subsequent/O to/O the/O holding/O of/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O call/O a/O part/O of/O this/O to/O your/O attention/O ,/O and/O then/O let/O you/O examine/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Fine/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O article/O begins/O as/O follows/O :/O The/O campaign/O to/O reelect/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON to/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION City/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION is/O winning/O strong/O support/O from/O outstanding/O figures/O in/O the/O various/O cultural/O fields/O ./O 
Davis/PERSON will/O have/O the/O active/O backing/O of/O leaders/O in/O the/O theater/O ,/O radio/O ,/O motion-picture/O ,/O literary/O ,/O fine/O arts/O ,/O music/O ,/O dance/O ,/O educational/O ,/O and/O allied/O fields/O ./O 
Headed/O by/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON ,/O more/O than/O 1,000/O citizens/O in/O these/O crafts/O last/O week/O announced/O the/O formation/O of/O an/O artists/O ,/O writers/O and/O professional/O division/O of/O the/O Davis/ORGANIZATION Nonpartisan/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O believe/O with/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON that/O ``/O If/O Ben/PERSON is/O reelected/O ,/O that/O means/O we/O 're/O in/O there/O ./O ''/O 
And/O further/O down/O in/O the/O article/O it/O states/O :/O ``/O Sponsors/O of/O the/O artists/O ,/O writers/O ,/O and/O professional/O division/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O Paul/PERSON Robeson/PERSON as/O chairman/O ,/O include/O ''/O various/O persons/O ,/O and/O among/O them/O appears/O the/O name/O of/O Jose/PERSON Ferrer/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O the/O second/O article/O ,/O you/O see/O ,/O that/O appeared/O on/O this/O subject/O ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O it/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O that/O further/O refreshes/O your/O recollection/O ,/O and/O that/O you/O now/O recall/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O so-called/O nonpartisan/O group/O ?/O 
552/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O to/O say/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O that/O this/O does/O not/O refresh/O my/O memory/O ./O 
I/O repeat/O that/O among/O these/O people/O are/O many/O many/O people/O whom/O I/O know/O ,/O whom/O I/O have/O worked/O with/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O pos/O -/O sible/O and/O even/O probable/O that/O I/O did/O allow/O the/O use/O of/O my/O name/O ,/O but/O I/O can/O not/O in/O all/O honesty/O tell/O you/O that/O I/O remember/O doing/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O have/O a/O question/O to/O ask/O ?/O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O your/O attention/O ,/O Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O to/O the/O letter/O that/O the/O chairman/O spoke/O about/O ,/O under/O date/O of/O May/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O directed/O to/O him/O ,/O of/O which/O I/O believe/O all/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O received/O a/O copy/O ./O 
I/O am/O simply/O searching/O for/O the/O truth/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O reconcile/O your/O statement/O with/O that/O portion/O of/O your/O letter/O which/O states/O :/O ``/O I/O also/O permitted/O my/O name/O to/O be/O used/O in/O support/O of/O the/O candidacy/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON as/O councilman/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON just/O asked/O me/O about/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O told/O him/O that/O when/O I/O am/O now/O asked/O under/O oath/O ,/O do/O I/O remember/O ,/O I/O can/O not/O honestly/O say/O ``/O I/O do/O remember/O ''/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O wrote/O this/O this/O way-and/O I/O still/O say/O it/O was/O careless/O on/O my/O part-was/O that/O I/O come/O here/O to/O testify/O before/O you/O gentlemen/O assuming/O that/O most/O of/O the/O charges/O leveled/O against/O me/O are/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Is/O this/O true/O :/O ``/O I/O also/O permitted/O my/O name/O to/O be/O used/O in/O support/O of/O the/O candidacy/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON as/O councilman/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O but/O I/O say/O it/O probably/O was/O ,/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ./O 
Under/O oath/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O say/O it/O was/O ./O 
For/O the/O purposes/O of/O brevity/O and/O simplicity/O ,/O in/O this/O letter/O I/O said/O it/O was/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
We/O want/O to/O know/O if/O it/O was/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O honestly/O ,/O completely/O say/O it/O was/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
This/O letter/O was/O written/O 2/O days/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
A/O lot/O of/O the/O matters/O you/O testified/O about/O occurred/O in/O 1942/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O and/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Here/O ,/O only/O 2/O days/O ago/O ,/O you/O stated/O definitely/O that/O you/O permitted/O your/O name/O to/O be/O used/O to/O further/O the/O candidacy/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON as/O councilman/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
It/O is/O now/O 10/O minutes/O after/O 12/O ,/O and/O there/O is/O a/O quorum/O call/O ;/O and/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O enable/O the/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O answer/O that/O call/O and/O get/O lunch/O ,/O we/O will/O suspend/O until/O 2/O o'clock/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Thereupon/O ,/O at/O 12/O :/O 10/O p./O m./O ,/O a/O recess/O was/O taken/O until/O 2/O p./O m./O of/O the/O same/O day/O ./O -RRB-/O 
AFTER/O RECESS/O The/O hearing/O reconvened/O at/O 2:20/O p./O m./O ,/O upon/O the/O expiration/O of/O the/O recess/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Acting/O under/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O resolution/O establishing/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O ,/O as/O chairman/O ,/O have/O set/O up/O a/O subcommittee/O ,/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O continuing/O this/O hearing/O ,/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON are/O present/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSI'RY/O 553/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O JOSE/O FERRER/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ABE/O FORTAS/O AND/O EDWARD/O REISKIND-Resumed/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Ferrer/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O asking/O you/O this/O morning/O about/O your/O alleged/O endorsement/O of/O Benjamin/PERSON Davis/PERSON for/O election/O to/O the/O position/O of/O councilman/O of/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O 1945/O ./O 
In/O connection/O with/O that/O ,/O you/O were/O asked/O a/O question/O by/O a/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O regarding/O the/O alleged/O endorsement/O of/O Davis/PERSON by/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O made/O the/O statement/O at/O that/O time/O 1/O had/O certain/O exhibits/O which/O I/O wanted/O to/O use/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O regarding/O those/O matters/O ./O 
As/O I/O understand/O it/O ,/O you/O made/O a/O statement/O this/O morning/O that/O he/O was/O endorsed/O by/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Am/O I/O correct/O in/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O or/O had/O been/O endorsed/O when/O I/O first/O met/O him/O ,/O which/O was/O earlier/O that/O same/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O met/O him/O in/O April/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O only/O time/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O ,/O that/O I/O ever/O met/O him/O ,/O I/O was/O introduced-he/O was/O introduced/O to/O me/O ,/O or/O he/O was/O referred/O to.me/O as/O having/O been/O endorsed/O by/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVE/PERSON NNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O will/O read/O to/O you/O from/O the/O July/O 26/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O in/O which/O Councilman/O Benjamin/PERSON J./PERSON Davis/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O is/O stated/O to/O have/O charged/O that/O the/O action/O of/O the/O Democrats/O in/O withdrawing/O their/O designation/O of/O him/O for/O reelection/O was/O a/O disservice/O to/O the/O Democratic/O coalition/O of/O forces/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O Davis/PERSON himself/O recognized/O ,/O as/O shown/O by/O this/O article/O appearing/O in/O July/O 1945/O ,/O that/O he/O recognized/O that/O that/O action/O had/O been/O taken/O by/O the/O local/O organization/O of/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O withdrawing/O support/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O recall/O that/O that/O support/O was/O withdrawn/O after/O I/O have/O refreshed/O your/O recollection/O about/O it/O from/O this/O news/O article/O ?/O 
SMr/O ./O 
FERRER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O know/O it/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O because/O if/O I/O had/O known/O that/O Davis/PERSON was/O to/O all/O intents/O and/O purposes/O a/O candidate/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O he/O was/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O that/O he/O was/O serving/O allegiance/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O would/O never/O have/O lent/O my/O name/O to/O support/O him/O ./O 
And/O ,/O as/O we/O went/O into/O it/O this/O mormng/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O doing/O so/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O willing/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O list/O of/O people/O you/O showed/O me/O ,/O to/O admit/O that/O I/O probably/O did/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O seen/O an/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O what/O you/O just/O quoted/O to/O me/O from/O ./O 
So/O I/O certainly/O never/O saw/O that/O article/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON entered/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ;/O it/O is/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O which/O is/O an/O organ/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O if/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION openly/O and/O avowedly/O takes/O a/O position/O ,/O it/O is/O certainly/O reasonable/O to/O suppose/O that/O the/O public/O generally/O are/O aware/O of/O that/O situation/O ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Definitely/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refer/O now/O to/O an/O article/O in/O the/O October/O 21/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O edition/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O I/O meant/O to/O say-which/O is/O an/O organ/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
554/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O I/O think/O before/O I/O refer/O to/O that/O article/O I/O desire/O to/O refer/O to/O one/O appearing/O in/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O on/O August/O 28/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O which/O is/O still/O a/O date/O ahead/O of/O the/O time/O it/O is/O alleged/O that/O you/O gave/O your/O endorsement/O of/O Davis/PERSON ;/O in/O which/O this/O statement/O is/O made/O :/O The/O progressive/O forces/O in/O the/O labor/O and/O people/O 's/O movement/O are/O also/O rallying/O to/O the/O reelection/O of/O their/O champion/O ./O 
The/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION CIO/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION has/O endorsed/O and/O will/O actively/O campaign/O for/O Davis/PERSON 's/O reelection/O ./O 
True/O ,/O Davis/PERSON is/O the/O nominee/O of/O only/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O he/O was/O elected/O through/O the/O support/O of/O broad/O circles/O of/O our/O citizens/O in/O 1943/O as/O the/O candidate/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION alone/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O statement/O appearing/O in/O the/O Communist/O press/O in/O August/O 1945/O as/O to/O Davis/PERSON '/O status/O in/O 1943/O ,/O when/O he/O ran/O for/O the/O council/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON entered/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O may/O interject/O something/O ,/O I/O was/O told/O during/O the/O luncheon/O recess/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner-which/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O I/O submit/O it/O in/O the/O interests/O of/O accuracy-I/O was/O told/O that/O candidates/O for/O council/O do/O not/O run/O on/O a/O party/O ticket/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O are/O not/O petitions/O filed/O by/O those/O who/O become/O candidates/O for/O the/O city/O council/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O FERRER/PERSON ./O 
Apparently/O on/O a/O nonpartisan/O basis/O ,/O as/O I/O was/O told/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O not/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
I/O am/O passing/O this/O on/O in/O the/O interests/O of/O accuracy/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O do/O they/O not/O have/O to/O state/O on/O what/O party/O ticket/O they/O are/O running/O ?/O 
