COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 7/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THEIR/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O JANUARY/O 24/O ,/O 28/O ,/O FEBRUARY/O 5/O ,/O MARCH/O 20/O ,/O AND/O APRIL/O 10/O ,/O 30/O ,/O 1952/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 95829/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1952/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/O M/O MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O Jn./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H/PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOBN/O W./O CaaRRIGTON/O ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RArni/PERSON L/PERSON L./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O i/O CONTENTS/O January/O 24/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O appearance/O of/O M./PERSON William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON .../O ------/O January/O 28/O ,/O 1952/O :/O Testimony/O ofMelvin/O Levy/PERSON -/O ./O 
---------------------------------------------/O Michael/PERSON Seymour/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON _/O ---------------------------------/O George/PERSON Bassman/PERSON ./O 
--/O _/O February/O 5/O ,/O 19.52/O ,/O testimony/O of/O M/O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ------------------/O March/O 20/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Hyman/PERSON -LRB-/O ``/O Hy/O ''/O -RRB-/O Solomon/PERSON Kraft/PERSON ------------/O .../O April/O 10/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Elia/PERSON Kazan/PERSON __/O ------------------------------/O April/O 30/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Edward/PERSON G./PERSON Robinson/PERSON ----------------------/O MI/O Page/O 2307/O 2:09/O 2328/O 36-2373/O 2397/O 2409/O 2417/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION/O PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 7/O THURSDAY/O ,/O JANUARY/O 24/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O ad/O -/O journment/O ,/O at/O 2/O :/O 28/O p./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ;/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O committee/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
For/O the/O purposes/O of/O the/O hearing/O this/O afternoon/O ,/O acting/O under/O the/O authority/O and/O resolution/O establishing/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O as/O chairman/O set/O up/O the/O subcommittee/O composed/O of/O the/O following/O members/O :/O Messrs./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Potter/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/O ;/O and/O they/O are/O all/O present/O ./O 
Who/O do/O you/O have/O for/O the/O first/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O call/O Mr./O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Pomerance/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O will/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O POMERANCE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ,/O please/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O M./PERSON WILLIAM/PERSON POMERANCE/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O DAVID/PERSON REIN/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O my/O purpose/O in/O calling/O the/O witness/O was/O merely/O to/O have/O him/O respond/O to/O the/O subpena/O and/O to/O have/O the/O com/O -/O mittee/O set/O a/O date/O for/O his/O appearance/O ,/O as/O it/O is/O quite/O evident/O with/O the/O work/O we/O have/O planned/O here/O for/O today/O and/O tomorrow/O ./O 
that/O we/O are/O not/O likely/O to/O reach/O him/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O will/O ask/O him/O one/O or/O two/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O Pomerance/PERSON ,/O you/O were/O served/O with/O a/O subpena/O to/O appear/O here/O today/O ,/O the/O 24th/O day/O of/O January/O ?/O 
2307/O 2308/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O POMERANCE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O subpena/O served/O on/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O POMERANCE/PERSON ./O 
Tuesday/O morning/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Pomerance/PERSON ,/O owing/O to/O the/O schedule/O that/O we/O have/O had/O this/O week/O ,/O and/O its/O taking/O more/O time/O than/O the/O committee/O contemplated/O ,/O I/O regret/O very/O much/O that/O we/O are/O not/O going/O to/O be/O able/O to/O hear/O your/O testimony/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O going/O to/O excuse/O you/O until/O Tuesday/O ,/O the/O 5th/O of/O February/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O witness/O was/O excused/O and/O the/O committee/O proceeded/O with/O the/O witness/O ,/O A./PERSON Marburg/PERSON Yerkes/PERSON ,/O whose/O testimony/O is/O printed/O in/O a/O separate/O publication/O entitled/O ``/O Communist/O Infiltration/O Into/O Professional/O Groups/O ./O ''/O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 7/O MONDAY/O ,/O JANUARY/O 28/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIvrrTES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./O 0/O ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O adjournment/O ,/O at/O 10/O :/O 10/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O -LRB-/O appearance/O as/O noted/O in/O record/O -RRB-/O ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O -LRB-/O appearance/O as/O noted/O in/O record/O -RRB-/O ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O there/O are/O present/O Messrs./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Velde/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O Potter/PERSON ,/O and/O Walter/PERSON ./O 
Who/O is/O your/O next/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O call/O Mr./O Melvin/PERSON Levy/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Melvin/PERSON Levy/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
Will/O you/O rise/O please/O ,/O and/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O MELVIN/O LEVY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Melvin/PERSON Levy/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Levy/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
In/O Salt/LOCATION Lake/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O on/O May/O 11/O ,/O 1902/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O voice/O just/O a/O little/O bit/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O briefly/O ,/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
2310/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O graduate/O with/O a/O master/O 's/O degree/O of/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O rather/O difficult/O to/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O will/O try/O to/O raise/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O you/O were/O a/O graduate/O of/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
The/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O have/O a/O master/O 's/O degree/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O master/O 's/O degree/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O a/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O writer/O of/O screen/O plays/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O am/O a/O writer/O of/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O briefly/O what/O your/O record/O of/O employment/O or/O achievement/O has/O been/O in/O the/O field/O of/O writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O my/O first/O novel/O was/O published/O when/O I/O was/O 21/O ,/O called/O Matrix/O ,/O M-a-t-r-i-x/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Matrix/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Matrix/O ./O 
And/O I/O published/O four/O novels/O ./O 
My/O first/O play/O was/O Gold/O Eagle/O Gyv/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O having/O difficulty/O hearing/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O terribly/O sorry/O ./O 
My/O first/O play/O was/O Gold/O Eagle/O Guy/O ./O 
It/O was/O done/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O 1934/O ./O 
And/O I/O have/O done/O ,/O I/O suppose/O ,/O a/O dozen/O or/O 15/O or/O 20/O pictures/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ;/O Bandit/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Sherwood/ORGANIZATION Forest/ORGANIZATION ;/O Sunday/O Dinner/O for/O a/O Soldier/O ;/O Renegades/O ;/O She/O 's/O a/O Soldier/O ,/O Too/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O the/O names/O of/O the/O last/O two/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
The/O last/O two/O that/O I/O said/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O see/O ,/O did/O I/O say/O ``/O Bandit/O of/O Sherwood/O Forest/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
Bandit/O of/O Sherwood/PERSON Forest/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Sunday/O Dinner/O for/O a/O Soldier/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVExNER/O ./O 
Sunday/O Dinner/O for/O a/O Soldier/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Hitler/PERSON 's/O Hangman/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Hitler/PERSON 's/O Hangman/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
She/O 's/O a/O Soldier/O ,/O Too/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
She/O 's/O a/O Soldier/O ,/O Too/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Renegades/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Renegades/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
It/O covers/O aMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
That/O is/O sufficient/O ./O 
Mr./O Levy/PERSON ,/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O conducted/O by/O this/O committee/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O September/O of/O 1951/O ,/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Berkeley/PERSON appeared/O as/O a/O witness/O ,/O and/O identified/O you/O as/O having/O been/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O Addressing/O news/O photographers/O :-RRB-/O May/O I/O ask/O that/O you/O get/O your/O pictures/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
You/O can/O have/O a/O lot/O of/O them/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2311/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O that/O is/O over/O with/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O very/O happy/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O stated/O that/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Berkeley/PERSON had/O identified/O you/O as/O having/O been/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O then/O voluntarily/O get/O in/O touch/O with/O the/O committee/O and/O ask/O the/O privilege/O of/O appearing/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
To/O make/O such/O statement/O or/O explanation/O of/O your/O membership/O as/O you/O desired/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O did/O announce/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O as/O it/O has/O frequently/O announced/O ,/O whenever/O a/O person/O has/O been/O named/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O any/O testimony/O is/O given/O relating/O to/O him/O or/O his/O organization/O ,/O that/O either/O he/O or/O his/O organization/O is/O invited/O to/O appear/O here/O for/O such/O explanation/O as/O the/O individual/O or/O the/O association/O desires/O to/O present/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O is/O in/O response/O to/O that/O that/O you/O have/O appeared/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O what/O is/O it/O that/O you/O desire/O to/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O about/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ./O 
Mr./O Berkeley/PERSON 's/O testimony/O was/O true/O ./O 
I/O was/O twice/O in/O my/O life/O ./O 
I/O was/O once/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O once/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION at/O various/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O it/O is/O ,/O at/O different/O times/O ,/O and/O with/O no/O connection/O between/O ,/O no/O connection/O between/O the/O two/O things/O ./O 
I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1933/O at/O the/O request/O of/O Mr./O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
Where/O did/O that/O take/O place/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
In/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O occasion/O of/O Mr./O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON 's/O talking/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O precisely/O how/O I/O met/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O that/O he/O spoke-asked/O me/O if/O he/O could/O come/O to/O my/O house/O and/O speak/O ,/O in/O an/O apartment/O with/O my/O wife/O on/O Fifteenth/O Street/O ,/O and/O he/O came/O there/O ,/O and/O brought/O other/O people/O with/O him/O ,/O whom/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
And/O I/O met/O him/O then/O ./O 
And/O as/O asked/O me/O over/O some/O time/O if/O I/O would/O come/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O I/O said/O ``/O no/O ,/O ''/O because/O I/O said/O that/O I/O was/O a/O writer/O and/O that/O as/O a/O writer/O I/O wanted/O no/O obligation/O to/O anything/O except/O my/O writing/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O appreciate/O it/O if/O the/O gentleman/O would/O raise/O his/O voice/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O ``/O no/O ,/O ''/O because/O I/O told/O him/O that/O I/O was/O a/O writer/O and/O wanted/O to/O have/O no/O obligation/O to/O anything/O except/O my/O writing/O ./O 
I/O had/O never/O ,/O even/O in/O college-because/O I/O have/O always/O thought/O of/O myself/O as/O a/O writer/O ,/O even/O when/O I/O was/O little/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O belong/O to/O anything/O ./O 
And/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON then/O suggested/O I/O become/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O would/O not/O be/O asked/O to/O go/O t.o/O meetings/O ,/O or/O anything/O of/O the/O sort/O ./O 
And/O I/O became/O a/O member/O at/O large/O in/O his/O office/O ,/O and/O was/O given/O a/O name/O then/O ,/O and/O a/O card/O ./O 
I/O no/O longer/O remember/O the/O name/O ./O 
I/O tried/O to/O think/O of/O it/O several/O times/O ./O 
It/O could/O have/O been/O Martin/PERSON ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
2312/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O -LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
And/O then/O ,/O about/O some/O months/O later/O ,/O I/O went-this/O was/O at/O a/O time/O when/O I/O was/O engaged/O in/O a/O biography/O of/O a/O man/O named/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O met/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON on/O the/O coast/O ./O 
I/O had/O a/O contract/O with/O Harcourt/ORGANIZATION Brace/ORGANIZATION to/O publish/O this/O book/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O interrupt/O you/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Am/O I/O saying/O more/O than/O I/O should/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O you/O to/O present/O it/O as/O you/O desire/O ,/O but/O at/O times/O I/O would/O like/O to/O interrupt/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Please/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O ask/O you/O for/O more/O detailed/O information/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Please/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O interested/O to/O know/O why/O it/O was/O that/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON was/O interested/O in/O your/O membership/O to/O the/O extent/O that/O he/O would/O suggest/O that/O you/O become/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O can/O not/O answer/O that/O in/O any/O accurate/O way/O ./O 
I/O imagine/O that/O I/O was/O not/O the/O only/O person/O in/O this/O situation/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O regarded/O me/O as/O a/O good/O writer/O ,/O which/O I/O like/O to/O think/O of/O myself/O as/O being/O ./O 
That/O is/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O that/O you/O became/O a/O member/O at/O the/O solicitation/O of/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O engage/O in/O any/O particular/O study/O in/O company/O with/O other/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
This/O was/O my/O understanding/O :/O That/O I/O was/O not/O to/O be/O required/O to/O go/O to/O any/O meetings/O of/O any/O kind/O ;/O that/O I/O was/O to/O have/O conversations/O with/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON ,/O as/O I/O desired/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O efforts/O were/O made/O to/O indoctrinate/O you/O in/O the/O principles/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O just/O trying/O to/O think/O ./O 
I/O talked/O to/O him/O a/O number/O of/O times/O ,/O and/O I/O suppose/O that/O would/O be/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O there/O wasthere/O was/O no/O intense/O program/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O nothing/O that/O I/O can/O say/O ``/O This/O is/O it/O ./O ''/O 
We/O had/O a/O number/O of/O discussions/O ;/O I/O suppose/O four/O or/O five/O or/O six/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
You/O may/O proceed/O ./O 
You/O were/O telling/O us/O about/O your/O work/O in/O writing/O the/O life/O story/O of/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ./O 
And/O I/O went/O to/O the/O coast/O then/O ,/O to/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O and/O had/O met/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O LevY/PERSON ./O 
I/O met/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON ,/O and/O he/O was/O an/O extraordinary/O man/O ./O 
And/O I/O very/O quickly/O found/O that/O the/O book/O was/O being/O destroyed/O for/O my/O purposes/O ,/O because/O there/O were/O things/O going/O on/O ./O 
The/O Mooney/ORGANIZATION Molders/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION was/O fighting/O with/O other/O people/O ,/O and/O the/O book/O was/O being/O molded/O by/O decisions/O that/O were/O made/O that/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O book/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
These/O decisions/O that/O were/O made/O that/O seemed/O to/O alter/O the/O normal/O course/O that/O such/O a/O book/O should/O take/O were/O being/O made/O by/O whom/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
They/O came/O to/O me/O from/O Mooney/PERSON ./O 
They/O came/O to/O me/O from/O Mooney/PERSON or/O his/O sister/O ./O 
But/O they/O were/O having/O fights/O with/O all/O kinds/O of/O people/O whom/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O their/O confidante/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O find/O out/O as/O to/O what/O extent/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION endeavored/O ,/O if/O at/O all/O ,/O there/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2313/O Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
This/O I/O can/O not/O answer/O ./O 
All/O of/O my/O conversations/O were/O either/O with/O Mooney/PERSON or/O with/O his/O sister/O ,/O Miss/O Mooney/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O her/O first/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O the/O changes/O or/O the/O difficulties/O that/O you/O had/O of/O such/O a/O character/O that/O you/O could/O determine/O the/O source/O of/O them/O ;/O that/O is/O ,/O whether/O they/O came/O from/O problems/O in/O the/O Communist/O ideology/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O that/O they/O came/O from/O many/O sources/O ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O that/O the/O AFL/ORGANIZATION would/O say/O something/O ;/O that/O the/O molders/O committee/O would/O say/O something/O ,/O probably/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O say/O something/O ./O 
There/O were/O many/O people/O interested/O in/O Mooney/LOCATION in/O a/O different/O way/O than/O I/O was/O interested/O in/O him/O ./O 
I/O remember/O one/O of/O the/O things-it/O is/O a/O long/O time/O ago/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O hard/O for/O me/O to/O remember/O details-one/O of/O the/O things/O that/O went/O back/O and/O forth/O was/O the/O attitude/O about/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O sometimes/O was/O for/O and/O sometimes/O it/O was/O against/O ,/O and/O this/O man/O was/O just/O lost/O sight/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O your/O selection/O as/O a/O person/O to/O write/O the/O life/O of/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEvy/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
This/O preceded/O it/O ./O 
No/O ,/O this/O was/O Harcourt/PERSON Brace/PERSON and/O I/O that/O had/O this/O idea/O ./O 
It/O began/O with/O another/O firm/O whose/O name/O I/O do/O longer/O reniember/O ,/O which/O was/O later/O absorbed/O by/O Harcourt/PERSON Brace/PERSON who/O thought/O this/O was/O a/O good/O idea/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O this/O work/O commenced/O before/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O the/O contract/O was/O made/O before/O the/O negotiations/O ,/O but/O just/O before/O I/O went/O to/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION to/O meet/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON ,/O I/O had/O these/O meetings/O with/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON ./O 
Counsel/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
IMr/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON -LRB-/O presiding/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O you/O talked/O with/O Mr./O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON concerning/O your/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O Browder/PERSON the/O leader/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O America/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O he/O was/O a/O leader/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O very/O important/O man/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O he/O was/O at/O the/O top/O ./O 
He/O was/O an/O important/O man/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O had/O a/O special/O interest/O in/O writers/O and/O artists/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
He/O had/O a/O special/O interest/O in/O obtaining/O recruits/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O lie/O also/O had/O an/O interest/O in/O writers/O and/O artists/O and/O painters/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O for/O recruitment/O into/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O but/O I/O think-this/O is/O judgment/O ,/O personally-that/O he/O was/O a/O widely/O read/O man/O ,/O and/O a/O very/O literate/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O reason/O he/O had/O ?/O 
That/O is/O the/O question/O I/O was/O trying/O to/O get/O at/O a/O moment/O ago/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O reason/O that/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON had/O for/O taking/O this/O special/O interest/O in/O writers/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O think/O it/O was/O to/O influence/O the/O course/O of/O their/O writings/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O think/O it/O was/O two/O things/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O certainly/O it/O was/O to/O influence/O the/O course/O of/O writings/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O also/O that/O this/O particular/O thing/O came/O out/O of/O his/O own/O personality-this/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O 2314/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O judgment-he/O was/O a/O man/O who/O I/O remember/O had/O read/O more/O poets/O than/O I/O had/O read/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O at/O a/O time/O when/O I/O was/O reading/O a/O great/O many/O poets/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O man/O who/O read/O a/O great/O deal/O ./O 
I/O think/O both/O things/O existed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O discuss/O with/O you/O at/O any/O time/O your/O assignment/O to/O write/O the/O story/O of/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O told/O him/O what/O I/O wanted/O to/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O before/O he/O asked/O you/O to/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Did/O he/O knowMr/O ./O 
LEVY/O ./O 
I/O understand/O your/O question/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O sequence/O of/O events/O ./O 
It/O was/O all/O about/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
It/O all/O happened/O about/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
and/O I/O can/O not/O say/O what/O preceded/O what/O each/O time/O ./O 
He/O might/O very/O well/O have/O known/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O course/O of/O your/O work/O in/O connection/O with/O that/O assignment/O feel/O that/O you/O were/O being/O influenced/O in/O any/O way/O by/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O performance/O of/O your/O task/O that/O was/O being/O attempted/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O from/O the/O time/O I/O got/O to/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION until/O the/O job/O was/O finished/O all/O of/O my/O contacts/O were/O either/O with/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON or/O his/O sister/O ./O 
But/O it/O was/O obvious/O that/O these/O contacts/O were/O reflecting/O a/O great/O many-I/O think/O you/O have/O to/O understand/O what/O kind/O of/O a/O man/O Mooney/PERSON was/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O man/O ,/O who/O was/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O as/O interesting/O as/O any/O man/O I/O have/O ever/O known/O ./O 
He/O had/O a/O particular/O quality/O ./O 
But/O he/O had/O a/O tremendous/O egotism/O ,/O and/O he/O thought/O of/O himself/O in/O all/O the/O meetings/O I/O had/O with/O him/O ,/O he/O spoke/O of/O himself/O in/O the/O third/O person/O ./O 
And/O he/O thought/O of/O himself/O as/O a/O nation/O thinks/O of/O itself/O ,/O or/O as/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION thinks/O of/O itself/O ./O 
He/O never/O thought/O of/O himself/O as/O a/O man/O named/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON ./O 
He/O would/O never/O say/O ,/O ``/O I/O think/O ''/O ;/O he/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON thinks/O ./O ''/O 
I/O never/O heard/O him/O use/O the/O first/O person/O singular/O pronoun/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O these/O were/O things/O that/O I/O wanted/O to/O have/O in/O the/O book/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O great/O many/O things/O ./O 
To/O me/O he/O was/O a/O character/O ,/O and/O a/O great/O character/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Mr./O Mooney/PERSON at/O any/O time/O make/O a/O statement/O to/O you/O regarding/O either/O his/O membership/O or/O nonthembership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O but/O he/O said/O to/O me/O a/O number/O of/O times/O ,/O ``/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON and/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O ''/O as/O if/O they/O both/O occupied/O the/O same/O size/O of/O territory/O ./O 
So/O I/O would/O doubt/O thatMr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O sequence/O would/O seem/O to/O indicate/O that/O he/O perhaps/O occupied/O more/O space/O than/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O always/O a/O sequence/O ,/O an/O accidentalMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O right/O there/O :/O At/O the/O time/O he/O used/O that/O phrase/O ,/O ``/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON and/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O ''/O did/O he/O use/O it/O in/O such/O a/O way/O that/O it/O indicated/O to/O you/O that/O there/O was/O cooperation/O or/O functioning/O together/O by/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON and/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O think/O not/O ./O 
I/O would/O think/O that/O it/O indicated/O that/O there/O might/O be/O a/O temporary/O alliance/O at/O one/O point/O or/O another/O ,/O but/O at/O no/O time/O a/O breaking/O down/O of/O the/O borders/O ,/O bo/O to/O speak/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2315/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O publish/O your/O book/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
The/O book/O was/O a/O fiasco/O ./O 
Harcourt/PERSON did/O n't/O want/O to/O publish/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O publish/O it/O ,/O either/O ./O 
The/O book/O was/O just/O a/O hodgepodge/O ./O 
Then/O I/O went/O to/O Browder/PERSON and/O said/O that/O this/O was/O why/O I/O did/O not/O want/O to/O have/O anything/O ,/O any/O organizational/O contacts/O ,/O and/O asked/O to/O be/O released/O ,/O and/O returned/O my/O card/O he/O had/O given/O me/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O and/O was/O released/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O period/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O must/O have/O been/O right/O around/O a/O year/O ,/O shading/O one/O way/O or/O the/O other/O ,/O right/O around/O a/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O year/O ?/O 
I/O do/O not/O know/O that/O you/O have/O fixed/O the/O exact/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O through/O most/O of/O the/O year/O 1933/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O reasons/O I/O felt/O most/O strongly/O about/O this/O in/O terms/O of/O my/O experience/O was/O that/O I/O was/O them/O embarking/O on/O a/O series/O of/O what/O were/O going/O to/O be/O five/O novels/O on/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION coast/O from/O which/O I/O come/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O going/O to/O treat/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION coast/O in/O terms/O of/O industry/O and/O industrialists/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Could/O you/O speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O can/O ./O 
I/O say/O I/O was/O going/O to/O write/O ;/O I/O had/O the/O project/O of/O writing/O what/O was/O going/O to/O be/O a/O series/O of/O five/O novels/O on/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION coast/O ,/O which/O is/O my/O home/O ,/O in/O terms/O of/O industries/O ,/O and/O the/O protagonists/O in/O each/O case/O were/O to/O be/O industrialists/O ./O 
And/O I/O felt/O that/O this/O was/O a/O field/O in/O which/O there/O could/O be/O all/O kinds/O of/O interference/O ,/O the/O kind/O I/O did/O n't/O want/O ./O 
I/O took/O two/O of/O these/O ./O 
The/O first/O of/O these/O was/O the/O The/O Last/O Pioneers/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O novel/O ./O 
The/O second/O was/O Gold/O Eagle/O Guy/O ,/O which/O was/O done/O as/O a/O play/O ./O 
And/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O this/O is/O apropos/O ,/O or/O not/O ,/O but/O both/O of/O these/O were/O reviewed/O adversely/O in/O the/O left-wing/O press/O ,/O generally/O on/O the/O basis/O that/O I/O had/O romanticized/O industrialists/O ,/O although/O ,/O I/O may/O say/O ,/O that/O in/O at/O least/O one/O case/O ,/O one/O who/O thought/O he/O was/O the/O protagonist/O ,/O or/O his/O family/O ,/O was/O just/O as/O adverse/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O that/O you/O did/O not/O want/O to/O feel/O any/O restraints/O at/O the/O time/O that/O you/O prepared/O these/O ,/O or/O wrote/O these/O two/O novels/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O feel/O any/O restraint/O about/O writing/O at/O all/O ,/O but/O particularly/O because/O I/O knew/O I/O was/O going/O to/O deal/O with/O industry/O and/O industrialists/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O reason/O did/O you/O have/O to/O believe/O that/O you/O would/O have/O any/O restraint/O placed/O upon/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O just/O been/O through/O it/O with/O the/O Mooneys/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O that/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O your/O leaving/O the/O party/O at/O that/O particular/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
It/O had/O everything/O to/O do/O with/O it/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
That/O is/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O it/O was/O because/O of/O the/O restraint/O that/O sou/O felt/O would/O be/O imposed/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O you/O withdrew/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O restraint/O from/O anybody/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O restraint/O from/O anybody/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O were/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O that/O would/O interfere/O with/O your/O own/O creative/O work/O in/O the/O writing/O of/O the/O novels/O The/O Last/O Pioneer/O and/O so/O on/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
2316/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O counsel/O ,/O when/O Mr./O Levy/PERSON testified/O before/O he/O did/O not/O use/O the/O word/O ``/O restraint/O ./O ''/O 
He/O said/O ``/O no/O obligation/O ./O ''/O 
I/O am/O wondering/O if/O there/O is/O any/O difference/O in/O his/O mind/O between/O the/O terms/O ./O 
You/O used/O the/O term/O ``/O obligation/O ''/O ;/O you/O did/O not/O use/O the/O term/O ``/O restraint/O ,/O ''/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O but/O let/O me/O say/O this/O :/O That/O I/O have/O been/O writing/O most/O of/O my/O life/O ,/O and/O only/O once/O has/O anybody/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O this/O is/O what/O you/O are/O to/O write/O ,/O and/O this/O is/O the/O way/O you/O are/O to/O write/O it/O ./O ''/O 
Nobody/O in/O my/O life/O has/O ever/O said/O to/O me/O excepting/O once/O ``/O this/O is/O the/O way/O the/O thing/O has/O got/O to/O be/O done/O ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O using/O the/O word/O ``/O obligation/O ,/O ''/O but/O I/O think/O obligation/O is/O the/O closer/O word/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O exact/O language/O was-and/O I/O wrote/O it/O down/O because/O I/O thought/O it/O was/O significant/O -/O ``/O I/O wanted/O to/O have/O no/O obligation/O except/O to/O my/O writing/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O conscious/O of/O using/O that/O word/O ,/O but/O that/O is/O the/O more/O accurate/O thing/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O meant/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O understand/O is/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O felt/O that/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O hinder/O you/O in/O carrying/O out/O your/O work/O in/O the/O preparation/O of/O the/O novels/O you/O spoke/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
I/O felt/O ,/O and/O do/O feel/O ,/O that/O membership/O in/O any/O organization/O that/O has/O a/O program/O to/O which/O you/O bind/O yourself/O by/O being/O a/O member/O must/O give/O you/O an/O obligation-and/O thank/O you/O for/O giving/O me/O back/O that/O word-must/O give/O you/O an/O obligation/O to/O those/O things/O which/O must/O influence/O your/O writing/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O in/O Gold/O Eagle/O Guy/O ,/O the/O protagonist/O is/O a/O shipping/O man/O ,/O a/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION man/O ,/O who/O is/O a/O shipper/O who/O creates/O a/O shipping/O empire/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O the/O family/O of/O the/O man/O who/O thought/O that/O I/O was/O writing/O about/O him/O was/O very/O indignant/O that/O I/O had/O treated/O him/O this/O way/O ,/O but/O to/O me/O he/O was/O a/O character/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O say/O ,/O because/O the/O family/O may/O object/O to/O it/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O paint/O him/O one/O way/O ,/O but/O also/O to/O me/O lie/O was/O a/O very/O romantic/O and/O powerful/O ,/O creative/O character/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O be/O under-this/O was/O his/O significance/O to/O me/O ,/O was/O that/O he/O was/O both/O things/O ,/O was/O that/O lie/O was/O creative/O ,/O that/O lie/O built/O ,/O that/O he/O was/O essential/O ,/O and/O also/O on/O the/O other/O side/O that/O he/O was/O animmnoral/O ,/O that/O he/O was/O ruthless/O ,/O and/O you/O must/O have/O both/O these/O things/O to/O make/O a/O character/O ,/O to/O make/O a/O man/O ./O 
And/O if/O you/O leave/O out/O either/O thing/O you/O are/O lying/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEn/O ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O there/O was/O only/O one/O occasion/O when/O you/O were/O told/O ,/O or/O directed/O what/O to/O write/O ./O 
Has/O that/O any/O bearing/O upon/O the/O matters/O which/O this/O committee/O is/O investigating/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEvy/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O working/O for/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Journal/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O the/O problem/O which/O you/O mentioned/O ,/O you/O withdrew/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1933/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O year/O 's/O period/O when/O you/O were/O a/O member/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O did/O you/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O think/O I/O paid/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON something/O when/O he/O gave/O me/O the/O card/O ,/O some/O small/O sum/O ,/O but/O no/O others/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENN/PERSON ./O 
R./O But/O as/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ,/O you/O did/O not/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2317/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O next/O affiliation/O or/O connection/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O either/O in/O late/O 1944/O or/O early/O in/O 1945/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O stress/O the/O name/O because/O this/O was/O the/O connection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O desire/O to/O say/O to/O the/O committee/O regarding/O your/O experience/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O asked/O to/O join/O ,/O and/O said/O what/O had/O happened/O there/O before/O ,/O said/O what/O had/O happened/O ;/O said/O much/O of/O what/O I/O have/O said/O to/O you/O here/O now/O ./O 
And/O then/O was/O told/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION no/O longer/O existed/O ;/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION existed/O ,/O and/O that/O it/O was/O an/O entirely/O different/O kind/O of/O thing/O ;/O that/O it/O was/O part/O of/O the/O unity/O between/O wartime/O allies/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ,/O and/O I/O joined/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O because/O of/O those/O representations/O your/O attitude/O toward/O your/O work/O and/O your/O party/O was/O different/O from/O what/O it/O had/O been/O back/O in/O 1933/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O party/O no/O longer-there/O was/O no/O more/O party/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O this/O was/O the/O thing/O :/O That/O there/O was/O no/O more/O party/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O more/O Communist/O Party/O at/O this/O time/O ./O 
And/O that/O the/O situation/O that/O I/O had/O found/O unpleasant/O did/O not/O exist/O and/O could/O not/O exist/O ,/O and/O that/O we/O were/O wartime/O allies/O with/O them/O ,/O and/O we/O were-I/O can/O not/O finish/O that/O sentence/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O instrumental/O in/O bringing/O you/O into/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
A/O man/O named/O Willner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O George/PERSON Willner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O he/O is/O the/O same/O George/PERSON Will/PERSON -/O ner/O who/O was/O an/O agent/O for/O various/O writers/O andMr/O ./O 
LEVY/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O who/O appeared/O before/O this/O committee/O and/O refused/O to/O testify/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O to/O do/O so/O might/O incriminate/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O that/O he/O had/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O but/O he/O was/O an/O agent/O ,/O lie/O was/O my/O agent/O ,/O or/O he/O worked/O for/O my/O agent/O ./O 
He/O was/O an/O employee/O of/O my/O agent/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O tell/O us/O a/O little/O more/O in/O detail/O of/O what/O Mr./O Willner/PERSON did/O to/O bring/O you/O into/O the/O party/O again/O in/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O either/O late/O 1944/O or/O 1945-I/O am/O not/O sure/O which/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION had/O its/O inception/O in/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O ended/O in/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O in/O my/O own/O mind/O ,/O whether/O it/O was/O 1944/O or/O 1945/O ./O 
That/O is/O why/O I-and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O to/O establish/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O recite/O the/O events/O or/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O George/PERSON Willner/PERSON approached/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
He/O spoke/O to/O me/O about/O this/O a/O number/O of/O times/O saying/O more/O or/O less/O what/O I/O have/O said/O now/O ,/O in/O different/O ways/O ,/O and/O finally/O I/O said/O ,/O or/O finally/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O would/O like/O you/O to/O go/O to/O a/O meeting/O ,/O ''/O and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O 0/O ./O 
K./O ''/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
A/O little/O louder/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O terribly/O sorry/O ./O 
2318/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O And/O he/O gave/O me/O an/O address/O ,/O and/O I/O went/O to/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
He/O was/O not/O there/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON reentered/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O is/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O there/O ./O 
And/O the/O assumption/O was/O thatthere/O was/O nothing/O more/O formal/O than/O that/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O this/O meeting/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O went/O to/O some/O others/O ,/O not/O a/O lot/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O these/O meetings/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O in/O the/O valley/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
You/O say/O whose/O house/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not-I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
It/O was/O in/O the/O valley/O ./O 
It/O was/O on/O the/O flat/O part/O of/O the/O valley/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O house/O I/O never/O went/O to/O again/O ,/O and/O Bill/PERSON I/PERSON asked/O me/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O tried/O to/O remember/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O tried/O to/O remember/O since/O ,/O and/O I/O just/O do/O n't/O know/O whose/O house/O it/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O did/O you/O attend/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Six/O or/O eight/O over/O a/O period/O of/O time/O ;/O maybe/O five/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Over/O what/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Over/O a/O period/O of/O several/O months/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O half/O dozen/O ,/O I/O should/O think/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O note/O was/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
This/O note/O just/O says/O ``/O Louder/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O you/O should/O read/O it/O because/O I/O would/O not/O want/O it/O to/O appear/O that/O we/O were/O handing/O you/O private/O notes/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
You/O looked/O so/O distressed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O note/O says/O ``/O Louder/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O try/O to/O speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Over/O a/O period/O of/O several/O months/O ,/O I/O think/O there/O were/O five/O or/O six/O or/O eight/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O these/O meetings/O held/O ?/O 
If/O you/O attended/O about/O five/O meetings/O ,/O can/O you/O tell/O us/O ,/O or/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O the/O homes/O of/O any/O of/O the/O persons/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
A/O man/O named/O Bill/PERSON Blowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Bill/PERSON ,/O is/O that/O Blowitz/PERSON ,/O B-1-o-w-i-t-z/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O is/O apparently/O the/O same/O man/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O the/O way/O you/O pronounce/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFr/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O his/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Bill/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O in/O what/O business/O was/O he/O engaged/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O a/O publicity/O man/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O ,/O counsel/O for/O the/O committee/O interrupted/O the/O proceedings/O to/O discuss/O another/O matter/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O attended/O a/O meeting/O in/O the/O home/O of/O William/PERSON Blowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O other/O persons/O in/O whose/O homes/O you/O met/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O do/O that/O now/O ./O 
At/O a/O later/O time/O ,/O Lester/PERSON ColeI/PERSON think/O not/O at/O this/O time/O ;/O I/O 'm/O not/O sure-it/O 's/O hard/O to/O remember/O them/O ,/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2319/O because/O they/O were/O often/O in/O the/O homes/O of/O people/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ,/O and/O because/O it/O was/O so/O irregular/O ,/O they/O were/O usually/O with/O people/O whom/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O have/O something/O in/O front/O of/O you/O thereMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O meeting/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mortimer/PERSON Offner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O so/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O there/O was/O one/O of/O these/O that/O was/O at/O my/O house/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O any/O other/O members/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
1/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O Bill/PERSON has/O the/O names/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O Berkeley/PERSON was/O one/O ;/O Betty/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ,/O who/O also/O testified/O that/O I/O met/O her/O at/O such/O a/O meeting/O ,/O has/O testified/O accurately/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O she/O testified/O in/O the/O Hollywood/O hearings/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O this/O was/O accurate/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON ,/O H-u-e-b-s-c-h/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O do/O you/O base/O your/O statement/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Because/O he/O asked/O me/O if/O I/O would/O like-when/O I/O had/O left/O ,/O if/O I/O would/O likeMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O had/O left/O ,/O he/O asked/O me/O if/O I/O wanted/O to/O be/O in/O or/O out/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Alfred/PERSON Levitt/PERSON ,/O L-e-v-i-t-t/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O something/O that/O I/O have/O been/O trying/O to/O remember/O ./O 
I/O have/O said-when/O I/O read/O this/O ,/O I/O found/O his/O name/O there/O ,/O and/O I/O can/O not/O now/O say-I/O would/O say/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O ''/O but/O I/O cannot-I/O would/O say/O he/O is/O ,/O but/O I/O keep/O trying/O to/O find/O a/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O you/O to/O say/O so/O unless/O you/O know/O it/O of/O your/O own/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O find/O the/O reason/O in/O my/O mind/O that/O I/O would/O say/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O if/O you/O have/O any/O reason/O ,/O state/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O trying/O to/O think/O if/O I/O ever/O was/O at/O that/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O this/O ,/O that/O before/O you/O express/O any/O opinion/O you/O should/O first/O conclude/O in/O your/O own/O mind/O whether/O you/O know/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O difficult/O thing/O ./O 
I/O read/O it/O there/O ,/O and/O when/O I/O said/O it/O 1/O must/O have/O had/O a/O reason/O for/O saying/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O ,/O you/O read/O it/O there/O ?/O 
I/O Bill/PERSON refers/O to/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O committee/O investigator/O 95829-52-pt/O ./O 
7-2/O 2320/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O read/O over/O the/O testimony/O I/O gave/O Bill/PERSON ,/O what/O I/O gave/O Bill/PERSON earlier/O ./O 
And/O then/O ,/O afterward/O ,/O when/O I/O saw/O it/O there/O ,/O I/O began/O to/O try/O to/O remember/O why/O I/O said/O it/O ./O 
I/O can/O not/O remember/O now/O whether/O I/O was/O at/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O or/O not/O ./O 
I/O was/O with/O him/O at/O a/O number/O of/O Screen/O Actors/O '/O Guild/O meetings/O and/O that/O kind/O of/O thing/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O say/O that/O I/O am/O pretty/O sure/O the/O answer/O is/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O ''/O but/O I/O can/O not/O say/O right/O now/O why/O I/O say/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ,/O because/O this/O has/O bothered/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O T/O \/O WENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O is/O that/O all/O you/O have/O to/O say/O with/O regard/O to/O Mr./O Levitt/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O for/O your/O information/O ,/O as/O you/O were/O not/O at/O the/O Hollywood/O hearings/O ,/O Mr./O Levitt/PERSON was/O identified/O by/O witnesses/O there/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O were/O you/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O way/O between/O the/O years/O 1936/O and/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O any/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION during/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEv/O Y./O No/O ./O 
sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Or/O Marxist/O study/O groups/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O was/O living/O on/O a/O farm/O in/O Bucks/O County/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
And/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O attending/O any/O public/O things/O except/O auction/O sales/O ./O 
But/O during/O that/O time/O ,/O I/O certainly/O had/O no/O connection/O with/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVErNNER/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O go/O to/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
1941/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O T.xkvNNrn/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O you/O were/O in/O California/LOCATION in/O 1933/O ?/O 
Mr./O Livy/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNZR/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O were/O working/O on/O the/O Tom/PERSON Mooney/PERSON book/O ?/O 
Mr./O LrvY/O Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION then/O ./O 
Then/O when/O Gold/PERSON Eagle/PERSON Guy/PERSON was/O running/O ,/O I/O was/O out/O to/O do/O one/O picture/O for/O Metro/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVFNNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O in/O California/LOCATION between/O 1936/O and/O 1941/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O had/O a/O job/O for/O Universal/O ./O 
I/O was/O out/O there/O for/O 6/O weeks/O ,/O in/O 1939/O ./O 
But/O I/O did/O not/O have/O any/O connection/O with/O anything/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNE.R/O ./O 
Were/O you/O out/O there/O between/O 1936/O and/O 1939/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O out/O in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O LrvY/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O was/O there/O for/O the/O first/O time/O in/O 1933/O ./O 
Then/O I/O was/O there/O in/O 1935/O at/O Metro/ORGANIZATION ./O 
And/O in/O 1939/O ./O 
at/O Universal/O ./O 
Then/O I/O came/O out/O again/O just/O before/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION in/O 1941/O ,/O shortly/O before/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ./O 
And/O that/O time/O I/O brought/O my/O family/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O stayed/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1944/O ,/O were/O you/O issued/O a/O membership/O card/O ,/O or/O was/O your/O affiliation/O just/O by/O attendance/O at/O meetings/O which/O you/O recognized/O or/O assumed/O to/O be/O Communist/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEV/O '/O ./O 
Which/O I/O recognized/O ./O 
So/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O the/O only/O card/O I/O ever/O remember/O was/O the/O one/O Mr./O Browder/PERSON gave/O me/O in/O 1933/O ./O 
There/O may/O have/O been/O cards/O made/O out/O that/O were/O not/O issued/O to/O me/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O remember/O seeing/O them/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2321/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O could/O we/O assume/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1941/O other/O than/O attending/O meetings/O ,/O or/O what/O was/O your/O attitude/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O regarded/O myself/O so/O ./O 
Of/O the/O political/O association/O ,/O rather/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O you/O said/O there/O was/O no/O more/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O political/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O Do-LE/O ./O 
It/O was/O your/O understanding/O that/O it/O did/O not/O exist/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O was/O true/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O party/O did/O not/O exist/O then/O ,/O or/O did/O not/O exist/O in/O any/O form/O thatMr/O ./O 
MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O point/O that/O I/O referred/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON used/O the/O words/O interchangeably/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O your/O own/O mind/O ,/O was/O not/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION the/O same/O as/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
What/O ,/O in/O your/O mind/O ,/O was/O the/O difference/O between/O the/O two/O ?/O 
Was/O there/O any/O difference/O in/O the/O personnel/O or/O the/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
This/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O membership/O was/O ./O 
There/O was/O certainly/O a/O difference/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O a/O difference/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O there/O was/O a/O difference/O in/O your/O own/O mind/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O difference/O ./O 
ship/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O difference/O in/O member/O -/O Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
You/O had/O belonged/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION prior/O to/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
But/O I/O left/O for/O the/O specific/O reasons/O I/O stated/O ,/O and/O would/O not/O have/O gone/O back/O ,/O for/O those/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O little/O confused/O about/O this/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
I/O understood/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION prior/O to/O its/O change/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O LEvY/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O in/O 1933/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvi/O :/O NNI/O :/O R./O In/O 1933/O lie/O dropped/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
And/O yon/O did/O not/O rejoin/O it/O againMr/O ./O 
L/O :/O vY/O ./O 
Until/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O VrLinr/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O VELrD/O ./O 
I/O see/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O \/O vExN-rn/O ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEaY/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O actually/O ,/O technically/O ,/O I/O suppose/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O member/O until/O 1947/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O some/O time/O in/O 1947/O ./O 
I/O had/O stopped/O going/O to/O meetings/O a/O long/O time/O before/O that/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O technically/O it/O was/O in/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEn/O ./O 
Actually/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION went/O out/O of/O existence/O in/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O Lrvy/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O you/O just/O remained/O in/O the/O Communist/O organization/O ,/O which/O had/O converted/O in/O 1945/O back/O to/O its/O former/O title/O ,/O that/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
What/O happened/O was/O that/O finally-I/O was/O n't/O being/O around/O ,/O and/O finally/O I/O was/O called/O on/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O What/O do/O you/O want/O to/O do/O ?/O ''/O 
Finally/O Mr./O Hnebsch/PERSON called/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O What/O do/O you/O want/O to/O do/O ?/O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O called/O ?/O 
2322/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Huebsch/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O the/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
You/O spelled/O it/O a/O minute/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
H-u-e-b-s-c-h/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
During/O all/O that/O time/O you/O referred/O to/O ,/O as/O being/O associated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O the/O Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O would/O you/O say/O it/O influenced/O your/O writings/O ,/O books/O ,/O or/O any/O other/O publications/O or/O works/O that/O you/O have/O done/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEvy/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O it/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O the/O association/O you/O had/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION organization/O ,/O or/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ,/O did/O not/O influence/O in/O any/O way/O your/O publications/O or/O the/O work/O that/O you/O were/O doing/O ;/O that/O is/O ,/O the/O philosophy/O or/O the/O belief/O of/O those/O people/O or/O the/O party/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O answer/O is/O ``/O No/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
My/O answer/O is/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O am/O smiling/O because/O one/O meeting/O that/O I/O remember/O clearly/O ,/O the/O content/O of/O it/O was/O on/O literature/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
The/O one/O meeting/O I/O remember/O clearly/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O why/O I/O remember/O it/O ,/O was/O on/O the/O question/O of/O literature/O ./O 
It/O was/O on/O the/O question/O of/O realism/O and/O naturalism/O ./O 
The/O announced/O subject/O was/O Marxist/O Criticism/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O of/O myself/O as/O knowing/O something/O about/O these/O subjects/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O told/O by/O a/O girl/O whom/O I/O had/O never/O seen/O before/O or/O since/O that/O I/O had/O no/O right/O to/O know/O about/O these/O subjects/O ,/O because/O she/O ,/O who/O represented/O the/O working/O class/O ,/O understood/O them/O instinctively/O ,/O and/O she/O disagreed/O with/O me/O ,/O and/O therefore/O I/O must/O be/O in/O error/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O ever/O any/O attempt/O on/O the/O part/O of/O any/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O the/O organizations/O you/O mentioned/O in/O your/O testimony/O to/O influence/O you/O or/O to/O persuade/O you/O to/O write/O in/O such/O manner/O as/O would/O include/O the/O Communist/O philosophy/O or/O belief/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Nothing/O that/O is/O overt/O ,/O excepting/O in/O a/O kind/O of/O an/O almost/O automatic/O sense/O ,/O that/O you/O are/O influenced/O by/O the/O people/O that/O you/O are/O with/O ./O 
If/O I/O spent/O time/O with/O you/O ,/O I/O would/O be/O influenced/O by/O you/O ,/O and/O you/O would/O be/O influenced/O by/O me/O ,/O I/O mean/O ,/O that/O kind/O of/O thing/O ./O 
But/O there/O is/O only/O one/O time/O in/O my/O life/O that/O somebody/O has/O said/O ,/O ``/O This/O is/O what/O you/O have/O to/O write/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O was/O it/O your/O purpose/O ,/O in/O joining/O the/O party/O in/O 1933/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O associating/O yourself/O with/O the/O meetings/O that/O you/O have/O mentioned/O in/O 1944/O ,/O to/O inform/O yourself/O or/O to/O broaden/O your/O information/O concerning/O the/O workings/O and/O the/O functions/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION organizations/O in/O this/O country/O ?/O 
Was/O it/O curiosity/O ,/O or/O what/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O find/O a/O way/O of/O saying/O this/O so/O that/O it/O does/O n't/O sound/O kind/O of/O silly/O ./O 
But/O my/O purpose/O both/O times/O was/O in/O the/O hope/O that/O I/O would/O find/O a/O way/O of/O leaving/O my/O kids/O a/O better/O world/O than/O I/O lived/O in/O ./O 
And/O when/O I/O found/O that/O I/O was/O not/O doing/O that/O ,/O then/O I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O do/O it/O any/O more/O ./O 
I/O have/O lots/O of/O kids/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O this/O person/O who/O stated/O to/O you/O that/O you/O should/O not/O think/O as/O you/O were/O thinking/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O girl/O I/O never/O saw/O before/O or/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O in/O one/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2323/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O anything/O about/O it/O excepting/O this/O ,/O that/O I/O felt/O such/O a/O fury/O ./O 
I/O find/O the/O kind/O of/O an/O automobile/O mechanic/O or/O somebody/O might/O feelMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
During/O this/O part/O of/O your/O experience/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION literature/O made/O available/O to/O you/O for/O study/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
There/O was/O always/O literature/O ,/O but/O a/O great/O variety/O of/O literature/O ./O 
There/O was/O both/O Communist/O literature/O and/O general/O literature/O available/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O expected/O to/O study/O and/O master/O the/O Communist/O Party/O literature/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
You/O could/O either/O buy/O it/O or/O not/O buy/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O discussion/O groups/O held/O on/O Communist/O matters/O ,/O matters/O involving/O Communist/O ideology/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O never/O attended/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O in/O all/O did/O you/O attend/O ?/O 
I/O believe/O you/O have/O stated/O about/O five/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O not/O less/O than/O five/O nor/O more/O than/O eight/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O just/O left/O ./O 
I/O just/O was/O n't/O there/O ./O 
And/O then/O after/O a/O long/O period/O of/O time/O Mr./O Huebsch/PERSON came/O to/O see/O me/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O What/O do/O you/O want/O to/O do/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O be/O in/O or/O out/O ?/O ''/O 
And/O I/O say/O ,/O ``/O Out/O ./O ''/O 
In/O my/O own/O mind/O ,/O I/O had/O been/O gone/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O during/O this/O period/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O paid/O some/O dues/O in/O meetings/O ./O 
They/O were/O small/O dues/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O to/O whom/O you/O paid/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O think/O somebody/O would/O get/O up/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O Give/O me/O your/O quarter/O ,/O ''/O or/O something/O of/O that/O kind/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O it/O was/O more/O than/O a/O quarter/O ./O 
It/O may/O have/O been/O as/O much/O as/O 50/O cents/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O contribute/O to/O any/O functions/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION by/O making/O special/O contributions/O ,/O or/O such/O things/O as/O bene/O -/O fits/O for/O the/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O bought/O a/O picture/O once/O at/O a/O New/LOCATION Masses/LOCATION sale/O ,/O a/O very/O good/O picture/O ./O 
This/O was/O before/O I/O had/O any/O connection/O withMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O attend/O a/O fraction/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Not/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O knowing/O that/O I/O was/O so/O doing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O a/O member/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O were/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O have/O some/O place/O a/O note/O from/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON thanking/O me/O for/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O engaged/O in/O any/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O that/O group/O after/O the/O termination/O of/O the/O war/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O that/O it/O existed/O after/O the/O war/O ./O 
I/O was/O later/O told/O it/O had/O ./O 
But/O I/O was/O told/O it/O went/O out/O of/O existence/O during/O the/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O anything/O of/O the/O purpose/O that/O the/O or/O -/O ganization/O had/O in/O perpetuating/O itself/O after/O the/O period/O of/O the/O war/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O it/O did/O ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O was/O told/O quite/O recently/O that/O it/O had/O ./O 
But/O as/O far/O as/O I/O knew/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O wartime/O thing/O ,/O for/O civilian/O defense/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ?/O 
2324/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O by/O the/O testimony/O adduced/O at/O numerous/O hearings/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O has/O been/O shown/O to/O be/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O him/O as/O such/O ./O 
I/O met/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON in/O 1925/O ,/O when/O my/O first/O novel/O was/O published/O ./O 
We/O had/O the/O same/O publisher/O ./O 
And/O this/O was/O the/O way/O I/O knew/O himMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Were/O you/O going/O to/O say/O something/O else/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O was/O just/O hesitating/O as/O to/O whether/O it/O was/O worth/O while/O to/O tell/O the/O circumstances/O of/O my/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O it/O is/O ./O 
They/O are/O amusing/O ,/O but/O they/O are/O not/O pertinent/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O active/O in/O the/O work/O of/O the/O committee/O for/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O held/O in/O the/O campus/O at/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION October/O 1/O ,/O 2/O ,/O and/O 3/O ,/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O and/O so/O were/O a/O great/O many/O people/O from/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O the/O university/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O shown/O by/O hearings/O before/O the/O committee/O that/O that/O work/O was/O done/O as/O a/O result/O of/O being/O influenced/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O anything/O about/O that/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O was/O introduced/O to/O it/O and/O asked/O to/O participate/O in/O it/O by/O Phil/PERSON Dunn/PERSON of/O the/O OWI/O ,/O who/O is/O certainly/O not/O by/O the/O farthest/O stretch/O of/O the/O imagination/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O signing/O a/O petition/O dated/O October/O 18/O ,/O 1948/O ,/O for/O the/O nomination/O of/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON and/O Ring/PERSON Lardner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O as/O members/O of/O the/O executive/O board/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O LrvY/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
1948/O is/O a/O period/O of/O time/O later/O than/O that/O when/O you/O said/O you/O withdrew/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
That/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O in/O favor/O in/O 1948/O of/O electing/O to/O the/O executive/O board/O of/O the/O guild/O persons/O who/O were/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O only/O tell/O you/O that/O either/O in/O that/O year/O or/O the/O year/O before/O I/O also/O signed/O a/O nominating/O petition/O for/O a/O man/O named/O Fred/PERSON Niblo/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O who/O is/O as/O far/O to/O the/O right/O as/O you/O can/O get/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O was/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNrER/O ./O 
And/O was/O Ring/O Lardner/O ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O not/O known/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNrR/O ./O 
But/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON was/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
But/O I/O signed/O these/O two/O petitions/O ,/O the/O Niblo/PERSON petition/O and/O this/O petition/O ,/O on/O the/O basis/O that/O a/O man/O who/O had/O anything/O to/O say/O to/O the/O guild/O ought/O to/O have/O a/O chance/O to/O say/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O speaking/O of/O the/O opportunity/O to/O say/O what/O he/O wanted/O to/O say/O ,/O what/O one/O wants/O to/O say/O ,/O before/O the/O guild/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O the/O election/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O executive/O board/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O this/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O nomination/O ,/O putting/O a/O name/O on/O the/O ballot/O and/O letting/O the/O members/O decide/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2325/O -LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O mean/O to/O say/O you/O would/O sign/O a/O person/O 's/O petition/O for/O nomination/O and/O then/O vote/O against/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEIR/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O your/O view/O in/O this/O instance/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O what/O you/O expected/O to/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
In/O this/O case/O I/O would/O have/O voted/O for/O one/O of/O the/O men/O and/O against/O the/O other/O one/O ./O 
In/O the/O case/O of/O Mr./O Niblo/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O ,/O and/O told/O him/O I/O would/O ,/O vote/O against/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O speaking/O about/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON ,/O the/O person/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O say/O of/O these/O two/O people/O I/O would/O have/O voted/O for/O one/O and/O against/O the/O other/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O how/O I/O did/O vote/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O intend/O in/O signing/O the/O petition/O to/O support/O Lester/PERSON Cole/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a/O person/O then/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Lester/PERSON is/O the/O person/O I/O would/O not/O have/O voted/O for/O and/O did/O not/O vote/O for/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Although/O you/O did/O sign/O his/O nominating/O petition/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O would/O and/O assume/O I/O did/O vote/O for/O Ring/O Lardner/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O statement/O that/O you/O desire/O to/O make/O to/O the/O committee/O with/O regard/O to/O the/O character/O of/O your/O break/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O is/O ,/O whether/O it/O was/O full/O and/O complete/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O assume/O that/O I/O have/O made/O that/O statement/O ,/O that/O it/O was/O full/O and/O complete/O ,/O I/O mean/O ,/O that/O this/O is/O the/O content/O of/O my/O appearance/O here/O ;/O that/O it/O is/O full/O and/O complete/O ,/O that/O I/O have/O not/O heard/O anything/O nor/O have/O any/O desire/O or/O reason/O to/O hear/O anything/O ,/O since/O this/O last/O time/O ,/O about/O 4/O years/O ago/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O there/O would/O beMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Tlat/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Levy/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O legal/O counsel/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O identify/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Gang/PERSON ,/O sir/O ./O 
-LSB-/O Martin/ORGANIZATION Gang/ORGANIZATION ./O -RSB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O interested/O in/O your/O comment/O that/O back/O in/O 1943/O ,/O as/O I/O thought/O you/O said/O ,/O you/O thought/O you/O paid/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON some/O dues/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O ask/O you/O for/O dues/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O how/O did/O you/O happen/O to/O pay/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O Li/PERSON :/O vY/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O ,/O he/O gave/O me/O this/O card/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O the/O words/O ,/O but/O the/O sense/O of/O it/O was/O ,/O ``/O I/O want/O a/O quarter/O ,/O ''/O or/O it/O may/O have/O been/O a/O dime/O ./O 
The/O sums/O were/O very/O ,/O very/O small/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O it/O just/O seemed/O to/O me/O the/O way/O things/O were/O done/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Kearney/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O Potter/PERSON ?/O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O there/O is/O one/O question/O I/O may/O desire/O to/O ask/O the/O witness/O ,/O if/O you/O will/O bear/O with/O me/O a/O moment/O ,/O please/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O witness/O who/O appeared/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O response/O to/O a/O subpena/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Carl/PERSON Foreman/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
2326/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O do/O you/O base/O your/O statement/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVy/PERSON ./O 
Because/O I/O was/O invited/O to/O hear/O him/O talk/O to/O a/O meeting/O ,/O which/O I/O have/O every/O presumption/O was/O a/O Communist/O meeting/O ,/O to/O talk/O about/O his/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O meeting/O held/O ,/O as/O nearly/O as/O you/O can/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Possibly/O '/O 46/O ./O 
It/O was/O at/O a/O time/O when/O I/O had/O not/O been/O around/O for/O a/O long/O while/O ,/O and/O I/O went/O to/O this/O because/O I/O was/O very/O interested/O in/O hearing/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O he/O the/O same/O person/O who/O appeared/O in/O the/O hearings/O at/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O refused/O to/O answer/O questions/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O to/O do/O so/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
I/O assume/O so/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O hear/O that/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O was/O Carl/PERSON Foreman/PERSON employed/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O the/O one/O that/O you/O were/O speaking/O of/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEvy/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O he/O appeared/O ?/O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O who/O was/O he/O working/O for/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O LEv/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
He/O is/O not/O a/O man/O that/O I/O have/O known/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O before/O concluding/O my/O testimony/O I/O should/O like/O to/O repeat/O part/O of/O the/O testimony/O I/O gave/O to/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON on/O October/O 22/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
My/O name/O was/O mentioned/O at/O the/O recent/O hearings/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION as/O having/O formerly/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
I/O also/O heard/O statements/O made/O by/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O any/O person/O named/O as/O having/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O have/O the/O opportunity/O to/O testify/O before/O this/O committee/O as/O to/O whether/O the/O statement/O was/O true/O or/O untrue/O ,/O and/O if/O true/O that/O any/O statements/O with/O reference/O to/O disaffiliation/O with/O the/O party/O might/O be/O given/O to/O the/O committee/O under/O oath/O ./O 
I/O am/O taking/O advantage/O of/O the/O opportunity/O offered/O by/O the/O committee/O since/O the/O statement/O made/O with/O reference/O to/O my/O past/O affiliation/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O true/O and/O correct/O statement/O ./O 
I/O have/O for/O a/O considerable/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O however/O ,/O not/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O left/O because/O I/O did/O not/O believe/O in/O the/O aims/O ,/O purposes/O ,/O or/O operation/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
I/O found/O it/O had/O nothing/O to/O offer/O me/O and/O had/O no/O place/O in/O this/O country/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O offer/O to/O testify/O before/O the/O committee/O since/O I/O frankly/O felt/O that/O I/O had/O had/O such/O a/O minor/O connection/O with/O the/O party/O that/O I/O would/O serve/O no/O useful/O purpose/O in/O volunteering/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O my/O name/O has/O been/O mentioned/O and/O I/O am/O grateful/O to/O the/O committee/O for/O granting/O me/O this/O opportunity/O to/O get/O the/O record/O straight/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
The/O witness/O may/O be/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O LEVY/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O gentlemen/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O until/O 2/O o'clock/O this/O afternoon/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 11/O :/O 55/O a./O m./O ,/O the/O committee/O recessed/O to/O reconvene/O at/O 2/O p./O m./O of/O the/O same/O day/O ./O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2327/O -LRB-/O The/O following/O statement/O was/O inserted/O at/O this/O point/O by/O Representative/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON :-RRB-/O It/O is/O my/O opinion/O that/O the/O committee/O should/O commend/O and/O express/O appreciation/O to/O all/O witnesses/O who/O cooperate/O and/O truthfully/O testify/O and/O reveal/O all/O of/O their/O knowledge/O and/O information/O of/O communistic/O activities/O in/O our/O country/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O record/O to/O show/O that/O witness/O Melvin/PERSON Levy/PERSON voluntarily/O appeared/O and/O has/O so/O cooperated/O and/O testified/O in/O his/O assistance/O of/O tins/O committee/O of/O its/O work/O of/O exposing/O communistic/O activities/O in/O this/O country/O ./O 
AFTERNOON/O SESSION/O -LRB-/O The/O hearing/O reconvened/O at/O 2:15/O p./O m./O ,/O Representatives/O Morgan/PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O being/O present/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O presiding/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ./O 
Who/O is/O your/O first/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O please/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O MICHAEL/PERSON SEYMOUR/PERSON BLANKFORT/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
Michael/PERSON Seymour/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O horn/O ,/O Mr./O Blankfort/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
December/O 10/O ,/O 1907/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O for/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O and/O background/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O educated/O in/O the/O public/O schools/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O an/O undergraduate/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Pennsylvania/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O graduated/O with/O the/O degree/O of/O bachelor/O of/O arts/O in/O 1929/O ./O 
I/O was/O an/O instructor/O of/O psychology/O at/O Bowdoin/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ,/O Brunswick/LOCATION ,/O Maine/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O an/O instructor/O in/O psychology/O at/O Princeton/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O years/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
At/O Princeton/ORGANIZATION it/O was/O from/O 1930/O to/O 1932/O ,/O where/O I/O took/O graduate/O work/O as/O well/O as/O teaching/O ,/O and/O received/O my/O master/O 's/O degree/O ./O 
My/O educational/O record/O includes/O teaching/O at/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O adult/O education/O ,/O in/O playwriting/O ;/O a/O session/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Heidelberg/ORGANIZATION in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O as/O a/O student/O of/O the/O language/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O years/O were/O you/O teaching/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
1934/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O or/O 1935/O ./O 
It/O may/O even/O have/O been/O later/O than/O that/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O certain/O now/O ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O a/O member/O of/O the/O regular/O faculty/O of/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O was/O teaching/O adults/O playwriting/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O actively/O engaged/O in/O the/O writing/O profession/O ?/O 
2328/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
Since/O the/O early/O 1930/O 's/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O briefly/O what/O some/O of/O the/O more/O outstanding/O productions/O have/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O both/O a/O novelist/O and/O a/O screen/O writer/O ./O 
I/O have/O particular/O pride/O in/O my/O novels/O ,/O since/O they/O are/O the/O sole/O product/O of/O whatever/O ability/O I/O have/O ,/O and/O they/O are/O not/O collaboration/O efforts/O as/O moving/O pictures/O sometimes/O are/O ./O 
My/O first/O novel/O was/O called/O I/O Met/O a/O Man/O ./O 
It/O was/O published/O in/O 1936/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O or/O 1937/O ./O 
I/O published/O a/O novel/O in/O 1938/O called/O The/O Brave/O and/O the/O Blind/O ;/O one/O in/O 1942/O called/O A/O Time/O To/O Live/O ;/O another/O in/O 1946/O called/O The/O Widow/O Makers/O ./O 
I/O published/O a/O biography/O of/O Brig./O Gen./O Evans/PERSON Carlson/PERSON in/O 1946/O ./O 
They/O are/O my/O books/O ,/O generally/O speaking/O ./O 
I/O may/O have/O left/O out/O one/O or/O two/O that/O I/O wrote/O under/O a/O pseudonym/O which/O I/O was/O not/O particularly/O proud/O of/O ./O 
But/O to/O clear/O that/O up/O ,/O they/O are/O just/O mystery/O stories/O ,/O and/O I/O wrote/O them/O to/O earn/O a/O having/O ./O 
My/O screen/O productions/O have/O been-I/O believe/O the/O first/O one/O was/O Blind/O Alley/O ,/O which/O was/O about/O a/O psychologist/O ,/O which/O is/O why/O I/O got/O the/O job/O ./O 
That/O was/O 1939/O ./O 
Perhaps/O the/O best/O known/O of/O my/O screen/O work/O is/O Broken/O Arrow/O ,/O produced/O by/O Fox/PERSON ;/O Halls/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Montezuma/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O picture/O ,/O obviously/O ,/O about/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Marine/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION in/O 1950/O ./O 
Those/O are/O the/O best/O known/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mentioned/O the/O Marine/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O serve/O with/O the/O Marine/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Immediately/O after/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ,/O though/O I/O was/O married/O and/O had/O two/O children/O ,/O and/O was/O above/O draft/O age-and/O also/O had/O a/O contract/O at/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O writer-I/O volunteered/O ./O 
I/O received/O my/O commission/O in/O the/O summer/O of/O 1942/O as/O a/O first/O lieutenant/O ,/O and/O I/O served/O for/O a/O little/O over/O 21\/2/O years/O ,/O and/O was/O honorably/O discharged/O as/O a/O captain/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Blankfort/PERSON ,/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O conducted/O here/O in/O Washington/LOCATION on/O January/O 15/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O Mr./O Louis/PERSON Francis/PERSON Budenz/PERSON was/O a/O witness/O ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O his/O testimony/O ,/O the/O following/O questions/O were/O asked/O him/O ,/O and/O answers/O given/O by/O him/O to/O those/O questions/O ,/O which/O I/O will/O read/O to/O you/O :/O Mr./O JACKION/PERSON I/O have/O several/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O may/O depart/O from/O this/O particular/O phase/O of/O the/O inquiry/O ,/O I/O have/O some/O corollary/O questions/O which/O deal/O with/O another/O aspect/O of/O the/O committee/O hearings/O ,/O and/O not/O knowing/O when/O we/O will/O have/O the/O pleasure/O of/O having/O Mr./O Budenz/PERSON here/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O him/O at/O this/O time/O :/O During/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O in/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION Subcommittee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Internal/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION dealing/O with/O the/O Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Pacific/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O believe/O you/O were/O a/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O BUDENZ.Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O direct/O your/O attention/O to/O page/O 582/O of/O the/O published/O hearings/O ,/O or/O the/O testimony/O on/O those/O hearings/O when/O the/O matter/O of/O Evans/PERSON F./PERSON Carlson/PERSON 's/O book/O The/O Big/ORGANIZATION Yankee/ORGANIZATION was/O under/O discussion/O ./O 
There/O was/O one/O quotation/O given/O from/O that/O book/O ,/O and/O you/O were/O asked/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O in/O your/O opinion/O ,/O this/O quotation/O represented/O Communist/O propaganda/O ,/O and/O your/O answer/O to/O that/O ,/O as/O quoted/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O was/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O I/O also/O would/O recognize/O the/O author/O of/O General/O Carlson/PERSON 's/O biography/O as/O a/O Communist/O ,/O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O well/O known/O to/O myself/O as/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
He/O had/O many/O consultations/O with/O me/O as/O such/O ./O ''/O 
And/O then/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON continues/O :/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 2329/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Inasmuch/O as/O his/O name/O has/O occurred/O a/O number/O of/O times/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O committee/O hearings/O in/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION matter/O ,/O I/O should/O like/O to/O ask/O several/O questions/O on/O that/O particular/O Individual/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O first/O meet/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1935/O ,/O at/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O occasion/O of/O the/O meeting/O ,/O or/O what/O brought/O it/O about/O ,/O or/O in/O what/O connection/O you/O met/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ.Yes/O ;/O he/O was/O then/O writing/O for/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O that/O is/O ./O 
1/O would/O n't/O say/O he/O was/O a/O regular/O member/O of/O the/O staff/O although/O in/O a/O way/O he/O was/O ./O 
He/O wrote/O reviews/O and/O other/O articles/O for/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Over/O how/O long/O a/O period/O of/O time/O did/O sour/O association/O with/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON continue/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O continued-I/O can/O not/O tell/O you/O the/O exact/O year/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O but/O until/O he/O went/O out/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O first/O place/O ,/O when/O he/O came/O to/O me/O and/O had/O a/O 3-hour/O conference/O with/O me/O in/O regard/O to/O how/O to/O penetrate/O thlie/O ranks/O of/O the/O Catholics/O of/O the/O west/O coast/O ,/O he/O told/O me/O he/O had/O received/O instructions/O from/O the/O Politburo/O to/O endeavor/O to/O look/O into/O that/O while/O he/O was/O on/O the/O west/O coast/O He/O was/O driving/O through/O ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O and/O came/O to/O see/O me/O before/O he/O left/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O effort/O to/O penetrate/O the/O Catholics/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O mean/O on/O behalf/O of/O and/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ.That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON.Did/O you/O know/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ?/O 
And/O I/O say/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON because/O there/O is/O also/O a/O Henry/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON who/O testified/O or/O refused/O to/O testify/O before/O the/O committee/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O hearings/O ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O be/O came/O to/O me/O as/O such/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON.These/O consultations/O that/O you/O had/O with/O Mr./O Blankfort/PERSON took/O place/O in/O the/O offices/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ.Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON.Did/O you/O ever/O see/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O or/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION function/O where/O those/O present/O would/O have/O to/O be/O presumed/O to/O be/O Communists/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ;/O I/O have/O seen/O him/O ,/O not/O in/O a/O branch/O meeting/O ,/O or/O anything/O of/O that/O sort/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O seen/O him/O in/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Mr./O Michael/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON an/O open/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O or/O was/O he/O a/O concealed/O member/O ?/O 
Mr/O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O say/O he/O was/O a/O concealed/O member/O ,/O although/O he/O did/O not/O conceal/O it/O very/O much/O while/O he/O was/O around/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
He/O did/O not/O conceal/O it/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O he/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O Mr./O Blankfort/PERSON 's/O profession/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O writer/O ./O 
He/O wrote/O for/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O was/O going/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION also/O to/O get/O in/O some/O writing/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O last/O see/O Mr./O Blankfort/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O last/O time/O I/O saw/O him/O ,/O when/O he/O went/O out/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O where/O he/O was/O going/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O or/O what/O employment/O he/O was/O going/O to/O undertake/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ.He/O discussed/O it/O with/O me/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O for/O the/O moment/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON.Was/O it/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O moving-picture/O industry/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUDENZ/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O in/O my/O remembrance/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Mr./O Louis/PERSON Budenz/PERSON in/O 1935/O ?/O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O May/O I/O comment/O generally/O on/O the/O point/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O BLANKFORT/PERSON ./O 
First/O ,/O may/O I/O say/O that/O through/O my/O attorney/O ,/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O able/O to/O read/O the/O testimony/O given/O by/O Mr./O Budenz/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O have/O worked/O hard/O and/O searched/O my/O memory/O for/O any/O recollection/O of/O the/O testimony/O which/O he/O has/O presented/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
I/O have/O made/O a/O few/O notes/O ,/O and/O if/O you/O will/O permit/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O refer/O to/O them/O in/O reply/O to/O the/O general/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Louis/PERSON Budenz/PERSON ?/O 
2330/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
