COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 9/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O AUGUST/O 19/O AND/O SEPTEMBER/O 29/O ,/O 1952/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 21546/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1952/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Coun8el/O LoUIs/O J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Setior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O Page/O 4249/O August/O 19/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Bernard/PERSON C./PERSON Schoenfeld/PERSON -------------/O 4264/O ------------/O Huggins/PERSON of/O Roy/PERSON testimony/O September/O 29/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O III/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 9/O TUESDAY/O ,/O AUGUST/O 19/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O AcTIvrrIES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 10:30/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon/PERSON ,/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O and/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Come/O to/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O disclose/O that/O for/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O hearing/O I/O have/O set/O up/O a/O subcommittee/O composed/O of/O Messrs./O Velde/PERSON and/O Wood/PERSON ,/O who/O are/O both/O present/O ./O 
Whom/O do/O you/O call/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Bernard/PERSON C./PERSON Schoenfeld/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O sir/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O BERNARD/PERSON C./PERSON SCHOENFELD/PERSON Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ,/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O desire/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O at/O the/O outset/O I/O would/O like/O to/O explain/O that/O when/O Mr./O Stanley/PERSON Roberts/PERSON testified/O in/O open/O session/O before/O the/O committee/O regarding/O his/O open/O participation/O in/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION as/O a/O screen/O writer/O ,/O he/O identified/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON as/O a/O person/O who/O collaborated/O with/O him/O in/O regard/O to/O his/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O the/O following/O day/O ,/O an/O attorney/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION called/O me/O and/O stated/O that/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON had/O been/O to/O see/O him/O ,/O and/O that/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON desired/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O response/O to/O the/O general/O 4249/O 4250/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O invitation/O which/O you/O have/O from/O time/O to/O time/O issued/O ,/O namely/O ,/O that/O whenever/O a/O person/O or/O an/O organization/O has/O been/O mentioned/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O he/O or/O it/O should/O have/O the/O opportunity/O to/O appear/O and/O give/O such/O explanation/O or/O denial/O as/O he/O or/O it/O desires/O to/O make/O ./O 
In/O response/O to/O that/O telephone/O communication/O ,/O I/O arranged/O for/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON to/O interview/O a/O member/O of/O the/O staff/O ;/O which/O was/O done/O ,/O and/O finally/O ,/O as/O a/O result/O ,/O Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON ,/O at/O his/O request/O ,/O appears/O here/O today/O ./O 
Before/O giving/O him/O an/O opportunity/O to/O make/O the/O statement/O that/O he/O desires/O to/O make/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O him/O a/O few/O preliminary/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O Schoenfeld/PERSON ,/O when/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
In/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O August/O 17/O ,/O 1907/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Screen/O writer/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O educational/O background/O for/O the/O profession/O of/O which/O you/O are/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Harvard/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O which/O I/O graduated/O in/O 1928/O ,/O and/O then/O post/O graduate/O course/O in/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Drama/ORGANIZATION Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
at/O Yale/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O which/O I/O graduated/O in/O 1930/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O experience/O in/O your/O profession/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O upon/O graduation/O from/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Drama/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O wrote/O plays/O ,/O one/O of/O which/O was/O introduced/O on/O Broadway/O ,/O then/O another/O which/O was/O produced/O on/O Broadway/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O are/O those/O plays/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O play/O was/O called/O Shooting/O Star/O ,/O in/O 1933/O or/O 1934/O ,/O and/O the/O other/O one/O was/O called/O Hitch/O Your/O Wagon/O ,/O which/O was/O produced/O in/O 1936/O ./O 
In/O 1936/O ,/O I/O left/O playwriting/O and/O came/O to/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O where/O I/O worked/O for/O 7/O years/O in/O Government/O service/O ./O 
From/O 1936/O to/O 1938/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O radio/O writer/O for/O the/O Office/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Education/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O then/O in/O 1938/O I/O became/O chief/O script/O writer/O for/O the/O Radio/O Section/O of/O the/O Department/O of/O the/O Interior/O ./O 
In/O 1940/O ,/O I/O was/O appointed/O Chief/O of/O the/O Radio/O Section/O of/O the/O Office/O for/O Emergency/O Management/O ./O 
In/O 1942/O ,/O I/O was/O editor/O of/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION OWI/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O was/O in/O 1943/O that/O I/O became/O a/O screen/O writer/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O have/O been/O a/O screen/O writer/O since/O ,/O writing/O for/O motion/O pictures/O ./O 
Those/O are/O Phantom/O Lady/O ,/O Dark/O Corner/O ,/O Caged/O ,/O C-a-g-e-d/O ,/O and/O Macao/LOCATION ,/O M-a-c-a-o/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O extent/O of/O my/O career/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O you/O worked/O for/O the/O Government/O between/O 1936/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O and/O 1943/O ,/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O you/O did/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O it/O was/O then/O known/O ,/O in/O April/O or/O May/O of/O 1945/O ,/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4251/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O you/O are/O at/O liberty/O to/O make/O any/O statement/O that/O you/O desire/O to/O the/O committee/O regarding/O your/O alleged/O participation/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O or/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O until/O 1944/O ,/O the/O words/O '/O ``/O Communist/O ''/O and/O ``/O communism/O ''/O had/O absolutely/O no/O meaning/O to/O me/O ,/O save/O that/O I/O knew/O them/O as/O any/O layman/O ,/O but/O was/O completely/O disinterested/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O always/O ,/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O been/O connected/O with/O the/O New/O Deal/O and/O with/O the/O liberal/O policies/O of/O President/O Roosevelt/PERSON ,/O and/O upon/O his/O death/O Mr./O Stanley/PERSON Roberts/PERSON and/O I/O ,/O wishing/O some/O participation/O in/O what/O we/O con/O -/O sidered/O the/O liberal/O cause/O ,/O accepted/O what/O was/O told/O to/O us/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION and/O joined/O ,/O after/O the/O death/O of/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON ./O 
I/O joined/O believing/O what/O I/O had/O been/O told/O ,/O what/O I/O had/O been/O told/O by/O Mr./O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ,/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O Dalton/PERSON Trumbo/PERSON ,/O Henry/PERSON Myers/PERSON ./O 
These/O four/O gentlemen/O had/O ,/O previous/O to/O April/O 1945/O ,/O at/O various/O times/O talked/O to/O me/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O knew/O me/O to/O be/O a/O follower/O of/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O policies/O ,/O and/O they/O kept/O explaining/O to/O me/O how/O the/O CPA/O had/O backed/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON in/O the/O last/O election/O ./O 
They/O pointed/O out/O to/O me/O that/O the/O association/O had/O no/O candidate/O of/O its/O own/O ,/O since/O it/O was/O not/O a/O political/O party/O ./O 
They/O emphasized/O that/O the/O association/O believed/O in/O gradual/O social/O change/O and/O was/O working/O and/O would/O continue/O to/O work/O within/O the/O framework/O of/O the/O existing/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O Roberts/PERSON and/O I/O kept/O discussing/O the/O pros/O and/O cons/O of/O joining/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O only/O with/O the/O shock/O of/O President/O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O death/O in/O April/O 1945/O that/O he/O and/O I/O agreed/O that/O the/O CPA/O was/O a/O group/O where/O we/O could/O best/O function/O as/O liberals/O ./O 
I/O got/O in/O touch/O with/O Mr./O Maltz/PERSON ,/O who/O arranged/O for/O me/O to/O attend/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O Mr./O Roberts/PERSON and/O I/O joined/O at/O approximately/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O interrupt/O you/O there/O ./O 
How/O long/O had/O you/O known/O Mr./O Maltz/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Mr./O Maltz/PERSON ,/O I/O had/O known/O personally/O since/O the/O Yale/ORGANIZATION Drama/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O he/O had/O been/O a/O fellow/O student/O ,/O but/O I/O had/O not/O seen/O him/O until/O the/O fall/O of/O 1944/O ./O 
I/O had/O not/O seen/O him/O at/O all/O ./O 
And/O because/O we/O were/O both/O screen/O writers/O ,/O I/O met/O him/O at/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O subsequently/O was/O invited/O to/O his/O house/O ,/O where/O he/O then/O began/O to/O talk/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O the/O conversations/O that/O you/O had/O with/O Mr./O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Dalton/PERSON Trumbo/PERSON ,/O Mr./O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O and/O Mr./O Henry/PERSON Myers/PERSON ,/O were/O those/O discussions/O of/O a/O character/O which/O were/O designed/O to/O induce/O you/O to/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O solicit/O your/O membership/O ,/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O conversation/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O took/O ,/O you/O see/O ,/O from/O the/O early/O fall/O of/O 1944/O until/O April/O 1945/O for/O me/O to/O be/O convinced/O ./O 
They/O emphasized/O the/O way/O in/O which-how/O the/O association/O had/O a/O program/O of/O gradual/O political/O change/O ./O 
And/O since/O in/O Washington/LOCATION I/O had/O been/O a/O stanch/O follower/O of/O the/O liberal/O doctrines/O of/O the/O administration/O ,/O and/O here/O I/O was/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION with/O no/O activity/O ,/O I/O finally/O believed/O them/O ./O 
4252/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O the/O time/O of/O your/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O or/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ,/O had/O you/O united/O with/O organizations/O which/O you/O later/O found/O out/O were/O Communist-front/O organizations/O '/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Two/O organizations/O ./O 
When/O I/O arrived/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O automatically/O ,/O and/O almost/O the/O entire/O membership/O of/O the/O guild/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O in/O the/O war/O years/O ,/O almost/O the/O entire/O membership/O ,/O with/O other/O guilds/O and/O unions/O ,/O belonged/O to/O what/O was/O called/O the/O Hollywood/O Mobilization/O ./O 
This/O was/O the/O joining/O of/O these/O unions/O and/O guilds/O to/O work/O for/O the/O war/O effort/O ./O 
I/O joined/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O I/O wrote/O probably/O a/O half/O dozen/O Red/ORGANIZATION Cross/ORGANIZATION ./O 
radio/O messages/O and/O a/O few/O skits/O for/O the/O USO/O ./O 
That/O was/O my/O participation/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEAXER/PERSON ./O 
In/O referring/O to/O the/O Hollywood/O Mobilization/O ,/O did/O you/O mean/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
And/O at/O that/O time/O thousands/O of/O writers/O ,/O directors/O ,/O and/O technicians/O belonged/O ./O 
The/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O was/O part/O of/O the/O larger/O Hollywood/LOCATION Mobilization/LOCATION ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
And/O with/O hindsight/O it/O now/O becomes/O clear/O ,/O when/O you/O read/O the/O names/O of/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O guild/O at/O that/O time/O and/O the/O leaders/O of/O the/O mobilization/O ,/O Lawson/PERSON ,/O Maltz/PERSON ,/O that/O it/O was/O a/O front/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O League/O of/O Amer/PERSON -/O ican/O Writers/O for/O approximately/O 6/O months/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O the/O fall/O of/O 1938/O ,/O or/O perhaps/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1939/O ./O 
Somewhere/O in/O 1939/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O still/O here/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O I/O sent/O a/O letter/O of/O resignation/O and/O resigned/O from/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O because/O I/O was/O incensed/O by/O the/O attack/O of/O the/O U./PERSON S./PERSON S./PERSON R./PERSON on/O Finland/LOCATION ./O 
At/O that/O time/O ,/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O sent/O me/O some/O kind/O of/O document/O standing/O by/O the/O position/O that/O it/O was/O not/O an/O invasion/O ,/O and/O I/O sent/O such/O a/O letter/O of/O resignation/O to/O the/O league/O in/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O was/O the/O national/O president/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O name/O of/O any/O official/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O to/O whom/O you/O addressed/O your/O letter/O of/O resignation/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O am/O positive/O that/O all/O I/O did/O was/O send/O the/O letter/O to/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O receive/O an/O acknowledgment/O of/O your/O resig/O -/O nation/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O remember/O having/O received/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
That/O was/O the/O second/O front/O organization/O ,/O or/O I/O believe/O it/O to/O have/O been/O a/O front/O organization/O ./O 
It/O was/O n't/O an/O organization/O that/O you/O joined/O ./O 
It/O was/O merely/O ,/O if/O I/O remember/O ,/O a/O week/O of/O seminars/O on/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O which/O technicians/O in/O all/O media/O of/O communication/O gave/O lectures/O ./O 
And/O I/O was/O asked-I/O can/O not/O remember/O by/O whom/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O asked-if/O I/O would/O one/O afternoon/O give/O a/O lecture/O with/O Norman/PERSON Corwin/PERSON and/O Arch/PERSON Oboler/PERSON COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4253/O on/O documentary/O radio/O ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O my/O one/O and/O only/O participation/O in/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Again/O ,/O with/O hindsight/O ,/O I/O am/O positive/O that/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O Communist/O front/O ,/O and/O that/O my/O name/O and/O my/O reputation/O were/O being/O used/O with/O those/O of/O other/O liberals/O as/O come-ons/O ./O 
And/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O it/O was/O just/O one/O afternoon/O that/O I/O spoke/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENIER/PERSON ./O 
And/O that/O was/O before/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O ,/O sir/O ;/O by/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O this/O Congress/O was/O conducted/O by/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O swear/O to/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O ./O 
At/O least/O ,/O remembering/O back/O there/O ,/O I/O believe/O that/O there/O was/O some/O linkage/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O recollection/O at/O all/O of/O how/O your/O participation/O in/O the/O program/O was/O solicited/O and/O obtained/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Oboler/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Corwin/PERSON ,/O and/O myself/O ,/O and/O others/O ,/O being/O notified/O of/O the/O hour/O and/O the/O afternoon/O that/O we/O were/O to/O speak-and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O who/O it/O was/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O that/O whoever/O it/O was/O ,/O if/O I/O knew/O the/O person/O ,/O I/O would/O remember/O ./O 
It/O might/O easily/O have/O been/O someone/O from/O the/O mobilization/O ,/O since/O it/O was/O the/O same/O period/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
It/O was/O 1943/O ,/O if/O I/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
NOW/O ,/O what/O other/O front/O organizations/O did/O you/O join/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
The/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ./O 
Those/O three/O ./O 
And/O I/O am/O not/O at/O all/O certain/O that/O I/O ever/O joined/O the/O Hollywood/O IndependentMr/O ./O 
BEALE/PERSON ./O 
-/O Citizens/O '/O Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O attended/O two/O meetings/O in/O 1948/O ,/O and/O I/O remember/O giving/O a/O check/O for/O $/O 10/O at/O the/O Hotel/ORGANIZATION Roosevelt/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O that/O was/O my/O entire/O extent/O of/O activity/O in/O HICCASP/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O am/O certain/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O roster/O of/O names/O which/O since/O have/O come/O out/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O must/O have/O been/O a/O Communist/O front/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O affiliate/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION AntiNazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O there/O any/O other/O organizations/O which/O you/O have/O reason/O to/O believe/O were/O Communist-front/O organizations/O ,/O which/O you/O joined/O prior/O to/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
One/O ,/O sir/O ,/O which/O I/O remember/O ./O 
I/O was/O asked/O for/O the/O People/O 's/O -/O ca/O n't/O remember/O the/O name-School/O ./O 
Mr./O BEALE/PERSON ./O 
People/O 's/O Educational/O Center/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right-to/O give/O in/O the/O same/O year/O a/O course/O in/O radio/O ,/O war/O radio/O ,/O documentary/O radio/O ,/O which/O once/O a/O week/O I/O did/O for/O a/O half/O dozen/O times/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O the/O last/O I/O ever/O had/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O it/O ./O 
That/O was/O not/O an/O organization/O ,/O ./O 
but/O ,/O looking/O back/O again/O over/O the/O same/O names/O ,/O the/O constant/O repetition/O of/O names/O ,/O Lawson/PERSON ,/O Maltz/PERSON ,/O Dalton/PERSON TrumboThat/PERSON was/O some/O girl/O in/O the/O guild/O who/O asked/O me/O to/O teach/O there/O ./O 
And/O when/O I/O had/O arrived/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O I/O knew/O no/O one/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O alone/O ,/O and/O I/O wanted/O to/O help/O as/O I/O had/O helped/O in/O Washington/LOCATION with/O the/O war/O effort/O ./O 
21546-52-pt/O ./O 
9-2/O 4254/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O In/O all/O this/O speaking/O at/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Mobilization/ORGANIZATION and/O lectures/O on/O radio/O ,/O there/O seemed/O to/O me/O to/O be/O the/O ways/O by/O which/O I/O could/O help/O the/O war/O effort/O ./O 
But/O at/O that/O time/O I/O had/O no/O thought/O of/O or/O identification/O with/O or/O really/O understanding/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O interrupted/O you/O ./O 
You/O were/O telling/O the/O committee/O of/O your/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION in/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O tell/O the/O committee/O just/O what/O your/O experience/O was/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O you/O met/O ,/O the/O names/O of/O persons/O who/O met/O with/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O at/O the/O meetings/O which/O I/O subsequently/O attended/O ,/O I/O met/O the/O following/O members/O ./O 
I/O have/O them/O written/O down/O here/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O read/O them/O :/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON ,/O U-r-i-s/O ,/O Dorothy/PERSON Tree/PERSON ,/O T-r-e-e/O ,/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON ,/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O Tanya/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON ,/O H-u-e-b-s-c-h/O ,/O Bernard/PERSON Vorhaus/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Vorhaus/PERSON ,/O Vo-r-h-a-u-s/O ,/O Stanley/PERSON Roberts/PERSON ,/O Herbert/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ,/O Michael/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ,/O Paul/PERSON Trivers/PERSON ,/O Jane/PERSON Trivers/PERSON ,/O Meta/PERSON Reis/PERSON ,/O M-e-t-a/O R-e-i-s/O ,/O Hetty/PERSON Vorhaus/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
H-e-t-t-y/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Jack/PERSON Berry/PERSON ,/O Gale/PERSON Sondergaard/PERSON ,/O Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON ./O 
Between/O the/O time/O I/O joined/O ,/O in/O April/O or/O May/O 1945/O ,/O and/O October/O 1945/O ,/O I/O attended/O no/O more/O than/O a/O dozen/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O took/O no/O political/O assignments/O ./O 
At/O those/O meetings/O there/O were/O discussions/O mostly/O about/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O sit/O and/O listen/O ,/O and/O was/O a/O passive/O member/O ,/O inasmuch/O as/O I/O was/O given/O no/O political/O assignments/O of/O any/O kind/O ./O 
I/O attended/O no/O fraction/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O paid/O only/O the/O basic/O dues/O ./O 
And/O I/O refused/O even/O to/O be/O assessed/O according/O to/O salary/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O in/O October/O 1945/O ,/O I/O left/O for/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O remained/O there/O a/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O just/O at/O that/O point/O :/O Where/O was/O your/O meeting/O place/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O meeting/O that/O I/O ever/O attended/O ,/O in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1945/O ,/O was/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O geographically/O ,/O the/O meetings/O were/O held/O in/O homes/O adjacent/O to/O or/O around/O that/O district/O ,/O where/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON lived/O ,/O and/O those/O homes/O belonged/O to/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON ,/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O Herbert/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ,/O Jack/PERSON Berry/PERSON ,/O Paul/PERSON Trivers/PERSON ,/O and/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O meet/O in/O the/O homes/O of/O each/O of/O those/O persons/O whose/O names/O you/O have/O just/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O by/O that/O statement/O also/O to/O say/O that/O each/O of/O those/O persons/O were/O members/O of/O your/O group/O or/O unit/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O these/O meetings/O to/O which/O you/O referred/O :/O Were/O they/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4255/O Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O they/O never/O mentioned/O ,/O until/O 1947/O ,/O I/O think/O -/O they/O always/O spoke/O of/O the/O association/O ,/O but/O they/O were/O definitely/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O ,/O each/O and/O every/O one/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
YOU/O state/O that/O at/O those/O meetings/O they/O discussed/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O ./O 
Will/O you/O define/O that/O a/O little/O more/O ?/O 
In/O what/O direction/O was/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O being/O aimed/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Mr./O Roberts/PERSON and/O I/O used/O to/O fight/O constantly/O on/O this/O ,/O because/O it/O was/O obvious/O after/O the/O first/O half/O dozen/O meetings/O that/O we/O attended/O that/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O was/O to/O obey/O whatever/O the/O party/O told/O you/O to/O do/O as/O a/O writer/O ./O 
You/O were/O supposed/O to/O have/O no/O creative/O thoughts/O of/O your/O own/O ./O 
You/O were/O supposed/O to/O use/O your/O talent/O for/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O ,/O a/O strike/O ./O 
If/O there/O was/O a/O strike/O ,/O you/O were/O told/O to/O write/O something/O pro/O or/O con/O ,/O whatever/O the/O party/O position/O was/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O the/O individuality/O of/O the/O creative/O writer/O was/O to/O be/O stamped/O on/O ,/O and/O your/O own/O individual/O position/O was/O never/O taken/O into/O account/O ./O 
And/O this/O was/O always/O discussed/O in/O rather/O abstract/O terms/O ,/O too/O ,/O because/O they/O gave/O you/O pamphlets/O to/O read/O ./O 
And/O not/O being/O very/O talented/O in/O political/O science/O or/O in/O economics/O ,/O I/O could/O n't/O make/O them/O out/O ,/O and/O from/O the/O very/O begin/O -/O ning/O I/O would/O be/O rebuked/O for/O my/O inability/O to/O read/O or/O comprehend/O the/O material/O that/O they/O gave/O me/O to/O read/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O a/O group/O which/O never/O concretely/O told/O me/O to/O write/O anything/O ,/O but/O would/O discuss/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O over/O and/O over/O again/O until/O ,/O frankly/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O devil/O they/O were/O driving/O at/O ,/O because/O they/O would/O never/O pin/O it/O down/O except/O philosophically/O ./O 
It/O was/O intellectualized/O constantly/O ./O 
I/O had/O joined/O thinking/O that/O there/O would/O be/O concrete/O liberal/O activities/O which/O ,/O as/O a/O creative/O writer/O I/O could/O help/O ,/O even/O as/O I/O had/O in/O war/O work/O ./O 
I/O thought/O there/O would/O be/O work/O for/O me/O to/O do/O ./O 
And/O they/O did/O nothing/O except/O sit/O and/O discuss/O pamphlets/O on/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O constantly/O ,/O these/O first/O 12/O meetings/O ,/O before/O I/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O consider/O that/O the/O way/O in/O which/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O was/O discussed/O and/O taught/O was/O an/O effort/O to/O influence/O you/O in/O your/O thinking/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O certainly/O did/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O gradual/O disillusionment/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O and/O a/O gradual/O technique/O of/O superimposing/O a/O whole/O philosophy/O and/O a/O whole/O ideology/O on/O the/O individual/O member/O ,/O so/O that/O whatever/O he/O thinks/O gradually/O works/O in/O a/O vacuum/O and/O no/O longer/O obtains/O ,/O so/O that/O he/O has/O no/O longer/O any/O ideas/O of/O his/O own/O ./O 
And/O this/O I/O kept/O sensing/O ,/O and/O hoping/O that/O it/O was/O not/O so/O ./O 
Because/O ,/O having/O made/O this/O step/O ,/O idealistically/O ,/O and/O believing/O that/O the/O association/O was/O following/O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O policies/O ,/O and/O since/O they/O were/O very/O smart/O and/O used/O many/O of/O the/O liberal/O phrases/O ,/O and/O spoke/O of/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON for/O quite/O a/O while/O ,/O I/O kept/O giving/O them/O that/O second/O chance/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O through/O its/O efforts/O in/O these/O meetings/O ,/O could/O be/O successful/O in/O influencing/O the/O screen/O writers/O in/O their/O thinking/O ,/O that/O would/O be/O the/O best/O way/O to/O influence/O the/O context/O of/O films/O ,/O would/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O it/O could/O be/O done/O ,/O sir/O ,/O for/O two/O reasons/O ./O 
One/O ,/O the/O vast/O majority/O of/O screen/O writers/O are/O highly/O individual/O ,/O and/O most/O of/O the/O ones/O I/O know/O ,/O including/O myself/O ,/O have/O always/O wanted/O to/O think/O for/O themselves/O And/O the/O second/O reason/O is/O that/O the/O way/O the/O ¥/O -LSB-/O ./O 
4256/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O motion-picture/O industry/O is/O organized/O ,/O there/O would/O be/O too/O many/O factors/O which/O would/O not/O allow/O this/O material/O to/O be/O infiltrated/O into/O a/O movie/O ./O 
I/O myself/O ,/O in/O these/O groups/O ,/O never/O heard/O discussed/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O the/O way/O in/O which/O the/O party/O could/O take/O over/O the/O ideology/O of/O the/O industry/O ./O 
This/O I/O never/O did/O hear/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O if/O they/O were/O successful/O in/O influencing/O the/O thinking/O of/O some/O of/O the/O individuals/O ,/O that/O naturally/O would/O affect/O their/O writings/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O although/O the/O Communist/O Party/O could/O not/O ,/O be/O -/O cause/O of/O the/O mechanical/O difficulties/O and/O because/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O many/O of/O you/O were/O independent/O in/O your/O thinking/O ,/O succeed/O in/O actually/O producing/O a/O Communist/O film/O ,/O yet/O if/O they/O influenced/O the/O writer/O 's/O thinking/O they/O could/O influence/O the/O content/O of/O his/O work/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O bound/O to/O influence/O the/O content/O of/O his/O work/O ,/O would/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFEID/O That/O is/O true/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O did/O you/O observe/O anything/O of/O the/O same/O character/O in/O the/O work/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ?/O 
no/O ,/O s/O ,/O ir/O ./O 
Because/O I/O never/O attended/O any/O Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
We/O meetings/O ./O 
It/O was/O while/O I/O was/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O merely/O a/O paidup/O member/O ;/O that/O is/O all/O ;/O and/O never/O attended/O any/O meetings/O or/O knew/O anyone/O here/O who/O at/O all/O belonged/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O activity/O whatsoever/O in/O that/O league/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O indicated/O a/O resentment/O toward/O the/O effort/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O influence/O the/O way/O in/O which/O you/O would/O carry/O out/O the/O work/O of/O your/O own/O profession/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O in/O mind/O any/O particular/O instances/O in/O which/O either/O you/O or/O other/O members/O of/O your/O profession/O were/O influenced/O or/O attempted/O to/O be/O influenced/O in/O any/O particular/O way/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFEJl/O -RRB-/O ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O any/O specific/O illustration/O of/O it/O ;/O merely/O ,/O as/O you/O said/O ,/O sir/O ,/O the/O hope/O that/O from/O these/O discussions/O their/O philosophy/O would/O so/O be/O superimposed/O on/O yours/O that/O automatically/O ,/O I/O presume/O ,/O as/O you/O wrote/O you/O would/O orient/O yourself/O in/O this/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O telling/O the/O committee/O that/O you/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O in/O October/O 1945/O I/O left/O for/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION and/O I/O remained/O there/O a/O year/O ./O 
I/O had/O not/O asked/O for/O a/O transfer/O ./O 
I/O paid/O no/O dues/O while/O I/O was/O in/O INew/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O no/O contract/O whatsoever/O with/O the/O association/O ,/O personally/O or/O by/O mail/O ./O 
I/O saw/O no/O association/O members/O while/O I/O was/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O working/O on/O a/O play/O during/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O no/O political/O activity/O of/O any/O kind/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O October/O 1946/O ,/O and/O between/O October/O 1946/O and/O the/O spring/O of/O 1947/O ,/O I/O attended/O ,/O oh/O ,/O at/O most/O I/O should/O say/O five/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O political/O activity/O within/O the/O group/O ,/O and/O continued/O to/O just/O remain/O a/O passive/O member/O ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O that/O these/O meetings/O pertained/O to/O the/O breaking/O off/O ,/O the/O change/O ,/O from/O the/O association/O into/O the/O party/O again/O ,/O the/O DuclosBrowder/O conflict/O ./O 
And/O this/O was/O the/O beginning/O of/O the/O straw/O that/O broke/O the/O camel/O 's/O back/O as/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O ,/O because/O I/O ,/O from/O the/O very/O beginning/O ,/O championed/O Browder/PERSON 's/O attempts/O at/O collective/O security/O ,/O the/O way/O he/O had/O identified/O with/O what/O I/O thought/O was/O a/O philosophy/O of/O gradual/O social/O change/O ,/O the/O united/O front/O ,/O and/O I/O remember/O Mr./O Biberman/PERSON and/O Mr./O Butler/PERSON attacking/O Browder/PERSON as/O the/O party/O chief/O ./O 
And/O I/O became/O con/O -/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4257/O fused/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O argued/O the/O point/O and/O again/O was/O rebuked/O ./O 
I/O talked/O with/O Mr./O Roberts/PERSON constantly/O about/O this/O new/O step/O ;/O because/O we/O had/O felt/O that/O Browder/PERSON had/O tried/O to/O continue/O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O liberalism/O ./O 
And/O since/O this/O had/O been/O the/O reason/O ,/O the/O continuance/O of/O liberal/O ideals/O ,/O that/O we/O had/O joined/O in/O the/O first/O place/O ,/O we/O were/O pretty/O upset/O by/O now/O ./O 
It/O was/O either/O the/O second/O or/O third/O meeting/O when/O once/O more/O I/O was/O given/O pamphlets/O to/O read/O ./O 
I/O remember/O one/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O was/O by/O Duclos/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O there/O was/O one/O by/O Foster/PERSON and/O one/O by/O Stalin/PERSON ./O 
And/O again/O ,/O I/O went/O home/O and/O tried/O to/O read/O them/O ,/O and/O came/O back/O ,/O and/O they/O asked/O questions/O ,/O as/O one/O would/O do/O to/O a/O pupil/O in/O school/O ,/O and/O must/O have/O considered/O me/O an/O idiot/O ,/O because/O they/O rebuked/O me/O for/O my/O inability/O to/O have/O comprehended/O them/O ./O 
They/O were/O statistical/O in/O nature/O ,/O and/O dealt/O with/O political/O science/O ./O 
And/O they/O tried/O to/O make/O me/O once/O more/O agree/O that/O Browder/PERSON ,/O in/O some/O way/O ,/O had/O committed/O some/O kind/O of/O a/O sin/O ,/O and/O I/O fought/O them/O on/O that/O ./O 
And/O ,/O oh/O ,/O weeks/O and/O weeks/O went/O by/O before/O I/O attended/O the/O last/O meeting/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O spring/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
And/O by/O that/O time/O I/O was/O pretty/O disillusioned/O and/O disgusted/O with/O what/O had/O occurred/O ./O 
And/O in/O May/O ,/O I/O left/O Hollywood/LOCATION again/O ,/O to/O travel/O through/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION Northwest/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O did/O ,/O and/O returned/O in/O the/O last/O part/O of/O September/O or/O the/O beginning/O of/O October/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
I/O was/O pretty/O convinced/O by/O this/O time/O that/O there/O was/O nothing/O any/O longer/O that/O I/O could/O identify/O with/O ,/O nothing/O that/O I/O believed/O that/O they/O were/O telling/O me/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O it/O was/O Mr./O Huebsch/PERSON who/O called/O me/O up/O ,/O hearing/O I/O was/O back/O in/O town/O ,/O and/O I/O attended/O one/O meeting/O ./O 
This/O was/O my/O last/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O interrupt/O you/O at/O that/O point/O ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O refused/O to/O pay/O assessments/O ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O more/O about/O that/O ?/O 
What/O effort/O was/O made/O to/O have/O you/O pay/O assessments/O ,/O and/O what/O assessments/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O the/O percentages/O ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O ,/O however/O ,/O that/O where/O I/O believe/O the/O basic/O dues/O were/O $/O 2/O ,/O they/O would/O want/O a/O portion/O of/O my/O salary/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O what/O portion/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O percentage/O ./O 
Because/O I/O was/O adamant/O about/O it/O ,/O and/O merely/O paid/O the/O basic/O dues/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O in/O and/O out/O of/O town/O and/O so/O seldom/O in/O studios/O by/O this/O time/O working/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O attempted/O to/O collect/O assessments/O from/O you/O Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Huebsch/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O remember/O Tanya/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON and/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O those/O three/O kept/O the/O moneybags/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
To/O whom/O did/O you/O pay/O your/O dues/O ,/O your/O $/O 2/O dues/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
have/O been/O ./O 
The/O treasurer/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O who/O these/O three/O must/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O discussions/O that/O took/O place/O ,/O who/O were/O the/O leaders/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Herbert/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ,/O certainly/O ,/O I/O would/O call/O the/O discussion/O leader/O ./O 
After/O that/O ,/O I/O suppose/O Paul/PERSON Trivers/PERSON would/O be/O the/O next/O most/O vocal/O member/O of/O the/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O literature/O was/O given/O you/O to/O read/O at/O the/O time/O that/O the/O role/O of/O the/O cultural/O worker/O was/O being/O discussed/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
4258/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O remember/O what/O type/O of/O literature/O it/O was/O ,/O or/O the/O names/O of/O the/O pamphlets/O that/O were/O given/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCIIOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O who/O wrote/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O remember/O a/O pamphlet/O just/O called/O the/O Role/O of/O the/O Cultural/O Worker/O ./O 
That/O I/O remember/O ./O 
And/O I/O remember/O a/O pamphlet/O by/O Gorki/PERSON on/O writing/O ,/O one/O by/O Browder/PERSON ,/O and/O ,/O yes/O ,/O one/O by-am/O I/O correct-Magil/O ./O 
Mr./O BEALE/PERSON ./O 
A./PERSON B./PERSON Magil/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCIIOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
And/O is/O that/O the/O same/O as/O V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BEALE/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Because/O there/O was/O one/O by/O that/O gentleman/O ,/O too/O ./O 
I/O remember/O those/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O representatives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION from/O higher/O levels/O meeting/O with/O your/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O how/O your/O particular/O group/O or/O cell/O of/O the/O party/O received/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION instructions/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O heard/O of/O fraction/O meetings/O ,/O but/O never/O attended/O any/O ./O 
Lawson/PERSON 's/O name/O was/O constantly/O being/O mentioned/O ./O 
It/O was/O he/O who/O I/O always/O assumed/O was/O the/O spearhead/O ./O 
Because/O whenever/O any/O point/O of/O discussion/O between/O Biberman/PERSON and/O Trivers/PERSON or/O Michael/PERSON Wilson/PERSON came/O up/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O ,/O ``/O Let/O 's/O see/O Jack/PERSON ./O ''/O 
So/O I/O presume/O that/O Mr./O Lawson/PERSON at/O that/O time/O must/O have/O been/O the/O spearhead/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O if/O you/O will/O return/O to/O your/O narrative/O statement/O ,/O you/O stated/O that/O you/O returned/O in/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
From/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION area/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
And/O I/O attended/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O one/O meeting/O ,/O and/O one/O last/O meeting/O ./O 
And/O I/O remember/O being/O surprised/O ,/O because/O ,/O having/O been/O away/O all/O this/O time/O again/O ,/O instead/O of/O the/O large/O group/O there/O were/O only/O five/O or/O six/O members/O present/O ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O I/O know/O ,/O that/O Michael/PERSON Wilson/PERSON was/O there/O ,/O Jack/PERSON Berry/PERSON ,/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON ,/O Dick/PERSON Collins-Richard/PERSON Collins-and/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O so/O was/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O it/O was/O held/O at/O the/O Jack/PERSON Berry/PERSON home/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O rebuked/O again/O for/O having/O gone/O away/O and/O written/O on/O things/O that/O I/O wanted/O to/O write/O on/O ,/O not/O having/O stayed/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O paid/O little/O attention/O to/O that/O before/O the/O meeting/O began/O ./O 
And/O there/O was/O a/O blast/O at/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O remember/O that/O ./O 
And/O the/O Marshall/PERSON plan/O ./O 
And/O throughout/O the/O meeting/O ,/O I/O sat/O silently/O and/O disgusted/O ,/O until/O the/O meeting/O was/O over/O ,/O and/O then/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON came/O over/O to/O me/O and/O asked/O me/O why/O I/O had/O been/O away/O ,/O and/O I/O told/O him/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O was/O rebuked/O because/O I/O had/O been/O delinquent/O in/O dues/O while/O I/O was/O gone/O ,/O and/O I/O told/O them/O I/O was/O n't/O paying/O any/O ,/O and/O I/O also/O told/O them/O that/O I/O was/O planning/O to/O move/O to/O the/O beach/O to/O write/O a/O novel/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O was/O not/O going/O to/O attend/O any/O more/O meetings/O ;/O that/O I/O felt/O that/O the/O time/O had/O come/O when/O what/O they/O believed/O in/O and/O what/O I/O believed/O in/O were/O mutually/O exclusive/O by/O now/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O over/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O ./O 
I/O did/O move/O to/O the/O beach/O in/O May/O in/O 1948/O ,/O and/O in/O those/O months/O in/O between/O I/O would/O get/O phone/O calls/O by/O unfamiliar/O voices/O ,/O contact/O voices/O ,/O I/O would/O suppose/O you/O would/O call/O them/O ,/O to/O come/O to/O meetings/O ,/O and/O ``/O What/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4259/O was/O the/O matter/O ?/O ''/O 
And/O I/O would/O say/O I/O had/O told/O Mr./O Huebsch/PERSON I/O did/O not/O intend/O coming/O to/O any/O more/O ./O 
And/O I/O did/O n't/O do/O so/O ./O 
I/O moved/O to/O the/O beach/O to/O write/O my/O novel/O ,/O and/O some/O time/O in/O the/O spring/O ,/O not/O too/O long/O after/O I/O had/O moved/O to/O the/O beach/O ,/O someone/O whose/O name/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O is/O the/O son-in-law/O of/O a/O writer/O called/O Sonya/PERSON Levine-I/PERSON do/O n't/O know/O his/O name/O ,/O and/O I/O may/O even/O be/O wrong/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O that/O is/O who/O it/O was-visited/O me/O at/O the/O beach/O and/O asked/O me/O why/O I/O had/O n't/O attended/O meetings/O ./O 
Once/O more/O I/O repeated/O that/O I/O had/O no/O intention/O of/O doing/O so/O ./O 
He/O asked/O me/O for/O back/O dues/O ./O 
I/O refused/O ./O 
I/O remember/O he/O asked/O me/O for/O a/O check/O for/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O ./O 
I/O refused/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O told/O him/O I/O was/O no/O longer/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O that/O my/O novel/O was/O going/O to/O take/O up/O all/O my/O time/O ,/O that/O I/O was/O completely/O against/O what/O the/O party/O now/O stood/O for/O ./O 
And/O he/O argued/O ,/O and/O he/O got/O nowhere/O ,/O and/O he/O left/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O my/O last/O contact/O with/O any/O member/O of/O the/O association/O or/O party/O ,/O in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O this/O cell/O or/O group/O have/O a/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O had/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O never/O heard/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O it/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O were/O reprimanded/O for/O writing/O things/O that/O you/O wanted/O to/O write/O about/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O if/O I/O wanted/O to/O write/O of/O anything/O that/O had/O no/O what/O they/O loved/O to/O call/O ``/O social/O content/O ./O ''/O 
And/O a/O writer/O would/O like/O to/O write/O about/O ,/O oh/O ,/O almost/O anything/O ,/O whether/O it/O is/O a/O story/O about/O marriage/O or/O a/O story/O about/O a/O dog/O or/O anything/O else/O ./O 
But/O it/O was/O always/O :/O ``/O You/O are/O wasting/O your/O time/O ./O 
You/O should/O be/O writing/O as/O a/O cultural/O worker/O ./O 
You/O should/O be/O writing/O ''/O '/O -/O what/O they/O would/O suggest/O you/O write/O ./O 
And/O they/O would/O criticize/O very/O often/O at/O meetings/O those/O well-known/O writers/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O who/O at/O one/O time/O had/O written/O of/O social/O change/O and/O now/O were/O doing/O so/O no/O longer/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
And/O any/O creative/O artist/O worth/O his/O salt/O ca/O n't/O put/O up/O with/O this/O kind/O of/O superimposition/O very/O long/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O reply/O did/O you/O receive/O ,/O or/O what/O reaction/O did/O you/O receive/O ,/O when/O you/O advised/O Ed/PERSON Huehsch/PERSON that/O you/O would/O discon/O -/O tinue/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O spent/O about/O 10/O to/O 15/O minutes/O after/O that/O last/O meeting/O was/O over/O trying/O to/O give/O me/O every/O intellectual/O reason/O why/O I/O should/O n't/O ,/O and/O said/O that/O he/O would/O meet/O with/O me/O ./O 
I/O told/O him/O it/O would/O n't/O do/O any/O good/O ,/O and/O he/O never/O did/O ./O 
All/O I/O got/O were/O the/O telephone/O calls/O ./O 
And/O then/O this/O chap/O who/O came/O down/O to/O the/O beach/O tried/O to/O argue/O ;/O never/O on/O an/O emotional/O level/O ,/O always/O on/O a/O kind/O of-I/O do/O n't/O know/O why/O ,/O a/O high/O intellectual/O and/O philosophical/O line/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O your/O name/O appeared/O in/O the/O amicus/O curiae/O of/O the/O brief/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O Dalton/PERSON Trumbo/PERSON case/O ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O your/O name/O was/O used/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O went/O to/O a/O guild/O meeting/O ,/O and/O I/O learned/O that/O Judge/O Arnold/PERSON had/O been/O hired/O to/O represent/O the/O guild/O itself/O as/O a/O friend/O of/O the/O court/O ./O 
And/O since/O the/O guild/O itself/O appeared/O as/O amicus/O curiae/O ,/O I/O saw/O no/O reason/O for/O not/O signing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Committee/O for/O the/O First/O Amendment/O ?/O 
4260/O COlMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
One/O night/O ,/O I/O think/O in/O 1947/O ,/O I/O joined/O some/O writers/O and/O helped/O prepare/O a/O coast-to-coast/O broadcast/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O whose/O solicitation/O did/O you/O join/O in/O that/O effort/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
I/O think-I/O am/O not/O sure/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O it/O was/O at/O the/O solicitation/O of/O Millard/PERSON Lampell/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O take/O part/O in/O the/O work/O of/O the/O Stockholm/LOCATION peace/O petition/O drive/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O did/O not/O ,/O nor/O did/O I/O sign/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENINER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Waldorf/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
1/O Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O it/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O there/O anything/O else/O that/O you/O wish/O to/O advise/O the/O committee/O or/O that/O you/O can/O advise/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHOENFELD/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Since/O 1948/O ,/O I/O have/O actively/O done/O nothing/O except/O use/O my/O time/O and/O energy/O for/O creative/O writing/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O repudiated/O the/O party/O ,/O because/O I/O want/O to/O remain/O an/O individual/O in/O the/O meaning/O that/O that/O word/O has/O attained/O in/O a/O democracy/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O recommend/O that/O the/O Communist/O Party/O be/O outlawed/O and/O also/O that/O in/O order/O to/O keep/O liberals/O and/O people/O of/O good/O will/O from/O having/O my/O experience/O ,/O a/O greater/O and/O greater/O vigilance/O be/O made/O in/O finding/O out/O what/O Communist-front/O organizations/O still/O exist/O and/O publicizing/O such/O Communist-front/O organizations/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O I/O personally/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O sure/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O who/O are/O not/O present/O here/O now/O ,/O join/O in/O these/O sentiments/O :/O We/O are/O very/O grateful/O to/O you/O for/O taking/O ad/O -/O vantage/O of/O our/O invitation/O to/O come/O here/O and/O talk/O to/O us/O out/O of/O your/O heart/O as/O you/O have/O about/O your/O experiences/O in/O this/O organization/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O very/O much/O interested/O in/O your/O reaction/O and/O particularly/O in/O your/O present/O views/O ,/O which/O ,/O in/O the/O main/O ,/O coincide/O with/O the/O recent/O practices/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
For/O the/O very/O valuable/O information/O you/O have/O given/O us/O ,/O we/O are/O also/O grateful/O ,/O as/O are/O the/O American/O people/O ./O 
Because/O ,/O after/O all/O ,/O that/O is/O what/O we/O are/O trying/O to/O do/O here/O ,/O aid/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O and/O the/O American/O Government/O and/O our/O way/O of/O life/O to/O maintain/O themselves/O and/O not/O yield/O to/O subversive/O outside/O influences/O that/O seek/O to/O destroy/O us/O ./O 
We/O appreciate/O very/O much/O your/O expression/O ,/O and/O if/O there/O are/O no/O further/O questions/O from/O counselMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O there/O are/O one/O or/O two/O questions/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O in/O executive/O session/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
We/O will/O ask/O you/O to/O remain/O for/O a/O few/O minutes/O in/O execu/O -/O tive/O session/O after/O we/O adjourn/O here/O ,/O then/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 11:40/O a./O m./O ,/O Tuesday/O ,/O August/O 19/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O the/O committee/O proceeded/O in/O executive/O session/O ./O -RRB-/O 
1Cultural/O and/O Scientific/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Peace/ORGANIZATION ,/O arranged/O by/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O ,/O and/O held/O at/O the/O Waldorf-Astoria/LOCATION Hotel/LOCATION ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O March/O 25-27/O ,/O 1949/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 9/O MONDAY/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 29/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O notice/O ,/O at/O 1/O :/O 30/O p./O m./O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O and/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON McKillips/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ;/O and/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Let/O us/O have/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O Reporter/O ,/O please/O let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O acting/O under/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O resolution/O establishing/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O UnAmerican/O Activities/O of/O the/O Seventy-ninth/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O I/O have/O set/O up/O a/O subcommittee/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O conducting/O hearings/O beginning/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION today/O and/O composed/O of/O the/O following/O members/O :/O Representatives/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O and/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O myself/O ,/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O as/O the/O chairman/O ,/O all/O of/O whom/O are/O present/O with/O the/O exception/O of/O Representative/O Velde/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O expected/O to/O arrive/O later/O in/O the/O day/O ./O 
In/O this/O connection/O ,/O I/O desire/O personally/O to/O express/O my/O very/O deep/O appreciation/O to/O these/O members/O of/O this/O committee/O who/O have/O left/O their/O respective/O districts/O in/O this/O election/O year/O where/O the/O general/O election/O is/O so/O near/O at/O hand/O ,/O to/O come/O here/O and/O aid/O in/O the/O discharge/O of/O this/O very/O important/O task/O and/O responsibility/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O placed/O upon/O us/O ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O I/O bespeak/O the/O sentiments/O of/O the/O law-abiding/O American/LOCATION citizens/O of/O this/O community/O ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O conducted/O by/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION a/O little/O more/O than/O a/O year/O ago/O in/O this/O room/O ,/O Mr./O Harold/PERSON Ashe/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O downtown/O section/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION and/O a/O State/O chairman/O of/O the/O State/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION testified/O that/O he/O convinced/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION 21546/O --/O 52-pt/O ./O 
9-3/O 4261/O 4262/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O that/O a/O professional/O unit/O of/O the/O party/O should/O be/O organized/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O Ashe/PERSON ,/O according/O to/O his/O testimony/O ,/O organized/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION unit/O ,/O known/O as/O ``/O The/O One/O Hundred/O ,/O ''/O from/O which/O another/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION unit/O designated/O ``/O The/O One/O Hundred/O Fifty/O ''/O was/O formed/O ./O 
The/O members/O of/O various/O professions/O were/O recruited/O into/O these/O professional/O tuits/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O basis/O that/O their/O identity/O would/O not/O be/O exposed/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O hearing/O is/O to/O ascertain/O whether/O this/O organizational/O work/O begun/O by/O Mr./O Ashe/PERSON has/O developed/O into/O an/O organized/O effort/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O establish/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cells/O within/O various/O professions/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION area/O ,/O the/O extent/O and/O nature/O of/O such/O alleged/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION penetration/O into/O the/O various/O professions/O ,/O and/O the/O purpose/O and/O objectives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O such/O alleged/O activities/O ./O 
Testimony/O will/O also/O be/O introduced/O at/O this/O hearing/O relating/O to/O the/O motion-picture/O and/O radio-entertainment/O field/O ./O 
Two/O public/O statements/O have/O come/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O committee/O which/O it/O is/O felt/O are/O de/O -/O serving/O of/O public/O mention/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O and/O incorporated/O into/O the/O record/O of/O this/O proceeding/O ./O 
I/O will/O read/O from/O a/O public/O release/O as/O follows/O :/O Following/O is/O an/O official/O statement/O by/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION :/O ``/O The/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION AFL/ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O composed/O of/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION unions/O and/O guilds/O representing/O more/O than/O 27,000/O workers/O in/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION motion-picture/O studios/O ,/O condemns/O in/O the/O strongest/O possible/O terms/O certain/O widely/O circulated/O statements/O by/O the/O so-called/O Citizens/O '/O Committee/O To/O Preserve/O American/O Freedoms/O and/O the/O so-called/O Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION To/O Abolish/O the/O UnAmerican/O Committee/O ./O 
``/O These/O two/O groups/O are/O attempting/O to/O fool/O the/O public/O into/O thinking/O that/O A./O F./O of/O L./O unions/O ,/O and/O specifically/O A./O F./O of/O L./O unions/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ,/O are/O supporting/O their/O attacks/O on/O the/O House/O Un-American/O Activities/O Committee/O ./O 
The/O unions/O are/O doing/O no/O such/O thing/O ./O 
These/O A./O F./O of/O L./O unions/O are/O strongly/O antiCommunist/O ./O 
``/O The/O same/O interests/O which/O try/O to/O use/O the/O name/O of/O the/O A./O F./O of/O L./O are/O planning/O a/O picket/O line/O on/O Tuesday/O ,/O September/O 30/O ,/O to/O protest/O the/O hearings/O which/O will/O be/O conducted/O at/O the/O Federal/O Building/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Un-American/O Activities/O Committee/O ./O 
The/O hearings/O seek/O to/O help/O our/O Nation/O fight/O Russian/O imperialistic/O communism/O in/O all/O its/O aspects/O ./O 
``/O No/O A./O F./O of/O L./O union/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O will/O support/O nor/O be/O represented/O in/O the/O picket/O line/O ./O 
None/O of/O our/O unions/O and/O guilds/O will/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O any/O picket/O line/O or/O any/O other/O line/O which/O seeks/O to/O undermine/O our/O America/LOCATION in/O the/O interest/O of/O Stalinist/O Russia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
I/O read/O also/O a/O statement/O made/O by/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O heading/O of/O it/O is/O ``/O Once/O and/O for/O All/O ./O ''/O 
Once/O and/O for/O all/O ,/O let/O it/O be/O made/O clear/O that/O the/O guild/O ,/O union/O ,/O and/O management/O groups/O of/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O represented/O in/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O repudiate/O any/O attacks/O upon/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O made/O by/O the/O alleged/O Citizens/O '/O Committee/O To/O Preserve/O American/O Freedoms/O or/O any/O other/O organizations/O seeking/O to/O give/O the/O impression/O ,/O directly/O or/O indirectly/O ,/O that-by/O opposing/O those/O who/O would/O expose/O Communists/O wherever/O they/O may/O be-they/O speak/O in/O behalf/O of/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ./O 
This/O so-called/O Citizens/O '/O Committee/O has/O implied/O ,/O in/O a/O trade-paper/O advertisement/O ,/O that/O it/O seeks/O Hollywood/LOCATION support/O in/O its/O attacksupon/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
We/O denounce/O the/O actions/O of/O this/O Citizens/O '/O Committee/O ./O 
We/O condemn/O its/O tactics/O ./O 
We/O repudiate/O its/O view/O ,/O as/O we/O have/O repudiated/O similar/O views/O in/O the/O past/O by/O the/O Arts/O ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O Council/O ./O 
Representing/O virtually/O all/O of/O the/O major/O guild/O ,/O union/O and/O management/O groups/O of/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O the/O MPIC/ORGANIZATION ,/O through/O them/O ,/O speaks/O for/O the/O overwhelming/O body/O of/O local/O American/LOCATION citizens/O who/O compose/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4263/O On/O March/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O the/O full/O membership/O of/O the/O MPIO/ORGANIZATION gave/O its/O unanimous/O approval/O to/O a/O statement/O which/O declared/O :/O ``/O The/O MPIC/O offers/O its/O strength/O and/O support/O to/O any/O legally/O constituted/O body/O that/O has/O as/O its/O object/O the/O exposure/O and/O destruction/O of/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION conspiracy/O ./O 
``/O The/O MPIC/O hopes/O that/O all/O members/O of/O this/O industry/O who/O have/O been/O subpenaed/O will/O tell/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ./O 
It/O deplores/O those/O who/O stand/O on/O constitutional/O privileges/O to/O hide/O that/O truth/O ,/O or/O those/O who/O refuse/O to/O recognize/O the/O authority/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
``/O To/O those/O men/O and/O women/O of/O this/O industry/O who/O are/O former/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O who/O openly/O admit/O such/O membership/O and/O conclusively/O prove/O that/O they/O have/O repudiated/O utterly/O and/O forever/O that/O relationship/O ,/O the/O MPIC/O offers/O its/O commendation/O and/O encouragement/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O ``/O On/O September/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O the/O MPIC/ORGANIZATION reiterated/O that/O statement/O ,/O declaring/O that/O the/O industry/O `/O has/O no/O sympathy/O '/O for/O those/O who/O stand/O on/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O and/O again/O commending/O those/O who/O give/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O their/O sincere/O cooperation/O in/O its/O task/O of/O opposing/O communism/O ./O 
``/O Those/O were/O the/O views/O of/O the/O MPIC/O on/O March/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O and/O on/O September/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
``/O Those/O views/O have/O not/O changed/O one/O iota/O ./O 
``/O As/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O we/O support/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION committee/O ,/O hopeful/O that/O through/O and/O as/O a/O result/O of/O its/O hearings/O ,/O ways/O and/O means/O will/O be/O provided/O which/O will/O enable/O the/O Nation/O fairly/O ,/O legally/O ,/O and/O effectively/O to/O deal/O with/O the/O problem/O of/O Communist/O or/O subversive/O elements/O ./O ''/O 
Signed/O :/O The/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Industry/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION for/O :/O Association/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Producers/ORGANIZATION ,/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION A./ORGANIZATION F./ORGANIZATION L./ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION ,/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Producers/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ,/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION ,/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Actors/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Producers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O Screen/O Story/O Analysts/O '/O Guild/O ,/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O Society/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Producers/ORGANIZATION ,/O Society/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION Art/ORGANIZATION Directors/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Unit/ORGANIZATION Production/ORGANIZATION Managers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O would/O like/O also/O at/O this/O time/O before/O beginning/O the/O hearings/O to/O make/O this/O announcement/O to/O the/O public/O ./O 
We/O are/O here/O at/O the/O direction/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION trying/O to/O discharge/O the/O duty/O and/O obligation/O that/O has/O been/O placed/O upon/O us/O by/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
No/O one/O who/O is/O present/O here/O or/O who/O will/O be/O present/O in/O this/O room/O during/O these/O hearings/O ,/O except/O the/O witnesses/O who/O are/O subpenaed/O ,/O are/O required/O to/O be/O here/O ./O 
You/O are/O here/O by/O the/O permission/O of/O the/O committee/O and/O not/O by/O compulsion/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
This/O committee/O will/O not/O countenance/O any/O attempt/O to/O make/O a/O demonstration/O ,/O either/O favorable/O or/O unfavorable/O ,/O toward/O the/O committee/O 's/O undertaking/O or/O to/O what/O any/O person/O called/O as/O a/O witness/O may/O have/O to/O say/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O say/O this/O in/O any/O spirit/O of/O threat/O ,/O but/O if/O such/O conduct/O should/O occur/O ,/O I/O am/O going/O to/O promptly/O ask/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O to/O eject/O those/O who/O start/O or/O participate/O in/O any/O demonstration/O in/O this/O hearing/O room/O ,/O and/O if/O necessary/O ,/O clear/O the/O entire/O room/O ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ,/O who/O will/O you/O call/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Roy/PERSON Huggins/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Will/O Mr./O Huggins/PERSON come/O around/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Will/O you/O have/O the/O chair/O right/O up/O here/O ,/O please/O ,/O Mr./O Huggins/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O hold/O your/O right/O hand/O up/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O shall/O ask/O the/O photographers/O to/O please/O refrain/O from/O taking/O pictures/O while/O the/O witness/O is/O being/O sworn/O ./O 
Do/O 4264/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O you/O have/O any/O objection/O to/O the/O photographers/O taking/O your/O picture/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O HIUOINS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ,/O gentlemen/O ./O 
You/O will/O proceed/O and/O then/O let/O us/O get/O along/O with/O the/O testimony/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ROY/O HUGGINS/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O Mr./O HuoGINs/O ./O 
Roy/PERSON Huggins/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Huggins/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Lytle/PERSON ,/O Wash./LOCATION ,/O in/O 1914/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINs/PERSON ./O 
Malibu/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O in/O a/O general/O way/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O graduated/O in/O 1939/O ,/O and/O did/O 2/O years/O of/O graduate/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Could/O you/O speak/O a/O little/O louder/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O 2/O years/O of/O graduate/O work/O from/O 1939/O through/O 1941/O and/O that/O is/O all/O at/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O graduate/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O field/O did/O you/O do/O your/O graduate/O work/O Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O my/O major/O in/O college/O was/O political/O philosophy/O ,/O but/O my/O graduate/O work/O was/O done/O in/O public/O administration/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O briefly/O how/O you/O have/O been/O employed/O since/O the/O termination/O of/O your/O graduate/O work/O ?/O 
iMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O pardon/O me/O for/O a/O moment/O ?/O 
I/O neglected/O to/O ask/O the/O witness/O ,/O do/O you/O have/O counsel/O representing/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGIN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
If/O you/O desire/O to/O have/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O during/O the/O progress/O of/O your/O interrogation/O ,/O please/O let/O me/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
I/O have/O forgotten/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O to/O tell/O us/O the/O field/O in/O which/O you/O spe/O -/O cialized/O while/O in/O college/O ./O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Political/O philosophy/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ,/O You/O answered/O that/O question/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O then/O my/O question/O was/O :/O How/O have/O you/O been/O employed/O since/O completion/O of/O your/O educational/O training/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O employed/O by/O the/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION as/O a/O personnel/O technician/O ,/O and/O IMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O the/O approximate/O dates/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O in/O 1941/O ,/O just/O after/O I/O left/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O became/O a/O special/O representative/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Civil/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION from/O 1941/O to/O 1943/O ,/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O ,/O or/O 1944/O ./O 
I/O was/O an/O industrial/O engineer/O in/O 1944/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O until/O the/O end/O of/O the/O war/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O the/O war/O ,/O I/O started/O writing/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O been/O a/O writer/O ever/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O since/O the/O period/O of/O the/O war/O you/O have/O been/O engaged/O in/O work/O as/O a/O writer/O ./O 
In/O what/O general/O field/O have/O you/O been/O a/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O wrote/O about/O 100,000/O words/O of/O fiction/O for/O the/O Saturday/O Evening/O Post/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O written/O three/O novels/O ,/O and/O several/O screen/O plays/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4265/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O are/O the/O screen/O plays/O which/O you/O have/O been/O given/O credit/O for/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGOINs/O ./O 
Too/O Late/O for/O Tears/O ,/O The/O Lady/O Gambles/O ,/O Woman/O in/O Hiding/O ,/O Sealed/O Cargo/O ,/O story/O credit/O on/O the/O Fuller/PERSON Brush/PERSON Man/PERSON ,/O and/O the/O Good/O Humor/O Man/O ,/O and/O there/O were/O others/O but/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Huggins/PERSON ,/O this/O committee/O has/O been/O engaged/O for/O some/O time/O in/O the/O investigation/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O the/O field/O of/O entertainment/O ,/O especially/O in/O that/O field/O which/O relates/O to/O the/O moving-picture/O industry/O ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O information/O that/O your/O connection/O in/O the/O past/O has/O been/O such/O that/O you/O could/O enlighten/O the/O committee/O on/O some/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O that/O field/O ./O 
So/O ,/O I/O wanted/O to/O ask/O you/O ,/O first/O of/O all/O :/O Are/O you/O now/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O HUGOINS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O first/O the/O circum/O -/O stances/O under/O which/O you/O became/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O HUGGINs/PERSON ./O 
In/O detail/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O it/O should/O be/O in/O detail/O ,/O at/O least/O in/O detail/O enough/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O a/O clear/O picture/O of/O what/O transpires/O when/O persons/O in/O your/O position/O are/O induced/O or/O led/O to/O become/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O HUGGINS/PERSON ./O 
I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O my/O own/O volition/O ;/O but/O ,/O if/O I/O can/O state/O it/O in/O detail/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O the/O story/O should/O go/O back/O several/O years/O before/O I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O was/O ,/O I/O suppose/O ,/O a/O typical/O American/O citizen/O when/O I/O started/O school/O ./O 
I/O came/O from/O a/O Republican/O background/O ,/O and/O a/O very/O conservative/O background/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O very/O indefinite/O myself/O to/O politics/O until/O I/O read/O in/O the/O papers/O about/O a/O group/O called/O the/O Nazis/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O had/O taken/O power/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O guess/O I/O began/O to/O read/O it/O in/O 1934/O and/O 1935/O ./O 
My/O first/O reaction/O was/O simply/O disbelief/O that/O any/O recognized/O state/O could/O be/O using/O as/O an/O instrument/O of/O national/O policy/O persecution/O of/O a/O minority/O group/O ./O 
Even/O though/O I/O was/O not/O myself/O a/O member/O of/O that/O minority/O group/O ,/O I/O still/O thought/O it/O was/O appalling/O and/O unbelievable/O ,/O and/O when/O I/O started/O college/O I/O made/O it/O a/O point/O to/O find/O out/O what/O it/O was/O about/O ,/O a/O state/O that/O could/O lead/O it/O to/O that/O kind/O of/O despicable/O policy/O in/O which/O it/O exploits/O the/O very/O worst/O in/O human/O beings/O ./O 
I/O took/O political/O science/O ,/O and/O I/O suppose/O that/O was/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O I/O took/O political/O science/O ,/O because/O it/O did/O strike/O me/O as/O being/O a/O terribly/O important/O problem/O ,/O and/O I/O came/O to/O understand/O ,/O I/O thought/O ,/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O German/O state/O ./O 
It/O was/O fascism/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O could/O have/O been/O classified/O as/O a/O premature/O anti-Fascist/O ,/O and/O I/O ca/O n't/O understand/O how/O anyone/O could/O possibly/O have/O failed/O to/O be/O a/O premature/O anti-Fascist/O myself/O ,/O after/O seeing/O what/O was/O happening/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O to/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION in/O 1937/O from/O a/O junior/O college/O ,/O and/O changed/O my/O major/O to/O political/O philosophy/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O my/O politics/O were/O middle/O of/O the/O road/O ,/O and/O I/O just/O had/O a/O great/O faith/O and/O love/O for/O the/O democratic/O system/O ,/O which/O struck/O me/O as/O being/O the/O opposite/O of/O fascism/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O not/O know/O very/O much/O about/O communism/O ./O 
I/O took/O courses/O from/O a/O professor/O who/O was/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O I/O took/O several/O courses/O from/O him/O ,/O and/O all/O of/O his/O courses/O ,/O not/O only/O in/O political/O 4266/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O theory/O but/O in/O anything/O else/O ,/O whatever/O courses/O he/O gave/O ,/O were/O all/O given/O from/O the/O Marxist/O point/O of/O view/O ./O 
By/O that/O time/O I/O had/O made/O up/O my/O mind/O I/O was/O going/O to/O be/O a/O teacher/O ,/O a/O college/O professor/O ./O 
So/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O serious/O and/O hard-working/O student/O ,/O and/O this/O professor/O took/O me/O under/O his/O wing/O ,/O as/O it/O were/O ,/O and/O made/O me/O his/O reader/O and/O gave/O me/O special/O attention/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O very/O good/O teacher/O ,/O and/O very/O sincere/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O not/O a/O Communist/O that/O I/O know/O of/O ,/O but/O he/O was/O a/O Marxist/O ./O 
This/O was/O in/O 1937/O or/O 1938/O or/O 1939/O ,/O and/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O whole/O world/O was/O pretty/O troubled/O ,/O and/O Marxism/O has/O a/O wonderful/O thing/O about/O it/O ,/O in/O that/O ,/O being/O a/O closed/O system/O of/O thought/O ,/O if/O you/O feel/O great/O despair/O about/O the/O world/O or/O are/O having/O difficulty/O understanding/O it/O ,/O Marxism/O does/O something/O for/O you/O ./O 
It/O suddenly/O allows/O the/O whole/O universe/O to/O fall/O into/O a/O nice/O simple/O pattern/O ./O 
There/O are/O no/O unanswered/O questions/O once/O you/O become/O a/O Marxist/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O nice/O feeling/O ,/O particularly/O if/O your/O field/O is/O political/O philosophy/O ,/O and/O you/O like/O to/O feel/O that/O you/O do/O know/O all/O of/O the/O answers/O ./O 
I/O became/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O I/O guess/O ,/O sometime/O in/O 1938/O or/O 1939/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O a/O very/O hard-working/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O a/O lot/O of/O reading/O ,/O not/O in/O Lenin/LOCATION and/O Stalin/PERSON ;/O I/O was/O not/O particularly/O interested/O in/O Lenin/PERSON and/O Stalin/PERSON ,/O but/O I/O did/O a/O lot/O of/O reading/O in/O Marxist/O theories/O ,/O and/O especially/O in/O his/O methodology/O ,/O his/O approach/O to/O all/O phenomena/O ,/O in/O which/O he/O had/O an/O answer/O for/O everything/O ./O 
About/O that/O time/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O of/O course/O ,/O I/O was/O also/O interested/O in/O politics/O ,/O as/O everyone/O was/O in/O that/O day/O ,/O and/O my/O politics/O ,/O I/O guess/O ,/O were/O just/O democratic/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O in/O favor/O of/O Roosevelt/LOCATION 's/O foreign/O policy/O of/O `/O quarantining/O ''/O the/O aggressors/O as/O he/O stated/O it/O in/O 1937/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O often/O asked/O to/O speak/O at/O big/O student/O meetings/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O yearly/O peace/O meeting/O in/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O was/O chairman/O one/O year/O ,/O and/O the/O chief/O speaker/O another/O year/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O know/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O but/O I/O suspect/O now/O that/O the/O people/O who/O asked/O me/O to/O speak/O and/O the/O people/O who/O had/O organized/O and/O sort/O of/O taken/O over/O these/O things/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
But/O I/O knew/O no/O Communists/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O stating/O my/O beliefs/O which/O were/O pro-American/O and/O anti-Fascist/O and/O pro-Roosevelt/O ./O 
I/O graduated/O in/O 1939/O ,/O and/O I/O applied/O for/O a/O fellowship/O and/O so/O I/O could/O go/O on/O and/O get/O my/O Ph./O ./O 
D./O I/O received/O a/O card/O ,/O mimeographed/O card/O ,/O telling/O me/O my/O grades/O were/O not/O good/O enough/O for/O a/O fellowship/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O were/O sorry/O ./O 
This/O was/O the/O awakening/O ,/O because/O I/O had/O graduated/O a/O member/O of/O Phi/ORGANIZATION Beta/ORGANIZATION Kappa/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O have/O a/O diploma/O that/O says/O ``/O summa/O cum/O laude/O ''/O in/O a/O class/O of/O several/O thousand/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O get/O it/O ./O 
So/O ,/O I/O took/O my/O little/O mimeographed/O card/O up/O to/O the/O political-science/O department/O ./O 
and/O I/O found/O a/O graduate/O student/O up/O there/O whose/O name/O I/O have/O forgotten/O ,/O but/O he/O and/O I/O knew/O each/O other/O ,/O and/O we/O went/O down/O to/O Kirkhoff/PERSON Hall/PERSON and/O had/O a/O Coca-Cola/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O he/O told/O me/O I/O should/O know/O better/O than/O to/O think/O I/O was/O going/O to/O get/O a/O fellowship/O when/O I/O was/O also/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
And/O I/O did/O not/O believe/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O made/O a/O few/O other/O little/O inquiries/O from/O the/O professors/O who/O were/O not/O very/O clear/O on/O the/O subject/O ,/O but/O I/O gathered/O from/O what/O they/O did/O not/O say/O that/O I/O was/O refused/O a/O fellow/O -/O ship/O because/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O all/O through/O 1939/O I/O had/O been/O getting/O little/O hints/O from/O people/O that/O I/O really/O ought/O to/O become/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O Miss/O Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a/O well-known/O Communist/O ,/O who/O was/O talking/O to/O me/O at/O that/O time/O or/O not/O ,/O but/O I/O know/O whoever/O it/O was/O ,/O they/O kept/O saying/O ,/O ``/O Look/O ,/O you/O are/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O therefore/O you/O should/O belong/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O remember/O that/O one/O of/O my/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4267/O answers/O was/O that/O Sidney/PERSON Hook/PERSON was/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O he/O did/O not/O belong/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O he/O wrote/O articles/O every/O week/O condemning/O it/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O different/O kind/O of/O Marxist/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O I/O had/O discovered/O the/O differences/O ,/O and/O I/O read/O Sidney/PERSON Hook/PERSON right/O along/O with/O all/O of/O the/O other/O Marxists/O ,/O and/O found/O them/O to/O be/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O could/O see/O in/O basic/O agreement/O about/O what/O Marxism/O was/O all/O about/O ,/O and/O so/O I/O did/O not/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O I/O knew/O no/O Communists/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O associate/O with/O Communists/O ,/O and/O my/O friends/O were/O all/O fraternity/O brothers/O ,/O or/O fraternity/O boys/O ,/O at/O least/O ,/O who/O lived/O with/O me/O down/O at/O the/O beach/O ./O 
But/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O to/O the/O faculty/O of/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O was/O refused/O a/O fellowship/O on/O those/O grounds/O ./O 
I/O was/O already/O fairly/O despairing/O of/O democracy/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O not/O do/O anything/O about/O it/O ,/O but/O in/O 1940/O history/O had/O moved/O also/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O every/O democracy/O in/O any/O large/O industrial/O nation/O ,/O except/O England/LOCATION and/O America/LOCATION ,/O had/O now/O fallen/O to/O fascism/O ,/O and/O I/O began/O to/O despair/O of/O the/O thing/O that/O I/O had/O felt/O so/O deeply/O about/O ,/O the/O democratic/O system/O ./O 
I/O had/O been/O a/O victim/O of/O undemocratic/O treatment/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O just/O naive/O enough/O to/O believe/O that/O it/O was/O impossible/O that/O this/O could/O not/O really/O have/O happened/O ,/O but/O it/O did/O happen/O ,/O and/O I/O knew/O it/O ./O 
So/O ,/O when/O I/O got/O back/O to/O school/O in/O 1940/O ,/O the/O campaign/O took/O up/O again/O ,/O and/O ,/O through/O Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON working/O on/O me/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION sometime/O in/O 1940/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O I/O attended/O three/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O can/O t/O remember/O the/O meetings/O very/O well/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O remember/O that/O I/O was/O being/O asked/O to/O picket/O war/O plants/O and/O being/O asked/O to/O engage/O in/O other/O activities/O which/O were/O hindering/O our/O preparedness/O program/O and/O to/O do/O what/O I/O could/O to/O oppose/O draft/O laws/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O like/O that/O ./O 
I/O found/O ,/O having/O gotten/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O I/O did/O not/O agree/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O but/O apparently/O not/O a/O Communist/O ;/O and/O so/O ,/O after/O attending/O three/O or/O four/O meetings/O ,/O I/O quit/O ,/O and/O I/O wrote/O an/O article/O ,/O which/O appeared/O on/O the/O front/O page/O of/O the/O daily/O college/O paper/O ,/O condemning/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION position/O in/O toto/O ./O 
War/O was/O declared/O later/O ,/O and/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O changed/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O pay/O any/O attention/O to/O it/O ;/O but/O ,/O with/O the/O declaration/O of/O war/O ,/O I/O left/O college/O and/O I/O tried/O to/O join/O the/O Marine/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ./O 
and/O I/O was/O rejected/O because/O of/O my/O bad/O eyesight/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O tried/O the/O Navy/ORGANIZATION ,/O too-I/O am/O not/O sure-and/O I/O was/O rejected/O there/O ./O 
And/O so/O I/O got/O a/O job/O working/O for/O the/O city/O ,/O transferred/O to/O the/O Federal/O Government/O ,/O and/O became/O special/O representative/O in/O charge/O of/O recruitment/O for/O the/O national/O war/O agencies/O here/O ./O 
I/O was/O still/O a/O student/O of/O Marxism/O ,/O and/O I/O hoped/O when/O it/O was/O over/O to/O go/O back/O and/O get/O my/O Ph./O ./O 
D./O in/O political/O philosophy/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O still/O a/O Marxist/O ./O 
So/O ,/O around/O 1943/O ,/O the/O political/O climate/O had/O changed/O rather/O severely/O ,/O and/O Russia/LOCATION was/O our/O ally/O ,/O and/O I/O wish/O I/O could/O remember/O those/O quotes/O verbatim/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O I/O remember/O them/O well/O enough/O to/O state/O them/O here/O ,/O without/O contradiction/O ,/O that/O it/O was/O in/O 1943/O or/O maybe/O 1942/O that/O General/O MacArthur/PERSON made/O his/O statement/O that/O the/O hope/O of/O the/O world/O rests/O upon/O the/O valiant/O Red/O army/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O it/O was/O in/O 1943/O that/O Eddie/PERSON Rickenbacker/PERSON ,/O whose/O love/O of/O country/O is/O hardly/O questioned/O ,/O said-and/O this/O was/O quoted/O in/O Time/O magazine/O in/O 1943/O :/O ``/O When/O the/O war/O is/O over/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION will/O emerge/O as/O one/O of/O the/O world/O 's/O greatest/O democracies/O ./O ''/O 
Patrick/PERSON Hurley/PERSON ,/O Gen./O Patrick/PERSON Hurley/PERSON ,/O in/O 1944/O ,/O said/O in/O regard/O to/O China/LOCATION that/O the/O Communists/O are/O not/O Communist/O at/O all/O ,/O but/O just/O a/O type/O 4268/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O of/O democrat/O ,/O or/O fighting/O for/O a/O type/O of/O democracy/O ,/O or/O something/O of/O that/O sort/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O that/O was/O quoted/O in/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Drew/PERSON Pearson/PERSON rounded/O up/O all/O of/O these/O quotations/O just/O for/O fun/O one/O time/O to/O show/O that/O ,/O when/O you/O thought/O something/O was/O rather/O important.There/O were/O others/O ./O 
There/O was/O one/O from/O Admiral/O Standley/PERSON ,/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O Russia/LOCATION was/O a/O great/O democracy/O ./O 
While/O I/O began/O to/O wonder/O perhaps/O if/O I/O had/O gotten/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O gotten/O out/O without/O giving/O it/O a/O chance/O ,/O it/O looked/O to/O me/O as/O if/O I/O were/O wrong/O about/O their/O attitude/O toward/O democracy/O and/O the/O rest/O of/O it/O ,/O and/O so/O I/O rejoined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1943/O ./O 
As/O far/O as/O I/O could/O see/O ,/O there/O had/O not/O been/O any/O changes/O ,/O except/O that/O they/O were/O now/O ,/O at/O least-I/O could/O not/O oppose/O what/O they/O were/O doing/O and/O saying/O because/O they/O were/O selling/O war/O bonds/O ,/O and/O they/O were/O talking/O about/O how/O lo/O prevent/O strikes/O in/O the/O factories/O ,/O and/O they/O were/O a/O very/O patriotic/O group/O ./O 
I/O attended/O a/O couple/O or/O three/O meetings/O ,/O and/O then/O stopped/O attending/O meetings/O ,/O because/O I/O think/O that/O I/O felt/O ,/O as/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O I/O really/O ought/O to/O get/O into/O this/O thing/O and/O see/O what/O was/O happening/O ,/O and/O it/O seemed/O to/O me/O being/O a/O Communist/O was/O a/O part/O of/O being/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O this/O I/O think/O was/O my/O motivation/O ;/O but/O somehow/O or/O other/O ,/O after/O doing/O it/O ,/O I/O could/O n't/O stay/O with/O it/O ,/O and/O so/O I/O attended/O very/O few/O meetings/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O suppose/O not/O more/O than/O five/O or/O six/O meetings/O in/O the/O next/O 2/O or/O 3/O years/O ./O 
I/O suppose/O I/O retained/O my/O membership/O accordingly/O ./O 
In/O 1946/O ,/O I/O became/O a/O writer/O ,/O and/O I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Authors/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O think/O it/O was/O the/O first/O time/O I/O ever/O joined/O anything/O besides/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O steering/O committee/O of/O the/O Authors/O '/O Guild/O here/O on/O the/O coast/O ,/O and/O the/O chairman/O of/O that/O committee/O was/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ./O 
After/O a/O meeting/O one/O night/O ,/O after/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O steering/O committee/O of/O the/O Authors/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON asked/O me/O to/O have/O a/O drink/O with/O him/O in/O the/O bar/O of/O the/O hotel/O ,/O and/O we/O talked/O for/O a/O while/O ,/O and/O it/O came/O out/O that/O he/O understood/O that/O I/O was/O in/O some/O way/O still/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O not/O attending/O meetings/O or/O anything/O ,/O and/O why/O did/O n't/O I./O I/O gave/O him/O my/O reasons/O :/O that/O it/O did/O n't/O mean/O anything/O to/O me/O ;/O that/O I/O saw/O no/O reason/O why/O I/O should/O ./O 
He/O asked/O me/O if/O I/O were/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O ''/O and/O he/O asked/O me/O if/O I/O would/O allow/O him/O to/O transfer/O me/O to/O the/O Hollywood/O group/O ./O 
And/O I/O said/O ``/O I/O did/O n't/O think/O so/O ./O ''/O 
We/O had/O meetings/O ,/O I/O guess/O fairly/O regularly/O ,/O of/O the/O Authors/O '/O Guild/O ,/O and/O after/O each/O meeting/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON would/O ask/O me/O if/O I/O had/O changed/O my/O mind/O ,/O and/O he/O gave/O a/O glowing/O picture/O of/O the/O stimulation/O and/O understanding/O and/O the/O new/O understanding/O I/O would/O have/O of/O Marxism/O if/O I/O came/O into/O this/O group/O ,/O which/O was/O made/O up/O of/O highly/O intelligent/O people/O ,/O and/O finally/O ,/O sometime/O toward/O the/O end/O of/O 1946/O ,/O I/O said/O :/O ``/O All/O right/O ;/O tell/O me/O where/O to/O go/O ,/O and/O I/O will/O come/O to/O one/O of/O your/O meetings/O ./O ''/O 
Well/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O It/O will/O take/O a/O little/O time/O ,/O ''/O and/O so/O I/O think/O it/O was/O a/O few/O weeks/O later/O I/O was/O told/O to/O attend/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O did/O ,/O and/O for/O the/O first/O time/O in/O my/O connection/O with/O t/O he/O Communist/O Party/O I/O started/O attending/O meetings/O fairly/O regularly/O ./O 
I/O think/O in/O the/O period/O of/O 9/O months/O or/O so/O that/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION I/O must/O have/O attended/O a/O dozen/O or/O two/O dozen/O meetings/O ./O 
It/O was/O sufficient/O to/O know/O something/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O last/O ./O 
I/O discovered/O the/O usual/O things/O :/O That/O there/O was/O certainly/O no/O democracy/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O decisions/O were/O brought/O down/O and/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4269/O rendered/O or/O we/O found/O out/O about/O them/O by/O having/O to/O read/O the/O -LSB-/O Communist/O -RSB-/O press/O ,/O which/O I/O could/O not/O bear/O reading/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O supposed/O to/O read/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O I/O took/O it/O for/O a/O while/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O read/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O also/O supposed/O to/O read/O Political/O Affairs/O ,/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O which/O was/O on/O a/O little/O higher/O level/O ,/O but/O still/O was/O opinionated/O and/O without/O much/O force/O ,/O I/O felt/O ./O 
Discussions/O in/O the/O group/O seemed/O to/O be/O or/O to/O consist/O of/O restatement/O in/O slightly/O different/O wording/O of/O things/O that/O were/O appearing/O and/O the/O things/O I/O was/O being/O asked/O to/O read/O ./O 
Any/O difference/O of/O opinion/O was/O immediately/O pounced/O upon/O with/O name-calling/O and/O all/O of/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O things/O that/O you/O have/O heard/O about/O so/O many/O times/O before/O ./O 
But/O no/O one/O ever/O disagreed/O really/O ./O 
They/O might/O tentatively/O disagree/O ,/O and/O then/O immediately/O withdraw/O it/O ,/O very/O quickly/O withdraw/O when/O they/O got/O pounced/O upon/O by/O the/O chief/O intellectual/O of/O the/O group/O ./O 
At/O the/O same/O time/O history/O was/O moving/O forward/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O making/O a/O big/O change/O in/O my/O basic/O philosophy/O ./O 
In/O 1947/O a/O lot/O of/O things/O were/O happening/O ;/O the/O cold/O war/O had/O started/O ;/O the/O U./ORGANIZATION N./ORGANIZATION was/O a/O total/O loss/O because/O of/O Russian/LOCATION vetoes/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O that/O by/O the/O time/O I/O got/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O they/O had/O used/O the/O veto/O about/O two/O dozen/O times/O on/O crucial/O issues/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O great/O faith/O in/O the/O U./O N./O It/O looked/O to/O me/O as/O if/O it/O were/O being/O destroyed/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION was/O refusing/O to/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O control/O of/O the/O atomic/O bomb/O ,/O which/O appalled/O me/O ,/O and/O then/O sometime/O late/O in/O 1947/O they/O suddenly/O reformed/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Internationale/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O quit/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
This/O time/O I/O quit/O no/O longer/O a/O Marxist/O ,/O for/O reasons/O both/O that/O I/O could/O have/O found/O in/O the/O first/O place/O if/O I/O had/O read/O with/O less/O of/O an/O eager/O eye/O ,/O and/O for/O reasons/O of/O history/O ./O 
The/O historical/O reasons/O were/O now/O it/O became/O pretty/O obvious/O that/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION was/O not/O the/O hope/O of/O the/O world/O or/O the/O hope/O of/O democracy/O or/O anything/O else/O ,/O but/O was/O an/O imperialist/O power/O ./O 
I/O used/O to/O believe/O in/O the/O early/O days/O ,/O in/O 1943/O ,/O when/O I/O went/O back/O in/O ,/O that/O the/O only/O reason/O that/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION was/O not/O democratic/O was/O because/O it/O was/O surrounded/O by/O enemies/O like/O Germany/LOCATION and/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O and/O so/O on/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O on/O a/O wartime/O footing/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O the/O reason/O for/O it/O ./O 
But/O it/O got/O worse/O as/O we/O all/O know/O after/O the/O war/O was/O over/O ,/O and/O it/O had/O no/O enemies/O surrounding/O it/O at/O all/O ./O 
Its/O attacks/O on/O every/O kind/O of/O freedom/O of/O thought/O increased/O ,/O its/O attitude/O toward/O other/O peoples/O became/O clear/O in/O its/O dealings/O with/O all/O of/O its/O border/O nations/O ,/O Poland/LOCATION ,/O Yugoslavia/LOCATION ,/O and/O Hungary/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O six/O so-called/O satellite/O states/O ,/O and/O it/O had/O moved/O in/O and/O destroyed/O all/O freedom/O and/O had/O shot/O several/O leaders/O of/O those/O nations/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O good/O many/O things/O happening/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O all/O of/O them/O seemed/O to/O be/O building/O up/O and/O I/O ca/O n't/O even/O remember/O them/O all/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O obvious/O to/O me/O that/O there/O was/O no/O hope/O that/O the/O future/O was/O held/O in/O the/O hand/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
