COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 8/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O MAY/O 19/O ,/O 20/O ,/O AND/O 21/O ,/O 1952/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1952/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/O S/O WOOD/O ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Charman/PERSON HAROLD/PERSON H/PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION MORGAN/LOCATION M/LOCATION MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S/LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O II/O CONTENTS/O May/O 19/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ---------------------/O .../O May/O 20/O ,/O 1952/O Testimony/O ofClifford/O Odets/O -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ------------------------------/O ___/O Isobel/PERSON Lennart/PERSON ---------------------------------------/O .../O Stanley/ORGANIZATION Roberts/ORGANIZATION -------------------------------------/O .../O May/O 21/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Lillian/PERSON Hellman/PERSON -------------------------/O il/O Pag/O ./O 
3453/O 3491/O 3512/O 3529/O 3541/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 8/O MONDAY/O ,/O MAY/O 19/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 11/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representative/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O appearance/O noted/O in/O transcript/O -RRB-/O ,/O and/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O research/O director/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O for/O purposes/O of/O this/O hearing/O I/O ,/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O have/O set/O up/O a/O subcommittee/O consisting/O of/O Messrs./O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/PERSON ,/O who/O are/O all/O present/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVEN-ER/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O Mr./O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O ./O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O will/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O CLIFFORD/PERSON ODETS/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O EUGENE/PERSON GRESSMAN/PERSON Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O your/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ,/O Mr./O Odets/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O Mr./O Gressman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Please/O identify/O yourself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O GRESSM.AN/O ./O 
Eugene/PERSON Gressman/PERSON ,/O 1830/O Jefferson/LOCATION Place/LOCATION NW./LOCATION ,/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
During/O the/O progress/O of/O your/O examination/O ,/O you/O are/O at/O liberty/O to/O confer/O with/O your/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O you/O may/O desire/O ,/O to/O seek/O such/O information/O and/O advice/O from/O him/O as/O you/O want/O ./O 
He/O is/O at/O liberty/O to/O confer/O with/O you/O at/O any/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O you/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O executive/O session/O on/O April/O 24/O ,/O 1952/O ./O 
The/O purpose/O of/O your/O appearance/O 3453/O 3454/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O here/O today/O is/O to/O obtain/O your/O testimony/O in/O open/O hearings/O and/O to/O question/O you/O further/O on/O matters/O discussed/O at/O the/O earlier/O hearings/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O the/O time/O and/O place/O of/O your/O birth/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Philadelphia/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ,/O July/O 18/O ,/O 1906/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O formal/O education/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
Two/O years/O of/O high/O school/O ,/O and/O elementary/O school/O in/O the/O Bronx/LOCATION ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O playwright/O and/O a/O theater/O director/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O also/O engaged/O in/O the/O acting/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O in/O the/O past/O been/O an/O actor/O ./O 
I/O have/O written/O and/O directed/O for/O movies/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON entered/O the/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
In/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O have/O you/O lived/O during/O your/O professional/O career/O ?/O 
That/O is/O ,/O as/O an/O actor/O and/O as/O a/O playwright/O and/O director/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O lived/O in/O Philadelphia/LOCATION ,/O I/O have/O worked/O and/O lived/O in/O Camden/LOCATION ,/O N./PERSON J./PERSON ;/O Chester/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ;/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O now/O ,/O will/O you/O tell/O us/O when/O you/O went/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
My/O first/O visit/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION was/O after/O I/O became/O a/O playwright/O ,/O at/O the/O end/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
I/O went/O as/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O how/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O at/O that/O time/O about/O 10/O or/O 12/O weeks/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O return/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION at/O a/O later/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O been/O there/O a/O number/O of/O times/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O would/O you/O tell/O us/O as/O nearly/O as/O you/O can/O the/O periods/O when/O you/O were/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
At/O first/O I/O understood/O you/O to/O say/O it/O was/O the/O end/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
1935/O ./O 
After/O that/O I/O will/O guess/O two/O or/O three/O excursions/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION to/O make/O one/O picture/O ./O 
That/O would/O be/O between/O the/O years/O of/O 1936/O and/O perhaps/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O title/O of/O the/O picture/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O one/O time/O to/O make/O a/O picture/O for/O Paramount/O called/O Gettysburg/LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O one/O time/O for/O United/ORGANIZATION Artists/ORGANIZATION to/O make/O a/O picture/O called/O The/O River/O Is/O Blue/O ,/O which/O I/O did/O not/O finally/O write/O ./O 
I/O went/O at/O another/O time/O to/O write/O The/O Life/O of/O George/PERSON Gershwin/PERSON ;/O and/O finally/O in/O 1943/O I/O went/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION for/O a/O period/O of/O slightly/O over/O 4/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O leave/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O return/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O guess/O in/O 1947/O and/O a/O half/O or/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O since/O that/O time/O how/O have/O you/O been/O employed/O or/O in/O what/O work/O have/O you/O been/O engaged/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O since/O then/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION written/O and/O produced/O two/O plays/O ,/O one/O of/O which/O I/O directed/O ,/O my/O last/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O are/O their/O names/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O one/O was/O called/O The/O Big/O Knife/O ,/O and/O the/O second/O one/O was/O called/O The/O Country/O Girl/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Big/O Knife/O was/O in/O 1948/O and/O the/O Country/O Girl/O in/O 1951/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3455/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O cease/O being/O an/O actor/O and/O become/O a/O playwright/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O this/O happened/O at/O the/O end/O of/O 1934/O or/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1935/O ,/O in/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O from/O that/O time/O until/O you/O went/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O you/O were/O engaged/O solely/O in/O the/O work/O of/O a/O playwright/O ,/O is/O that/O correctly/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Since/O then/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O are/O the/O principal/O plays/O that/O were/O written/O by/O you/O after/O you/O became/O a/O playwright/O in/O 1934/O or/O 1935/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O play/O I/O wrote/O was/O called/O Awake/O and/O Sing/O ./O 
The/O second/O two/O plays/O after/O that/O were/O called/O respectively/O Waiting/O for/O Lefty/O and/O Till/O the/O Day/O I/O Die/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O were/O those/O plays/O produced/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Those/O three/O plays/O were/O produced/O the/O early/O part/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O certain/O that/O all/O three/O were/O produced/O 1935/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O possible/O that/O that/O Waiting/O for/O Lefty/O would/O produced/O at/O the/O end/O of/O 1934/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O a/O matter/O of/O a/O month/O two/O ./O 
of/O in/O be/O or/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O next/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
The/O next/O play/O was/O called/O Paradise/O Lost/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O was/O produced/O in/O 1936/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
About/O ,/O I/O guess/O so/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O quite/O certain/O of/O the/O dates/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O can/O you/O give/O us/O the/O other/O plays/O produced/O by/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O think/O in/O chronological/O order/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O Golden/O Boy/O the/O next/O in/O order/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Produced/O in/O 1937/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Then/O after/O that/O would/O come/O Rocket/O to/O the/O Moon/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Or/O maybe/O a/O little/O earlier/O ,/O 1938/O or/O 1938/O and/O a/O half/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O the/O production/O of/O Rocket/O to/O the/O Moon/O ,/O did/O you/O write/O a/O play/O entitled/O ``/O Silent/O Partner/O ?/O ''/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O except/O that/O is/O was/O not/O produced/O ./O 
It/O was/O imperfectly/O written/O ,/O therefore/O it/O was/O not/O produced/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O ,/O after/O your/O play/O Rocket/O to/O the/O Moon/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O write/O and/O produce/O Night/O Music/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O date/O of/O that/O was/O in/O 1940/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O what/O was/O the/O next/O after/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
After/O that/O Billy/PERSON Rose/PERSON produced/O a/O play/O of/O mine/O called/O Clash/O by/O Night/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in/O 1942/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O have/O already/O made/O reference/O to/O your/O plays/O The/O Big/O Knife/O and/O The/O Country/O Girl/O ./O 
Did/O that/O compose/O the/O entire/O list/O ,/O with/O the/O addition/O of/O the/O three/O pictures/O you/O produced/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
3456/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O written/O more/O movies/O ./O 
Not/O many/O of/O them/O saw/O production/O ,/O and/O frequently/O I/O was/O employed/O as/O a/O play/O doctor/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION to/O improve/O other/O writers/O '/O scripts/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O there/O has/O been/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O that/O you/O were/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Was/O that/O testimony/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
My/O best/O guess/O on/O that/O would/O be/O from/O toward/O the/O end/O of/O 1934/O to/O the/O middle/O of/O 19:5/O ,/O covering/O maybe/O anywhere/O from/O 6/O to/O 8/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O relate/O to/O the/O committee/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O joined/O the/O Communist/O Party/O Let/O me/O put/O it/O this/O way/O :/O How/O were/O you/O recruited/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O by/O whom/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
As/O has/O been/O testified/O here/O before/O ,/O there/O were/O a/O number/O a/O small/O group/O ,/O of/O Comnmnist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O in/O this/O Group/O Theater/O ,/O of/O a/O total/O Group/O Theater/O membership/O of/O perhaps/O 35/O there/O were/O four/O or/O five/O people/O who/O were/O connected/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Literature/O was/O passed/O around/O ,/O and/O in/O a/O time/O of/O great/O social/O unrest/O many/O people/O found/O themselves/O reaching/O out/O for/O new/O ideas/O ,/O new/O ways/O of/O solving/O depressions/O or/O making/O a/O better/O living/O ,/O fighting/O for/O one/O 's/O rights/O ,/O whatever/O those/O were/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O those/O rights/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Those/O rights/O would/O be/O to/O have/O steady/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Beg/O your/O pardon/O Mr./O ODET/O ./O 
The/O rights/O to/O be/O steadily/O employed/O ,/O for/O instance/O ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O that/O time/O there/O were/O perhaps/O 15/O or/O 16/O million/O unemployed/O people/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O myself/O was/O living/O on/O 10/O cents/O a/O day/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O was/O interested/O in/O any/O idea/O which/O might/O suggest/O how/O as/O an/O actor/O I/O could/O function/O as/O a/O working/O actor/O who/O could/O make/O a/O living/O at/O a/O craft/O lie/O had/O chosen/O for/O his/O life/O 's/O work/O ./O 
These/O were/O the/O early/O days/O of/O the/O New/O Deal/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O one/O has/O to/O describe/O them/O ./O 
They/O were/O horrendous/O days/O that/O none/O of/O us/O would/O like/O to/O go/O through/O again/O ./O 
On/O this/O basis/O there/O was/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O talk/O about/O amelioration/O of/O conditions/O ,/O about/O how/O should/O one/O live/O ,/O by/O what/O values/O should/O one/O work/O for/O ,/O and/O in/O line/O with/O this/O there/O was/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O talk/O about/O Marxist/O values/O ./O 
One/O read/O literature/O ;/O there/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O penny/O and/O 2-cent/O and/O 5-cent/O pamphlets/O ./O 
I/O read/O them/O along/O with/O a/O lot/O of/O other/O people/O ,/O and/O filially/O joined/O the/O Communisi/ORGANIZATION t/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O the/O belief/O ,/O in/O the/O honest/O and/O real/O belief/O ,/O that/O this/O was/O some/O way/O out/O of/O the/O dilemma/O in/O which/O we/O found/O ourselves/O ./O 
Does/O that/O answer/O your/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O does/O ,/O except/O that/O you/O have/O not/O told/O exact/O circumstances/O under/O which/O von/O were/O recruited/O into/O the/O us/O the/O party/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O process/O of/O recruitment/O used/O in/O your/O case/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O went/O that/O you/O read/O some/O pamphlets/O :/O you/O listened/O to/O some/O one/O talk/O ,/O and/O finally/O a/O person/O would/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O my/O case/O it/O happened/O did/O n't/O want/O ``/O No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
When/O I/O am/O ready/O ./O 
I/O will/O ./O ''/O 
I/O was/O not/O ready/O that/O month/O ,/O I/O was/O ready/O a/O iiiontih/O or/O two/O later/O ./O ''/O 
Mr.T/O \/O AVENINER/O ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O individual/O who/O made/O that/O suggestion/O to/O you/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3457/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
This/O would/O be/O an/O actor/O friend/O of/O mine/O named/O J./PERSON Edward/PERSON Bromberg/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENN/PERSON ER/O ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Group/O Theater/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O lie/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O the/O actor/O who/O died/O a/O few/O months/O ago/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O he/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O actually/O recruited/O you/O into/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
My/O best/O inmemor/O would/O be/O that/O Mr./O Bromberg/PERSON did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O were/O recruited/O into/O the/O party/O ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O particular/O cell/O or/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O OrDETS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O would/O be/O to/O be/O connected/O with/O those/O few/O people/O who/O were/O in/O the/O Group/O Theater/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEXNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O other/O persons/O who/O were/O members/O of/O the/O same/O cell/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O which/O von/O were/O assigned/O \//O AMr/O ./O 
ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O they/O have/O been/O mentioned/O here/O as/O Lewis/PERSON Leverett/PERSON ,/O a/O young/O actiess/O named/O Phoebe/PERSON Brand/PERSON ,/O and/O an/O actor/O about/O whom/O you/O refreshed/O my/O memory/O the/O last/O time/O I/O was/O here/O named/O Art/PERSON Smith/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O Art/PERSON Smith/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
And/O then/O from/O m/O reading/O of/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Times/ORGANIZATION a/O couple/O of/O other/O members/O were/O mentioned/O that/O I/O have/O no/O memory/O of/O ,/O as/O I/O told/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNr.R/O ./O 
Elia/PERSON Kazan/PERSON '/O Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O that/O group/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O Mr./O Kazan/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O meet/O with/O all/O of/O those/O persons/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O that/O is/O ,/O those/O you/O have/O named/O up/O to/O the/O present/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
\//O Mr./O TAV.ENNER/O ./O 
Tony/O Kraber/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
He/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENxNx.i/O He/O is/O included/O in/O the/O group/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Sid/PERSON Benson/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O knew/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O T.AVENNER/O ./O 
Was/O he/O an/O attendant/O at/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O in/O this/O Group/O Theater/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
He/O came/O in/O as/O an/O occasional/O visitor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O known/O to/O you/O as/O a/O functionary/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O actually/O did/O not/O know/O what/O lie/O did/O ./O 
I/O thought/O for/O a/O while/O he/O was/O a/O man/O who/O wrote/O newspaper/O articles/O ./O 
Then/O my/O impression/O became/O that/O he/O was/O some/O kind/O of/O party/O functionary/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O he/O was/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Group/O Theater/O as/O such/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O lie/O was/O not/O an/O actor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O this/O person/O ,/O Wellman/PERSON or/O Sid/PERSON Benson/PERSON ,/O ever/O visit/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O :/O he/O did/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O friend/O of/O mine/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O what/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O his/O visiting/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Were/O you/O at/O that/O time/O living/O in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O live/O in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O he/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O was/O subsequently/O transferred/O to/O the/O State/O of/O Tennessee/LOCATION ?/O 
3458/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O because/O one/O time/O on/O a/O long/O extended/O auto/O trip/O I/O did/O meet/O him/O in/O Tennessee/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O visit/O your/O home/O while/O he/O was/O in/O Tennessee/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O would/O remember/O ./O 
He/O would/O visit/O my/O home/O when/O he/O lived/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O his/O visits/O at/O your/O home/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O always/O social/O visits/O ./O 
We/O both/O were/O interested/O in/O music/O ,/O fine/O classical/O music/O ,/O records/O ./O 
We/O might/O go/O out/O to/O dinner/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O any/O of/O those/O visits/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O his/O interest/O or/O his/O work/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O in/O 1o/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O subsequently/O learn/O that/O he/O became/O an/O organizer/O for/O the/O Communist/O Party/O in/O Tennessee/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ;/O of/O my/O own/O personal/O knowledge/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Andrew/PERSON Obergaard/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O met/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Under/O what/O circumstances/O did/O you/O meet/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
In/O some/O way/O that/O I/O would/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
He/O came/O backstage/O in/O one/O of/O our/O plays/O ./O 
And/O perhaps/O we/O went/O out/O to/O get/O a/O bite/O to/O eat/O or/O something/O to/O drink/O ,/O some/O coffee/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O attend/O the/O group/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O meetings/O to/O which/O you/O referred/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O that/O he/O was/O introduced/O to/O people/O who/O were/O connected/O with/O this/O group/O within/O the/O group/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O recognize/O him/O as/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
This/O would/O be/O my/O good/O guess/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O do/O you/O base/O that/O statement/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functionaries/O ,/O when/O they/O are/O such/O ,/O are/O always/O secretive/O ./O 
They/O never/O announce/O themselves/O as/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functionaries/O ./O 
But/O they/O have/O a/O quality/O of/O authority/O ,/O a/O quality/O of/O talking/O with/O knowledge/O ,/O and/O one/O makes/O the/O surmise/O that/O this/O is/O some/O kind/O of/O functionary/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O was/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O that/O conduct/O on/O his/O part/O that/O your/O judgment/O was/O that/O he/O was/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O occasions/O when/O his/O advice/O was/O sought/O on/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION problems/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O one/O such/O occasion/O ./O 
The/O occasion/O ,/O as/O I/O think/O I/O have/O stated/O before/O ,/O was/O we/O thought/O that/O actors/O should/O get/O rehearsal/O pay/O ,/O which/O was/O an/O unheard/O of/O thing/O and/O rather/O a/O lunatic/O idea/O in/O those/O days/O ./O 
We/O wanted/O or/O perhaps/O we/O did/O first/O go/O to/O an/O Actors/O '/O Equity/O Association/O meeting/O and/O made/O no/O headway/O at/O all/O ./O 
My/O best/O memory/O is/O that/O we/O then/O in/O some/O way/O consulted/O with/O Mr./O Obergaard/PERSON ,/O who/O suggested/O certain/O tactical/O moves/O to/O make/O to/O get/O our/O proposal/O on/O the/O floor/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O no/O memory/O of/O particular/O details/O but/O I/O do/O know/O that/O this/O sm/O all/O group/O within/O the/O Group/O Theater/O did/O get/O for/O every/O actor/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION rehearsal/O pay/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O we/O were/O the/O beginning/O of/O such/O a/O movement/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3459/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Obergaard/PERSON was/O connected/O with/O any/O Communist/O trade-union/O organization/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O some/O such/O talk/O ./O 
It/O was/O obvious/O that/O he/O was/O a/O trade-union/O man/O ./O 
It/O was/O on/O that/O basis/O that/O we/O would/O have/O consulted/O with/O him/O ./O 
But/O what/O exactly/O it/O was/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O were/O you/O required/O to/O make/O a/O study/O of/O Marxist/O literature/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O it/O was/O a/O great/O day/O for/O literature/O ./O 
One/O read/O and/O one/O was/O supposed/O to/O read/O constantly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O take/O up/O those/O studies/O in/O meetings/O of/O your/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O personally/O did/O not/O do/O too/O much/O because/O it/O was/O a/O little/O beyond/O me/O ,/O and/O my/O interest/O was/O going/O toward/O writing/O plays/O ./O 
To/O study/O these/O matters/O required/O really/O months/O of/O very/O serious/O study/O which/O I/O did/O not/O give/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O where/O the/O principles/O of/O Marxism/O were/O discussed/O and/O studied/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O never/O did/O ./O 
I/O personally/O never/O did/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O you/O never/O attended/O or/O never/O studied/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODET/O ./O 
I/O never/O studied/O in/O such/O groups/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O a/O matter/O of/O taking/O home/O a/O newspaper/O or/O pamphlet/O and/O reading/O it/O ./O 
There/O were/O such/O study/O groups/O but/O I/O did/O not/O attend/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O obtain/O the/O material/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
The/O material/O was/O bought/O ./O 
The/O material/O was/O bought/O at/O the/O Workers/O '/O Bookshop/O ./O 
Or/O it/O was/O given/O to/O you/O or/O bought/O for/O you/O by/O some/O other/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O did/O you/O attend/O in/O the/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O quite/O certain/O they/O were/O very/O few/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O meetings/O held/O regularly/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O meetings/O are/O held/O regularly/O ./O 
Let/O us/O say/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O once/O a/O week/O ./O 
And/O that/O special/O meetings/O would/O be/O called/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O some/O complaint/O or/O something/O that/O had/O to/O be/O fixed/O ./O 
I/O gave/O you/O what/O seemed/O to/O be/O a/O rather/O silly/O example/O of/O saying/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O we/O do/O n't/O get/O clean/O drinking/O glasses/O around/O here/O ./O ''/O 
They/O would/O call/O a/O meeting/O at/O 10/O or/O 11/O o'clock/O that/O night/O to/O discuss/O that/O subject/O ./O 
I/O thought/O it/O was/O a/O little/O silly/O ,/O and/O I/O refused/O to/O attend/O such/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O held/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O had/O a/O home/O then/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O very/O poor/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O period/O of/O time/O that/O Wellman/PERSON was/O visiting/O you/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
This/O would/O be/O later/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O much/O later/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O might/O think/O in/O the/O next/O 6/O months/O or/O a/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O fix/O the/O time/O as/O nearly/O as/O you/O can/O by/O giving/O us/O the/O months/O of/O the/O year/O that/O it/O may/O have/O occurred/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O difficult/O ,/O because/O ,/O because/O this/O was/O on/O and/O off/O for/O a/O number/O of/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O state/O the/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O guessing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O not/O a/O guess/O ,/O but/O your/O best/O judgment/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O I/O said/O he/O visited/O me/O once/O or/O twice/O in/O 1935/O and/O then/O perhaps/O later/O in/O 1936/O ,/O this/O would/O be/O my/O best/O judgment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O visit/O you/O at/O any/O time/O after/O 1936/O ?/O 
3460/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O a/O number/O of/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O occasion/O of/O those/O visits/O and/O the/O time/O ,/O approximate/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O sleep/O very/O late/O ,/O sometimes/O until/O 2/O or/O 3/O o'clock/O in/O the/O afternoon/O ,/O because/O I/O work/O very/O late/O ./O 
I/O work/O frequently/O until/O 5/O or/O 6/O in/O the/O morning/O ./O 
So/O ,/O I/O might/O get/O up/O in/O the/O afternoon/O and/O he/O might/O telephone/O me/O and/O say/O ``/O What/O are/O you/O doing/O for/O dinner/O ?/O ''/O 
I/O would/O Come/O on/O over/O and/O we/O will/O go/O for/O a/O walk/O and/O go/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O Nothing/O ./O ''/O 
such-and-such/O a/O restaurant/O ./O ''/O 
The/O visits/O would/O be/O of/O that/O sort/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O ,/O over/O what/O period/O of/O time/O did/O that/O take/O place/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O up/O until/O 1938/O ,/O perhaps/O 1939/O ,/O I1don/O '/O t/O know/O ;/O quite/O late/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEi/PERSON ?/O 
./O 
1938/O or/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearing/O conducted/O by/O this/O committee/O regarding/O -LSB-/O William/PERSON Walter/PERSON -RSB-/PERSON Remington/PERSON ,/O there/O was/O testimony/O by/O Mr./O -LSB-/PERSON Howard/PERSON Allen/PERSON -RSB-/O Bridgman/PERSON that/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON was/O the/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O for/O the/O State/O of/O Tennessee/LOCATION ./O 
That/O was/O at/O the/O time/O that/O Remington/PERSON was/O employed/O at/O the/O Tennessee/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION Authority/LOCATION ./O 
And/O the/O period/O of/O time/O that/O Wellman/PERSON was/O the/O State/O organizer/O of/O Tenn-ee/O was/O during/O tl/O is/O period/O that/O you/O say/O he/O visited/O you/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O 1938/O and/O 1939/O ,/O and/O earlier/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON 's/O business/O was/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION on/O those/O occasions/O when/O he/O visited/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O way/O of/O knowing/O ./O 
My/O best/O memory/O is/O that/O he/O lived/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
My/O best/O memory/O would/O be/O that/O around/O 1939/O ,/O perhaps/O even/O 1940/O ,/O that/O he/O lived/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mind/O you/O ,/O I/O can/O not/O be/O exact/O becanue/O my/O memory/O is/O not/O that/O good/O on/O date/O -/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O ./O 
\/O VENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Remington/PERSON testified/O before/O this/O committee/O that/O he/O knew/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON and/O that/O he/O met/O him/O in/O Tennessee/LOCATION in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1937/O ,/O and/O again/O in/O June/O of/O that/O year/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O did/O lie/O visit/O you/O during/O the/O period/O of/O 1/O !/O 
17/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O I/O have/O no/O way/O of/O remembering/O that/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O way/O that/O I/O can/O tie/O it/O up/O in/O mv/O mind/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Having/O met/O with/O him/O as/O a/O member/O of/O Lhe/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O year/O of/O 1935/O ,/O it/O would/O seem/O no/O more/O than/O logical/O to/O expect/O that/O he/O discussed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION matters/O with/O you/O when/O he/O later/O met/O you/O and/O was/O a/O visitor/O in/O your/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O think/O that/O the/O mostMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
We/O would/O like/O to/O know/O about/O it/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O the/O case/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
1/O always/O thought/O of/O him/O as/O a/O kind/O of/O political/O commentator/O ,/O later/O ,/O because/O he/O read/O every/O newspaper/O that/O came/O out/O ./O 
I/O know/O he/O wrote/O some/O kind/O of/O articles/O ,/O and/O he/O gave/O me/O the/O impression/O of/O being/O ,/O later/O ,/O not/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION organizer/O but/O ome/O kind/O of/O professional/O political/O commentator/O ./O 
And/O if/O any/O politics/O were/O brought/O up/O in/O my/O house/O or/O when/O we/O met/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O his/O kind/O of/O comments/O on/O what/O was/O happening/O in/O the/O world/O ;/O that/O was/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TA.VENNER/O ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O leader/O of/O the/O group/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O ,/O the/O group/O within/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O any/O leader/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O there/O was/O a/O leader/O in/O the/O sense/O that/O you/O used/O the/O word/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3461/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O who/O would/O call/O the/O special/O meetings/O and/O act/O as/O chairman/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O treasurer/O of/O the/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
To/O whom/O did/O you/O pay/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
My/O only/O thought/O would/O be/O that/O it/O was/O to/O one/O of/O these/O members/O of/O the/O group/O within/O the/O group/O ,/O but/O who/O that/O was/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O much/O dues/O did/O you/O pay/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O it/O must/O have/O been/O a/O very/O slight/O amount/O ,/O perhaps/O 50/O cents/O or/O a/O dollar/O a/O week/O ,/O or/O something/O of/O that/O sort/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O required/O to/O subscribe/O to/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O asked/O to/O do/O that/O ,/O but/O if/O you/O were/O a/O poor/O actor/O you/O were/O n't/O going/O to/O pay/O $/O 10/O a/O year/O for/O a/O newspaper/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O subscribe/O to/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O maybe/O I/O did/O ,/O for/O 3/O months/O ./O 
You/O could/O get/O quarter/O subscriptions/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O very/O expensive/O item/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O made/O financial/O contributions/O of/O any/O character/O to/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O above/O the/O subscription/O ,/O above/O your/O subscription/O amounts/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODEIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember-Mr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Either/O while/O you/O were/O within/O the/O party/O or/O afterward/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O doing/O it/O for/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O been/O tapped/O ,/O I/O was/O tapped/O then/O ,/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O for/O a/O contribution/O to/O the/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
Someone/O might/O come/O up/O and/O say/O we/O are/O hard/O pressed/O ,/O you/O can/O give/O us/O or/O lend/O us/O $/O 25/O or/O $/O 50/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O during/O the/O period/O of/O the/O time/O that/O you/O were/O a/O poor/O actor/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O during/O the/O period/O when/O I/O first/O began/O to/O make/O money/O a/O ,/O a/O playwright/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
What/O period/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
January/O ,/O February/O ,/O March/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O you/O were/O requested/O to/O make/O donations/O to/O the/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
They/O came/O up/O frequently/O after/O that/O ,/O too/O ,/O and/O asked/O for/O donations/O ./O 
Mr./O TAX/O ENN/O ER/O ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O memory/O ./O 
I/O may/O have/O ,/O but/O not/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O memory/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O last/O contribution/O you/O made/O for/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O had/O to/O make/O a/O guess/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O some/O time/O in/O 1935/O ./O 
iMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Going/O back/O again/O to/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON ,/O you/O told/O us/O that/O you/O visited/O Tennessee/LOCATION ,/O and/O did/O you/O state/O that/O while/O you/O were/O there/O that/O you/O saw/O Wellman/ORGANIZATION 2/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O see/O him/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O had/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O your/O visit/O to/O Tennessee/LOCATION ?/O 
3462/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O when/O you/O come/O up/O from/O Mexico/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O you/O pass/O through/O Texas/LOCATION and/O you/O pass/O through/O certain/O States/O ,/O and/O anywhere/O in/O any/O State/O where/O I/O knew/O anyone/O ,/O I/O stopped/O and/O said/O hello/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O this/O visit/O made/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O make/O a/O guess/O 1937/O or/O 1938/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O Ted/PERSON Wellman/PERSON 's/O occupation/O in/O Tennessee/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O you/O visited/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O say/O of/O my/O own/O knowledge/O ,/O because/O of/O my/O own/O knowledge/O I/O thought/O that/O he/O was/O some/O kind/O of/O newspaper/O writer/O ./O 
There/O was/O some-I/O forget/O the/O name/O of/O it-there/O was/O some/O very/O liberal/O newspaper/O there/O ,/O with/O a/O very/O liberal/O editor/O ./O 
And/O I/O thought/O that/O he/O worked/O for/O that/O newspaper/O ./O 
In/O looking/O back/O now/O ,/O that/O would/O be/O my/O memory/O of/O my/O impression/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O occasion/O of/O your/O trip/O to/O Mexico/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O unhappily/O divorcing/O a/O wife/O ,/O and/O I/O wanted/O to/O go/O on/O a/O trip/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O mean/O to/O inquire/O into/O your/O personal/O matters/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O will/O tell/O you/O honestly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEr/O ./O 
Have/O you/O made/O any/O financial/O contributions/O other/O than/O membership/O dues/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODE.TS/O ./O 
No/O memory/O of/O any/O such/O contribution/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O since/O the/O days/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O T.AENNER/O ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O between/O 6/O and/O 8/O or/O 9/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O T/O i/O N/O xrN/O ./O 
Whlat/O were/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O terminated/O your/O party/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODeTS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O connected/O with/O what/O you/O would/O call/O or/O did/O call/O then/O ,/O the/O cultural/O front/O ,/O and/O it/O came/O to/O the/O point/O of/O where/O I/O thought/O if/O I/O ca/O n't/O respect/O these/O people/O on/O a/O so-called/O cultural/O basis/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O as/O literary/O or/O theater/O critics/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O I/O am/O doing/O here/O ./O 
I/O remember/O telling/O you/O that/O when/O my/O plays/O came/O out/O one/O after/O another/O ,/O they/O received/O fantastically/O bad/O notices/O ,/O although/O a/O play/O like/O Waiting/O for/O Lefty/O was/O widely/O used/O not/O only/O by/O the/O Communists/O but/O by/O all/O liberal/O organizations/O and/O trade-union/O movements/O ./O 
I/O not/O only/O disagreed/O with/O their/O critical/O statements/O of/O my/O work/O ,/O but/O I/O disagreed/O with/O their/O critical/O estimates/O of/O anybody/O 's/O work/O ,/O writers/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ,/O as/O I/O mentioned/O ,/O like/O Steinbeck/PERSON and/O Hemingway/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O a/O great/O number/O of/O fights/O about/O that/O ./O 
And/O I/O simply/O thought/O this/O is/O not/O for/O me/O ,/O there/O is/O no/O reason/O for/O me/O to/O be/O mixed/O up/O in/O there/O ;/O I/O am/O a/O playwright/O ;/O I/O have/O established/O myself/O as/O a/O playwright/O ;/O I/O have/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O work/O to/O do/O ;/O I/O have/O enough/O to/O say/O out/O of/O my/O own/O mind/O and/O heart/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O better/O leave/O ./O 
This/O would/O be/O the/O general/O attitude/O under/O which/O I/O left/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O be/O specific/O as/O to/O the/O month/O of/O the/O year/O in/O which/O you/O left/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O ail/O sorry/O ,/O '/O I/O ca/O n't/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O would/O guess/O it/O was/O somewhere/O in/O the/O latter/O half/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O :/O xNNiR/O ./O 
During/O the/O time/O of/O your/O affiliation/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O engage/O imnany/O special/O activity/O for/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
None/O that/O I/O remember/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEINNiER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O having/O been/O made/O chairman/O of/O the/O American/O -LRB-/O `/O onuinion/O '/O i/O to/O Investigate/O Labor/O and/O Social/O Conditions/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3463/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O distinctly/O remember/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O make/O a/O trip/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION as/O a/O member/O of/O that/O commission/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O that/O was/O in/O June/O of/O 1935/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O information/O in/O the/O files/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O this/O commission/O was/O composed/O of/O yourself/O as/O chairman/O ,/O representing/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O is/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODTrs/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O have/O that/O memory/O of/O it/O until/O you/O mentioned/O it/O the/O last/O time/O ./O 
It/O is/O correct/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O that/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O Commission/O of/O which/O you/O were/O the/O chairman/O were/O Fred/PERSON L./PERSON Gordo/PERSON ,/O secretary/O ,/O representing/O the/O League/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION ;/O also/O ,/O Manning/PERSON Johnson/PERSON of/O the/O Food/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION Industrial/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ;/O Herman/PERSON Reissig/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O American/O League/O Against/O War/O and/O Fascism/O ;/O Mary/PERSON Gruber/PERSON ,/O also/O of/O the/O American/O League/O Against/O War/O and/O Fascism/O ;/O Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Students/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ;/O Elsa/PERSON Waldman/PERSON of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Students/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ;/O Paul/PERSON Crosbie/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Ex-Servicemen/ORGANIZATION ;/O Lucille/PERSON Perry/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O Provisional/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION for/O Cuba/LOCATION ;/O Dora/PERSON Zucker/PERSON of/O International/ORGANIZATION Ladies/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Garment/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION ;/O Conrad/PERSON Komorowski/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O All/ORGANIZATION American/ORGANIZATION Anti-Imperialist/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ;/O Paul/PERSON Irving/PERSON of/O the/O Unemployed/ORGANIZATION Teachers/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ;/O Jose/PERSON Santag/PERSON ,/O representing/O 13/O Latin-Amneicain/O orgumzatiomii/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ;/O Mason/PERSON Shaffer/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O ;/O and/O Frank/PERSON Griffin/PERSON of/O the/O International/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Defense/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O any/O of/O these/O people/O before/O you/O made/O the/O trip/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION with/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O not/O one/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O any/O of/O them/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O did/O you/O discover/O their/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION while/O on/O your/O trip/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION or/O in/O a/O subsequent/O period/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O on/O the/O boat/O I/O discovered/O that/O some/O of/O them/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O names/O ,/O I/O just/O wrote/O them/O down/O ,/O and/O you/O did/O mention/O them/O the/O last/O time/O ./O 
I/O actually/O right/O now/O do/O not/O remember/O but/O about/O half/O of/O these/O people/O ./O 
I/O am/O hard/O put/O to/O place/O in/O my/O mind/O who/O some/O of/O these/O others/O were/O ./O 
But/O I/O would/O guess/O that/O the/O number/O of/O these/O persons/O were/O certain/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O us/O which/O of/O them/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O going/O to/O guess/O that/O Komorowski/PERSON was/O ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O guess/O that/O Manning/PERSON Johnson/PERSON was/O ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O guess/O that/O Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON was/O ./O 
And/O that/O is/O where/O I/O shall/O have/O to/O stop/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O was/O this/O commission/O chosen/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O think/O we/O should/O leave/O the/O record/O in/O that/O condition/O ,/O unless/O the/O witness/O has/O some/O knowledge/O about/O it/O ./O 
The/O fact/O that/O he/O said/O he/O would/O guess/O at/O it/O ,/O the/O record/O ought/O to/O be/O clarified/O on/O the/O three/O names/O that/O were/O mentioned/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O think/O the/O committee/O would/O want/O it/O to/O stand/O in/O that/O condition/O ./O 
See/O if/O you/O can/O clarify/O that/O ./O 
If/O not/O ,/O there/O is/O the/O mere/O fact/O that/O he/O is/O guessing/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O that/O any/O of/O the/O three/O names/O that/O you/O mentioned/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O Perty/O and/O ,/O if/O so/O ,/O you/O can/O name/O them/O ./O 
3464/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Read/O the/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O pending/O question/O was/O read/O by/O the/O official/O reporter/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O think/O that/O Komorowski/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O definitely/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O say/O you/O should/O think/O that/O Komorowski/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O upon/O what/O do/O you/O base/O that/O assumption/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O only/O nominally/O the/O chairman/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
When/O I/O got/O on/O the/O boat/O and/O the/O committee/O started/O for/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O I/O discovered/O ,/O should/O I/O say/O to/O my/O disgust/O ,/O that/O this/O man/O actually/O was/O the/O expert/O and/O I/O was/O the/O idealist/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ,/O that/O was/O connected/O ./O 
I/O was/O the/O idealist/O who/O had/O some/O kind/O of/O publicity/O value/O and/O he/O was/O the/O expert/O on/O Latin-American/O affairs/O ./O 
He/O spoke/O with/O such/O authority/O and/O such/O knowledge/O that/O I/O simply/O supposed/O that/O lie/O was/O ,/O if/O there/O were/O other/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION delegates/O on/O this/O committee/O ,/O that/O he/O was/O the/O top/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O that/O he/O spoke/O with/O such/O authority/O on/O Communist/O affairs/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O put/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O ever/O tell/O you/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O :/O they/O never/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
What/O else/O transpired/O on/O the/O voyage/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O Cuba/LOCATION that/O would/O lead/O you/O to/O believe/O that/O this/O individual/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O with/O him/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION affairs/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O but/O there/O were/O ./O 
what/O I/O should/O call/O tactical/O discussions/O ,/O what/O do/O you/O do/O when/O you/O get/O there/O ,/O what/O happens/O ,/O what/O kind/O of/O statements/O shall/O one/O give/O the/O pres/O And/O since/O this/O man/O led/O the/O discuIson/O ,/O since/O this/O man/O planned/O the/O tactics/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O he/O was/O a/O Conunit/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O and/O was/O really/O the/O head/O of/O the/O delegation/O ./O 
Mr./O KEIARNFY/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O by/O planning/O tactics/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O mean/O Communist/O Party/O tactics/O ?/O 
Mr./O OBETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O mean/O in/O relation/O to/O this/O particular/O expedition/O ,/O let/O 's/O call/O it/O ,/O this/O particular/O junket/O ./O 
I/O was/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O astonished/O to/O learn/O on/O the/O boat/O that/O when/O we/O got/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION we/O were/O going/O to/O be/O arrested/O ./O 
This/O was/O news/O to/O me/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O anything/O about/O that/O ,/O to/O make/O an/O example/O ./O 
So/O there/O would/O be/O a/O meeting/O `/O on/O what/O do/O we/O do/O when/O we/O get/O arrested/O ./O 
And/O this/O was/O the/O man/O who/O seemed/O to/O know/O what/O we/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O KE/PERSON IRNiEY/O ./O 
You/O were/O advised/O you/O were/O to/O be/O arrested/O ./O 
Did/O they/O tell/O you/O what/O you/O were/O to/O be/O arrested/O for/O ?/O 
On/O what/O grounds/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODE/O -RRB-/O TS/O ./O 
What/O grounds/O ?/O 
Well/O ,/O the/O grounds/O weie/O that/O we/O were/O per-ona/O non/O grata/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O Ki/PERSON ,/O ERXNEY/O ./O 
That/O covers/O a/O lot/O of/O grounds/O ,/O does/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O kind/O of/O what/O happened/O ./O 
Mr./O KF/O ./O 
./O 
xRNI/O Y./O Were/O you/O accused/O directly/O of/O being/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O Partyv/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Thlle/PERSON delegation/O was/O being/O accused/O of/O being/O a/O Communist/O delegation/O ,/O and/O the/O inception/O of/O the/O delegation/O ,/O when/O it/O was/O brought/O to/O my/O attention/O ,/O was/O that/O it/O was/O a/O broad/O front/O delegation/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3465/O If/O I/O am/O not/O mistaken/O ,/O this/O was/O the/O time/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION ,/O this/O was/O the/O time/O when/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION tried/O to/O work/O with/O all/O other/O liberal/O and/O left/O groups/O ./O 
Actually/O ,/O there/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O on/O this/O delegation/O who/O in/O my/O opinion/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O Communists/O or/O communisin/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O arrested/O or/O were/O the/O members/O of/O the/O delegation/O arrested/O by/O the/O Cuban/O authorities/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODnTS/O ./O 
We/O were/O promptly/O arrested/O and/O promptly/O lined/O up/O and/O marched/O to/O jail/O ./O 
Mr./O KE/O \/O RNEY/O ./O 
Were/O you/O asked/O whether/O you/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O not/O liy/O the/O police/O of/O Cuba/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O we/O were/O not/O asking/O anything/O ./O 
We/O were/O not/O told/O anything/O and/O not/O asked/O ./O 
We/O were/O just/O arrested/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNI/PERSON v./O Arrested/O and/O put/O in/O jail/O ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O charges/O placed/O against/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O We/O were/O held/O incommunicado/O except/O for/O a/O phone/O call/O or/O two/O for/O about/O 24/O hours/O and/O to/O see/O the/O American/O consul/O ./O 
And/O then/O I/O asked/O him/O with/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O honest/O indignation/O why/O we/O were/O arrested/O ,/O what/O this/O was/O aboul/O ,/O and/O it/O hadMr/O ./O 
KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Pardon/O me/O for/O interrupting/O ,/O but/O was/O this/O the/O time/O that/O you/O yourself/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Commnunist/O Party/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O might/O have/O been/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O ?/O 
time/O that/O you/O asked/O with/O honest/O indignation/O what/O it/O was/O all/O about/O Mr./O OUETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O the/O indignation/O was/O honest/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O went/O there/O as/O a/O citizen/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O go/O theie/O as/O a/O Communist/O Party/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O KE/O \/O RNEY/O ./O 
I/O inferred/O from/O your/O answers/O that/O the/O group/O was/O arrested/O because/O they/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O Pai/PERSON ty/O ./O 
Mr./O ODFTS/PERSON ./O 
We/O were/O n't/O told/O why/O we/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O after/O reading/O the/O newspaper/O when/O I/O got/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O because/O I/O could/O n't/O read/O the/O Spanish/O newspapers/O ,/O I/O learned/O that/O that/O is/O why/O we/O had/O been/O arrested/O ./O 
I/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O suspected-I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O be/O naive-I/O suspected/O that/O that/O is/O why/O we/O were/O arrested/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O see/O the/O Ameiican/O consul/O or/O talk/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O O.DET/O ./O 
I/O saw/O him/O one/O time/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O very/O coyly/O ,/O ``/O You/O know/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O ''/O 
A/O very/O coy/O gentleman/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O were/O held/O there/O for/O 24/O hours/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Twenty-four/O or/O 36/O ,/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
What/O happened/O after/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Then/O we/O were/O very/O carefully/O marched/O back/O to/O another/O boat/O going/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O we/O were/O on/O our/O way/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
It/O was/O not/O a/O pleasant/O experience/O ./O 
Mr./O KEANFY/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O not/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O later/O found/O out/O that/O the/O person/O originally/O selected/O to/O act/O as/O chairman/O of/O this/O commission/O was/O Mother/PERSON Bloor/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O why/O was/O it/O that/O Mother/PERSON Bloor/PERSON did/O not/O go/O through/O with/O the/O assignment/O ,/O or/O the/O proposed/O assignment/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O when/O I/O got/O back/O I/O had/O a/O real/O indignation/O because/O I/O thought/O that/O if/O one/O went/O down/O there/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O saying/O there/O is/O a/O horrible/O ,/O repressive/O movement/O here/O against/O intellectuals/O and/O col21546-52-pt/O ./O 
8-2/O 3466/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O lege/O students/O ,/O that/O one/O should/O fight/O out/O on/O that/O line/O ./O 
If/O you/O believed/O that/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O simply/O a/O tactic/O to/O get/O your/O name/O in/O the/O newspaper/O or/O a/O tactic/O to/O get/O some/O newspaper/O space/O ,/O but/O you/O really/O should/O fight/O about/O that/O ./O 
When/O the/O arrest/O took/O place/O the/O whole/O matter/O seemed/O to/O be/O dropped/O ./O 
So/O I/O ,/O simply/O on/O that/O matter/O ,/O I/O went/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION with/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O indignation/O ,/O talked/O really/O to/O very/O few/O members/O of/O the/O delegation/O going/O back/O on/O the/O boat/O ,/O and/O later/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O whom/O ,/O but/O spoke/O to/O someone/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O was/O rather/O aroused/O by/O this/O idea/O that/O we/O had/O been/O manhandled/O ,/O because/O we/O were/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O indignant/O because/O no/O one/O seemed/O to/O make/O a/O fight/O about/O that/O ./O 
During/O this/O time/O I/O also/O said/O it/O was/O very/O dangerous/O ,/O which/O it/O was/O ,/O because/O there/O were/O dozens/O of/O secret/O police/O there/O with/O machine/O guns/O ,/O some/O of/O them/O dressed/O as/O dock/O workers/O in/O overalls/O ./O 
I/O said/O it/O was/O t/O very/O dangerous/O matter/O and/O they/O said/O ,/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O it/O was/O so/O dangerous/O that/O we/O had/O originally/O intended/O to/O send/O Mother/PERSON Bloor/PERSON down/O as/O head/O of/O the/O delegation/O but/O it/O was/O so/O dangerous/O we/O did/O n't/O send/O her/O ./O ''/O 
She/O was/O an/O old/O lady/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
They/O sent/O you/O down/O as/O chairman/O instead/O of/O Mother/PERSON Bloor/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODF.TB/O ./O 
So/O I/O said/O he/O might/O have/O at/O least/O told/O me/O this/O and/O given/O me/O the/O chance/O to/O decide/O whether/O I/O wanted/O to/O face/O machine/O guns/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O it/O that/O told/O you/O that/O it/O had/O been/O the/O decision/O to/O send/O Mother/PERSON Bloor/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Somebody/O that/O came/O to/O see/O me/O or/O I/O visited/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O the/O same/O person/O that/O designated/O you/O as/O chairman/O in/O the/O first/O instance/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O who/O that/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functionary/O who/O was/O giving/O this/O explanation/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O guess/O it/O had/O to/O be/O ./O 
But/O who/O that/O was/O ,/O I/O honestly/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O actually/O ,/O this/O was/O nothing/O more/O than/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION idea/O to/O send/O this/O commission/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION for/O its/O own/O propaganda/O purposes/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O today/O ,/O with/O a/O little/O more/O sophistication/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEa/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O Manning/PERSON Johnson/PERSON ,/O to/O whom/O you/O referred/O as/O a/O person/O that/O you/O guessed/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O testified/O before/O this/O committee/O and/O admitted/O his/O former/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O ,/O and/O in/O the/O course/O of/O his/O testimony/O he/O stated/O :/O I/O was/O secretary/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION to/O Cuba/LOCATION and/O I/O was/O sent/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION to/O help/O the/O revolutionary/O forces/O there/O ./O 
I/O might/O sav/O from/O the/O point/O of/O view/O of/O background/O that/O Cubhaat/O that/O time/O was/O in/O a/O state/O of/O revolution/O ./O 
They/O had/O overthrown/O the/O government/O of/O Machado/PERSON and/O the/O Mendieta-Batista/LOCATION revolutionary/O junta/O haid/O come/O into/O po/O -/O r./O We/O were/O assigned/O to/O tour/O the/O islands/O and/O assist/O the/O Communist/O forces/O to/O overthrow/O this/O Mendieta-Batista/O junta/O and/O put/O in/O power/O Grau/PERSON San/PERSON Martin/PERSON and/O his/O group/O They/O considered/O the/O Grau/PERSON San/PERSON Martin/PERSON government/O would/O he/O a/O government/O that/O would/O permit/O Communists/O to/O operate/O openly/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O I/O can/O recall/O at/O the/O present/O time/O But/O I/O do/O know/O we/O were/O thiuwn/O in/O jail/O down/O there/O and/O I/O never/O will/O forget/O the/O experience/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Referring/O to/O your/O guess/O that/O Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O ,/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O what/O do/O you/O base/O it/O ,/O on/O what/O facts/O do/O you/O base/O your/O guess/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3467/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O quick/O ,/O smart/O girl/O ./O 
Knew/O how/O to/O -/O move/O tactically/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
VELDE/O ./O 
Are/O all/O smart/O ,/O quick/O people/O Commnunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O certain/O kind/O of/O professionalism/O ./O 
There/O I/O must/O adis/O a/O certain/O kind/O of/O professionalism/O in/O certain/O situations/O ./O 
nmit/O I/O never/O had/O it/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O why/O this/O whole/O delegation/O was/O taken/O naive/O ,/O I/O 1/O was/O that/O ./O 
about/O nothing/O I/O knew/O over/O by/O other/O people/O ./O 
did/O n't/O even/O know/O what/O we/O were/O going/O into/O ./O 
So/O my/O guess/O about/O her/O comes/O from/O simply/O her/O tactical/O smartness/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O had/O a/O conversation/O or/O several/O conversations/O with/O her/O ,/O I/O suppose/O ,/O on/O the/O trip/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O she/O ever/O mention/O that/O she/O was/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
They/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O just/O how/O this/O commission/O was/O created/O ./O 
and/O the/O circumstances/O ,/O and/O more/O about/O the/O circumstances/O ,/O under/O which/O you/O were/O designated/O as/O chairman/O ?/O 
Mr./O OmDTS/O ./O 
I/O listened/O very/O carefully/O to/O what/O you/O read/O there/O ,/O the/O statement/O of/O Manning/PERSON Johnson/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O talking/O awfully/O big/O ./O 
Hie/PERSON is/O talking/O awfully/O big/O in/O a/O sense/O that/O ,/O or/O 10/O or/O whatever/O the/O number/O is/O left/O and/O hlberal/O people/O from/O Ne.v/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION could/O go/O down/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION and/O change/O the/O course/O of/O this/O horrible/O Cuban/O revolution/O ./O 
This/O is/O very/O big/O talk/O ./O 
If/O we/O were/O going/O to/O do/O what/O Mr./O Johnison/PERSON said/O ,/O we/O certainly/O should/O not/O have/O announced/O in/O a/O public/O press/O that/O we/O were/O all/O getting/O on/O a/O boat/O and/O going/O down/O there/O to/O make/O a/O fuss/O ./O 
So/O my/O simple/O point/O is/O that/O the/O point/O of/O the/O mission/O could/O not/O have/O been/O what/O lie/O said/O ./O 
that/O we/O were/O going/O to/O go/O in/O and/O take/O over/O anything/O ,/O or/O contact/O anyone/O ./O 
I/O suppose/O in/O the/O matter/O of/O common/O sense/O if/O you/O would/O contact/O anybody/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O that/O you/O would/O go/O down/O there/O silently/O and/O slip/O in/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O purpose/O in/O going/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION on/O this/O mission/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
The/O purpose/O that/O attracted/O me/O was/O that/O there/O were/O fears/O ,/O oppressive/O measures/O taken/O against/O thousands/O of/O intellectuals/O and/O college/O students/O ./O 
They/O were/O thrown/O into/O jail/O ,/O under/O the/O previous/O Machado/PERSON regime/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O horrible/O regime/O ./O 
I/O then/O was/O glad/O to/O go/O down/O in/O the/O sense/O of/O ,/O if/O nothing/O else/O did/O happen/O ,/O we/O would/O dramatize/O what/O the/O issues/O were/O down/O there/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O the/O stories/O that/O were/O coming/O out/O were/O very/O garbled/O ./O 
No/O one/O know/O what/O was/O happening/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O frankly/O think/O that/O later/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Embassy/ORGANIZATION straightened/O out/O the/O whole/O thing/O and/O was/O a/O salutary/O and/O moderating/O influence/O on/O the/O situation/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
What/O did/O you/O propose/O to/O do/O about/O it/O when/O you/O went/O down/O there/O ?/O 
What/O did/O you/O have/O in/O your/O mind/O ,/O what/O was/O your/O purpose/O in/O going/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O guess/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O our/O arrival/O would/O encourage/O and/O hearten/O certain/O sections/O of/O the/O Cuban/LOCATION people/O in/O the/O sense/O of/O saving/O ,/O you/O see/O ,/O here/O are/O people/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION who/O are/O interested/O in/O you/O and/O your/O problems/O and/O your/O employment/O ./O 
That/O ,/O I/O would/O guess/O ,/O would/O be/O tlie/O best/O point/O ,/O the/O best/O point/O of/O such/O a/O delegation/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O have/O a/O plan/O or/O a/O program/O as/O to/O the/O course/O of/O conduct/O when/O you/O got/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O to/O my/O surprise/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O before/O ,/O the/O plan/O was/O that/O we/O were/O going/O to/O get/O arrested/O ,/O which/O I/O did/O not/O know/O about/O ./O 
I/O must/O 3468/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O admit/O I/O was-let/O me/O admit/O I/O was/O politically/O extremely/O naive/O ,/O and/O I/O remember/O distinctly/O the/O night/O before/O the/O boat/O docked/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O festive/O occasion/O on/O an/O excursion/O boat/O ,/O we/O were/O called/O together/O and/O told/O ,/O I/O behei/O e/O by/O Komorowski/PERSON ,/O that/O this/O is/O what/O was/O going/O to/O happen/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O found/O that/O you/O were/O not/O in/O command/O of/O your/O own/O commission/O but/O that/O Komorowski/PERSON was/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNIE/PERSON ,/O ./O 
And/O that/O it/O was/O known/O that/O you/O were/O to/O be/O arrested/O before/O you/O reached/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O was/O part/O of/O the/O plan/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O say/O this/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Evidently/O a/O lot/O of/O these/O people/O had/O far/O more/O background/O than/O I/O did/O in/O political/O scuffling/O ,/O and/O they/O knew/O that/O that/O was/O going/O to/O happen/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
It/O was/O particularly/O in/O that/O sense/O that/O I/O meant/O I/O was/O politically/O namv/O '/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEXXNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O if/O it/O was/O planned/O that/O your/O group/O should/O be/O arrested/O ,/O I/O mean/O part/O of/O the/O plans/O of/O your/O commission/O ,/O then/O this/O was/O nothing/O more/O than/O a/O propaganda/O stunt/O ,/O is/O n't/O t/O hat/O true/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
It/O finally/O turned/O out/O that/O way/O ./O 
It/O finally/O turned/O out/O the/O way/O you/O say/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O parlance/O of/O everyday/O language/O ,/O you/O were/O known/O as/O the/O fall/O guy/O ,/O is/O that/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
A/O little/O bit/O ./O 
A/O little/O bit/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Komorowski/PERSON had/O definite/O knowledge/O that/O you/O were/O going/O to/O be/O arrested/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
He/O simply/O seemed/O to/O hax/O e/O sufficient/O political/O background/O to/O know/O that/O that/O was/O what/O was/O going/O to/O happen/O ./O 
And/O lie/O had/O that/O much/O grace/O to/O say/O the/O night/O before/O the/O boat/O ,/O lands/O to/O be/O prepared/O for/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O lie/O tell/O you/O that/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O the/O way/O you/O learned/O about/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O he/O the/O substance/O of/O what/O he/O said/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O certainly/O the/O way/O I/O learned/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O T/O _/O VEINxNER/O ./O 
Now/O ./O 
you/O have/O spoken/O several/O times/O of/O being/O rather/O naive/O in/O political/O matters/O yourself/O ,/O and/O others/O such/O as/O Komorowski/PERSON being/O experienced/O ./O 
You/O are/O actually/O referring/O there/O to/O experience/O in/O Communist/O Party/O tactics/O ,/O are/O n't/O you/O ?/O 
You/O are/O not/O speaking/O of/O experience/O in/O the/O broad/O field/O of/O politics/O ,/O but/O you/O are/O speaking/O of/O Komorowski/PERSON 's/O Cot/O omnnmunist/O Party/O tactics/O and/O experience/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETI/PERSON ./O 
I/O aln/O actually/O speaking/O of/O both/O ,/O of/O both/O ./O 
There/O are/O Communist/O Party/O tat/O '/O ./O 
cs/O which/O are/O exclusively/O their/O own/O and/O my/O knowledge/O would/O he/O that/O there/O ai/O e/O iommunist/O Party/O tactics/O which/O are/O shared/O typically/O by/O many/O polticians/O ,/O because/O they/O are/O also/O politicians/O ./O 
They/O would/O also/O be/O versed/O in/O the/O tactics/O of/O solidifying/O trade-unionism/O ,/O which/O is/O again/O shared/O by/O many/O non-C/O -LRB-/O omuinnist/O trade-unionists/O ./O 
There/O is/O simply/O professional/O know-how/O in/O all/O of/O those/O things/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENN/PERSON I./PERSON You/PERSON have/O told/O us/O about/O your/O experience/O when/O you/O returned/O ,/O and/O you/O met/O a/O person/O who/O you/O ijudged/O to/O be/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION who/O told/O you/O that/O the/O plan/O originally/O was/O to/O send/O someone/O else/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O commission/O ./O 
Was/O that/O the/O same/O person/O who/O placed/O you/O on/O this/O commission/O to/O begin/O with/O ,/O or/O suggested/O to/O you/O that/O you/O accept/O such/O a/O position/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODE'TS/O ./O 
It/O is/O possible/O ,/O but/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
It/O is/O possible/O ,/O but/O I/O actually/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O thins/O point/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3469/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O was/O it/O that/O you/O met/O this/O individual/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
That/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O either/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O chairman/O of/O this/O committee/O ,/O did/O you/O make/O a/O report/O to/O anyone/O on/O your/O return/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Whoever/O this/O person/O was/O ,/O the/O extent/O of/O my/O report/O I/O have/O told/O you/O ./O 
I/O was/O quite/O indignant/O about/O how/O routinely/O ,/O how/O cut/O and/O dried/O the/O matter/O seemed/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O that/O they/O knew/O in/O advance/O that/O it/O was/O going/O to/O be/O dangerous/O ,/O and/O I/O made/O some/O statement/O about/O the/O very/O disgraceful/O conduct/O of/O one/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O delegation/O ./O 
I/O told/O you/O about/O that/O the/O last/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O indignant/O about/O the/O actions/O of/O the/O Cuban/O police/O or/O the/O actions/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O for/O leading/O you/O into/O such/O a/O situation/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O a/O 50-50/O matter/O ./O 
I/O was/O indignant/O with/O the/O thing/O myself/O and/O indignant/O that/O ./O 
a/O really/O ,/O let/O my/O say/O ,/O idealistic/O fight/O was/O not/O being/O made/O about/O this/O matter/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O see/O it/O as/O a/O cut/O and/O dried/O matter/O ,/O you/O do/O something/O and/O then/O you/O turn/O your/O back/O on/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Your/O resentment/O was/O not/O directed/O against/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION for/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O ,/O leading/O you/O into/O such/O a/O trap/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O directed/O equally/O against/O the/O Cuban/O police/O and/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O ,/O Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O that/O when/O you/O returned/O from/O that/O junket/O that/O you/O made/O a/O report/O to/O somebody/O that/O you/O do/O n't/O now/O remember/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O someone/O I/O spoke/O to/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O not/O say/O it/O was/O a/O formal/O report/O ,/O because/O that/O would/O have/O beenMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O who/O procured/O you/O to/O go/O ?/O 
Mr./O -LRB-/O DETS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Who/O paid/O your/O expenses/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O paid/O my/O own/O expenses/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O get/O it/O back/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O on/O this/O idealistic/O swing/O I/O would/O n't/O think/O of/O taking/O any/O expenses/O ,/O I/O would/O pay/O my/O own/O ./O 
I/O am/O certain/O I/O paid/O my/O own/O expenses/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O recall/O now/O who/O procured/O you/O to/O go/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O was/O approached/O by/O someone/O and/O asked/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O anxious/O to/O get/O out/O of/O the/O country/O ,/O I/O was/O anxious/O to/O take/O a/O trip/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O beautiful/O trip/O on/O the/O water/O ./O 
My/O mother/O had/O just/O died/O 3/O or/O 4/O weeks/O before/O and/O I/O went/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
It/O seems/O so/O strange/O to/O me/O that/O you/O would/O make/O a/O trip/O of/O that/O significance/O at/O the/O behest/O of/O some/O individual/O ,/O and/O come/O back/O from/O the/O trip/O after/O having/O that/O experience/O and/O make/O a/O report/O to/O that/O individual/O ,/O and/O now/O you/O ca/O n't/O recall/O who/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O say/O so/O ,/O if/O I/O did/O remember/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O you/O supposed/O to/O contact/O when/O you/O reached/O Cuba/LOCATION Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
We/O had/O some/O letters/O to/O various/O college/O professors/O and/O students/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O packet/O of/O letters/O ,/O and/O when/O the/O police/O boarded/O the/O ship/O these/O letters/O were/O scuttled/O ,/O they/O were/O torn/O up/O and/O thrown/O overboard/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O these/O letters/O from/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
They/O would/O be/O from/O people/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
3470/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O FRAznm/O ./O 
Who/O gave/O you/O the/O letters/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O have/O them/O ,/O Komorowski/PERSON had/O them/O ./O 
But/O I/O remember/O they/O were/O passed/O like/O a/O hot/O plate/O from/O one/O to/O the/O other/O ./O 
The/O police/O were/O in/O earnest/O boarding/O that/O ship/O with/O machine/O guns/O ,/O and/O passed/O around/O and/O it/O got/O to/O be/O like/O a/O scene/O from/O a/O Charlie/PERSON Chaplin/PERSON movie/O ./O 
They/O were/O torn/O up/O and/O thrown/O overboard/O ./O 
I/O just/O remembered/O that/O for/O the/O first/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
So/O you/O did/O n't/O know/O who/O you/O were/O going/O down/O there/O to/O see/O ?/O 
Mr./O OnDrs/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Yet/O you/O were/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O the/O nominal/O chairman/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O let/O that/O happen/O today/O ,/O let/O me/O say/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O any/O articles/O for/O publication/O about/O the/O trip/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O wrote/O an/O article/O for/O the/O New/O York/O Evening/O Post/O ./O 
I/O was/O also/O an/O accredited/O correspondent/O for/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Evening/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION on/O that/O trip/O ./O 
And/O my/O memory/O is/O that/O I/O wrote/O some/O lengthy/O article/O for/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O other/O articles/O written/O by/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O possible/O there/O was/O a/O pamphlet/O written/O by/O two/O or/O three/O persons/O ,/O of/O which/O I/O was/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O other/O persons/O who/O assisted/O in/O the/O writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O guess/O a/O very/O interesting/O man/O named/O Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Give/O us/O the/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETs/PERSON ./O 
Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O a/O Communist/O ,/O but/O he/O was/O a/O fighting/O liberal/O and/O a/O very/O interesting/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O hand/O you/O a/O pamphlet/O entitled/O ``/O Rifle/O Rule/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O ''/O by/O Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON and/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ODETrs/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O that/O is/O it/O ./O 
That/O is/O more/O than/O I/O had/O in/O my/O files/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O that/O part/O of/O the/O pamphlet/O that/O you/O see/O on/O page/O 11/O ,/O beginning/O at/O page/O 11/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O tell/O you/O honestly/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O I/O did/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O wrote/O the/O New/O York/O Post/O article/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
When/O the/O witness/O has/O finished/O with/O that/O ,/O will/O you/O let/O me/O see/O it/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
At/O the/O conclusion/O ,/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O pamphlet/O is/O a/O report/O entitled/O ``/O Report/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION to/O Investigate/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION and/O Social/O Conditions/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O which/O appears/O the/O name/O ``/O American/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION to/O Investigate/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION and/O Social/O Conditions/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ,/O chairman/O ,/O Manning/PERSON Johnson/PERSON ,/O secretary/O ,/O ''/O and/O giving/O the/O names/O of/O the/O other/O members/O of/O it/O ./O 
On/O page/O 31/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O last/O page/O ,/O is/O this/O statement/O :/O The/O provisional/O committee/O for/O Cuba/LOCATION was/O organized/O precisely/O for/O the/O task/O of/O unifying/O the/O efforts/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O for/O assistance/O in/O the/O struggle/O of/O the/O Cuban/LOCATION people/O for/O freedom/O ./O 
It/O 1iespecially/O vital/O that/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O help/O ,/O for/O the/O way/O to/O freedom/O is/O barred/O primarily/O by/O American/O imperialist/O domination/O of/O Cuba/LOCATION Did/O you/O write/O that/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3471/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O certainly/O did/O not/O write/O that/O ./O 
I/O know/O some/O of/O the/O facts/O about/O that/O situation/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O write/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O which/O put/O out/O that/O report/O over/O your/O name/O ,/O were/O n't/O you/O aware/O of/O that/O language/O and/O did/O n't/O you/O approve/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O here/O that/O it/O says/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O commission/O ,/O has/O written/O a/O story/O of/O what/O happened/O to/O the/O commission/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
Here/O we/O want/O to/O present/O only/O your/O conclusions/O ./O 
So/O it/O is/O quite/O apparent/O to/O me/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O write/O that/O ./O 
But/O after/O ,/O what/O I/O am/O reputed/O to/O have/O written/O ,/O there/O is/O this/O extra/O statement/O by/O some/O executive/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O recognize/O fully/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O ,/O that/O this/O was/O all/O a/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION propaganda/O ,/O that/O it/O was/O embarking/O upon/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Except/O that/O I/O still/O right/O now/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O this/O was/O exclusively/O a/O Communist/O affair/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O I/O am/O almost/O certain/O that/O Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON is/O not/O and/O was/O not/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O well/O known/O for/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O it/O uses/O other/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Was/O Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON on/O the/O mission/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O he/O was/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Odet./PERSON ,/O who/O got/O you/O out/O of/O jail/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O give/O you/O my/O guess/O about/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O door/O just/O opened/O and/O you/O were/O turned/O out/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Pardon/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Did/O they/O open/O the/O doors/O and/O turn/O you/O out/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O :/O they/O very/O carefully/O waited/O until/O another/O ship/O was/O ready/O and/O carefully/O under/O guard/O marched/O us/O on/O the/O ship/O ,/O put/O us/O on/O the/O ship/O and/O said/O do/O n't/O come/O back/O again/O ./O 
I/O said/O we/O will/O come/O back/O and/O I/O will/O bring/O people/O you/O ca/O n't/O touch/O ./O 
I/O will/O bring/O famous/O liberals/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
And/O that/O is/O what/O I/O wanted/O to/O do/O ./O 
But/O that/O never/O happened/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Was/O there/O ever/O any/O formal/O charge/O made/O against/O you/O while/O you/O were/O in/O jail/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
None/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O having/O written/O any/O other/O articles/O relating/O to/O a/O commission/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O the/O one/O in/O the/O New/O York/O Evening/O Post/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O mean/O in/O addition/O to/O those/O you/O have/O named/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O have/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O writing/O an/O article/O for/O New/O Masses/O on/O the/O subject/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O show/O you/O a/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O an/O issue/O of/O New/O Masses/O for/O July/O 16/O ,/O 1935/O ,/O where/O there/O appears/O an/O article/O entitled/O ``/O What/O Happened/O to/O Us/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O ''/O by/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O it/O ,/O please/O ,/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O wrote/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
This/O one/O ,/O I/O know/O I/O wrote/O ./O 
When/O I/O read/O it/O ,/O I/O recognize/O my/O style/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O wrote/O that/O article/O for/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
3472/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O could/O only/O write/O this/O if/O I/O were/O asked/O to/O ,/O and/O I/O must/O have/O been/O asked/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O person/O that/O asked/O you/O to/O write/O that/O article/O for/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O guess/O it/O would/O be/O one/O of/O the/O editors/O of/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
I/O knew/O a/O little/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O a/O man/O named/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON ,/O and/O it/O might/O have/O been/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON who/O came/O up/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O quite/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O article/O you/O summed/O up/O your/O adventure/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION in/O part/O as/O follows/O :/O This/O impartial/O commission/O of/O investigation/O has/O shown/O its/O uncertainty/O of/O purpose/O by/O being/O honored/O by/O deportation/O by/O the/O present/O Cuban/LOCATION military/O dictatorship/O in/O collusion/O with/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Embassy/ORGANIZATION officials/O Their/O collusion/O is/O clearly/O marked/O out/O by/O their/O negative/O response/O to/O our/O call/O for/O help/O ./O 
I/O am/O interested/O in/O the/O term/O used/O in/O referring/O to/O your/O commission/O as/O an/O impartial/O commission/O of/O investigation/O ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O this/O commission/O which/O was/O in/O fact/O headed/O by/O Komorowski/PERSON ,/O though/O you/O were/O used/O as/O a/O cover/O for/O it/O ,/O was/O actually/O an/O impartial/O commission/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O that/O although/O it/O had/O all/O sorts/O of/O left/O and/O liberal/O elements/O in/O it/O ,/O that/O I/O would/O say/O now/O that/O the/O commission/O was/O definitely/O slanted/O ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION slanted/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNRR/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION controlled/O under/O the/O de/O facto/O leadership/O of/O Komorowski/PERSON ,/O was/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODFrTS/O They/O do/O n't/O quite/O do/O it/O that/O way/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
There/O is/O always/O a/O certain/O ,/O what/O I/O call/O a/O democratic/O procedure/O ./O 
Things/O are/O put/O to/O a/O vote/O ./O 
The/O only/O thing/O is/O that/O it/O doe-n/O '/O t/O help/O to/O put/O thimus/O to/O a/O vote/O and/O they/O have/O the/O know-how/O and/O you/O do/O n't/O have/O the/O know-how/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O the/O equivalent/O of/O telling/O you/O what/O to/O do/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O oui/O who/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O know-how/O ,/O so/O you/O had/O to/O rely/O upon/O people/O that/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNsY/O ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O I/O just/O hastily/O scanned/O your/O article/O in/O the/O pamphlet/O entitled/O ``/O Rifle/O Rule/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ,/O ''/O by/O Carleton/PERSON Beals/PERSON and/O Clifford/PERSON Odets/PERSON ,/O your/O article/O headed/O l/O ``/O acline-uiii/O Reception/O ./O ''/O 
Some/O few/O minutes/O ago/O you/O testified/O as/O to/O your/O indignant/O feeling/O against/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O was/O divided/O 50-S1/O against/O the/O police/O for/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O you/O were/O treated/O ./O 
I/O can/O see/O in/O this/O article/O over/O your/O name/O the/O indignant/O manner/O in/O which/O you/O write/O concerning/O your/O treatment/O by/O the/O Cuban/O police/O ./O 
But/O I/O fail/O to/O -/O ee/O any/O indignant/O protest/O of/O yours/O in/O this/O article/O ,/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION used/O you/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O some/O time/O ago/O ,/O as/O a/O fall/O guy/O ./O 
If/O there/O is/O ,/O I/O wish/O you/O would/O point/O it/O out/O to/O me/O ./O 
iMr/O ./O 
ODETS/PERSON ./O 
All/O that/O happened/O there/O was/O that/O I/O simply/O did/O n't/O know/O about/O this/O all/O until/O later/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O realization/O of/O it/O and/O did/O not/O really/O know/O what/O happened/O ./O 
When/O it/O did/O happen/O ,/O I/O moved/O out/O of/O the/O Commnunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O found/O out/O about/O it/O ,/O did/O you/O make/O any/O effort/O to/O change/O your/O statement/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O made/O no/O effort/O to/O change/O my/O statement/O ./O 
I/O should/O think/O it/O would/O have/O been/O much/O too/O late/O ./O 
Mr./O TA1/O ENNER/O ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O when/O von/O discovered/O the/O real/O facts/O relating/O to/O the/O mission/O to/O Cuba/LOCATION that/O you/O withdrew/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 3473/O Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
A/O short/O time/O after/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O this/O experience/O have/O any/O motivating/O effect/O upon/O your/O decision/O ,/O to/O either/O stay/O in/O or/O get/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/O Pal/O ty/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O it/O had/O considerable/O effect/O on/O my/O decision/O ./O 
I/O must/O admit/O frankly/O I/O resented/O the/O professionalism/O ./O 
I/O thought/O ,/O let/O me/O say/O it/O this/O way/O ,/O in/O a/O certain/O moral/O and/O idealistic/O level/O ,/O and/O I/O resented/O the/O professionalism/O of/O the/O cut/O and/O dried/O way/O in/O which/O this/O was/O done/O ./O 
I/O simply/O said/O this/O is/O not/O for/O me/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O a/O professional/O businessman/O ,/O my/O business/O is/O writing/O plays/O and/O I/O better/O get/O out/O ,/O of/O this/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O le/O used/O ./O 
And/O if/O this/O is/O an/O example/O ,/O the/O expedition/O was/O largely/O responsible/O for/O me/O leaving/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
But/O that/O article/O was/O written/O before/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O OD.Trs/O ./O 
I/O guess/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TA.ENNER/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O return/O from/O Cuba/LOCATION Mr./O OET/O `/O r./O I/O guess/O this/O all/O happened/O in/O June/O of/O 1935-June/O or/O maybe/O eai/O ly/O July/O ./O 
Mr./O T.A/PERSON EXNNER/PERSON ./O 
Doe/PERSON -/O that/O aid/O you/O in/O any/O way/O in/O stating/O just/O what/O month/O it/O was/O that/O you/O left/O the/O Comiuinist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION '/O Mr./O ODET/O -/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O will/O say/O again/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O it/O would/O be/O in/O the/O latter/O half/O of/O 1./O :95/O ,/O the/O year/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O TA.VEiXNNER/O ./O 
Did/O you/O advise/O anyone/O in/O writing/O or/O verbally/O of/O your/O intention/O to/O withdraw/O from/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O have/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O until/O half-past/O two/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 12:20/O p./O m./O ,/O the/O hearing/O was/O recessed/O until/O 2/O :/O 30/O p./O m./O the/O same/O day/O ./O -RRB-/O 
AFTERNOON/O SESSION/O -LRB-/O The/O subcommittee/O reconvened/O at/O 3:10/O p./O m./O ,/O with/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O chairman/O ,/O and/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Come/O to/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O CHaRm.AN/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O at/O this/O point/O to/O have/O made/O a/O part/O of/O the/O record/O information/O contained/O in/O the/O files/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O in/O the/O files/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O regarding/O several/O of/O those/O who/O participated/O as/O members/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION To/ORGANIZATION Investigate/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION and/O Social/O Conditions/O in/O Cuba/LOCATION ./O 
Jose/PERSON Santiago/PERSON ,/O as/O shown/O by/O the/O committee/O files/O ,/O was/O a/O candidate/O for/O the/O State/O assembly/O for/O the/O Seventeenth/O District/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION County/LOCATION on/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ticket/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O of/O November/O 2/O ,/O 1936/O ,/O at/O page/O 5/O ./O 
Frank/PERSON Griffin/PERSON was/O a/O candidate/O for/O district/O attorney/O ,/O Kings/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O on/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ticket/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O of/O October/O 19/O ,/O 1935/O ,/O at/O page/O 5/O ./O 
Celeste/PERSON Strack/PERSON was/O a/O candidate/O on/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ticket/O for/O nomination/O to/O the/O office/O of/O Representative/O to/O Congress/ORGANIZATION from/O the/O Thirteenth/O Congressional/O District/O for/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O in/O 1940/O ./O 
Mr./O Odets/PERSON ,/O in/O your/O earlier/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O you/O referred/O to/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O your/O plays/O had/O been/O received/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O criticism/O which/O you/O said/O your/O 3474/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O plays/O received/O ./O 
I/O recall/O that/O you/O stated/O that/O your/O play/O ,/O Waiting/O for/O Lefty/O ,/O was/O referred/O to/O as/O a/O Trotskyite/O production/O ,/O and/O that/O that/O was/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O that/O impelled/O you/O to/O fall/O out/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
You/O have/O stated/O today/O in/O your/O testimony/O that/O the/O criticisms/O that/O your/O productions/O received/O from/O the/O Communist/O press/O were/O instrumental/O in/O your/O taking/O the/O stand/O ,/O and/O finally/O determining/O that/O you/O would/O break/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O our/O examination/O of/O the/O Communist/O press/O ,/O we/O have/O been/O unable/O to/O find/O any/O statement/O that/O your/O play/O ,/O Waiting/O for/O Lefty/O ,/O was/O ever/O referred/O to/O by/O way/O of/O criticsm/O as/O a/O Trotskyite/O play/O ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O thought/O you/O had/O a/O clipping/O that/O would/O so/O indicate/O ./O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O left/O Washington/LOCATION the/O last/O time/O I/O was/O here/O I/O went/O through/O my/O press/O clipping/O books/O and/O found/O a/O number-in/O fact/O ,/O I/O found/O for/O every/O play/O that/O I/O produced/O very/O bad/O critical/O reception/O from/O the/O left/O ./O 
So/O ,/O as/O of/O two/O or/O three/O nights/O ago/O ,/O I/O copied/O some/O of/O these/O out/O in/O my/O own/O handwriting/O ,/O on/O a/O pad/O ,/O and/O brought/O them/O along/O ./O 
I/O found/O that/O the/O phrase/O ``/O Trotskyite/O tendencies/O ''/O had/O been/O marked/O down/O as/O left/O tendencies/O ,/O that/O I/O had/O better/O be/O careful/O of/O left/O tendencies/O ,/O which/O in/O those/O days/O meant/O that/O one/O had/O better/O be/O careful/O not/O to/O be/O a/O Trotskyite/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O it/O was/O your/O interpretation/O that/O the/O criticism/O meant/O Trotskyite/O although/O there/O was/O no/O actual/O reference/O to/O Trotskyite/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O a/O rather/O amusing/O detail/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O papers/O was/O Yiddish/O ,/O from/O a/O paper/O called/O the/O Daily/O Freiheit/O ,/O which/O was/O or/O is/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O the/O paper/O is/O still/O in/O existence/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O Yiddish/O Daily/O Worker/O ./O 
My/O memory/O would/O be/O in/O that/O ,/O in/O the/O translation/O of/O that/O ,/O the/O actual/O phrase/O Trotskyite/O was/O used/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEER/PERSON ./O 
You/O spoke/O of/O the/O severity/O of/O the/O criticisms/O ./O 
The/O criticisms/O that/O you/O referred/O to/O were/O criticisms/O of/O a/O technical/O character/O regarding/O your/O plays/O ,/O were/O they/O not/O ,/O as/O distinguished/O from/O the/O criticism/O of/O your/O ability/O and/O your/O skill/O in/O portraying/O the/O characters/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O this/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O :/O I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O you/O a/O few/O of/O them/O ,/O and/O put/O a/O few/O of/O them/O in/O the/O record/O by/O reading/O them/O ,/O and/O then/O let/O you/O make/O your/O own/O judgment/O of/O those/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O they/O are/O generally/O all/O around/O very/O bad/O notices/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O generally/O bad/O ./O 
Was/O there/O a/O period/O of/O time/O in/O which/O the/O Communist/O press/O seemed/O to/O change/O its/O attitude/O regarding/O your/O plays/O ?/O 
Mr./O ODETS/PERSON ./O 
