COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O THE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 10/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O NOVEMBER/O 12/O AND/O 13/O ,/O 1952/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 21643/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1952/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O IIOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ./O 
Chairman/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION HAROLD/LOCATION H./LOCATION VELDE/LOCATION ,/O Illinois/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O Loris/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOiHN/O W./LOCATION CARRINGTON/LOCATION ,/O Clerk/O of/O Commnittee/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O Page/O November/O 12/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Abram/PERSON S./PERSON Burrows/PERSON -----------/O November/O 13/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O testimony/O of/O Karan/PERSON Morley/PERSON -------------------/O III/O 4471/O 4503/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OFITHE/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 10/O TUESDAY/O ,/O NOVEMBER/O 12/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 11/O :/O 20/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O and/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Come/O to/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O Reporter/O ,/O will/O you/O let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O ,/O acting/O under/O the/O authority/O vested/O in/O me/O by/O the/O resolution/O establishing/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O have/O set/O up/O a/O subcommittee/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O hearing/O today/O composed/O of/O Messrs./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Velde/O ,/O and/O myself/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O all/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Abram/PERSON S./PERSON Burrows/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O be/O sworn/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ABRAM/PERSON S./PERSON BURROWS/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O MARTIN/O GANG/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
Abram/PERSON S./PERSON Burrows/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O Martin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O December/O 18/O ,/O 1910/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O address/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
1161/O York/O Avenue/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O briefly/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
4471/O 4472/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O elementary/O school/O ,/O high/O school/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION and/O in/O Manhattan/LOCATION and/O in/O Brooklyn/LOCATION ;/O went/O to/O College/O of/O the/O City/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O NYU/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Finance/ORGANIZATION ,/O Pace/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Accounting/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O writer/O and/O director/O in/O the/O theater/O ,/O and/O I/O also/O appear/O periodically/O as/O a/O performer/O on/O television/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O what/O the/O record/O of/O your/O employment/O has/O been/O since/O ,/O say/O ,/O 1936/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O 1936/O I/O gave/O up/O accounting/O and/O was/O in/O a/O business/O called/O the/O woven-label/O business/O ,/O in/O which/O I/O did/O n't/O do/O very/O well/O ./O 
Then/O I/O worked/O as/O a/O salesman/O in/O this/O woven-label/O company/O for/O a/O while/O ,/O and/O finally/O in/O 1938/O I/O went/O into/O show/O business/O ./O 
I/O wrote/O gags/O for/O a/O great/O many/O comedians/O around/O town/O ,/O and/O then/O finally/O started/O on/O a/O regular/O radio/O program/O for/O the/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Broadcasting/ORGANIZATION System/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O me/O to/O go/O on/O from/O there/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Please/O tell/O the/O committee/O where/O you/O engaged/O in/O these/O various/O lines/O of/O activity/O and/O as/O near/O as/O you/O can/O when/O you/O changed/O the/O location/O of/O your/O work/O ,/O give/O us/O the/O dates/O ./O 
Mr./O BUERows/O ./O 
Right/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION I/O worked/O on/O this/O radio/O program/O in/O 1938/O ./O 
Then/O in/O 1939/O I/O was/O hired/O to/O do/O a/O program/O called/O the/O Texaco/O Star/O Theater/O in/O California/LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O to/O California/LOCATION and/O wrote/O this/O Texaco/ORGANIZATION Star/O Theater/O for/O Ken/PERSON Murray/PERSON and/O Frances/PERSON Langford/PERSON and/O Kenny/PERSON Baker/PERSON ,/O and/O then/O in/O 1940/O I/O was/O employed/O to/O write/O the/O Rudy/PERSON Vallee-John/PERSON Barrymore/PERSON radio/O program/O ./O 
I/O started/O that/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O went/O back/O to/O California/LOCATION with/O it/O ./O 
While/O in/O California/LOCATION ,/O we/O got/O an/O idea/O for/O a/O program/O called/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ./O 
The/O idea/O was/O picked/O up/O and/O sponsored/O and/O I/O went/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O write/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ./O 
I/O was/O head/O writer/O of/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O for/O about/O 5/O years/O ,/O after/O which/O I/O left/O the/O field/O of/O radio/O and/O went/O to/O Paramount/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O writer/O and/O producer/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O write/O or/O produce/O anything/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/O What/O was/O that/O date/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O about/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O 1945/O ./O 
After/O that/O I/O wrote/O a/O program/O of/O my/O own/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O one/O I/O owned/O myself/O and/O wrote/O ,/O called/O Holiday/O and/O Company/O ./O 
I/O did/O that/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION from/O about/O the/O end/O of/O 1945/O until/O about/O June/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
I/O came/O back/O to/O California/LOCATION and/O did/O n't/O do/O anything/O for/O a/O couple/O of/O months/O ./O 
Then/O I/O wrote/O the/O Dinah/O Shore/O program/O and/O the/O Joan/PERSON Davis/PERSON program/O ./O 
Then/O I.took/O on/O my/O own/O program/O called/O the/O Abe/O Burrows/O Show/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1947/O ;/O did/O that/O for/O a/O while/O ./O 
Then/O I/O went/O out/O in/O night/O clubs/O for/O about/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O and/O went/O back/O into/O television/O ./O 
Then/O I/O wrote/O a/O Broadway/O show/O ./O 
I/O was/O coauthor/O of/O Guys/O and/O Dolls/O ./O 
Since/O then/O I/O have/O done/O several/O other/O things/O in/O the/O theater/O ./O 
I/O did/O Guys/O and/O Dolls/O ./O 
I/O did/O a/O play/O called/O Three/O Wishes/O for/O Jamie/PERSON ,/O which/O I/O was/O coauthor/O of/O and/O I/O directed/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O a/O play/O that/O won/O the/O Christopher/O award/O ./O 
I/O am/O presently/O engaged/O in/O writing/O a/O new/O play/O for/O the/O spring/O ,/O a/O musical/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O employed/O on/O a/O weekly/O television/O show/O called/O the/O Name/O Is/O the/O Same/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O you/O stated/O that/O you/O went/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1945/O and/O returned/O for/O periods/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O 1946/O and/O then/O returned/O again/O to/O California/LOCATION ,/O if/O I/O understood/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O the/O middle/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDtJSTRT/O 4473/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O when/O did/O you/O go/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O in/O California/LOCATION in/O 1945/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O was/O doing/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O there/O ,/O right/O up/O until/O the/O spring/O of/O 1945/O ./O 
Then/O I/O went/O with/O Paramount/O and/O that/O was/O in/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O when/O did/O you/O go/O to/O California/LOCATION prior/O to/O your/O working/O on/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O my/O first/O trip/O to/O California/LOCATION was/O in/O 1939/O ./O 
Then/O my/O next/O trip/O to/O stay/O for/O any/O length/O of/O time/O was/O in/O 1943/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1943/O in/O the/O middle/O of/O the/O year/O sometime/O ,/O and/O I/O stayed/O from/O then/O until/O the/O time/O I/O left/O for/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O do/O Holiday/O and/O Company/O in/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O stated/O how/O you/O were/O employed/O or/O in/O what/O work/O you/O were/O engaged/O in/O California/LOCATION from/O 1943/O up/O until/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O writing/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O I/O did/O that/O for/O 5/O years/O ./O 
I/O was/O completely/O identified/O with/O that/O show/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O do/O anything/O else/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
M/O Burrows/PERSON ,/O you/O appeared/O in/O executive/O session/O of/O this/O committee/O on/O March/O 20/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O at/O which/O time/O you/O were/O interrogated/O about/O your/O activities/O in/O California/LOCATION and/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O and/O at/O that/O time/O your/O testimony/O was/O very/O vague/O with/O regard/O to/O your/O knowledge/O of/O individuals/O who/O have/O been/O shown/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O your/O contacts/O with/O those/O individuals/O ./O 
The/O investigation/O by/O the/O committee/O has/O continued/O ,/O and/O during/O the/O course/O of/O our/O hearings/O in/O California/LOCATION there/O was/O a/O witness/O who/O appeared/O on/O October/O 2/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O before/O the/O committee/O while/O sitting/O in/O California/LOCATION ./O 
His/O name/O was/O Mr./O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON testified/O as/O to/O his/O own/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O ,/O first/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION and/O then/O his/O transfer/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION ./O 
He/O testified/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O unit/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION established/O within/O radio/O ,/O within/O a/O group/O of/O radio/O writers/O ./O 
He/O further/O testified/O that/O he/O was/O treasurer/O of/O that/O group/O for/O a/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O possibly/O as/O much/O as/O 10/O or/O 12/O months/O ./O 
He/O fixed/O the/O time/O at/O which/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O that/O group/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O that/O is/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O within/O radio/O writers/O ,/O as/O being/O from/O October/O 1945/O or/O the/O middle/O of/O 1946-his/O recollection/O was/O not/O clear/O as/O to/O the/O exact/O date-for/O a/O period/O of/O approximately/O 2/O years/O ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O his/O testimony/O he/O identified/O a/O number/O of/O persons/O as/O having/O been/O members/O of/O that/O group/O ./O 
And/O among/O them/O was/O yourself/O ./O 
I/O will/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O of/O what/O his/O testimony/O was/O ,/O with/O regard/O to/O you/O ./O 
given/O :/O The/O following/O questions/O were/O asked/O and/O answers/O QUESTION/O ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Abe/PERSON Burrows/PERSON ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Was/O Abe/PERSON Burrows/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Abe/PERSON Burrows/PERSON attended/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O I/O attended/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Have/O you/O collected/O dues/O from/O him/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O have/O ./O 
I/O recall/O many/O instances/O of/O trying/O to/O ,/O or/O at/O least/O a/O '/O few/O instances/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O by/O that/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O Burrows/PERSON was/O a/O little/O hard/O to/O pin/O down/O when/O it/O came/O to/O collecting/O dues/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
You/O say/O hard/O to/O pin/O down/O in/O the/O collection/O of/O dues/O ?/O 
ANmW/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
4474/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O QUESTION/O ./O 
You/O mean/O difficult/O to/O collect/O them/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Then/O this/O question/O was/O asked/O by/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O :/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON ./O 
did/O you/O ever/O collect/O dues/O other/O than/O at/O private/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Only/O on/O rare/O occasions/O when/O it/O appeared/O more/O convenient/O for/O the/O person/O who/O owed/O the/O dues/O to/O pay/O at/O a/O given/O time/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O at/O the/O moment/O any/O specific/O instance/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O case/O of/O Abe/PERSON Burrows/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O recall/O any/O instances/O where/O you/O attempted/O to/O collect/O dues/O from/O him/O other/O than/O at/O a/O private/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
I/O never/O did/O ./O 
And/O then/O I/O resumed/O the/O questioning/O :/O QUESTION/O ./O 
But/O ,/O at/O party/O meetings/O you/O endeavored/O to/O collect/O dues/O from/O him/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O was/O there/O any/O occasion/O when/O he/O paid/O the/O dues/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ,/O there/O were/O a/O few/O occasions/O when/O he/O paid/O at/O least/O a/O part/O of/O them/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
What/O reason/O did/O he/O ascribe/O at/O any/O time/O for/O not/O paying/O all/O of/O the/O dues/O that/O were/O supposed/O to/O be/O paid/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Principally/O that/O he/O did/O not/O have/O money/O with/O him/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Was/O there/O ever/O a/O time/O when/O any/O question/O was/O raised/O by/O him/O that/O he/O was/O not/O supposed/O to/O pay/O dues/O because/O he/O was/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
ANSwER/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O such/O instances/O ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
As/O treasurer/O of/O the/O group/O ,/O did/O you/O consider/O that/O he/O was/O one/O of/O those/O from/O whom/O you/O should/O collect/O dues/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O he/O was/O one/O whom/O I/O considered/O I/O should/O collect/O dues/O from/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
What/O part/O did/O he/O play/O in/O the/O meetings/O that/O were/O held/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O Mr./O Burrows/PERSON was/O an/O infrequent/O attender/O of/O the/O meetings/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O considerably/O vocal/O and/O he/O is/O an/O extrovert/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O he/O did/O not/O particularly/O stick/O to/O the/O subject/O very/O well/O and/O what/O was/O going/O on/O ,/O and/O he/O seemed/O more/O interested/O in/O being/O an/O extrovert/O than/O sticking/O to/O the/O business/O at/O hand/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Over/O how/O long/O a/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O consider/O that/O he/O was/O a/O person/O from/O whom/O you/O should/O collect/O dues/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O guess/O at/O that/O ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O ,/O Mr./O Burrows/PERSON commuted/O between/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O and/O he/O would/O probably/O be/O out/O here/O a/O few/O months/O or/O weeks/O at/O a/O time/O ,/O and/O '/O I/O would/O say/O over/O a/O period/O of/O time/O that/O I/O was/O responsible/O for/O dues/O it/O was/O probably/O not/O more/O than/O 4/O to/O 6/O months/O at/O the/O most/O when/O I/O would/O consider/O him/O as/O a/O member/O out/O here/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
And/O that/O 4/O to/O 6/O months/O were/O not/O consecutive/O months/O as/O I/O under/O -/O stood/O you/O to/O say/O ?/O 
ANSWER/O ./O 
I/O would/O not/O say/O for/O sure/O on/O it/O ./O 
That/O is/O purely/O a/O guess/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O exactly/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O has/O ,/O at/O many/O times/O during/O the/O course/O of/O our/O hearings/O ,/O invited/O any/O person/O whose/O name/O had/O been/O adversely/O mentioned/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O to/O make/O denial/O or/O explanation/O ,/O as/O the/O witness/O may/O think/O proper/O to/O those/O accusations/O ./O 
Promptly/O upon/O the/O taking/O of/O this/O testimony/O ,/O we/O heard/O from/O you/O that/O you/O desired/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O ./O 
And/O I/O assume/O it/O is/O in/O pursuance/O to/O that/O request/O that/O you/O are/O here/O now/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
BURROws/O ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
First/O of/O all/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O that/O I/O was/O very/O anxious/O to/O come/O back/O ,/O outside/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O wanted/O to/O clear/O up/O everything/O ./O 
The/O first/O time/O I/O was/O subpenaed/O by/O this/O com/O -/O mittee/O I/O got/O in/O touch/O with/O my/O lawyer/O instantly/O and/O we/O asked/O to/O come/O down/O as/O quickly/O as/O possible/O ./O 
That/O was/O last/O year/O ,/O in/O March/O ./O 
I/O would/O just/O like/O to/O say-that/O I/O was/O very/O frightened/O when/O I/O got/O that/O first/O subpena/O ./O 
I/O had/O been/O around/O in/O an/O atmosphere/O of/O people/O for/O a/O while/O who/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4475/O disliked/O this/O committee/O very/O much/O ,/O and/O I/O knew/O nothing/O about/O it/O except/O some/O of/O the/O stuff/O I/O had/O heard/O ,/O and/O there/O had/O been/O a/O lot/O of-well/O ,/O I/O might/O use/O the/O word/O propaganda/O ./O 
So/O I/O was/O pretty/O scared/O ./O 
But/O I/O came/O down/O here/O and/O spoke/O to/O the/O people/O here/O and/O the/O investigators/O and/O everybody/O was/O very/O fair/O to/O me/O ./O 
There/O were/O no/O monsters/O here/O ,/O no/O Fascists/O ,/O nobody/O trying/O to/O kill/O me/O ./O 
And/O so/O ,/O I/O welcome/O this/O chance/O to/O come/O back/O here/O ./O 
The/O minute/O I/O heard/O Vinson/PERSON had/O said/O something/O about/O me/O I/O said/O I/O wanted/O to/O come/O back/O and/O talk/O to/O you/O people/O because/O I/O really/O want/O to/O get/O this/O whole/O thing/O cleared/O up/O ,/O this/O whole/O point/O of/O my/O Americanism/O being/O under/O suspicion/O is/O very/O painful/O to/O me/O ,/O not/O just/O painful/O economically/O but/O painful/O as/O it/O is/O to/O a/O guy/O who/O loves/O his/O country/O ,/O loves/O his/O home/O ,/O and/O loves/O his/O people/O ./O 
So/O I/O want/O to/O get/O this/O whole/O thing/O cleared/O up/O and/O tell/O you/O anything/O I/O can/O in/O answer/O to/O this/O thing/O ./O 
In/O answer/O to/O what/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON said/O ,/O let/O me/O say/O the/O following/O :/O I/O have/O no/O recollection/O ,/O no/O recollection/O at/O all/O of/O ever/O applying/O for/O party/O membership/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O ever/O having/O possession/O of/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ,/O although/O I/O have/O been/O told/O by/O a/O private/O source/O that/O somebody/O had/O seen/O a/O card/O with/O my/O name/O on/O it/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O seen/O such/O a/O card/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O it/O ./O 
there/O ,/O I/O have/O just/O never/O seen/O it/O ./O 
If/O it/O is/O I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O paying/O dues/O or/O anything/O that/O could/O be/O called/O dues/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O any/O formal/O participation/O in/O anything/O that/O could/O be/O called/O this/O organization/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O must/O say/O I/O did/O associate/O with/O Communists/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O various/O meetings/O ,/O I/O belonged/O to/O a/O lot/O of/O their/O fronts/O ,/O I/O attended/O lectures/O ,/O what/O was/O called/O study/O groups/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
I/O entertained/O for/O their/O causes/O ./O 
I/O gave/O them/O money/O for/O these/O causes/O over/O a/O short/O time/O ./O 
And/O so/O ,/O if/O someone/O testifies/O that/O he/O thought/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O ,/O I/O guess/O he/O is/O telling/O the/O truth/O as/O he/O sees/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O around/O with/O those/O fellows/O ,/O and/O he/O saw/O me/O ,/O and/O so/O I/O ca/O n't/O say/O that/O he/O is/O lying/O in/O that/O way/O ./O 
However/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O I/O keep/O making/O or/O trying/O to/O make/O myself/O clear/O on/O one/O point/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O that/O it/O is/O kind/O of/O a/O stubborn/O pride/O on/O my/O part/O that/O makes/O me/O happy/O in/O the/O belief/O that/O maybe/O I/O did/O n't/O take/O the/O final/O step/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O final/O step/O ,/O what/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O BumRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O mean/O the/O actual/O applying/O or/O going/O through/O any/O of/O the/O ritualistic/O stuff/O which/O I/O was/O told/O and/O I/O always/O understood/O you/O had/O to/O go/O through/O before/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O how/O did/O you/O learn/O where/O the/O ritualistic/O stepsMr/O ./O 
BURROWS/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O have/O read/O a/O good/O deal/O about/O it/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O have/O read/O it/O in/O testimony/O from/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O have/O read/O a/O lot/O of/O articles/O about/O communism/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O period/O when/O I/O was/O around/O with/O these/O fellows/O ivhen/O the/O Communists/O were/O n't/O Communists/O as/O we/O know/O them/O or/O knew/O them/O before/O ./O 
Their/O role/O during/O the/O war/O was/O completely/O one/O of/O unity/O ./O 
They/O attacked/O anyone/O who/O talked/O about/O strikes/O ,/O they/O talked/O about/O the/O war/O effort/O and/O unity/O and/O everything/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O their/O whole/O approach/O ./O 
So/O they/O sounded/O like/O superpatriots/O ,/O completely/O superpatriots/O ./O 
It/O was/O n't/O until/O later/O that/O they/O began/O to/O show/O themselves/O ./O 
That/O iron/O fist/O ,/O in/O that/O intellectual/O glove/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O began/O to/O show/O itself/O ,/O and/O people/O began/O to/O recognize/O what/O they/O were/O ./O 
But/O in/O those/O days/O it/O was/O n't/O anything/O like/O that/O ,/O and/O there/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O these/O fellows/O ,/O a/O lot/O of/O them/O said/O they/O were/O Communists/O ,/O 21546-52/O --/O pt/O ./O 
1/O --/O 2/O 4476/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O a/O lot/O of/O them/O were/O on/O the/O masthead/O of/O the/O New/O Masses/O ,/O other/O people/O spoke/O for/O Communist/O causes/O ,/O and/O there/O was/O no/O hiding/O of/O it/O or/O anythulg/O like/O that/O ./O 
But/O since/O I/O have/O discovered/O ,/O I/O have/O read/O ,/O about/O the/O conspiratorial/O nature/O of/O it/O ,/O my/O role/O in/O this/O whole/O thing/O certainly/O does/O n't/O jibe/O with/O the/O conspiratorial/O nature/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
When/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON asked/O you/O about/O your/O associa/O -/O tion/O ,/O or/O you/O referred/O to/O your/O association/O ,/O was/O that/O at/O Communist/O meetings/O ,/O Communist/O cell/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O BmRRows/PERSON ./O 
Not/O anything/O that/O was/O called/O a/O Communist/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O have/O since/O read/O inr/O testimony/O of/O other/O people/O ,/O where/O they/O use/O the/O words/O ``/O open/O Communist/O meetings/O ,/O ''/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O it/O was/O anything/O like/O that/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O at/O anything/O that/O I/O could/O say/O was/O formally/O set/O up/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O I/O have/O read/O a/O lot/O of/O stuff/O about/O it/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O I/O mean/O was/O ,/O was/O it/O an/O organization/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION itself/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON ;/O I/O only/O recall/O his/O name/O because/O I/O ran/O into/O him/O in/O front/O of/O the/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION Hotel/O about/O a/O year/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O just/O want/O to/O be/O specific/O about/O what/O you/O testified/O to/O about/O your/O associations/O ,/O the/O extent/O of/O your/O associations/O and/O the/O kind/O ./O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O in/O a/O great/O many/O of/O those/O front/O organizations/O ./O 
I/O was/O around/O with/O people/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O back/O in/O 1943/O ,/O where/O I/O testified/O in/O my/O 1951/O testimony/O ,/O that/O I/O had/O met/O a/O fellow/O named/O Samuel/PERSON Sillen/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O one/O of/O the/O editors/O of/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
And/O lie/O introduced/O himself/O to/O me/O and/O we/O met/O somewhere/O in/O the/O country/O or/O somewhere/O and/O started/O to/O talk/O books/O ./O 
Then/O he/O introduced/O me/O to/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O editor/O of/O the/O New/O Masses/O ,/O and/O another/O fellow/O named/O John/PERSON Stewart/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O and/O they/O would/O sit/O around/O and/O talk/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O at/O one/O timeI/O refer/O to/O my/O earlier/O testimony-they/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O You/O ought/O to/O be/O much/O closer/O to/O us/O ,/O ''/O that/O term/O ./O 
So/O I/O associated/O with/O these/O fellows/O ./O 
When/O I/O came/O to/O California/LOCATION ,/O about/O a/O week/O after/O I/O arrived/O ,/O I/O was/O called/O by/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ,/O and/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON said/O ,/O ``/O Samuel/PERSON Sillen/PERSON said/O for/O me/O to/O get/O in/O touch/O with/O you/O ./O ''/O 
He/O came/O with/O his/O wife/O and/O visited/O me/O at/O my/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O was/O Samuel/PERSON Sillen/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O he/O never/O said/O to/O me/O in/O those/O words/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O a/O member/O ./O ''/O 
I/O do/O n't/O ever/O remember/O anybody/O actually/O saying/O that/O to/O me/O ./O 
But/O I/O know/O he/O was/O literary/O editor/O of/O the/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
He/O wrote/O a/O column/O or/O something/O which/O was/O called/O A/O Marxist/O Approach/O to/O the/O Theater/O ,/O so/O I/O would/O assume/O ,/O sir/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
There/O was/O no/O doubt/O in/O my/O mind/O ,/O I/O mean/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
And/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON ;/O did/O you/O know/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O planning/O editor/O of/O the/O New/O Masses/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O think/O the/O managing/O editor/O of/O the/O New/O Masses/O would/O have/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
And/O when/O he/O spoke/O ,/O he/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O the/O Communists/O ,/O we/O Communists/O ./O ''/O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O they/O once/O invited/O me/O to/O a/O lecture/O that/O was/O given/O under/O the/O auspices/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O which/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON had/O a/O debate/O with/O George/PERSON Sokolsky/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O how/O everybody/O got/O along/O in/O these/O days/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IX/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4477/O It/O was/O in/O 1943/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
And/O it/O was/O a/O big/O crowd/O and/O stuff/O like/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
How/O about/O John/PERSON Stewart/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O wrote/O a/O book/O with/O a/O fellow/O who/O used/O to/O give/O lectures/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O attended/O ,/O a/O fellow/O named/O Bruce/PERSON Minton/PERSON ./O 
Bruce/PERSON Minton/PERSON gave/O lectures/O on/O what/O he/O called/O a/O Marxist/O Approach/O to/O History/O ,/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
Everything/O was/O called/O things/O like/O that/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Bruce/PERSON Minton/PERSON used/O any/O other/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
His/O real/O name/O was/O Richard/PERSON Bransten/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
How/O well/O did/O you/O know/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O him/O at/O his/O lectures/O and/O I/O was/O at/O his/O home/O a/O couple/O of/O times/O ./O 
His/O wife/O was/O Ruth/PERSON McKinney/PERSON ,/O a/O writer/O ,/O and/O they/O invited/O me/O there/O ./O 
In/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O in/O those/O days/O ,/O I/O was/O invited/O everywhere/O ./O 
I/O attended/O more/O parties/O ,/O I/O guess/O ,/O than/O anyone/O ./O 
The/O Saturday/O Evening/O Post/O ,/O in/O 1945/O or/O the/O end/O of/O 1945/O ,/O did/O an/O article/O about/O me/O ,/O and/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O played/O at/O parties/O all/O over/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O it/O got/O a/O little/O out/O of/O hand/O ./O 
I/O used/O to/O go/O to/O too/O many/O ,/O and/O I/O began/O to/O quit/O going/O when/O I/O started/O to/O get/O asked/O by/O people/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O people/O would/O say/O ``/O Come/O to/O the/O party/O ,/O ''/O and/O you/O would/O sit/O ,/O and/O then/O you/O would/O sit/O down/O to/O the/O party/O and/O go/O to/O work/O ./O 
So/O I/O attended/O at/O parties/O ,/O with/O all/O kinds/O of/O people/O ,/O the/O right/O wing/O and/O the/O left/O wing/O ,/O and/O the/O middle/O ,/O and/O all/O down/O the/O line/O ./O 
I/O guess/O I/O never/O turned/O down/O an/O invitation/O to/O go/O to/O the/O piano/O ./O 
It/O was/O in/O a/O period/O before/O I/O became/O a/O performer/O ,/O and/O I/O guess/O maybe/O I/O was/O hammy/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O liked/O to/O sing/O ./O 
I/O played/O up/O these/O songs/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O specifically/O with/O reference/O to/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O recall/O any/O time/O he/O collected/O or/O that/O he/O attempted/O to/O collect/O dues/O from/O you/O for/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O the/O terms/O of/O dues/O ./O 
The/O way/O I/O remember/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON is/O that/O his/O wife/O was/O named/O Pauline/PERSON Hopkins/PERSON ,/O and/O she/O was/O a/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O member/O ./O 
She/O came/O out/O from/O Chicago/LOCATION ./O 
She/O got/O very/O active/O in/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
We/O used/O to/O have/O meetings/O `/O at/O their/O house/O ./O 
I/O know/O one/O specific/O kind/O of/O meeting/O we/O did/O have/O at/O their/O house/O was/O committee/O of/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O ways/O and/O means/O committee/O meeting/O which/O would/O be/O held/O over/O there/O ./O 
I/O know/O she/O had/O meetings/O over/O there/O of/O the/O radio/O writers/O '/O division/O of/O HICCASP/O ,/O which/O was/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O ./O 
I/O remember/O seeing/O Vinson/PERSON there/O then/O ,/O somewhere/O in/O 1945/O ./O 
I/O remember/O giving/O him/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O for/O what/O ,/O really/O ,/O if/O I/O could/O state/O clearly/O ./O 
giving/O him/O any/O money/O ./O 
There/O was/O an/O anti-Fascist/O fund/O some/O of/O those/O guys/O used/O to/O collect/O for/O ./O 
But/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O paying/O Vinson/PERSON anything/O that/O you/O would/O call/O dues/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O would/O remember/O that/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O he/O says/O he/O had/O trouble/O collecting/O dues/O from/O me/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O used/O an/O excuse/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O money/O with/O me/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O anyone/O who/O knows/O me/O knows/O I/O am/O not/O that/O sort/O of/O a/O fellow/O ./O 
If/O I/O had/O an/O obligation/O to/O pay/O dues/O ,/O I/O would/O pay/O them/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O point/O could/O have/O possibly/O come/O up/O ,/O if/O I/O owed/O dues/O ,/O not/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O VELD/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O as/O to/O these/O study/O groups/O that/O you/O mentioned/O ,/O you/O studied/O communism/O in/O groups/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
4478/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O used/O the/O words/O ``/O study/O groups/O ./O ''/O 
They/O were/O groups/O that/O ,/O in/O those/O days/O ,/O I/O guess/O it/O was/O kind/O of/O to/O orientate/O people/O on/O what/O they/O called/O a/O Marxist/O approach/O to/O show/O business/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O they/O used/O to/O have/O continual/O squabbles/O to/O the/O role/O of/O a/O writer/O and/O one/O group/O would/O hold/O the/O writer/O was/O a/O citizen/O and/O should/O be/O a/O completely/O active/O citizen/O ,/O another/O group/O would/O hold/O that/O a/O writer/O was/O purely/O a/O writer/O ./O 
If/O you/O recall/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O tremendous/O controversy/O that/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON had/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O where/O he/O said/O art/O is/O a/O weapon/O and/O they/O said/O art/O is/O n't/O a/O weapon/O ,/O or/O rather/O he/O said/O art/O is/O n't/O a/O weapon/O and/O they/O said/O it/O is/O a/O weapon/O ./O 
But/O it/O was/O a/O steady/O controversy/O over/O the/O role/O of/O the/O writer/O ./O 
I/O used/O to/O find/O myself/O periodically/O engaged/O in/O arguments/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O satirist/O ,/O and/O one/O of/O my/O best/O known/O satires/O is/O something/O that/O is/O a/O satire/O of/O a/O kind/O of/O documentary/O radio/O program/O that/O was/O very/O common/O among/O the/O liberal/O and/O left-wing/O writers/O of/O the/O day/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O big/O tendency/O in/O those/O days/O to/O do/O these/O very/O pontifical/O radio/O programs/O with/O everybody/O talking/O very/O loud/O and/O introducing/O Thomas/PERSON Jefferson/PERSON and/O Abra/PERSON -/O ham/PERSON Lincoln/PERSON at/O every/O opportunity/O ./O 
So/O I/O did/O a/O satirical/O thing/O on/O that/O at/O the/O piano/O ./O 
I/O remember/O the/O first/O time/O I/O did/O it/O was/O for/O some/O kind/O of/O a/O cause/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O cause/O was/O exactly/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O it/O and/O there/O was/O a/O pretty/O large/O left-wing/O crowd/O ,/O I/O guess/O ,/O and/O there/O was/O kind/O of/O a/O quiet/O in/O the/O room/O ./O 
It/O did/O n't/O go/O as/O well/O as/O it/O did/O with/O others/O of/O my/O friends/O ./O 
And/O then/O one/O of/O the/O fellows/O came/O over/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O a/O fellow-I/O mentioned/O his/O name-Henry/O Blankfort/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O Henry/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O because/O I/O guess/O I/O remember/O criticism/O ./O 
He/O came/O over/O and/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O think/O that/O is/O a/O very/O bad/O thing/O for/O you/O to/O do/O ,/O Abe/PERSON ,/O you/O know/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Why/O ,/O ''/O and/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O Because/O I/O think/O it/O is/O wrong/O ./O ''/O 
These/O guys/O had/O no/O sense/O of/O humor/O about/O themselves/O at/O all/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O that/O I/O was/O n't/O too/O trusted/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Henry/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O that/O he/O testified/O and/O took/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O that/O he/O has/O been/O around/O ;/O he/O was/O around/O all/O of/O the/O time/O ./O 
It/O was/O another/O case/O of/O one/O of/O my/O assumptions/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
In/O some/O of/O the/O cases/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O I/O know/O a/O fellow/O was/O a/O Com/O -/O munist/O from/O reading/O about/O it/O in/O this/O committee/O 's/O testimony/O or/O whether/O I/O knew/O it/O before/O ./O 
It/O kind/O of/O overlaps/O in/O your/O mind/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O coming/O back/O a/O little/O bit/O more/O specifically/O ,/O if/O you/O can/O ,/O to/O the/O study/O groups/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O of/O the/O instructors/O at/O these/O study/O groups/O ?/O 
And/O the/O approximate/O date/O that/O they/O were/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O somewhere/O in/O the/O 1945/O period/O I/O think/O ./O 
But/O some/O of/O them/O were/O the/O study/O groups/O that/O Bruce/PERSON Minton/PERSON ran/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O lecture/O ,/O a/O regularly/O organized/O lecture/O ./O 
They/O were/O called/O a/O study/O ,/O but/O he/O just/O talked/O ./O 
He/O ,/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O was/O engaged/O in/O a/O terrific/O controversy/O with/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON over/O how/O history/O was/O to/O be/O interpreted/O ./O 
1/O frankly/O did/O n't/O know/O what/O either/O of/O them/O meant/O ./O 
I/O was/O kind/O of/O baffled/O by/O the/O whole/O thing/O ;/O I/O truly/O was/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O that/O was/O one/O group/O ./O 
Then/O there/O was/O a/O book/O put/O out/O called/O Literature/O and/O Arts/O ,/O by/O Marx/PERSON and/O Engels/PERSON ,/O or/O something/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O collection/O ./O 
And/O a/O group/O gathered/O to/O discuss/O this/O and/O I/O think/O it/O was/O a/O group/O of/O people/O from-well/O ,/O who/O I/O largely/O knew/O to/O be/O radio/O members/O of/O HICCASP/LOCATION ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O names/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTR/O 4479/O In/O my/O earlier/O testimony-I/O do/O n't/O remember/O the/O names/O of/O these/O specific/O people-but/O in/O my/O earlier/O testimony/O when/O I/O was/O asked/O about/O some/O of/O these/O meetings/O and/O gatherings/O I/O was/O at/O ,/O I/O said/O that/O a/O lot/O of/O the/O people/O were/O kind/O of/O faceless/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O when/O I/O saw/O the/O list/O of/O people/O that/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON named/O as/O being/O part/O of/O the/O people/O in/O the/O group/O that/O I/O was/O supposed/O to/O have/O been/O part/O of/O ,/O I/O knew/O ,/O maybe/O ,/O two/O of/O them/O ./O 
The/O others/O I/O really/O had/O not/O known/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O even/O know/O them/O by/O name/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O recall/O their/O faces/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O them/O talking/O in/O these/O groups/O about/O the/O Duclos/PERSON letter/O Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O in/O this/O group/O ./O 
I/O remember/O a/O great/O deal/O of/O conversation/O ,/O socially/O and/O such/O ,/O when/O the/O Duclos/PERSON letter/O hit/O ./O 
And/O all/O over/O Hollywood/LOCATION there/O was/O a/O good/O deal/O of/O whispering/O and/O hushing/O and/O stuff/O like/O that/O ./O 
But/O I/O remember/O the/O discussion/O in/O one/O group/O ,/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O remember/O ,/O on/O one/O evening/O where/O they/O were/O trying/O ,/O one/O fellow/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O ,/O was/O trying/O to/O make/O sense/O out/O of/O this/O thing/O ./O 
That/O seemed/O to/O be/O always/O the/O role/O of/O these/O guys/O ,/O to/O try/O to/O make/O sense/O out/O of/O it/O ./O 
They/O spoke/O of/O how/O this/O would/O be/O a/O force/O for/O good/O ./O 
I/O remember/O way/O back/O in/O 1936-37/O ,/O I/O told/O the/O committee/O the/O last/O time/O I/O was/O here/O ,/O that/O I/O had/O belonged/O to/O the/O American/O League/O for/O Peace/O and/O Democracy/O ./O 
When/O the/O Nazi-Soviet/O pact/O hit/O ,/O I/O resigned/O with/O a/O letter/O to/O the/O league/O ./O 
But/O at/O that/O time/O I/O remember/O they/O said/O when/O the/O NaziSoviet/O pact/O was/O put/O through/O ,/O they/O said/O ,/O ``/O This/O is/O going/O to/O be/O a/O force/O for/O peace/O ;/O a/O great/O thing/O ./O ''/O 
And/O the/O talk/O after/O the/O Duclos/PERSON letter/O hit/O was/O about/O the/O same/O ./O 
They/O said/O ,/O ``/O This/O was/O going/O to/O do/O a/O great/O thing/O ./O ''/O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O what/O anybody/O meant/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O you/O are/O a/O fairly/O intelligent/O man/O ,/O I/O think/O your/O testimony/O has/O shown/O that/O ./O 
Could/O n't/O you/O tell/O from/O the/O way/O their/O party/O line/O shifted/O that/O you/O were/O studying/O about/O Marxist/O communism/O :/O Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O knew/O that-Mr/O ./O 
VELDE/O ./O 
And/O if/O you/O were/O interested/O in/O Marxist/O communism/O ,/O do/O n't/O you/O think/O it/O is/O reasonable/O to/O assume/O ,/O or/O for/O us/O to/O assume/O and/O for/O you/O to/O assume/O ,/O too/O ,/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
But/O the/O study/O groups/O I/O mentioned/O ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O were/O in/O 1945/O ,/O when/O there/O was/O absolutely/O no/O word/O mentioned/O of/O Marxist/O communism/O as/O we/O know/O it/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O case/O of/O the/O writers/O '/O aid/O in/O the/O war/O ,/O the/O writers/O '/O role/O in/O the/O war/O ,/O the/O writers/O '/O role/O in/O establishing/O unity/O ,/O how/O the/O writers/O should/O treat/O minorities/O ,/O how/O he/O should/O treat/O the/O war/O effort/O ,/O he/O should/O n't/O make/O jokes/O about/O gas/O rationing/O ;/O stuff/O like/O that/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
I/O attended/O no/O such/O study/O groups/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O after/O thinking/O ,/O when/O it/O switched/O to/O what/O seems/O to/O be/O back/O to/O a/O revolutionary/O role/O ./O 
Mr./O VET/O ,/O DE/O ./O 
But/O you/O know/O now/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O ,/O that/O in/O order/O to/O get/O into/O those/O study/O groups/O in/O the/O first/O place/O ,/O that/O you/O had/O to/O be/O an/O applicant/O or/O at/O least/O considered/O for/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O an/O actual/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O deny/O that/O I/O may/O have/O been/O considered/O for/O membership/O ,/O and/O they/O may/O have/O been/O trying/O to/O prepare/O for/O it/O ./O 
I/O actually/O think/O that/O because/O of/O my/O work/O ,/O my/O humor/O and/O my/O satire/O ,/O that/O I/O was/O n't/O very/O well/O trusted/O ,/O I/O was/O called/O ``/O chi-chi/O ,/O ''/O phoney/O ,/O I/O will/O use/O any/O word/O I/O can/O think/O of/O ,/O because/O I/O mingled/O with/O people/O who/O were/O n't/O of/O the/O left/O ./O 
I/O did/O satires/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O on/O folk/O songs/O in/O a/O period/O when/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION had/O taken/O the/O folk/O song/O very/O dearly/O to/O its/O bosom/O ,/O 4480/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O because/O the/O folk/O song/O and/O the/O square/O dance/O seemed/O to/O be/O a/O way/O to/O establish/O American/O roots/O ./O 
And/O I/O used/O to/O rib/O that/O and/O was/O considered/O very/O irresponsible/O for/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O at/O this/O point/O ?/O 
from/O 1943/O to/O 1945/O ./O 
what/O was/O your/O annual/O income/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1943/O ?/O 
During/O the/O period/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O 1943-45/O ,/O approximately/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1943/O I/O guess/O I/O made/O about/O $/O 40,000/O ,/O and/O then/O in/O 1944/O about/O $/O 50,000/O ,/O and/O in/O 1945/O a/O little/O over/O $/O 50,000/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
When/O you/O made/O contributions/O to/O any/O organization/O ,/O did/O you/O keep/O a/O list/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRow/O ,/O ./O 
./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O did/O when/O they/O were/O charity/O contributions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O deducted/O them/O from/O your/O income/O tax/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
If/O they/O were/O charity/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
And/O others/O you/O did/O n't/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
And/O I/O did/O n't/O make/O many/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O were/O for/O charity/O ,/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
But/O you/O did/O make/O some/O that/O you/O knew/O were/O not/O for/O charity/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Can/O you/O name/O some/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O made/O contributions/O to/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION Commlittee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O knew/O what/O you/O were/O doing/O then/O ./O 
Mr./O BPRRows/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
The/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ,/O when/O I/O joined/O it/O ,/O was/O a/O very/O broad/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O understood/O that/O ;/O I/O want/O to/O know/O if/O you/O knew/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
What/O other/O organizations/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O the/O Hollywood/O Independent/O Citizens/O Com/O -/O mittee/O ./O 
I/O gave/O money/O once/O to/O a/O People/O 's/O World/O fund/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O knew/O what/O you/O were/O doing/O then/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O knew/O where/O the/O money/O was/O going/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O fund/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O knew/O where/O that/O was/O going/O ./O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
All/O right/O ,/O then/O ,/O categorically/O did/O you/O pay/O dues/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O never/O paid/O anything/O I/O thought/O could/O be/O called/O dues/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Categorically/O were/O you/O ever/O requested/O to/O pay/O dues/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O such/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
Categorically/O ,/O did/O you/O ever/O decline/O to/O pay/O dues/O because/O you/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O money/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O categorically/O ,/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Because/O it/O just/O does/O n't/O sound/O like/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O asking/O you/O what/O it/O sounds/O like/O ./O 
Did/O you/O or/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTR/O 4481/O Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O refuse/O to/O pay/O dues/O because/O you/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O money/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O I/O have/O to/O ask/O ./O 
MAr./O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O go/O back/O a/O little/O bitMr/O ./O 
WooD/O ./O 
Wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O one/O other/O question/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O him/O very/O slightly/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O do/O know/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/O Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O met/O him/O at/O his/O house/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O give/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON any/O money/O for/O any/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O have/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O you/O did/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O answer/O that/O for/O sure/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O say/O now/O under/O oath/O that/O you/O have/O no/O recollection/O now/O of/O ever/O having/O put/O into/O his/O hands/O any/O money/O for/O any/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O that/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O really/O am/O not/O ./O 
The/O one/O thing/O I/O am/O sure/O about/O is/O the/O thing/O that/O you/O call/O dues/O ./O 
But/O as/O far/O as/O giving/O him/O money/O for/O any/O purpose-if/O he/O said/O he/O was/O collecting/O money/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O every/O time/O we/O had/O these/O meetings/O of/O any/O kind/O ,/O whether/O it/O was/O HICCASP/O ,/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O somebody/O was/O always/O collecting/O money/O for/O something/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O know/O ,/O but/O he/O testified/O before/O this/O committee/O that/O you/O paid/O him/O Communist/O Party/O dues/O ./O 
and/O that/O on/O certain/O occasions/O you/O did/O n't/O pay/O him/O and/O offered/O as/O an/O excuse/O why/O you/O did/O n't/O that/O you/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O money/O with/O you/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O categorically/O ,/O when/O he/O said/O that/O you/O paid/O to/O him/O money/O for/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O ,/O was/O he/O telling/O the/O truth/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRowS/PERSON ./O 
He/O may/O have/O thought/O he/O was/O telling/O the/O truth/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O ask/O you/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O what/O you/O are/O saying/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O diffi/O -/O cult/O for/O me/O to/O say/O this/O ,/O because/O I/O think/O when/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON said/O he/O thought/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O partyMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
That/O is/O n't/O the/O question/O at/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O is/O :/O Did/O you/O pay/O him/O money/O as/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O dues/O ,/O as/O he/O swore/O before/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
IMr/O ./O 
BURROWS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
sir/O ;/O not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
These/O contributions/O that/O you/O made/O ,/O that/O you/O say/O you/O made/O ./O 
to/O other/O organizations/O ./O 
other/O than/O charitable/O organizations/O ,/O were/O in/O what/O amounts/O ?/O 
AMr/O ./O 
BURROWS/O ./O 
What/O is/O that/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
~/O r./O -LRB-/O WOOD.In/O what/O amounts/O ?/O 
i/O r./O BURRMWs/O ./O 
Very/O sumll/O amounts/O ./O 
MIr/O ./O 
Woon/PERSON ./O 
By/O that/O what/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
IMr/O ./O 
BUIiROws/O ./O 
I/O mean/O like/O $/O i/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O or/O $/O 20/O ./O 
MIr/O ./O 
Won/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O you/O had/O paid/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O in/O the/O Sn111/O off/O $/O 15/O ,/O $/O 20/O ,/O or/O 25/O ./O 
would/O not/O your/O recollection/O have/O been/O as/O good/O about/O that/O as/O it/O would/O about/O the/O other/O organizations/O you/O contributed/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O will/O tell/O you/O ./O 
I/O read/O about/O the/O dues/O ;/O I/O Nread/O them/O described/O ./O 
I/O read/O where/O they/O were/O regular/O things/O ./O 
I/O read/O 4482/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O where/O assessments/O were/O made/O ./O 
mean/O ,/O that/O is/O specific/O ./O 
INDUSTRY/O I/O think/O I/O would/O remember/O that/O ./O 
I/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O know/O you/O were/O a/O member/O if/O you/O did/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O no/O ,/O I/O say/O if/O a/O thing/O is/O specific/O ,/O when/O it/O sayswell/O ,/O you/O say/O to/O me/O ,/O I/O presume/O you/O mean/O that/O if/O it/O were/O small/O amounts/O I/O might/O not/O remember/O any/O more/O than/O I/O did/O about/O the/O other/O groups/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
If/O a/O man/O had/O walked/O up/O to/O you/O in/O a/O meeting/O that/O you/O knew/O to/O be/O attended/O by/O known/O Communists/O ,/O and/O told/O you/O that/O he/O wanted/O to/O collect/O your/O dues/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O any/O amount/O ,/O $/O 1/O ,/O $/O 5/O ,/O $/O 10/O ,/O $/O 25/O ,/O any/O amount/O ,/O and/O you/O paid/O it/O or/O told/O him/O you/O did/O n't/O have/O the/O money/O and/O would/O pay/O him/O later/O ,/O would/O n't/O you/O remember/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O do/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O BmRRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Vinson/PERSON further/O testified/O as/O follows/O about/O the/O dues/O schedule/O ./O 
He/O said/O :/O As/O I/O recall/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O certain/O set/O dues/O based/O on/O income/O up/O to-I/O do/O not/O recall/O exactly-I/O think/O it/O was/O $/O 50/O a/O week/O ,/O which/O was/O probably/O $/O 2/O a/O month/O ./O 
And/O above/O that/O there/O was/O an/O assessment/O or/O dues/O of/O 4/O percent/O of/O the/O gross/O salary/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O were/O you/O ever/O consulted/O ,/O or/O did/O you/O ever/O learn/O that/O you/O were/O to/O pay/O 4/O percent/O or/O any/O other/O percent/O of/O your/O gross/O salary/O to/O anyone/O for/O any/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
My/O salary/O in/O 1945/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O must/O have/O been/O about/O $/O 50,000/O or/O better/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O exactly/O sure/O ./O 
But/O that/O would/O be/O a/O considerable/O sum/O and/O I/O would/O know/O about/O that/O ./O 
I/O never/O paid/O out/O anything/O like/O that/O ,/O sir/O ,/O or/O any/O part/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O know/O of/O the/O requirement/O to/O pay/O a/O certain/O percentage/O of/O dues/O ,/O or/O assessment/O of/O the/O group/O that/O you/O were/O attached/O to/O or/O that/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O ?/O 
Or/O associated/O with/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O had/O heard/O vague/O talk/O about/O people/O paying/O part/O of/O their/O money/O and/O that/O is/O the/O only/O way/O I/O knew/O of/O it/O ./O 
I/O never/O knew/O it/O as/O something/O presented/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O that/O mean/O that/O at/O the/O time/O that/O you/O were/O asso/O -/O ciating/O with/O these/O people/O ,/O that/O you/O heard/O discussed/O the/O payment/O of/O part/O of/O their/O salaries/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O mean/O that/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O mean/O that/O ./O 
I/O mean/O I/O had/O heard/O talk/O around/O ./O 
It/O is/O one/O of/O those/O things/O that/O kind/O of/O comes/O through/O ,/O like/O a/O process/O of/O osmosis/O ./O 
I/O knew/O that/O big/O wheel/O Communists/O paid/O money/O ./O 
I/O had/O heard/O that/O ,/O I/O had/O heard/O accusations/O about/O that/O in/O the/O paper/O ./O 
I/O heard/O that/O people/O gave/O portions/O of/O their/O income/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ./O 
I/O had/O heard/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O hear/O that/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O in/O 1945/O and/O 1946/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRowS/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O hear/O it/O where/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O place/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O say/O I/O heard/O it/O vaguely/O ./O 
I/O thought/O you/O meant/O did/O I/O hear/O it/O at/O these/O particularMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O tell/O whether/O you/O meant/O you/O heard/O it/O recently/O or/O back/O in/O those/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O heard/O it/O back/O in/O those/O days/O ,/O too/O ,/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O anyone/O on/O any/O occasion/O ask/O you/O to/O contribute/O a/O percentage/O of/O your/O salary/O to/O any/O cause/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4483/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
By/O that/O you/O mean/O that/O there/O was/O never/O any/O demand/O made/O upon/O you/O to/O make/O a/O contribution/O of/O a/O sJecific/O percentage/O of/O the/O income/O that/O you/O had/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Never/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Or/O any/O other/O organizations/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O testimony/O has/O reflected/O that/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cells/O were/O formed/O within/O various/O professions/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O the/O legal/O profession/O ,/O the/O medical/O profession/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O guild/O ,/O and/O in/O this/O instance/O among/O radio/O writers/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON told/O us/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O that/O group/O of/O radio/O writers/O ,/O and/O he/O named/O other/O persons/O ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O knew/O two/O of/O them/O ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O two/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O knew/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O him/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
I/O know/O him/O back/O since/O 1938/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O who/O was/O the/O other/O one/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O :/O I/O thought/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON wanted/O me/O to/O stop/O ./O 
The/O other/O one/O ?/O 
I/O think/O I-would/O you/O read/O meMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O irrespective/O of/O what/O you/O testified/O to/O before/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O who/O it/O was/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O talking/O about/O what/O I/O testified/O before/O ./O 
I/O wanted/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON to/O read/O me/O the/O list/O ,/O if/O lie/O would/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O tell/O us/O who/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O BUTows/O ./O 
I/O knew/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ./O 
From/O the/O list/O I/O remember/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O remember/O Georgia/LOCATION Backus/LOCATION ./O 
I/O remember/O her/O ;/O she/O was/O very/O active/O in/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION Artists/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O she/O was/O an/O actress/O ./O 
I/O know/O her/O both/O socially/O and/O at/O ./O 
a/O lot/O of/O HICCASP/O meetings/O ,/O and/O stuff/O like/O that/O ./O 
Those/O are/O people/O I/O really/O knew/O ./O 
The/O others/O ,/O I/O knew/O of/O some/O of/O them/O ./O 
I/O saw/O the/O list/O ./O 
And/O some/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O at/O ./O 
all/O ./O 
I/O just/O have/O no/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O the/O sense/O that/O he/O never/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O ''/O or/O showed/O mea/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ./O 
He/O was/O active/O in/O a/O lot/O of/O these/O Commnunist/O things/O ,/O and/O he/O seemed/O to/O be-the/O word/O you/O use/O is/O he/O was/O around/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
He/O seemed/O to/O be/O always/O around/O ./O 
And/O Sam/PERSON was/O the/O first/O one/O who/O ever/O introduced/O me/O to-toolk/O me/O to/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O had/O any/O conversation/O with/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON with/O regard/O to/O testifying/O before/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O Bumiows/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
The/O last/O time/O I/O saw/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON was/O right/O after/O I/O lald/O made/O up/O my/O plans/O to/O come/O down/O to/O Washington/LOCATION and/O testify/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
I/O got/O the/O subpoena/O ,/O got/O in/O touch/O with/O my/O lawyer/O ,/O and/O we/O agreed/O that/O we/O were/O going/O to/O ask/O for/O immediate/O hearing/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
We/O came/O down/O well/O in/O advance/O of/O the/O date/O we/O were/O called/O ./O 
And/O Sam/PERSON called/O me/O up/O ,/O I/O had/O n't/O seen/O him/O for/O a/O number/O of/O years/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O he/O would/O like/O to/O see/O me/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O a/O rehearsal/O today/O ,/O at/O the/O Forty-eighth/O Street/O Theater/O ./O ''/O 
He/O said/O could/O I/O see/O him/O a/O few/O minutes/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O I/O would/O meet/O him/O ./O 
We/O met/O at/O Moore/PERSON 's/O Restaurant/O right/O next/O to/O the/O theater/O ./O 
Sam/PERSON said/O ,/O ``/O I/O hear/O you/O got/O a/O subpena/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Yep/O ,/O ''/O and/O he/O said/O ``/O I/O got/O one/O ,/O too/O ./O ''/O 
2/O 15/O 46-52-pt/O ./O 
10/O --/O 3/O 4484/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O I/O had/O n't/O known/O that/O ,/O it/O was/O n't/O in/O the/O paper/O ./O 
you/O going/O to/O do/O with/O it/O ?/O ''/O 
INDUSTRY/O He/O said/O ,/O ``/O What/O are/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O have/O to/O keep/O that/O to/O myself/O ./O ''/O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O only/O thing/O to/O do/O is/O to/O stick/O with/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Sam/PERSON ,/O it/O is/O something/O I/O do/O n't/O agree/O with/O you/O on/O ,/O but/O I/O ca/O n't/O argue/O with/O you/O ./O ''/O 
It/O got/O very/O cold/O in/O the/O restaurant/O and/O I/O got/O up/O ,/O and/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O we/O ordered/O coffee/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O finish/O the/O coffee/O ,/O I/O paid/O the/O bill/O and/O went/O to/O my/O rehearsal/O and/O he/O left/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O n't/O seen/O him/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O take/O the/O initiative/O of/O getting/O in/O touch/O with/O you/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
He/O called/O me/O ./O 
I/O had/O n't/O seen/O him/O in/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O the/O provision/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O is/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O refusing/O to/O testify/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O refusal/O to/O testify/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O what/O you/O say/O might/O incriminate/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O knew/O that/O then/O ,/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Why/O would/O he/O ask/O you/O to/O avail/O yourself/O of/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O in/O appearing/O before/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
His/O theory/O was/O that/O everybody/O ought/O to/O stick/O together/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Everybody/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Everybody/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O mean/O the/O pastor/O of/O the/O First/ORGANIZATION Presbyterian/ORGANIZATION Church/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ought/O to/O hide/O behind/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ,/O if/O I/O may/O point/O out/O ,/O back/O in/O the/O days/O when/O the/O first/O group/O of/O people/O from/O Hollywood/LOCATION were/O called/O ,/O I/O remember/O reading/O a/O thing/O about/O them/O ,/O in/O which/O one/O of/O them/O said-whether/O it/O was/O a/O public/O statement/O or/O what/O ,/O I/O forget/O what-in/O which/O they/O said/O that/O everybody/O ,/O regardless/O of/O whether/O they/O had/O been/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O whether/O they/O had/O never/O been/O members/O ,/O were/O to/O stick/O together/O in/O bucking/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O do/O you/O know/O there/O were/O 12/O of/O them/O that/O came/O here/O and/O did/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O 12/O of/O them/O came/O from/O Hollywood/LOCATION before/O this/O committee/O and/O claimed/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O how/O many/O had/O done/O it/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O that/O every/O one/O of/O them/O have/O been/O iden/O -/O tified/O in/O sworn/O testimony/O before/O this/O committee/O that/O they/O were/O members/O ,/O and/O a/O lot/O of/O them/O have/O come/O before/O the/O committee/O voluntarily/O since/O they/O served/O their/O sentence/O in/O jail/O and/O admitted/O their/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O know/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Why/O would/O this/O party/O be/O asking/O you/O or/O suggesting/O to/O you/O that/O you/O also/O avail/O yourself/O of/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Because/O I/O think/O the/O Communists/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O everybody/O who/O was/O subpenaed/O back/O in/O ,/O for/O instance/O 1948/O ,/O whenever/O that/O was/O ,/O was/O a/O Communist/O or/O not/O ./O 
But/O I/O know/O the/O Communists/O in/O their/O requests/O said/O they/O thought/O everybody/O should/O refuse/O to/O talk/O to/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Every/O Communist/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4485/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O everyone/O ,/O regardless/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O a/O single/O human/O being/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION who/O has/O been/O subpenaed/O before/O this/O committee/O that/O was/O n't/O a/O Communist/O who/O availed/O himself/O of/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O of/O any/O of/O the/O background/O ./O 
All/O I/O know/O is/O that/O I/O have/O never/O asked/O to/O avail/O myself/O of/O it/O since/O the/O beginning/O ./O 
I/O said/O to/O my/O lawyer/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O sometimes/O it/O seems/O it/O might/O be/O easier/O for/O me/O if/O I/O just/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O give/O up/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O let/O 's/O get/O down/O to/O cases/O ./O 
What/O this/O man/O wanted/O you/O to/O say/O here/O or/O suggested/O that/O you/O say/O here/O was/O that/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O had/O been/O ,/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O to/O do/O so/O would/O incriminate/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O connotation/O was/O meant/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
But/O you/O say/O you/O knew/O what/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O you/O knew/O then/O what/O he/O was/O referring/O to/O ;/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O he/O was/O referring/O to/O this/O aspect/O of/O it/O ./O 
What/O he/O was/O referring/O to/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O was/O that/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O ,/O in/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O discovered/O a/O way/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O questions/O of/O the/O committee/O without/O being/O cited/O for/O contempt/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O they/O would/O like/O everyone/O who/O is/O called/O ,/O and/O that/O includes/O non-Communists/O ,/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O let/O 's/O follow/O that/O up/O just/O for/O a/O minute/O ;/O permit/O me/O to/O follow/O it/O up/O for/O a/O minute/O ./O 
If/O I/O am/O called/O for/O any/O investigation/O that/O is/O empowered/O by/O law/O to/O administer/O an/O oath/O ,/O and/O I/O take/O that/O oath/O that/O I/O will/O swear/O to/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O am/O asked/O a/O question/O whether/O I/O am/O a/O Communist/O or/O not/O ,/O and/O I/O say/O I/O wo/O n't/O answer/O that/O because/O to/O do/O so/O would/O involve/O criminal/O prosecution/O against/O me/O ,/O or/O might/O have/O a/O tendency/O to/O subject/O me/O to/O criminal/O prosecution/O ,/O is/O there/O any/O alternative/O in/O your/O thinking/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O I/O am/O telling/O the/O truth/O ,/O if/O I/O am/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
If/O I/O am/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O I/O am/O swearing/O to/O a/O lie/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O alternative/O ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ;/O none/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O heard/O of/O branch/O D/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O northwest/O section/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O have/O n't/O ./O 
I/O was/O asked/O that/O question/O in/O my/O last/O testimony/O ./O 
The/O names/O and/O the/O symbols/O mean/O nothing/O to/O me/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O adjust/O one/O little/O note/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O ,/O something/O I/O was/O saying/O to/O Judge/O Wood/O before/O ,/O that/O it/O is/O possible/O ,/O just/O like/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON said/O ,/O that/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON may/O have/O assumed/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O ,/O Judge/O Wood/O ./O 
That/O is/O entirely/O possible/O ./O 
And/O that/O would/O explain/O ,/O sir/O ,/O the/O differenceMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Why/O would/O he/O assume/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O there/O ./O 
I/O was/O around/O a/O good/O many/O of/O those/O things/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O I/O was/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Georgia/LOCATION Backus/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
4486/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O known/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O kind/O of/O assumed/O it/O ./O 
She/O was/O very/O intense/O about/O everything/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O the/O kind/O of/O thing/O you/O associate/O with/O that/O ./O 
She/O was/O very/O intense/O and/O terribly/O active/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O she/O was/O one/O of/O those/O named/O by/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O this/O radio/O group/O of/O which/O he/O claimed/O you/O were/O a/O member/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O attending/O meetings/O at/O which/O she/O was/O present/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O recall/O meetings/O of/O the/O radio/O writers/O '/O group/O of/O HICCASP/O at/O Pauline/PERSON Hopkins/PERSON '/O house/O ,/O where/O Georgia/PERSON Backus/PERSON was/O present/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O what/O kind/O of/O meetings/O other/O than/O that/O I/O was/O with/O her/O at/O ./O 
I/O saw/O Georgia/LOCATION at/O meetings/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O she/O was/O at/O everything/O ./O 
I/O saw/O her/O at/O meetings/O a/O couple/O of/O times/O a/O week/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
With/O what/O regularity/O -LRB-/O lid/O these/O meetings/O occur/O that/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O no/O regularity/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Vinson/PERSON himself/O says/O it/O ./O 
He/O says/O I/O was/O commuting/O ,/O but/O actually/O I/O never/O attended/O any/O of/O these/O meetings/O with/O any/O regularity/O ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O commuting/O ./O 
Mr./O T.VEXXER/O ./O 
Who/O acted/O as/O a/O chairman/O at/O those/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O BVRROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O definite/O chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O \/O VE/O _/O -/O NER/O ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Hy/PERSON Alexander/PERSON '/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O him/O as/O a/O radio/O writer/O ,/O slightly/O ,/O not/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEXNNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O at/O which/O lie/O was/O present/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Various/O meetings/O ./O 
He/O was/O an/O active/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O `/O TAVE/O ER/O ./O 
Was/O lie/O chairman/O of/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O that/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
He/O was/O n't/O the/O type/O of/O fellow/O that/O was/O a/O chairman/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O kind/O of/O quiet/O fellow/O as/O I/O recall/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O him/O well/O ,/O but/O I/O recall/O him/O being/O a/O very/O quiet/O fellow/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O was/O married/O to/O Georgia/PERSON Backus/PERSON ,/O was/O he/O not/O ?/O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
He/O waq/O married/O to/O somebody/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ./O 
do/O I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O that/O you/O have/O never/O signed/O an/O application/O for/O the/O Communist/O ./O 
Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRROWS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O would/O remem/O -/O ber/O signing/O such/O an/O application/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O are/O pretty/O sure/O you/O never/O signed/O such/O an/O application/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
Pretty/O sure/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
And/O ,/O furthermore/O ,/O are/O you/O as/O equally/O as/O sure/O that/O you/O never/O signed/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ,/O yourself/O ,/O signed/O your/O name/O on/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
As/O I/O said/O before/O ,/O somebody/O told/O me/O they/O saw/O a/O card/O with/O my/O name/O on/O it/O ./O 
First/O of/O all/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O anybody/O would/O have/O a/O card/O that/O I/O signed/O ,/O and/O I/O think-well/O ,/O let/O me/O put/O it/O this/O way/O ,/O I/O think/O to/O sign/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O would/O have/O seemed/O like/O the/O height/O of/O insanity/O to/O me/O ,/O even/O though/O I/O was/O around/O and/O listening/O and/O involved/O in/O the/O fronts/O and/O entertaining/O with/O them/O ,/O I/O was/O n't/O really/O one/O of/O the/O fellows/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O sign/O documents/O that/O you/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O they/O are/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
What/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O sign/O instruments/O without/O knowing/O what/O they/O are/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Not/O ever/O ,/O do/O you/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4487/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O read/O what/O you/O sign/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Then/O why/O are/O you/O indefinite/O about/O whether/O you/O signed/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O indefinite/O about/O it/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
You/O say/O now/O categorically/O you/O did/O not/O do/O it/O ?/O 
BURROWS/O ./O 
To/O my/O recollection/O I/O never/O signed/O any/O such/O thing/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
That/O is/O still/O indefinite/O ./O 
You/O just/O testified/O that/O you/O do/O not/O sign/O documents/O without/O knowing/O what/O is/O in/O them/O ,/O and/O what/O they/O are/O ./O 
On/O that/O basis/O ,/O will/O you/O tell/O us/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O signed/O an/O application/O for/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O signed/O a/O Communist/O membership/O card/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O did/O not/O ./O 
do/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recollection/O of/O doing/O such/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O did/O you/O do/O it/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O say/O ,/O sirMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O leave/O the/O committee/O in/O doubt/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Then/O did/O you/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Reuben/PERSON Ship/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O not/O acquainted/O ./O 
I/O knew/O Reuben/PERSON to/O be/O a/O radio/O writer/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O attended/O any/O meetings/O with/O him/O that/O I/O knew/O of/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O would/O know/O what/O he/O looked/O like/O ,/O if/O I/O saw/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Charles/PERSON Glenn/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O of/O him/O slightly/O ./O 
I/O remember/O him/O around/O some/O of/O these/O literature/O discussions/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O these/O discussions/O regarding/O literature/O take/O place/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O by/O when/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Under/O what/O circumstances/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Somebody/O ,/O either/O at/O the/O guild/O or/O HICCASP/O of/O something/O would/O say/O a/O group/O of/O us/O are/O getting/O together/O for/O a/O talkfest/O Monday/O night/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
iMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Who/O would/O notify/O you/O about/O those/O meetings/O to/O discuss/O literature/O and/O other/O things/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O sometimes/O would/O get/O a/O card/O ,/O which/O would/O say/O ,/O at/O so/O forth/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O literature/O and/O art/O is/O going/O to/O be/O discussed/O ,/O or/O a/O new/O book/O or/O something/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O these/O meetings/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
In/O various/O homes/O ./O 
From/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON 's/O name/O coming/O up/O ,/O I/O remember/O that/O some/O of/O them/O were/O held/O in/O his/O house/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O other/O houses/O ,/O the/O names/O of/O the/O owners/O of/O the/O homes/O ?/O 
Mr./O BtRRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O made/O the/O point/O in/O my/O last/O testimony/O that/O a/O lot/O of/O them/O were/O held/O in/O places/O that/O did/O n't/O seem/O to/O be/O homes/O ./O 
They/O seemed/O to/O be/O houses/O but/O not/O homes/O ./O 
They/O were/O sparsely/O furnished/O ./O 
I/O remember/O one/O on/O the/O Crescent/O Heights/O Boulevard/O or/O something/O ./O 
Nobody/O seemed/O to/O live/O there/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O remember/O Vinson/PERSON 's/O house/O was/O he/O was/O the/O one/O who/O put/O up/O the/O chairs/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
So/O you/O figure/O it/O ,/O is/O the/O host/O who/O is/O doing/O that/O ./O 
4488/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O any/O meetings/O of/O that/O character/O held/O at/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
There/O were/O HICCASP/O meetings/O held/O at/O my/O house/O ,/O but/O none/O of/O these/O literature/O meetings/O that/O I/O know/O of/O ./O 
HICCASP/O meetings/O ,/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Elizabeth/PERSON Glenn/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O acquainted/O with/O her/O ./O 
She/O was/O in/O my/O house/O once/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O and/O I/O met/O her/O ./O 
She/O was/O never/O at/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O that/O we/O were/O talking/O about/O ,/O any/O of/O the/O gatherings/O ./O 
I/O never/O knew/O her/O ./O 
But/O she/O used/O to/O kind/O of/O wheel/O around/O at/O benefits/O and/O big/O functions/O ./O 
She/O seemed/O to/O be/O a/O person/O of/O some/O authority/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
She/O was/O ./O 
She/O has/O been/O shown/O to/O have/O been/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O remember/O her/O ,/O because/O she/O was/O an/O exceptionally/O large/O lady/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O her/O reason/O for/O being/O at/O your/O house/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
She/O came/O to/O my/O house/O one/O night/O with/O some/O other/O people/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O a/O lot/O of/O these/O people/O on/O the/O left/O would/O show/O up/O at/O my/O place/O socially/O ,/O periodically/O ,/O and/O she/O was/O brought/O by/O somebody/O ./O 
I/O think/O she/O was/O brought/O by/O Richard/PERSON Bransten/PERSON ,/O by/O Bruce/PERSON Minton/PERSON ,/O at/O the/O time/O she/O came/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O her/O visit/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
They/O dropped/O by/O ./O 
It/O was/O after/O some/O kind/O of/O thing/O ,/O where/O everybody/O dropped/O by/O at/O somebody/O 's/O house/O for/O a/O drink/O ,/O and/O I/O knew/O him/O ,/O and/O I/O guess/O I/O told/O him/O to/O drop/O by/O for/O a/O drink/O and/O I/O know/O her/O ./O 
It/O was/O after/O a/O rally/O or/O something/O ,/O and/O he/O brought/O her/O ./O 
The/O only/O thing/O I/O remember/O is/O that/O she/O was/O engaged/O at/O the/O time/O -/O she/O introduced/O herself/O to/O me/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O she/O said/O ,/O ``/O Did/O you/O read/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON '/O new/O book/O ?/O ''/O 
Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON had/O just/O written/O the/O Cross/O and/O the/O Arrow/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O a/O book/O about/O war/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O said/O ``/O No/O ,/O ''/O and/O she/O said/O it/O was/O terrible/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O I/O know/O ./O 
She/O was/O very/O critical/O of/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O guess/O I/O gave/O her/O a/O book/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O at/O that/O time/O that/O she/O was/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O one/O of/O the/O things/O you/O felt/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O about/O the/O word/O functionary/O ,/O but/O I/O assumed/O she/O was/O a/O wheel/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O guess/O this/O would/O be/O a/O good/O time/O to/O recess/O ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O until/O 2/O o'clock/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 12:30/O p./O m./O the/O subcommittee/O recessed/O ,/O to/O reconvene/O at/O 2/O p./O m./O the/O same/O day/O ./O -RRB-/O 
AFTERNOON/O SESSION/O -LRB-/O The/O subcommitte/O reconvened/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O recess/O ,/O at/O 2:10/O p./O m./O ,/O Representatives/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O and/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O called/O to/O order/O and/O hearing/O re/O -/O sumed/O with/O and/O by/O a/O subcommittee/O composed/O of/O three/O members/O ,/O Mr./O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O and/O Mr./O Moulder/PERSON as/O acting/O chairman/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4489/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O ABRAM/PERSON S./PERSON BURROWS/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O MARTIN/O GANG-Resumed/O Mr./O TAVE1NNER/O ./O 
Mr./O Burrows/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O interrogating/O you/O about/O the/O other/O persons/O whose/O membership/O in/O the/O radio/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O testified/O to/O by/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON ./O 
Among/O them/O is/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Billy/PERSON Wolff/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Billy/PERSON Wolff/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Only/O as/O a/O radio/O writer/O ./O 
I/O knew/O him/O as/O a/O guy/O trying/O to/O get/O a/O job/O in/O radio/O ,/O and/O he/O also/O belonged/O to/O the/O guild/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O him/O in/O any/O political/O capacity/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O in/O the/O earlier/O part/O of/O your/O testimony/O that/O most/O of/O those/O whose/O names/O were/O mentioned/O by/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON were/O faceless/O people/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O you/O were/O concerned/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Sort/O of/O ,/O sir/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O could/O Mr./O Wolff/PERSON have/O attended/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O which/O you/O attended/O and/O you/O not/O have/O recognized/O him/O as/O Mr./O Wolff/PERSON ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
He/O could/O have/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
He/O could/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Stanley/PERSON Waxman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Dave/PERSON Ellis/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O radio/O actor/O and/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O never/O heard/O the/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Lee/PERSON Barrie/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURRowS/PERSON ./O 
I/O vaguely/O remember/O a/O radio/O actress/O by/O that/O name/O or/O a/O singer/O or/O something/O by/O that/O name/O ,/O but/O I/O could/O not/O really/O place/O her/O ,/O sir/O ,/O not/O in/O any/O real/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Lynn/PERSON Whitney/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
She/O was/O a/O quite/O well-known/O radio/O actress/O ./O 
She/O worked/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O on/O some/O shows/O that/O I/O did/O ,/O and/O also/O I/O believe/O she/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Independent/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O her/O having/O been/O in/O attendance/O at/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O which/O you/O described/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Has/O she/O been/O at/O any/O meetings/O in/O your/O house/O ,/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O she/O may/O have/O been/O in/O my/O home/O socially/O ./O 
She/O was/O a/O radio/O actress/O ,/O and/O she/O might/O have/O come/O socially/O with/O some/O people/O ./O 
I/O vaguely/O remember/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O sir/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O her/O in/O any/O meeting/O connection/O as/O far/O as/O I/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O previously/O asked/O you/O a/O question/O regarding/O your/O knowledge/O of/O Charles/PERSON Glenn/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O at/O the/O time/O that/O you/O knew/O Mr./O Glenn/PERSON that/O he/O was/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O assuming/O so/O ./O 
He/O sounded/O like/O a/O fellow/O who/O was/O very/O politically/O conscious/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O in/O discussions/O ,/O I/O remember/O ,/O on/O this/O literature/O and/O art/O thing/O ,/O now/O that/O you/O bring/O it/O up/O ,/O he/O was/O one/O of/O the/O fellows/O that/O led/O the/O thing/O ./O 
I/O vaguely/O remember/O him/O ,/O not/O too/O well/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O remember/O him/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O doing/O radio/O writing/O at/O the/O time/O that/O you/O knew/O him/O ?/O 
4490/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLL1YWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
As/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O le/O was/O never/O employed/O in/O radio/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O of/O any/O shows/O he/O might/O have/O written/O ./O 
Mr./O T.AENNER/O ./O 
What/O did/O he/O do/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O remember/O at/O the/O time/O I/O kind/O of/O used/O to/O wonder/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O there/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O around/O that/O I/O mentioned/O who/O called/O themselves/O radio/O actors/O ,/O radio/O writers/O ,/O but/O who/O actually/O do/O n't/O write/O in/O radio/O or/O act/O in/O radio/O but/O they/O call/O themselves/O actors/O and/O writers/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O this/O fellow/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O ever/O writ/O -/O ing/O for/O radio/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Elaine/PERSON Gonda/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
I/O made/O a/O note/O of/O that/O when/O I/O saw/O her/O name/O ./O 
I/O remembered/O her/O when/O I/O read/O Charles/PERSON Glenn/PERSON 's/O name/O because/O I/O think/O that/O they/O were/O having/O a/O kind/O of/O romance/O or/O something/O ,/O it/O struck/O me/O ,/O because/O I/O remember/O seeing/O them/O sittingMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O they/O became/O married/O ,/O did/O n't/O they/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWs/PERSON ./O 
Really/O ?/O 
Well/O ,/O that/O is/O the/O end/O of/O the/O romance/O ./O 
Mr./O TA.VENNER/O ./O 
That/O was/O Elaine/PERSON Gonda/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O remember/O her/O in/O connection/O with-I/O do/O n't/O quite/O remember/O what/O she/O looked/O like/O ,/O but/O I/O remember/O they/O used/O to/O sit/O and/O hold/O hands/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O type/O of/O meetings/O were/O these/O at/O which/O this/O occurred/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O they/O were/O present/O together/O at/O this/O one/O study/O group/O that/O I/O told/O you/O about/O which/O was/O based/O on/O this/O literature/O and/O art/O book/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Gene/PERSON Stone/PERSON ,/O another/O person/O identified/O by/O Mr./O Vinson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O vaguely/O remember/O his/O name/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O know/O his/O name/O now/O is/O because/O I/O heard/O gossip/O around/O Radio/O Row/O that/O he/O had/O married/O Pauline/PERSON Hopkins/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O married/O to/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O how/O I/O remember/O his/O name/O ./O 
I/O never/O knew/O of/O any/O work/O he/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Jack/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O radio/O gag/O writer/O ./O 
He/O tried/O out/O for/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O writing/O it/O ,/O and/O did/O n't/O get/O the/O job/O ,/O but/O I/O remember/O him/O at/O guild/O meetings/O and/O stuff/O like/O that/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O him/O in/O any/O political/O connection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Vinson/PERSON also/O identified/O Annette/PERSON Harper/PERSON as/O a/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
That/O name/O does/O n't/O mean/O anything/O to/O me/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O T/O \/O AVENNER/O ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Paul/PERSON Marion/PERSON '/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
Paul/PERSON Marion/PERSON I/PERSON knew/O as/O an/O actor/O ./O 
He/O was/O around/O in/O the/O Actor/O 's/O Lab/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O saw/O him/O in/O a/O performance/O and/O I/O remember/O lie/O once/O came/O up/O and/O auditioned/O for/O me/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O for/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ,/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O something/O I/O was/O to/O do/O ./O 
I/O used/O to/O hire/O actors/O ./O 
That/O is/O how/O I/O recall/O Paul/PERSON ./O 
I/O never/O remember/O any/O political/O meetings/O with/O Paul/PERSON Marion/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Paul/PERSON Marion/PERSON testified/O the/O same/O with/O regard/O to/O you/O :/O that/O you/O had/O not/O been/O present/O at/O the/O time/O he/O was/O present/O ,/O although/O Paul/PERSON Marion/PERSON testified/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O same/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O BURROWS/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O go/O back/O for/O a/O moment/O to/O your/O work/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
You/O stated/O while/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION you/O met/O Samuel/PERSON Sillen/PERSON ,/O and/O also/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O when/O was/O that/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O Mr./O BURRiWs/O ./O 
1943/O ./O 
HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 4491/O I/O met/O Sam/PERSON Sillen/PERSON somewhere/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
I/O got/O a/O feeling/O it/O was/O somewhere/O up/O in/O the/O suburbs/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O now/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O very/O intelligent/O fellow/O ./O 
He/O was/O literary/O critic/O for/O the/O New/O Masses/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O it/O the/O night/O I/O met/O him/O ./O 
I/O knew/O that/O this/O was/O a/O very/O bright/O fellow/O who/O was/O saying/O good/O words/O about/O good/O books/O ,/O when/O we/O talked/O ,/O and/O I/O found/O him/O good/O company/O ./O 
He/O and/O his/O wife/O called/O me/O a/O week/O later/O and/O asked/O me/O over/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O found/O out/O who/O he/O was/O ./O 
We/O talked/O ,/O and/O he/O introduced/O me/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O to/O these/O other/O people/O from/O the/O New/LOCATION Masses/LOCATION ,/O and/O they/O asked/O me/O to/O their/O houses/O ;/O and/O we/O had-I/O do/O n't/O know-seven/O or/O eight/O sessions/O of/O talk/O ./O 
They/O talked/O about/O the/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O if/O I/O recall/O ,/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON wanted/O me/O to/O do/O a/O column/O for/O the/O New/O Masses/O ,/O which/O I/O would/O n't/O do/O ./O 
They/O said/O they/O had/O n't/O had/O a/O humor/O column/O for/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O there/O was/O n't/O anything/O very/O humorous/O in/O the/O publication/O ./O 
So/O ,/O he/O asked/O me/O would/O I/O consider/O doing/O a/O humor/O column/O ./O 
I/O remember/O that/O now/O ./O 
And/O I/O said/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O the/O first/O time/O that/O you/O met/O Mr./O Sillen/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O can/O you/O state/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O were/O invited/O to/O this/O first/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O BuRRows/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O n't/O a/O meeting/O ./O 
It/O was/O at/O his/O house/O ./O 
And/O he/O said/O ``/O Come/O for/O dinner/O ./O ''/O 
I/O came/O over/O with/O my/O former/O wife/O ./O 
We/O had/O dinner/O ,/O and/O there/O were/O a/O few/O people/O there/O ./O 
Then/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON ,/O John/PERSON Stewart-I/PERSON do/O n't/O remember/O who/O else/O ,/O a/O couple/O of/O people-we/O all/O sat/O around/O and/O talked/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O the/O next/O time/O ,/O he/O called/O me/O about/O 3/O days/O later/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O I/O went/O up/O to/O the/O New/O Masses/O office/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O when/O Joe/PERSON North/PERSON asked/O me/O would/O I/O be/O interested/O in/O maybe/O doing/O a/O humor/O column/O ,/O he/O said/O ``/O A/O bright/O guy/O like/O you/O ,/O ''/O and/O I/O think/O I/O recall/O then/O that/O they/O used/O the/O words/O ``/O A/O bright/O guy/O like/O you/O who/O is/O widely/O accepted/O ./O ''/O 
I/O believe/O that/O was/O the/O kind/O of/O phrase/O he/O used/O ./O 
You/O know/O how/O tough/O it/O is/O dredging/O up/O things/O from/O this/O far/O back/O ;/O but/O ,/O as/O you/O talk/O to/O me/O about/O it/O ,/O I/O follow/O through/O ./O 
And/O then/O another/O time/O I/O met-it/O must/O have/O been/O about/O six/O or/O seven/O times/O I/O met/O him/O be/O -/O fore/O I/O went/O to/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Not/O much/O more/O ;/O it/O could/O n't/O have/O been/O ,/O more/O or/O less/O perhaps/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O refuse/O to/O write/O the/O column/O for/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURROws/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O do/O a/O column/O for/O New/LOCATION Masses/LOCATION ,/O even/O though/O I/O knew/O then-you/O will/O see/O ,/O in/O any/O records/O you/O have/O of/O me/O ,/O I/O never/O wrote/O for/O a/O Communist/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O ,/O if/O you/O would/O associate/O with/O all/O of/O these/O persons/O who/O were/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O you/O would/O contribute/O to/O the/O support/O of/O the/O People/O 's/O World/O and/O the/O New/O Masses/O ,/O it/O is/O n't/O much/O of/O a/O distinction/O between/O those/O things/O and/O writing/O a/O column/O ;/O is/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O BURRows/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O there/O is/O ,/O because/O it/O is/O my/O mind/O and/O it/O is/O my/O work/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O make/O one/O point/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O in/O all/O of/O this/O ,/O even/O in/O that/O ,/O I/O never/O went/O all/O the/O way/O ,/O I/O feel/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O want/O to/O leave/O this/O committee/O with/O the/O impression/O I/O was/O trying/O to/O evade/O anything/O or/O deny/O anything/O that/O was/O said/O about/O me/O ./O 
If/O Owen/PERSON Vinson/PERSON thought/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O ,/O I/O think/O he/O had/O a/O right/O '/O to/O assume/O so/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O other/O fellows/O around/O him/O had/O a/O right/O to/O assume/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O around/O with/O them/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O deny/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O here/O under/O oath/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O what/O 2/O 1546-52-pt/O ./O 
10-4/O 4492/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O it/O looks/O like/O ;/O I/O know/O what/O ./O 
my/O associations/O make/O it/O look/O like/O ./O 
And/O so/O I/O really/O want/O that/O understood/O :/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O come/O here/O to/O be/O evasive/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O deny/O anything/O like/O that/O ./O 
