COMMUNIST/O INF/O ''/O TRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 5/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O SEPTEMBER/O 20/O ,/O 21/O ,/O 24/O AND/O 25/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 81595/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1951/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION SUBCOMMITTEE/O APPOINTED/O TO/O SIT/O IN/O Los/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O UNDER/O THIS/O TITLE/O CALIF./O ,/O To/O HOLD/O HEARINGS/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION SFRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Inve8tigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O SActing/O chairman/O in/O the/O absence/O of/O Representative/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ./O 
CONTENTS/O September/O 20/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Pace/O Testimony/O ofRobert/O L./PERSON Richards/PERSON _/O ------------------------------------/O 164/O -LRB-/O 0/O 1650/O '/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON Richards/PERSON --/O ./O 
--/O ./O 
-----------------------/O 1654/O Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON --------------------------------------/O 1666/O Marguerite/PERSON Roberts/PERSON _/O ------------------------------/O --/O 1674/O Michael/PERSON Wilson/PERSON ---------------------------------------/O 1680/O ----------------------/O John/PERSON Sanford/PERSON ------------------/O 1682/O -----------------------------------/O David/PERSON Raskin/PERSON 1696/O William/PERSON Blowitz/PERSON -/O .../O -----------------------------------/O 1699/O Herta/ORGANIZATION Uerkvitz/ORGANIZATION -------/O .../O -------------------------------/O September/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of1703/O ------------/O Max/PERSON Howard/PERSON Schoen/PERSON -------------------/O 1716/O Elizabeth/PERSON Wilson/PERSON -------------------------------------/O 1733/O -------------------------------------------/O Jeff/PERSON Corey/PERSON 1736/O Mary/PERSON Virginia/PERSON Farmer/PERSON --------------------------------------------/O 1739/O Louise/PERSON Rousseau/PERSON ---------------------/O 1742/O Dr./O Murray/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON -----------------------------------/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of1753/O Carl/PERSON Foreman/PERSON ------------------------------------------------------------------------/O 1771/O Ship/O -------/O Reuben/PERSON Ship/PERSON Bernyce/PERSON Polifka/PERSON Fleury/PERSON ----------------------------------/O 1775/O 1785/O Donald/PERSON Gordon/PERSON ---------------------------------------/O 1793/O Josef/PERSON Mischel/PERSON ----------------------------------------/O 1905/O Lester/PERSON Koenig/PERSON ---------------------------------------/O September/O 25/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of1817/O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON _/O ---------------------------------------/O 1834/O ----------------------/O Karl/PERSON Tunberg/PERSON ---------------/O Sidney/PERSON Buchman/PERSON ----------------------------------------/O 1856/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 5/O THURSDAY/O ,/O SEPTEMBER/O 20/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O AcTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O adjournment/O at/O 10:10/O a./O m./O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ;/O and/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O committee/O be/O in/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O disclose/O that/O the/O entire/O subcommittee/O is/O present/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O es/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Who/O do/O you/O have/O first/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O representing/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
She/O does/O n't/O seem/O to/O have/O arrived/O yet/O ./O 
She/O will/O be/O here/O shortly/O ,/O I/O 'm/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Does/O it/O interfere/O with/O your/O program/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
If/O so/O we/O will/O take/O a/O short/O recess/O until/O she/O comes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O judgment/O of/O the/O time/O she/O will/O arrive/O ?/O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
I/O talked/O to/O her/O earlier/O this/O morning/O and/O she/O lives/O quite/O a/O distance/O out/O and/O she/O was/O on/O her/O way/O down/O ./O 
I/O expect/O her/O any/O moment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O that/O is/O so/O then/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O I/O suggest/O that/O we/O wait/O a/O few/O minutes/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O for/O 5/O minutes/O to/O see/O if/O she/O will/O arrive/O in/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O if/O not/O we/O will/O proceed/O with/O something/O else/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O short/O recess/O was/O here/O taken/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O committee/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O am/O informed/O that/O the/O witness/O has/O had/O transportation/O difficulties/O and/O it/O may/O be/O as/O much/O as/O a/O half/O hour/O before/O she/O arrives/O ./O 
In/O light/O of/O that/O I/O think/O we/O may/O as/O well/O proceed/O with/O another/O witness/O ./O 
1639/O 1640/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
Whom/O do/O you/O call/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Robert/PERSON L./PERSON Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O Mr./O Robert/PERSON Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Iam/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O sir/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O do/O sol/O -/O emnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ROBERT/PERSON L./PERSON RICHARDS/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROBERT/PERSON KENNY/PERSON Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
Robert/PERSON Kenny/PERSON ,/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O may/O proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O Mr./O Robert/PERSON Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O raise/O a/O question/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O I/O am/O being/O on/O television/O here/O or/O not/O ,/O but/O I/O see/O the/O television/O cameras/O here/O ./O 
Are/O they/O in/O operation/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O assumed/O that/O they/O are/O ./O 
I/O never/O know/O when/O they/O are/O and/O when/O they/O are/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O question/O as/O to/O my/O privilege/O of/O being/O on/O this/O television/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O should/O think/O if/O you/O have/O any/O objection/O to/O it/O ,/O the/O chairman/O and/O the/O committee/O will/O consider/O your/O objection/O and/O act/O upon/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O think/O I/O do/O ,/O if/O you/O have/O no/O objection/O to/O my/O objection/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O qualified/O objection/O ./O 
If/O you/O objectMr/O ./O 
RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O do/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Discussion/O off/O the/O record/O among/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O decision/O of/O the/O committee/O that/O your/O objections/O will/O be/O respectedMr/O ./O 
RICHARDs/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O you/O will/O not/O appear/O on/O any/O television/O that/O is/O in/O the/O room/O ./O 
Mr./O RIcHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O instruct/O them/O that/O the/O television/O be/O cut/O off/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O television/O people/O are/O instructed/O not/O to/O televize/O this/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O RichardsMr/PERSON ./O 
WALTER/O ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O television/O facilities/O are/O --/O may/O I/O have/O attention/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
That/O the/O television/O facilities/O are/O permitted/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O through/O the/O courtesy/O of/O the/O committee/O I/O am/O sure/O that/O it/O is/O n't/O necessary/O for/O me/O to/O caution/O them/O with/O respect/O to/O the/O directive/O that/O has/O been/O given/O now/O that/O the/O witness/O is/O not/O to/O be/O shown/O on/O television/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1641/O Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O n't/O understood/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
This/O means/O ,/O then/O ,/O that/O my/O face/O will/O not/O appear/O on/O television/O but/O my/O voice/O will/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Your/O voice/O will/O appear/O whether/O the/O television/O is/O in/O here/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O difference/O in/O the/O character/O of/O the/O testimony/O that/O you/O will/O give/O here/O now/O than/O it/O would/O be/O if/O these/O television/O cameras/O were/O not/O in/O the/O room/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O perfectly/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Is/O that/O satisfactory/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O indeed/O ./O 
By/O all/O means/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O may/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O Mr./O Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Robert/PERSON Loring/PERSON Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O March/O 1/O ,/O 1909/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O or/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O a/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O a/O writer/O since/O about/O 1936/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O briefly/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O for/O the/O practice/O of/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O attended/O the/O Horace/ORGANIZATION Mann/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION --/O high/O school-and/O graduated/O from/O Harvard/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION in/O 1932/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O briefly/O what/O your/O record/O of/O employment/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O Time/O ,/O Inc./ORGANIZATION ,/O for/O about/O 7/O years/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O writer/O for/O and/O subsequently/O producer/O of/O the/O March/O of/O Time/O radio/O program/O ./O 
screen/O ./O 
I/O was/O an/O associate/O producer/O of/O the/O March/O of/O Time/O on/O the/O That/O is/O ,/O the/O documentary-the/O newsreel/O ./O 
I/O left/O Time/O mag/O -/O azine/O and/O worked/O in/O an/O advertising/O agency/O for/O about/O a/O year/O ,/O in/O radio/O ./O 
I/O came/O out/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION about/O the/O end/O of/O 1942/O ,/O did/O some/O radio/O ,/O joined/O the/O merchant/O marine/O ,/O subsequently/O went/O into/O motion/O pictures/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O for/O about-I/O am/O a/O little/O vague/O on/O dates-about/O 4/O years/O quite/O steadily/O ,/O writing/O screen/O plays/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O in/O -/O dustry/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O state/O that/O you/O came/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O the/O end/O of/O 1942/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O 1942/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ,/O as/O it/O was/O recognized/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O was/O the/O establishment/O of/O a/O second/O front/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O anyone/O had/O the/O right/O to/O sponsor/O the/O establishment/O of/O a/O second/O front/O ./O 
We/O are/O interested/O now/O in/O learning/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ,/O which/O had/O consisted/O of/O that/O principle/O ,/O was/O advocated/O by/O organizations/O influenced/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
If/O you/O have/O any/O information/O on/O that/O subject/O the/O committee/O would/O like/O to/O have/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must-I/O shall-I/O will/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O ques/O -/O tion/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O incrimination/O and/O claim/O my/O privileges/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O so/O deny-to/O so/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O ./O 
1642/O COiNMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O there/O appeared/O an/O article/O in/O the/O September/O 14/O ,/O 1942./O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O was/O sponsoring/O the/O immediate/O opening/O of/O a/O second/O front/O ,/O and/O I/O hand/O you/O the/O article/O in/O question/O ./O 
It/O appears/O from/O this/O article/O that/O your/O name/O was/O endorsed/O to/O this/O plan/O as/O sponsored/O by/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ./O 
I/O am/O interested/O only/O to/O the/O extent/O of/O your/O participating/O in/O it/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHArNs/O ./O 
Your/O question/O ,/O then/O ,/O is/O \/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Whether/O or/O not/O you/O did/O take/O part/O in/O that/O publiciz/O -/O ing/O as/O indicated/O by/O the/O press/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
According/O to/O the/O November/O 3/O ,/O 1947/O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Reporter/O ,/O there/O appears/O an/O advertisement/O contributed/O by/O the/O Actors/O '/O Division/O of/O the/O Progressive/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O did/O not/O hear/O the/O date/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
The/O date/O was/O November/O 3/O ,/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TA-ENNER/O ./O 
I/O will/O hand/O you/O the/O article/O referred/O to/O so/O that/O you/O may/O have/O it/O before/O you/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O advertisement/O proclaims/O that/O the/O Thomas-Rankin/PERSON committee/O must/O go/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O raise/O no/O objection/O to/O anyone/O criticizing/O this/O committee/O or/O its/O predecessor/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O anxious/O to/O know/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION imposes/O its/O thought/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O upon/O other/O organizations/O in/O opposing/O the/O work/O of/O this/O committee/O or/O its/O predecessor/O ,/O so/O after/O having/O looked/O at/O the/O article/O will/O you/O identify/O it/O as/O an/O advertisement/O in/O which/O you/O participated/O as/O one/O of/O the/O signers/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Richards/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O indicating/O that/O you/O were/O transferred/O from/O the/O Communist/O Party-as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O 1944/O or/O 1945/O to/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O at/O the/O time/O you/O were/O transferred/O your/O book/O number/O was/O 41786/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O for/O you/O to/O tell/O the/O committee/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O transferred/O as/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O this/O area/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O I/O have/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Carl/PERSON Winter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O an/O individual/O whose/O name/O was/O mentioned/O either/O yesterday/O or/O the/O day/O before/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Harry/PERSON Appleton/PERSON ,/O of/O whom/O it/O was/O said/O that/O he/O was/O an/O executive/O member/O of/O the/O Bay/ORGANIZATION Cities/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Communist/O Party/O during/O the/O year/O 1944/O ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O attend/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O at/O which/O he/O was/O present/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O also/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O live/O in/O 1944/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1643/O Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O tough/O one/O ./O 
1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O at/O 607/O Ocean/O Front/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
In/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O renting/O the/O property/O at/O the/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O whether/O any/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION were/O held/O at/O 607/O Ocean/ORGANIZATION Front/ORGANIZATION while/O it/O was/O being/O rented/O by/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ,/O relying/O upon/O my/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O to/O so/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O named/O some/O of/O your/O screen/O plays/O Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
You/O never/O asked/O me/O about/O my/O screen/O plays/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O we/O should/O know/O just/O the/O general/O type/O and/O character/O of/O your/O work/O ,/O if/O you/O will/O let/O the/O committee/O have/O that/O information/O ,/O as/O to/O the/O major/O screen/O plays/O with/O which/O you/O have/O been/O accredited/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O ./O 
I/O wrote/O my/O first-my/O first/O screen/O credit/O was/O a/O picture/O called/O One/O Sunday/O Afternoon/O ,/O for/O Warner/ORGANIZATION Bros./ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O was/O a/O musical/O ./O 
My/O next/O screen/O credit/O was/O a/O picture/O called/O Act/O of/O Violence/O for/O Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer/ORGANIZATION That/O was/O about/O an/O informer/O ./O 
My/O next/O credit/O was/O a/O picture/O at/O UniversalMr/O ./O 
WooD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O pardon/O me/O just/O for/O a/O moment/O at/O this/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O indeed/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
There/O may/O be/O those/O in/O the/O audience/O who/O have/O not/O been/O here/O previously/O ,/O so/O I/O announce/O again/O that/O this/O committee/O will/O not/O condone/O or/O countenance/O any/O sort/O of/O demonstration/O ,/O favorable/O ,/O unfavorable/O ,/O or/O otherwise/O ,/O in/O this/O hearing/O room/O during/O the/O conduct/O of/O these/O hearings/O ./O 
I/O hope/O that/O I/O wo/O n't/O have/O to/O repeat/O that/O admonition/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O wish/O me/O to/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O very/O glad/O for/O you/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
By/O a/O curious/O coincidence/O my/O next/O screen/O credit/O for/O Universal-International/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O picture/O called/O Johnny/PERSON Stoolpigeon/PERSON ./O 
My/O next/O credit/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O written/O in/O collaboration/O ,/O a/O picture/O called/O Winchester/PERSON '/O 73/O ,/O a/O western/O ./O 
Let/O me/O see/O ,/O there/O were/O others/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O picture/O called/O Air/O Cadet/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O picture/O called/O Kansas/ORGANIZATION Raiders/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O have/O worked/O on/O several/O others/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O do/O enough/O work/O on/O to/O get/O credit/O ,/O if/O you/O understand/O what/O I/O mean/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O pretty/O representative/O list/O of/O my/O credits/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O informed/O in/O the/O course/O of/O our/O investigation/O that/O virtually/O all/O of/O those/O who/O worked/O as/O writers/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
I/O assume/O the/O same/O thing/O was/O true/O in/O your/O case/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
I/O still/O am/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1949/O ,/O which/O was/O some/O time/O after/O the/O first/O hearings/O before/O this/O committee/O in/O 1947/O ,/O I/O believe/O there/O was/O a/O contest/O of/O special/O interest/O in/O the/O guild/O regarding/O the/O election/O of/O officers/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O ,/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O identified/O a/O number/O of/O times/O in/O the/O course/O of/O this/O investigation/O by/O witnesses/O as/O having/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O a/O candidate/O for/O membership/O on/O the/O executive/O board/O ./O 
This/O was/O in/O 1949/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O every/O member/O had/O the/O 1644/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O right/O to/O the/O free/O expression/O of/O his/O choice/O in/O the/O election/O of/O officers/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O not/O attempting/O to/O criticize/O ,/O by/O inference/O ,/O you/O or/O any/O other/O person/O for/O exercising/O that/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O asking/O me/O ,/O sir/O ,/O who/O I/O voted/O for/O in/O this/O election/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O a/O somewhat/O similar/O question/O ./O 
We/O are/O anxious/O to/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O Mr./O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON was/O sponsored/O in/O that/O election/O for/O that/O position/O by/O a/O fraction/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O by/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION who/O were/O members/O of/O the/O guild/O ./O 
In/O that/O connection/O we/O have/O noted/O that/O you/O have/O signed/O a/O petition/O nominating/O Mr./O Maltz/PERSON for/O that/O position/O ./O 
With/O that/O knowledge/O ,/O it/O occurred/O to/O us/O that/O you/O could/O inform/O us/O about/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O RIcHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O I/O have/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O questions/O of/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Richards/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O a/O member/O ,/O or/O were/O you/O a/O member/O ,/O of/O the/O actors/O '/O division/O of/O the/O Progressive/ORGANIZATION Citizens/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O RIcHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O RicHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O do/O you/O very/O frankly/O admit/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O and/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O are/O a/O member/O of/O another/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICARDps/O ./O 
I/O am/O informed/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O -/O -LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O RIcHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O under/O no/O compulsion/O to/O give/O my/O reasons/O for/O declining/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O where/O you/O got/O that/O information/O ,/O but/O if/O your/O lawyer/O has/O given/O you/O that/O information/O I/O think/O you/O ought/O to/O get/O another/O lawyer/O ,/O because/O you/O ca/O n't/O decline/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O that/O you/O just/O do/O n't/O feel/O like/O answering/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O say/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O exactly/O what/O you/O said/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
In/O justice/O to/O myself/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O since/O my/O advice/O has/O been/O taken/O into/O question/O ,/O I/O advised/O him/O that/O no/O witness/O who/O has/O declined/O to/O answer/O a/O question/O is/O under/O any/O compulsion/O to/O give/O his/O reasons/O for/O that/O declination/O because/O the/O reasons/O are/O the/O same/O in/O effect/O as/O the/O question/O itself/O ,/O or/O rather/O an/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O itself/O ./O 
If/O you/O do/O suggest/O that/O I/O was/O wrong/O in/O representing/O himMr/O ./O 
WALTER/O ./O 
Distinguished/O counsel/O from/O California/LOCATION is/O well/O aware/O of/O the/O circuit/O court/O decision/O ,/O in/O your/O own/O circuit/O ,/O which/O held/O that/O where/O a/O witness/O decided/O he/O was/O not/O going/O to/O answer/O a/O question/O innocent/O on/O its/O face/O ,/O if/O in/O fact/O that/O question/O could/O not/O incriminate/O him/O ,/O then/O he/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O is/O responsible/O for/O the/O consequences/O of/O his/O failure/O to/O answer/O that/O instant/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O afraid/O we/O will/O bore/O other/O people/O with/O a/O discussion/O ,/O but/O it/O goes/O to/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O do/O n't/O enter/O into/O any/O legal/O discussions/O ,/O gentlemen/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O notice/O on/O this/O Hollywood/O Reporter/O of/O November/O 3/O ,/O 1947/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O was/O described/O as/O the/O Thomas-Rankin/O Committee/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O Mr./O Rankin/PERSON never/O was/O in/O a/O position/O where/O this/O committee/O could/O bear/O his/O name/O ,/O and/O the/O fact/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1645/O that/O this/O propaganda/O sheet-that/O you/O will/O not/O admit/O that/O you/O had/O anything/O to/O do/O with-contains/O the/O name/O indicates/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O I/O ask/O you/O whether/O or/O not/O this/O is/O a/O fact-whether/O you/O know/O anything/O about/O it-Mr/O ./O 
Rankin/PERSON ,/O coming/O from/O Mississippi/LOCATION ,/O and/O with/O the/O kind/O of/O legislative/O record/O ,/O which/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O record/O ,/O which/O he/O has/O ,/O his/O name/O was/O n't/O used/O only/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O trying/O to/O inflame/O minority/O groups/O against/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O committee/O directed/O by/O the/O Communists/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O RIcHARDs/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O afraid/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O the/O question/O might/O tend/O to/O link/O me/O to/O an/O exhibit/O which/O is/O considered/O to/O be/O subversive/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O linking/O your/O name/O with/O that/O of/O Thomas/PERSON -/O Rankin/PERSON would/O in/O no/O wise/O incriminate/O you/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Any/O questions/O you/O have/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O ,/O Mr./O Richards/PERSON ,/O that/O you/O were/O and/O still/O are/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O a/O member/O of/O the/O board/O of/O directors/O thereof/O ?/O 
./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O that/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O sure/O I/O can/O recall/O it/O ,/O I/O never/O held/O any/O office/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Never/O ./O 
I/O never/O stood/O for/O election/O and/O never/O was/O elected/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O you/O neverMr/O ./O 
RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O just/O never/O ran/O for/O any/O office/O ./O 
I/O am/O afraid/O I/O was/O n't/O a/O very/O good/O guild/O member/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O go/O to/O many/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYE/O ./O 
You/O attended/O the/O meetingMr/O ./O 
RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O some/O of/O the/O meetings/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DomE/O ./O 
What/O is/O there/O ,/O if/O anything/O ,/O in/O your/O judgment/O about/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O you/O ever/O were/O a/O member/O thereof/O ,/O which/O might/O incriminate/O you/O if/O you/O admitted/O or/O stated/O you/O were/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O the/O question/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Quite/O correctly/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O thought/O you/O were/O going/O to/O say/O something/O further/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O listed/O as/O a/O subversive/O group/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O or/O by/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O read/O the/O statute/O or/O the/O text/O of/O the/O statute/O under/O which/O this/O committee/O is/O functioning/O here/O this/O morning/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O not/O read/O it/O ,/O sir/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O heard/O it/O mentioned/O several/O times/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O ,/O in/O a/O general/O way/O ,/O I/O am/O familiar/O with/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O have/O you/O heard/O about/O it/O and/O when/O and/O where/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O heard/O about/O it/O here/O in/O this/O committee/O room/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yesterday/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O yesterday/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O heard/O you/O speak/O of/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O heard/O youMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O remember/O me/O speaking/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O your/O saying/O that/O Congress/ORGANIZATION had/O empow/O -/O ered/O this/O committee/O to/O investigate/O subversive/O activities/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O is/O approximately/O the/O gist/O of/O it/O ./O 
1646/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O now/O ,/O assuming/O that/O you/O agree/O with/O Mr./O Webster/PERSON ,/O that/O ``/O subversive/O ''/O indicates/O uprooting/O and/O upturning/O ,/O complete/O overthrow/O and/O destruction/O ,/O would/O you/O say/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O have/O an/O opinion/O ,/O and/O if/O so/O ,/O what/O is/O your/O opinion/O ?/O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O that/O is/O a/O good/O definition/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O a/O question/O of/O opinion/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O asking/O your/O opinion/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O will/O try/O to/O give/O you/O my/O opinion/O as/O best/O I/O can/O on/O this/O rather/O complex/O question/O ./O 
,/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O nothing/O complex/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O RIcHARDS/PERSON ./O 
To/O me/O it/O seems/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O very/O simple/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
To/O me/O it/O seems/O so/O ./O 
The/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O passed/O that/O law/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O law/O of/O the/O land/O ./O 
I/O will/O at/O all/O times/O obey/O the/O laws/O of/O my/O country/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O why/O I/O am/O here/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
I/O happen/O to/O disagree/O with/O that/O law/O ./O 
Nevertheless/O ,/O it/O is/O under/O the/O law/O certainly/O your/O right/O and/O duty/O to/O conduct/O this/O investigation/O which/O you/O are/O doing/O ./O 
Does/O that/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O I/O wish/O to/O assure/O you/O that/O we/O are/O not/O trying/O to/O embarrass/O anyone/O that/O does/O disagree/O with/O the/O law/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O say/O something/O here/O on/O this/O question/O of/O opinion/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O -/O Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O have/O opinions/O ,/O some/O of/O which/O may/O be/O unpop/O -/O ular/O ,/O unorthodox/O ,/O or/O even/O totally/O erroneous/O ./O 
I/O must/O strongly/O maintain/O ,/O sir/O ,/O my/O right/O to/O hold/O these/O opinions/O ,/O and/O I/O further/O believe/O it/O is/O the/O sacred/O duty/O of/O everyone/O in/O this/O room/O to/O maintain/O my/O right/O to/O hold/O those/O opinions/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
This/O committee/O would/O not/O disagree/O with/O that/O patriotic/O duty/O of/O anyone/O to/O hold/O their/O own/O opinion/O ;/O but/O ,/O in/O like/O manner/O ,/O young/O man/O ,/O I/O believe/O as/O a/O Member/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O as/O a/O fellow/O citizen/O of/O yours/O that/O it/O is/O also/O your/O duty/O ,/O as/O an/O American/LOCATION citizen/O ,/O when/O Congress/ORGANIZATION enunciates/O a/O law/O ,/O to/O help/O carry/O that/O law/O into/O effectiveness/O ;/O and/O I/O just/O wanted/O to/O state/O to/O you/O frankly/O that/O when/O you/O hide/O behind/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O which/O you/O have/O the/O right/O to/O do/O under/O your/O constitutional/O rights/O ,/O you/O are/O not/O cooperating/O with/O this/O committee/O in/O trying/O to/O put/O into/O effect/O the/O law/O ,/O in/O my/O judgment/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O gave/O your/O opinion/O ,/O I/O have/O given/O you/O mine/O ./O 
My/O time/O is/O up/O ,/O and/O therefore/O I/O will/O yield/O back/O to/O the/O chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O I/O will/O yield/O to/O you/O ./O 
Any/O questions/O you/O may/O have/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O in/O your/O opening/O statement/O you/O made/O mention/O of/O or/O used/O the/O word/O ``/O informer/O ''/O in/O several/O of/O your/O answers/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O definition/O of/O ``/O informer/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O I/O merely/O said/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O picture/O that/O it/O was/O about/O the/O informer/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O might/O add/O ,/O the/O informer/O in/O this/O picture/O was/O treated/O quite/O sympathetically/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O an/O informer/O is/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
An/O informer/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O by/O definition/O ,/O is/O a/O man/O who/O gives/O information/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
An/O informer/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O dictionary/O ,/O is/O one/O who/O gives/O information/O with/O respect/O to/O a/O criminal/O conspiracy/O or/O criminal/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1647/O activities/O ./O 
That/O is/O to/O say/O ,/O no/O one/O has/O ever/O given/O information/O regarding/O the/O Knights/O of/O Columbus/LOCATION ,/O The/O B'nai/O B'rith/O ,/O the/O Girl/O Scouts/O ,/O or/O the/O Boy/O Scouts/O ./O 
Do/O you/O believe/O that/O in/O informing/O on/O Communists/O and/O Communist/O activities/O one/O is/O giving/O information/O with/O respect/O to/O criminal/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O believe/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O constitute/O a/O conspiracy/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O oppose/O any/O method/O of/O changing/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION except/O those/O that/O are/O set/O forth/O in/O that/O Constitution/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O most/O certainly/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O oppose/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O most/O certainly/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O served/O in/O the/O Armed/O Forces/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O not/O served/O in/O the/O Armed/O Forces/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O merchant/O marine/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O serve/O in/O the/O Armed/O Forces/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION if/O conceivably/O ,/O such/O service/O meant/O taking/O arms/O against/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O defend/O my/O country/O ,/O sir/O ,/O in/O the/O event/O of/O an/O attack/O from/O any/O source/O whatever/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Including/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Including/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O ,/O Mr./O Potter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PorTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Richards/PERSON ,/O in/O reply/O to/O a/O question/O by/O my/O colleague/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O we/O are/O greatly/O concerned/O about/O the/O freedom/O of/O opinion/O of/O individuals/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O is/O interesting/O to/O me/O to/O note/O that/O persons/O who/O are/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION are/O greatly/O concerned/O about/O individual/O opinions/O ,/O while/O those/O same/O members/O are/O denied/O ,/O within/O the/O party/O ,/O the/O expression/O of/O those/O opinions/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O have/O here/O a/O document/O which/O I/O have/O read/O from/O many/O times/O during/O the/O course/O of/O this/O investigation/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O manual/O on/O the/O organization/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O many/O members/O have-many/O former/O members/O of/O the/O party/O have-informed/O the/O committee/O has/O served/O as/O more/O or/O less/O of/O a/O bible/O for/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O read/O you/O one/O paragraph/O of/O this/O manual/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION concerning/O the/O every/O expression/O of/O opinion/O ,/O and/O I/O quote/O .1/O We/O can/O not/O imagine/O a/O discussion/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O questioning/O the/O correctness/O of/O the/O leading/O role/O of/O the/O proletariat/O in/O the/O revolution/O ,/O or/O the/O necessity/O for/O the/O proletarian/O dictatorship/O ./O 
We/O do/O not/O question/O the/O theory/O of/O the/O necessity/O for/O the/O forceful/O overthrow/O of/O capitalism/O ./O 
We/O do/O not/O question/O the/O correctness/O of/O the/O revolutionary/O theory/O of/O the/O class/O struggle/O laid/O down/O by/O Marx/PERSON ,/O Engels/PERSON ,/O Lenin/PERSON ,/O and/O Stalin/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O that/O is/O the/O end/O of/O the/O quotation/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O when/O the/O party/O ,/O itself/O ./O 
limits/O even/O the/O discussion/O which/O will/O question/O the/O basic/O principles/O of/O the/O party/O as/O mentioned/O here/O ,/O to/O claim/O that/O this/O committee/O in/O some/O way/O I/O See/O appendix/O printed/O in/O a/O separate/O volume/O ./O 
1648/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O might/O hamper/O the/O expression/O of/O an/O opinion/O is-it/O puts/O the/O person/O in/O a/O contradictory/O position/O ./O 
That/O is/O no/O question/O ./O 
It/O is/O just/O a/O statement/O which/O I/O wish/O to/O relate/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Counsel/O ,/O any/O further/O questions/O of/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O I/O got/O the/O full/O import/O of/O the/O witness/O '/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O as/O asked/O him/O with/O reference/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O would/O willingly/O bear/O arms/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O Government/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O the/O event/O of/O an/O armed/O conflict/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O repeat/O my/O answer/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O a/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
From/O any/O source/O whatsoever/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Any/O source/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Let/O me/O go/O a/O little/O further/O with/O it/O ./O 
Suppose/O such/O a/O conflict/O conceivably/O was/O brought/O about/O by/O a/O declaration/O of/O the/O constituted/O authorities/O of/O America/LOCATION in/O order/O to/O withhold/O world-wide/O aggression/O ./O 
Short/O of/O an/O attack/O ,/O what/O would/O be/O the/O attitude/O you/O would/O take/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O assume/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O the/O only/O way/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION could/O become/O involved/O in/O war/O is/O by/O a/O threat/O ,/O an/O attack/O ,/O an/O aggressive/O threat/O against/O the/O territories/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O so/O my/O answer/O stands/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O see-I/O do/O n't/O get/O the/O distinction/O ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Maybe/O I/O can/O simplify/O it/O by/O asking/O you/O this/O simple/O ques/O -/O tion/O :/O Do/O you/O approve/O of/O the/O present/O conflict/O that/O is/O being/O waged/O in/O Korea/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDs/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O opinion/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O care/O to/O express/O one/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O think/O I/O had/O better/O ./O 
This/O seems/O to/O me/O an/O extremely/O difficultMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
I/O would/O rather/O you/O answer/O the/O question/O and/O then/O if/O you/O desire/O to/O make/O any/O explanation/O of/O your/O answer/O ,/O all/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wood/PERSON ,/O this/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O opinion/O ./O 
If/O you/O do/O n't/O mind/O I/O must/O answer/O it/O in/O my/O own/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O have/O a/O direct/O answer/O first/O and/O then/O you/O can/O ex/O -/O plain/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wood/PERSON ,/O unless/O I/O can/O answer/O this/O question/O of/O opinion/O in/O my/O own/O way/O I/O shall/O not/O choose/O to/O answer/O it/O from/O this/O forum/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O you/O would/O not/O give/O a/O simple/O answer/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O approveMr/O ./O 
RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O question/O of/O a/O simple/O answer/O ./O 
This/O is/O not/O a/O simple/O question/O ./O 
The/O whole/O business/O of/O the/O Korean/O thing/O is/O a/O big/O question/O and/O there/O is/O a/O vast/O difference/O of/O opinion/O of/O all/O kinds/O on/O this/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
By/O that/O do/O you/O mean/O you/O approve/O part/O of/O it/O and/O dis/O -/O approve/O other/O portions/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O a/O yes/O or/O no/O answer/O to/O that/O ?/O 
I/O can/O not/O give/O you/O a/O yes/O or/O no/O answer/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O can/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O objection/O to/O you/O going/O into/O a/O dissertation/O except/O in/O the/O interest/O of/O time/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O furnish/O a/O forum/O here/O for/O a/O stump/O speech/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O simply/O seeking/O to/O ascertain/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1649/O whether/O you/O are/O in/O opinion/O with/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION forces/O in/O its/O efforts/O to/O suppress/O Communist/O aggression/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O simple/O question/O and/O it/O ought/O to/O have/O a/O simple/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O that/O I/O believe/O that/O it/O was/O an/O error-an/O error/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O simple/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
great/O many/O people/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O this/O opinion/O is/O shared/O by/O a/O I/O am/O heartily/O in/O favor/O ,/O I/O hope/O ,/O that/O this/O con/O -/O flict/O will/O be/O settled/O under/O the/O present/O peace/O negotiations/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
We/O all/O devoutly/O hope/O that/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O sure/O we/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O that/O I/O understood/O what/O you/O meant/O when/O you/O said/O that/O it/O was/O an/O error/O ./O 
I/O assume/O that/O you/O meant/O it/O was/O an/O error/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION forces/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ./O 
I/O think/O there/O is/O still/O room/O for/O dissenting/O opinion/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O think/O that/O one/O is/O subversive/O because/O one/O holds/O a/O dissenting/O opinion/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O our/O right/O to/O hold/O a/O dissenting/O opinion/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O because/O there/O are/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O in/O Amer/LOCATION -/O ica/O who/O have/O some/O misgivings/O on/O the/O subject/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O there/O are/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O among/O them/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O a/O tragic/O thing/O ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O the/O sooner/O it/O is/O over/O the/O better/O ./O 
I/O sincerely/O trust/O that/O it/O will/O lead/O to/O nothing/O further/O ./O 
I/O can/O not/O imagine/O anything/O more/O calamitous/O for/O not/O only/O this/O country/O or/O for/O the/O entire/O human/O race/O than/O the/O extension/O of/O this/O conflict/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O think/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON has/O another/O question/O he/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O ./O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O make/O speeches/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Has/O any/O effort/O been/O made/O by/O counsel/O or/O by/O this/O committee/O to/O alter/O your/O opinions/O or/O to/O stifle/O your/O opinions/O or/O change/O them/O Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ;/O no/O effort/O has/O been/O made/O that/O I/O can/O see/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Have/O your/O constitutional/O rights/O been/O observed/O ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
My/O constitutional/O rights/O have/O been/O observed/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Nothing/O further/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Potter/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O additional/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O just/O one/O short/O question/O ./O 
Do/O you/O contend/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O dedicated/O to/O defend/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O previously/O stated/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O do/O you/O have/O additional/O questions/O for/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O of/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O from/O further/O attendance/O on/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
It/O is/O so/O ordered/O ./O 
Whom/O do/O you/O have/O next/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Has/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON come/O in/O yet/O Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
Apparently/O not/O yet/O ./O 
She/O lives/O way/O out/O in/O West/LOCATION Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION and/O she/O said/O 45/O minutes/O ./O 
she/O will/O arrive/O ./O 
I/O suppose/O almost/O momentarily/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
It/O there/O another/O witness/O that/O you/O can/O use/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O or/O would/O youMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Mrs./O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ,/O please/O ./O 
tESTIMONY/O OF/O ANN/PERSON ROTH/PERSON MORGAN/PERSON RICHARDS/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HER/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROBERT/PERSON W./PERSON KENNY/PERSON Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O very/O photogenic/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O television/O ,/O either/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O do/O not/O want/O television/O ?/O 
First/O I/O will/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O are/O represented/O here/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O object/O to/O the/O still/O photographs/O here/O before/O you/O begin/O your/O testimony/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O before/O ,/O but/O not/O during/O ,/O because/O it/O blinds/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Then/O I/O will/O have/O to/O ask/O the/O photographers/O to/O take/O what/O ./O 
pictures/O they/O desire/O now/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Richards/PERSON has/O indicated/O a/O disinclination/O to/O be/O tele/O -/O vised/O in/O the/O giving/O of/O her/O testimony/O so/O I/O issue/O the/O same/O instruction/O and/O direction/O to/O the/O operators/O of/O the/O television/O cameras/O that/O I/O did/O a/O moment/O ago/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O that/O she/O is/O not/O to/O appear/O on/O the/O television/O screen/O at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O progress/O of/O the/O testimony/O ./O 
You/O may/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Richards/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON ./O 
Roth/PERSON is/O my/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O the/O witness/O was/O interrogated/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O she/O has/O counsel/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O lady/O is/O represented/O by/O Robert/PERSON W./PERSON Kenny/PERSON ,/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O have/O the/O right/O ,/O Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ,/O at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O progress/O of/O your/O interrogation/O to/O confer/O with/O your/O counsel/O as/O fully/O as/O you/O desire/O and/O to/O obtain/O from/O him/O any/O advice/O or/O information/O that/O you/O may/O seek/O or/O be/O in/O need/O of/O ./O 
And/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O your/O counsel/O ,/O Mr./O Kenny/PERSON ,/O having/O been/O before/O this/O committee/O many/O times/O previously/O ,/O is/O ./O 
aware/O of/O his/O privileges/O in/O connection/O with/O representing/O you/O here/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O reside/O ,/O Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
In/O Sherman/LOCATION Oaks/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Sherman/LOCATION Oaks/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O lived/O in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O about/O 25/O years/O now/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O time/O where/O did/O you/O reside/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Minneapolis/LOCATION ,/O Minn./LOCATION ,/O and/O lived/O there/O until/O I/O came/O to/O California/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1651/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O reside/O in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O spent/O 8/O months/O there/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O during/O 1936/O and/O 1937/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O made/O one/O visit/O there/O since/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O lived/O there/O permanently/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O raise/O your/O voice/O a/O little/O bit/O more/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O difficult/O for/O us/O to/O hear/O you/O over/O here/O ./O 
I/O understood/O that/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O to/O see/O my/O face/O ./O 
I/O thought/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O yOU/O me/O ,/O we/O can/O all/O hear/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O realize/O because/O I/O could/O n't/O see/O that/O you/O had/O you/O heard/O me/O through/O the/O mike/O ./O 
will/O just/O speak/O as/O if/O you/O were/O speaking/O to/O you/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
is/O your/O profession/O or/O occupation/O ,/O Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O housewife/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O engaged/O in/O any/O profession/O or/O occupation/O other/O than/O that/O of/O being/O a/O housewife/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O ,/O prior/O to/O my/O marriage/O ,/O worked/O as/O an/O administra/O -/O tive/O secretary/O for/O several/O organizations/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
When/O was/O that/O ?/O 
When/O were/O you/O married/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
1949/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O your/O marriage/O what/O organizations/O did/O you/O serve/O in/O a/O secretarial/O capacity/O for/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O for/O fear/O of/O incrimination/O ,/O and/O I/O invoke/O my/O privileges/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O employed/O at/O any/O time/O by/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O in/O a/O secretarial/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O to/O state/O that/O you/O consider/O that/O employment/O by/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O constituted/O a/O type/O of/O employ/O -/O ment/O that/O might/O subject/O you/O to/O criminal/O prosecution/O if/O you/O divulged/O that/O fact/O '/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O here/O before/O me/O a/O pamphlet/O ,/O a/O 1938/O pamphlet/O ,/O entitled/O ``/O Who/O 's/O Who/O In/O Defense/ORGANIZATION Of/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O page/O 40/O of/O this/O pamphlet/O there/O appears/O the/O names/O of/O the/O officers/O of/O the/O several/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION chapters/O ./O 
When/O I/O say/O ``/O chapters/O ,/O ''/O I/O mean/O chapters/O of/O the/O Friends/O of/O the/O Abraham/ORGANIZATION Lincoln/ORGANIZATION Brigade/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O an/O organization/O ./O 
The/O name/O of/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON appears/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O Benson/PERSON Hurst/PERSON chapter/O in/O Brooklyn/LOCATION ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O page/O 40/O of/O this/O pamphlet/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O the/O chairman/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O previous/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Berkeley/PERSON ,/O reference/O was/O made/O to/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON as/O being/O a/O person/O known/O to/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION here/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
If/O you/O were/O such/O a/O member/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O you/O questions/O relating/O to/O such/O information/O as/O you/O may/O have/O ,/O or/O within/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O regarding/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O party/O here/O and/O the/O extent/O 81595-51-pt/O ./O 
5/O -/O 2/O 1652/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O of/O its/O infiltration/O here/O ./O 
Was/O his/O testimony/O ,/O in/O which/O he/O named/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O true/O or/O false/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O previous/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O name/O is/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O like/O to/O think/O of/O myself/O as/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Rich/PERSON -/O ards/O ./O 
Roth/PERSON is/O my/O maiden/O name/O ./O 
Morgan/PERSON was/O the/O name/O of/O a/O previous/O husband/O who/O is/O dead/O ./O 
So/O I/O really/O am/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O have/O been/O known/O as/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgan/PERSON ,/O also/O ,/O of/O course/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Until/O I/O married/O Mr./O Richards/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Might/O I/O inquire/O the/O approximate/O date/O ?/O 
I/O believe/O you/O have/O given/O the/O date/O of/O your/O marriage/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O you/O designated/O which/O one/O ,/O the/O first/O one/O or/O the/O second/O one/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O date/O of/O your/O marriage/O to/O Mr./O Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
December/O 25/O ,/O 1949/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O yield/O to/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON for/O any/O questions/O he/O may/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Richards/PERSON ,/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O has/O never/O been/O designated/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O by/O this/O committee/O ,/O or/O any/O other/O organization/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ./O 
That/O being/O the/O fact/O ,/O why/O do/O you/O decline/O ,/O or/O did/O you/O decline/O ,/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O employed/O by/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O grounds/O it/O might/O incriminate/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O I/O have/O just/O propounded/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O previously/O stated/O grounds/O and/O under/O the/O privilege/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O considerMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Please/O answer/O a/O little/O louder/O so/O I/O can/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O understand/O her/O ./O 
Then/O you/O are/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O permits/O peo/O -/O ple/O to/O select/O whatever/O questions/O they/O feel/O like/O refusing/O to/O answer/O ;/O is/O that/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O legal/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O prefer/O you/O discussed/O it/O with/O my/O legal/O counsel/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O get/O into/O any/O legal/O discussions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O have/O the/O privilege/O of/O discussing/O it/O with/O your/O counsel/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
I/O did/O n't/O think/O you/O asked/O a/O question/O ;/O I/O thought/O you/O asked/O for/O an/O opinion/O ./O 
If/O it/O is/O a/O legal/O opinion/O I/O will/O consult/O with/O my/O counsel/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O have/O to/O give/O it/O to/O you/O second-handed/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
No/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Potter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PorrER/O ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Any/O further/O questions/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O may/O not/O have/O been/O plain/O from/O her/O testimony/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O she/O is/O the/O wife/O of/O Mr./O Robert/PERSON Richards/PERSON who/O just/O preceded/O her/O on/O the/O witness/O stand/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1653/O Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O proud/O to/O say/O so/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O n't/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
It/O is/O so/O ordered/O ./O 
Mrs./O RICHARDS/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ,/O gentlemen/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Kenny/PERSON ,/O has/O your/O witness/O arrived/O Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O thing/O I/O can/O do/O is/O telephone/O again/O ,/O or/O perhaps/O by/O the/O time/O you/O have/O another/O witness/O she/O should/O be/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O will/O call/O another/O witness/O ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O ,/O Mr./O Kenny/PERSON ,/O would/O you/O mind/O checking/O on/O the/O progress/O she/O is/O making/O ?/O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
Assuming/O that/O the/O next/O witness/O is/O not/O also/O a/O client/O of/O mine/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O give/O you/O time/O now/O to/O check/O up/O on/O the/O itinerary/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
If/O you/O are/O going/O to/O do/O so/O we/O are/O going/O to/O have/O a/O break/O in/O the/O hearings/O anyway/O ,/O so/O what/O about/O taking/O 15/O or/O 20/O minutes/O recess/O ./O 
-/O We/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O for/O 20/O minutes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O recess/O was/O here/O taken/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O committee/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O undertand/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON is/O here/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O am/O ,/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ,/O ma'am/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O subcommittee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ,/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O Robert/PERSON W./PERSON Kenny/PERSON of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O be/O seated/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O like/O to/O inform/O you/O that/O under/O the/O rules/O of/O this/O committee/O of/O long/O standing/O you/O have/O the/O right/O to/O confer/O with/O your/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O progress/O of/O your/O interrogation/O and/O obtain/O any/O advice/O or/O suggestions/O which/O you/O find/O yourself/O in/O need/O of/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Counsel/O having/O been/O before/O this/O committee/O on/O frequent/O occasions/O is/O familiar/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O with/O his/O rights/O under/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Does/O one/O speak/O into/O any/O special/O microphone/O here/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O KENNY/PERSON ./O 
I/O tell/O you/O ,/O just/O speak/O at/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON over/O there/O and/O everybody/O will/O hear/O you/O and/O the/O mechanics/O will/O be/O taken/O care/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O can/O speak/O so/O I/O can/O hear/O you/O they/O will/O all/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O can/O hear/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O first/O want/O to/O say/O that/O I/O am/O very/O sorry/O to/O have/O inconvenienced/O all/O of/O you/O gentlemen/O this/O morning/O ./O 
However/O ,/O television/O is/O a/O very/O fine/O medium/O ./O 
At/O least/O five/O people/O called/O me/O up/O because/O they/O were/O watching/O the/O session/O here/O ,/O and/O a/O neighbor/O called/O me/O up/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Ellenore/O ,/O you/O better/O get/O down/O there/O immediately/O ./O 
You/O are/O going/O to/O be/O arrested/O ./O ''/O 
So/O I/O told/O her/O 1654/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O my/O problem/O ,/O and/O she/O offered/O to/O drive/O me/O down/O the/O hill/O ./O 
I/O live/O on/O a./O very/O high/O hill/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O 3/O miles/O from/O the/O closest/O public/O transportation/O ,/O so/O I/O wish/O to/O thank/O the/O television/O station/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O sorry/O if/O I/O have/O inconvenienced/O any/O of/O you/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ELLENORE/LOCATION ABOWITZ/LOCATION ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HER/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROBERT/PERSON W./PERSON KENNY/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
ABowrrz/O ./O 
Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O both/O names/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
E-l-l-e-n-o-r-e/O A-b-o-w-i-t-z/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Boston/LOCATION ,/O Mass./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O followed/O a/O profession/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITZ/O ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O followed/O a/O profession/O ?/O 
,/O Mrs./O Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O occupied/O a/O position/O of/O employment/O of/O any/O kind/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O have/O had-frankly/O ,/O I/O have/O n't/O had/O very/O much/O gainful/O employment/O ,/O and/O when/O you/O ask/O me/O about/O employment/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O exactly/O what/O you/O mean/O ./O 
The/O first/O job/O I/O had/O was/O when/O I/O got/O out/O of/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION Polytechnic/LOCATION High/O School/O ;/O for/O 2/O hours/O I/O was/O once/O working/O in/O a/O dime/O store/O and/O I/O was/O fired/O because/O I/O could/O n't/O make/O any/O change/O ./O 
That/O was/O during/O the/O depression/O ,/O and/O jobs/O were/O hard/O to/O get/O ,/O so/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O at/O this/O point/O the/O next/O time/O that/O I/O had/O a/O paid/O job/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O your/O positions/O of/O employment/O have/O been/O few/O ,/O you/O should/O not/O have/O any/O difficulty/O describing/O them/O to/O us/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOwITZ/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O perhaps/O if/O there/O is/O something/O you/O are/O particularly/O interested/O in/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O could/O be/O helpful/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O interested/O in/O general/O background/O information/O relating/O to/O all/O the/O witnesses/O who/O apper/O before/O our/O committee/O in/O order/O that/O the/O committee/O may/O properly/O understand/O and/O appreciate/O and/O evaluate/O the/O testimony/O of/O the/O witness/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowITZ/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O perhaps/O I/O better/O tell/O you/O about/O my/O education/O ,/O then/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
that/O first/O ,/O if/O you/O like/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Fine/O ./O 
I/O was/O coming/O to/O that/O ,/O but/O we/O will/O take/O It/O is/O very/O short/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O grammar/O high/O school/O at/O the/O Marengo/ORGANIZATION Grammer/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Alhambra/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O went/O to/O the/O Franklin/ORGANIZATION Junior/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Polytechnic/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O went/O to/O what/O is/O now/O the/O Long/ORGANIZATION Beach/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O extent/O of/O my/O formal/O education/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O if/O you/O will/O return/O to/O the/O question/O of/O your/O em/O -/O ployment/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITz/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O I/O was/O employed/O for/O about/O a/O year/O by/O the/O Works/ORGANIZATION Progress/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOwITZ/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O between/O 1939/O and/O 1940-I/O think/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O not/O very/O good/O at/O dates/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O had/O employment/O since/O that/O time/O ,/O that/O is/O paid/O employment/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 6155/O May/O I/O consult/O with/O my/O counsel/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O you/O may/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O have/O had/O paid/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O I/O could/O n't/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O have/O had/O paid/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O did/O that/O consist/O of/O ?/O 
I/O mean/O by/O that/O ,/O how/O were/O you/O employed/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Chairman/O ,/O but/O may/O I/O consult/O with/O counsel/O ?/O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O Mr./O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
You/O have/O that/O privilege/O any/O time/O you/O desire/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O like/O to/O delay/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
That/O 's/O all/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O be/O patient/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
Will/O you/O repeat/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
My/O question/O was/O :/O What/O other/O employment/O have/O you/O had/O since/O the/O time/O you/O were/O employed/O by/O the/O WPA/O ,/O and/O which/O Ithink/O you/O said/O was/O about/O 1938/O or/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O I/O am/O getting/O a/O bit/O rattled/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O seems/O to/O me/O it/O is/O a/O very/O simple/O question/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Perhaps/O it/O is/O simple/O to/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O but/O it/O is/O n't/O to/O me/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O it/O the/O question/O or/O the/O answer/O that/O is/O complicated/O ?/O 
If/O it/O is/O the/O question/O I/O will/O try/O to/O ask/O it/O in/O another/O way/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O position/O of/O employment/O have/O you/O had/O in/O the/O past/O 5/O years/O ?/O 
What/O positions/O ,/O if/O any/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O would/O 5/O years/O be/O ,/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O is/O a/O question/O of/O time/O then/O I/O think/O I/O will/O have/O to/O return/O to/O my/O former/O question/O and/O just/O ask/O you/O ,/O What/O employment/O have/O you/O had/O since/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
-LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O at/O some/O time/O since/O that/O time/O I/O have/O been/O a/O secretary/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
A/O secretary/O employed/O by/O whom/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O claim/O my/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O and/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O has/O information/O that/O you/O were/O at/O one/O time/O a/O witness/O before/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities-that/O is/O what/O is/O known/O as/O the/O Tenney/PERSON Committee-and/O that/O it/O appears/O from/O page/O 294/O of/O the/O records/O of/O that/O committee/O that/O you/O were/O questioned/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O had/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O that/O you/O replied/O that/O you/O had/O not/O been/O ./O 
Am/O I/O correct/O in/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O not/O remember/O what/O your/O answer/O was/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
May/O I/O consult/O counsel/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O ma'am/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
May/O I/O see/O the/O transcript/O ,/O please/O ,/O if/O you/O have/O one/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O try/O to/O look/O it/O up/O ./O 
While/O we/O are/O looking/O for/O it/O may/O I/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O recall/O having/O appeared/O as/O a/O witness/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
1656/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O do/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O in/O 1947/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refer/O to/O page/O 294/O of/O the/O 1947/O report/O ,/O which/O is/O known/O as/O the/O third/O report/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O where/O there/O appears/O this/O question/O by/O Mr./O Combs/O :/O Q./O A./O Q./O A./O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
No/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Did/O you/O affiliate/O with/O it/O ?/O 
No./O ,/O If/O you/O would/O like/O to/O examine/O the/O record/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O about/O it/O I/O will/O be/O very/O glad/O to/O hand/O it/O to/O you/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
-LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
It/O says/O that/O in/O the/O book/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O so/O I/O might/O have/O said/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O in/O the/O book/O just/O exactly/O as/O I/O read/O it/O ,/O is/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O doubts/O about/O your/O reading/O it/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O didn/O t/O get/O the/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O she/O gave/O that/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
She/O really/O has/O n't/O stated/O yet/O ./O 
She/O stated/O it/O was/O in/O the/O book/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Was/O that/O your/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
It/O might/O have/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O there/O any/O doubt/O in/O your/O mind/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O not/O the/O printed/O record/O made/O in/O 1947/O of/O your/O appearance/O before/O the/O committee/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O as/O to/O your/O appearance/O there/O and/O your/O testimony/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITZ/O ./O 
Frankly/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O am/O not/O even/O sure/O about/O the/O year/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O not/O even/O sure/O that/O it/O was/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O the/O matter/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O matter/O which/O one/O would/O not/O ordinarily/O forget/O ,/O it/O being/O questioned/O before/O an/O investigating/O committee/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O little/O hard/O for/O me/O to/O understand/O how/O you/O could/O possibly/O not/O remember/O having/O been/O asked/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O particularly/O after/O having/O been/O shown/O the/O record/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O vouch/O for/O the/O transcript/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O one/O of/O my/O problems/O ,/O incidentally/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O asking/O you/O to/O vouch/O for/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O you/O if/O you/O do/O not/O recall/O having/O been/O asked/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O that/O you/O answered/O ,/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
I/O have/O merely/O given/O you/O the/O record/O to/O help/O you/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O Mrs./O ABOWIr/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O say/O again/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O ,/O that/O I/O am/O not/O -/O I/O am/O neither/O vouching/O for/O the/O transcript/O nor/O for/O the/O record/O in/O that/O book/O ./O 
Strange/O things/O have/O happened-I/O think/O that/O strange/O things/O could/O happen/O in/O those/O particular/O transcripts/O and/O that/O particular/O bookMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O the/O question/O that/O is/O asked/O you/O now/O ,/O irrespective/O of/O what/O is/O in/O the/O book/O ,/O is/O :/O Did/O you/O appear/O before/O that/O committee/O and/O give/O the/O testimony/O that/O you/O have/O been/O asked/O about/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1657/O Mrs./O ABowrTZ/O ./O 
Having/O read/O what/O is/O supposed/O to/O be/O the/O transcript/O in/O the/O book/O which/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON had/O sent/O over/O here/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O probably/O I/O might/O have/O answered/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O there/O any/O uncertainty/O whatever/O in/O your/O mind/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
It/O has/O been/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O 4/O years/O is/O not/O very/O long/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrZ/O ./O 
Four/O years/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O 1947/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O that/O it/O was/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O whether/O 1946/O ,/O 1947/O ,/O or/O 1948/O ,/O it/O is/O an/O insignifi/O -/O cant/O matter/O as/O compared/O with/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O asked/O a/O question/O of/O that/O character/O and/O that/O you/O gave/O a/O categorical/O answer/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O to/O tell/O the/O members/O of/O this/O committee/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O asked/O that/O question/O and/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O answered/O it/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recallMrs/O ./O 
ABowrrz/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O be/O a/O re/O -/O calcitrant/O witness/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O take/O up/O too/O much/O time/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O find/O myself/O here/O feeling/O very/O comfortable/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O you/O can/O understand/O that/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O have/O an/O inclination/O to/O get/O a/O bit/O rattled/O ,/O please/O forgive/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O for/O that/O reason/O I/O do/O not/O want/O to/O hurry/O you/O ./O 
I/O want/O you/O to/O have/O every/O opportunity/O to/O recall/O this/O matter/O ,/O because/O it/O is/O important/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
And/O consequently/O ,/O I/O will/O have/O to/O ask/O your/O indulgence/O and/O discuss/O this/O matter/O with/O my/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O suggest/O that/O you/O may/O feel/O perfectly/O at/O ease/O ./O 
If/O you/O need/O time/O to/O consider/O ,/O if/O you/O need/O time/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O ,/O we/O are/O happy/O to/O have/O you/O have/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O prepared/O now/O to/O give/O an/O answer/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O remember/O substantially/O giving/O that/O testimony/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O also/O that/O it/O was/O suggested/O at/O that/O hearing/O that/O you/O were/O known/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O by/O a/O name/O other/O than/O your/O full/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOwrrz/O ./O 
I/O claim/O my/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O and/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O think/O you/O have/O misunderstood/O me/O ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O asked/O you/O what/O your/O Communst/O Party/O name/O was/O ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O if/O you/O recall/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O asked/O a/O question/O during/O that/O hearing/O regarding/O the/O use/O by/O you/O of/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION name/O ,/O other/O than/O your/O name/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O will/O have/O to-rather/O ,/O I/O desire/O to/O claim/O my/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O do/O you/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mrs./O AnowIrz/PERSON ./O 
I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O claim/O your/O privilege/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABoWITZ/O ./O 
Will/O you/O excuse/O me/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O say/O you/O desire/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
The/O question/O is/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O do/O claim/O your/O privilege/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowITZ/O ./O 
Will/O you/O excuse/O me/O ,/O please/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O see/O the/O transcript/O ,/O please/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
SMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
./O 
Yu/PERSON mean/O in/O order/O to/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O on/O the/O witness/O stand/O before/O the/O so-called/O Tenney/PERSON committee/O ,/O I/O believe/O I/O was/O there/O for/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O Tenney/PERSON and/O I/O got/O into/O a/O slight/O ruckus/O ,/O and/O this/O went/O on/O for/O several/O hours/O ./O 
I/O was/O also/O quite/O excited/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O and/O if/O you-you/O ca/O n't/O possibly/O think/O that/O testimony/O covering/O several/O hours/O is/O fresh/O in/O my/O mind/O at/O this/O point/O ./O 
Frankly/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O have/O too/O clear/O a/O recollection/O of/O what/O the/O questions/O and/O answers/O were/O ,/O because/O the/O whole/O thing/O developed/O into/O a/O rather/O personal/O feud/O between/O Mr./O Tenney/PERSON and/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O then/O ,/O let/O me/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O from/O the/O record/O ./O 
The/O record/O of/O this/O hearing/O ,/O the/O same/O hearing/O ,/O at/O page/O 295/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O page/O just/O following/O that/O which/O you/O saw/O before/O ,/O there/O appears/O this/O :/O Q./O Is/O it/O a/O fact/O or/O is/O it/O not/O that/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION name/O was/O Margaret/PERSON Pettos/PERSON ,/O P-e-t-t-o-s/O ?/O 
-/O A./O I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O the/O name/O is/O unfamiliar/O to/O me/O ./O 
Q./O That/O is/O not/O a/O fact/O ,/O then/O ?/O 
-/O A./O I/O say/O ,/O the/O name/O is/O not/O familiar/O to/O me/O ./O 
Q./O Yes/O ;/O but/O I/O have/O to/O get/O a/O categorical/O answer/O into/O the/O record/O ,/O either/O affirmative/O or/O negative.-A/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Will/O you/O hand/O the/O record/O to/O the/O witness/O that/O she/O may/O examine/O what/O I/O have/O read/O ,/O and/O I/O will/O ask/O you/O now/O ,/O after/O having/O heard/O what/O I/O read/O to/O you/O and/O after/O seeing/O it/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O yourself/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O that/O refreshes/O your/O recollection/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Witness/O consults/O with/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O Document/O was/O handed/O to/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O ABowTrz/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O want/O to/O say/O again/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O be/O recalcitrant/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O draw/O this/O thing/O out/O ,/O but/O I/O frankly/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O n't/O you/O examine/O that/O page/O at/O the/O time/O I/O handed/O you/O the/O record/O the/O first/O time/O Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O -/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O point/O out/O the/O reference/O that/O I/O have/O just/O made/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O am/O aMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O aside/O from/O that/O ,/O does/O not/O the/O examination/O of/O that/O record/O and/O my/O having/O read/O it/O to/O you/O refresh/O your/O recollection/O about/O the/O question/O concerning/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOWIrrz/O ./O 
It/O is/O in/O thebook/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
It/O might/O have-it/O possibly/O did/O happen/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O know/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O it/O was/O correctly/O transcribed-that/O is/O ,/O the/O question/O and/O the/O answer-was/O your/O answer/O correct/O and/O truthful/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O claim/O the/O privilege/O granted/O me/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O and/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 1659/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O were/O asked/O the/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O you/O gave/O the/O answer/O ,/O ``/O No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O ,/O ''/O were/O you/O telling/O the/O truth/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
The/O same/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O what/O is/O the/O answer/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
I/O claim/O my/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O \/O and/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O were/O asked/O the/O question/O ,/O ``/O Did/O you/O affili/O -/O ate/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O ''/O 
and/O the/O reply/O is/O alleged/O to/O have/O been/O made/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O ''/O if/O that/O reply/O was/O made/O ,/O was/O it/O truthful/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABOwITZ/O ./O 
The/O same/O question/O ,/O same/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O ,/O Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O that/O at/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O October/O 26/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O there/O were/O various/O commis/O -/O sions/O appointed/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O commissions/O to/O represent/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Communist/O Party/O in/O various/O activities/O ,/O and/O one/O of/O such/O commissions/O was/O that/O known/O as/O the/O political/O relations/O commission/O ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O that/O Charles/PERSON Gladstone/PERSON ,/O at/O that/O time/O a/O prominent/O labor/O official/O in/O the/O International/O Ladies/O '/O Garment/O Workers/O ,/O was/O a/O member/O of/O that/O commission/O ,/O and/O Philip/PERSON M./PERSON Connelly/PERSON ,/O at/O that/O time/O executive/O secretary/O of/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION CIO/ORGANIZATION Council/ORGANIZATION but/O who/O left/O that/O office/O and/O then/O became/O editor/O of/O the/O Daily/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Dorothy/PERSON R./PERSON Healey/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O known/O as/O organizational/O secretary/O of/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O William/PERSON O'Neal/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O been/O a/O prominent/O leader/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O having/O occupied/O a/O position/O on/O State/O committee/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O Nemmy/PERSON Sparks/PERSON ,/O who/O at/O the/O time/O was/O chairman/O of/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O were/O members/O ,/O and/O that/O you/O were/O also/O a/O member/O of/O that/O commission/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O extremely/O helpful/O to/O this/O committee/O ,/O if/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O that/O commission/O ,/O that/O you/O advise/O the/O committee/O regarding/O the/O part/O it/O played/O in/O the/O infiltration/O of/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
Are/O youMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
So/O I/O will/O ask/O you/O first/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O that/O commission/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABOWITZ/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O the/O answer/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O meetings/O of/O the/O political/O relations/O commis/O -/O sion/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION held/O in/O your/O home/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITZ/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Abowitz/PERSON ,/O there/O has/O been/O testimony/O taken/O in/O the/O executive/O session/O before/O this/O committee/O ,/O the/O testimony/O of/O Dr./O Mendell/PERSON Morton/PERSON Krieger/PERSON ,/O in/O which/O he/O makes/O a/O reference/O to/O your/O alleged/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O want/O to/O read/O that/O portion/O of/O it/O to/O you/O and/O obtain/O from/O you/O a/O statement/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O is/O true/O or/O false/O ,/O or/O to/O have/O you/O make/O any/O explanation/O that/O you/O desire/O to/O make/O of/O it/O ./O 
These/O questions/O and/O answers/O were/O made/O and/O given/O in/O referring/O to/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O and/O these/O questions/O were/O asked/O :/O How/O many/O individuals/O were/O in/O attendance/O at/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
Offhand/O ,/O it/O is/O hard/O for/O me/O to/O honestly/O answer/O you/O ./O 
1660/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O This/O question/O was/O asked/O :/O Where/O did/O these/O meetings/O take/O place/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIuEER/O ./O 
Various/O houses/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O any/O of/O the/O people/O who/O owned/O the/O houses/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O recall/O one/O whose/O house/O we/O met/O at/O a/O few/O times/O and/O then/O there/O were/O a/O couple/O of/O others/O and/O I/O very/O honestly/O can/O not/O recall/O their/O names/O at/O the/O present/O time/O ./O 
They/O did/O n't/O strike/O me/O as/O anything/O outstanding/O and/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O their/O names/O ./O 
What/O is/O the/O name/O of/O the/O one/O individual/O you/O do/O remember/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O a/O physician/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Murray/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON ./O 
Was/O his/O wife/O Ellenore/PERSON present/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
./O 
You/O knew/O both/O Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON and/O Murray/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O was/O chairman/O of/O this/O cell/O ?/O 
Dr./O KRIEGER/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time/O Ellenore/PERSON Abowitz/PERSON was/O ./O 
Is/O that/O testimony/O true/O or/O is/O it/O false/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O quesuon/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O year/O 1945-I/O mean/O to/O say/O in/O the/O year/O of/O 1944/O or/O 1945/O ,/O did/O you/O have/O any/O official/O position/O in/O a/O political/O party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
-LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O permitting/O that/O answer/O to/O stand/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O want/O to/O leave/O the/O inference/O that/O I/O consider/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION a/O political/O party/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O addressing/O my/O attention/O to/O that/O and/O possibly/O my/O question/O was/O misleading/O to/O you/O ,/O so/O I/O will/O put/O my/O question/O in/O another/O way/O ./O 
I/O will/O put/O it/O more/O direct/O so/O that/O there/O can/O be/O no/O misunderstanding/O of/O it/O :/O Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ABowITz/O ./O 
May/O I/O consult/O counsel/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O -LRB-/O after/O conferring/O with/O her/O counsel/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O difficulty/O that/O I/O am/O having/O here/O seems/O to/O be/O a/O good/O example/O of/O what/O this/O kind/O of/O investigation/O leads/O to/O ,/O that/O I/O am/O puzzled/O about/O answering/O a/O ques/O -/O tion/O ,/O the/O answer/O to/O which/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O public/O record/O ./O 
I/O thinkMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Maybe/O I/O can/O help/O you/O with/O that/O ,/O if/O you/O will/O permit/O ./O 
It/O is/O n't/O my/O purpose/O to/O criticize/O your/O membership/O in/O any/O political/O party/O ,/O but/O this/O committee/O will/O be/O interested/O in/O knowing/O whether/O or/O not/O while/O serving/O in/O such/O a/O capacity/O the/O influence/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O brought/O to/O bear/O upon/O it/O and/O how/O it/O was/O done/O ,/O if/O such/O be/O the/O fact/O ./O 
Mrs./O ABowrrz/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O that/O is/O a/O question/O at/O this/O point/O ./O 
I/O was/O about/O to/O say/O ,/O I/O am/O frankly/O puzzled/O ,/O but/O I/O really/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O am/O ./O 
