COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 2/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O APRIL/O 17/O ,/O 23/O ,/O 24/O ,/O 25/O ;/O MAY/O 16/O ,/O 17/O ,/O AND/O 18/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFlICB/O 81595/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1951/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ;/O Counsel/O LOUIS/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXQN/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O April/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofSam/O Moore/PERSON --------------------------------------------------------------/O Harold/PERSON Buchman/PERSON -----------------------------/O Anne/PERSON Revere/PERSON --/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ---------------------------/O April/O 23/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O John/PERSON Jules/PERSON Garfield/PERSON ---------------/O Page/O 303/O 312/O 318/O 321/O --/O 328/O -/O ------/O April/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofMarc/O Lawrence/O ------------------------------------------------------/O George/PERSON Willner/PERSON -------/O Morris/ORGANIZATION Carnovsky/ORGANIZATION -/O --------------------/O April/O 25/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O -----------------/O Abraham/PERSON Lincoln/PERSON Polonsky/PERSON -----/O Edward/PERSON Dmytryk/PERSON -------------------/O May/O 16/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofLeonardo/O Bercovici/PERSON --------------------/O Alvin/PERSON Hammer/PERSON -------------------------/O Bea/PERSON Winters/PERSON ------------------------------/O May/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O ofLloyd/O Gough/PERSON ------------------------/O Thad/O Page/O ---------------------------------/O Leonardo/PERSON Bercovici/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --------------------/O Roy/PERSON M./PERSON Brewer/PERSON -----------------------/O May/O 18/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Roy/PERSON M./PERSON Brewer/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ----------------/O In/O 365/O 376/O 389/O 396/O 408/O -/O 441/O 451/O 458/O 463/O 471/O 472/O 473/O 495/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OFIHOLLYWOODIMOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 2/O TUESDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O CpmMIrrmEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTivrrTEs/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./O 0/O ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O adjournment/O at/O 10/O :/O 30/O a./O m./O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O and/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O committee/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O ,/O please/O ,/O that/O there/O are/O present/O the/O following/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O :/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ,/O a/O majority/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O as/O the/O first/O witness/O this/O morning/O Mr./O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O SAM/PERSON MOORE/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O MARTIN/O POPPER/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O Moon/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
Martin/PERSON Popper/PERSON ,/O 160/O Broadway/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O state/O when/O and/O where/O you/O were/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Flushing/LOCATION ,/O N./PERSON Y./PERSON ,/O in/O November/O 1904/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O place/O of/O residence/O Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
444/O Central/O Park/O West/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
303/O 304/O COMMUNIioSM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O ./O 
INDUSTRY/O Mr./O MooR/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O a/O brief/O statement/O of/O your/O educational/O training/O Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O grade/O schools/O all/O over/O the/O country-in/O Cam/O -/O bridge/O ,/O Mass./LOCATION ;/O Bryn/LOCATION Mawr/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ;/O Madison/LOCATION ,/O Wis./LOCATION ;/O Ann/PERSON Arbor/PERSON ,/O Mich./LOCATION ./O 
I./O went/O to/O high/O school/O 2/O years/O in/O Ann/PERSON Arbor/PERSON ,/O and/O finished/O my/O preparatory/O school/O work/O at/O Kent/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O Kent/LOCATION ,/O Conn./LOCATION ./O 
I/O went/O to/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Michigan/ORGANIZATION at/O Ann/PERSON Arbor/PERSON and/O took/O my/O A./O B./O degree/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O the/O committee/O a/O brief/O statement/O of/O your/O employment/O record/O since/O the/O time/O of/O the/O completion/O of/O your/O education/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON left/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O worked/O in/O the/O advertising/O business/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION from/O about/O 1925/O to/O 1930/O ./O 
In/O 1931/O ,/O I/O became/O a/O reporter/O on/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Herald/ORGANIZATION Tribune/ORGANIZATION under/O Stanley/PERSON Walker/PERSON ./O 
After/O that/O I/O became/O a/O radio/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O approximate/O date/O when/O you/O became/O a/O radio/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O toward/O the/O end/O of/O 1931/O ./O 
I/O was/O employed/O by/O the/O J./ORGANIZATION Walter/ORGANIZATION Thompson/ORGANIZATION Advertising/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION and/O worked/O for/O them/O until/O 1936/O ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O them/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION until/O 1934/O ;/O then/O they/O sent/O me/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O worked/O there/O until/O 1936/O ./O 
In/O 1936/O ,/O I/O left/O them/O to/O go/O with/O th.e/O William/PERSON Este/PERSON Agency/PERSON ./O 
I/O left/O them/O in/O 1937/O and/O have/O been/O a/O free-lance/O writer/O ever/O since/O ./O 
I/O wrote/O for/O radio/O until/O 1947/O ./O 
From/O 1942/O to/O 1947/O ,/O I/O wrote/O in/O collaboration/O a/O program/O called/O The/O Great/O Gildersleeve/O ./O 
I/O stopped/O radio/O in/O 1947/O and/O came/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION because/O of/O a/O legitimate/O show/O that/O I/O was/O one/O of/O the/O authors/O of/O ./O 
I/O did/O one/O radio/O show/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O the/O summer/O of/O 1949/O ./O 
In/O the/O autumn/O of/O 1949/O Texas/LOCATION L'il/O Darlin/PERSON '/O was/O produced/O on/O Broadway/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O a/O little/O television/O since/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON returned/O to/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O left/O Hollywood/LOCATION about/O 1947/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O left/O Hollywood/LOCATION just/O for/O the/O summer/O in/O 1949/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O left/O again/O last/O summer/O and/O have/O been/O here/O since/O ./O '/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O first/O go/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
In/O February/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
While/O you/O were/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O an/O associate/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O for/O a/O very/O short/O time/O when/O I/O did/O work/O in/O pictures/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O hold/O any/O position/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O period/O during/O which/O you/O were/O asso/O -/O ciated/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O during/O 1937/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Just/O for/O the/O period/O of/O the/O 1/O year/O ,/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Probably/O ./O 
I/O only/O worked/O in/O pictures/O about/O 6/O or/O 8/O weeks/O ;/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O kept/O up/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O after/O I/O went/O back/O to/O radio/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 305/O Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O is/O one/O of/O the/O organiza/O -/O tions/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O classified/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O it/O may/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ,/O the/O privilege/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O ,/O you/O decline/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O relating/O to/O the/O conduct/O of/O the/O business/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O ground/O for/O refusal/O to/O answer/O questions/O relating/O to/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
The/O fact/O that/O although/O this/O organization-the/O fact/O that/O this/O organization/O ,/O whether/O it/O is/O in/O that/O book/O or/O not/O ,/O has/O been/O attacked/O by/O this/O committee/O and/O other/O groups/O as/O a/O so-called/O subversive/O group/O ,/O and/O for/O me/O to/O answer/O questions/O about/O it/O ,/O I/O feel/O would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O that/O guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O some/O dates/O on/O that/O ./O 
From/O about/O 1938/O or/O 1939/O until/O the/O present/O time/O ,/O including/O the/O present/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O official/O positions/O have/O you/O held/O with/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O served/O on/O the/O council/O of/O the/O western/O region/O of/O the/O guild/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION from/O 1940/O to/O 1943/O ./O 
I/O was/O vice/O president/O in/O charge/O of/O the/O western/O region/O in/O 1943/O and/O 1944/O ./O 
I/O was/O national/O president/O of/O the/O guild/O in/O 1945/O and/O 1946/O ./O 
And/O in/O 1947/O and/O 1948/O I/O served/O two/O more/O terms/O as/O western/O vice/O president/O ./O 
In/O 1949/O I/O was/O reelected/O to/O the/O council/O of/O the/O western/O region/O ./O 
In/O 1950/O I/O moved/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O was/O elected/O to/O the/O council/O of/O the/O eastern/O region/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O support/O financially/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MoORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O already/O declined/O to/O answer/O questions/O relating/O to/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O and/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O this/O is/O another/O question/O of/O the/O same/O kind/O which/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
According/O to/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON ,/O one/O of/O the/O projects/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O was/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O relating/O to/O atomic/O energy/O ,/O and/O to/O that/O end/O there/O was/O established/O within/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O a/O group/O known/O as/O the/O ``/O Atomic/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
Were/O you/O affiliated/O in/O any/O way/O with/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O ``/O Atomic/O Energy/O Commission/O ''/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O same/O type/O of/O question/O as/O the/O other/O question/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O a/O group/O within/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O that/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O of/O that/O same/O character/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer-Will/O you/O repeat/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O read/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O question/O referred/O to/O was/O read/O by/O the/O reporter/O ,/O as/O follows/O :/O ``/O Was/O there/O a/O group/O within/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O that/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O of/O that/O same/O character/O ?/O ''/O -RRB-/O 
306/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Could/O you/O make/O that/O question/O a/O little/O more/O specific/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O could/O not/O help/O but/O overhear/O ,/O from/O even/O at/O this/O distance/O ,/O what/O appeared/O to/O be/O prompting/O of/O your/O answer/O about/O making/O it/O more/O specific/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O counsel/O should/O indicate/O to/O the/O witness/O what/O answers/O to/O make/O ,/O but/O of/O course/O you/O are/O free/O ,/O as/O the/O chairman/O will/O advise/O you/O ,/O to/O confer/O with/O your/O counsel/O at/O all/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
I/O object/O to/O the/O comment/O because/O it/O is/O inconsistent/O with/O the/O fact/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O such/O statement/O made/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O has/O a/O right/O to/O confer/O with/O his/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O he/O desires/O ./O 
Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O my/O objection/O noted/O because/O it/O is/O contrary/O to/O the/O fact/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O not/O counsel/O make/O the/O statement/O to/O you/O ,/O when/O I/O first/O asked/O the/O question/O ,/O to/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O made/O more/O specific/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
He/O did/O not/O use/O the/O word/O ``/O specific/O ,/O ''/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O word/O did/O he/O use/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O but/O he/O did/O n't/O say/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O meaning/O of/O it/O ,/O was/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
I/O object/O to/O that/O on/O the/O ground/O this/O constitutes/O legitimate/O advice/O of/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O does/O not/O permit/O objections/O ./O 
Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
I/O appreciate/O that/O ,/O but/O the/O witness/O is/O being/O badgered/O about/O legitimate/O advice/O of/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O merely/O being/O asked/O a/O question/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O the/O view/O of/O the/O chairman/O that/O the/O questions/O asked/O are/O not/O a/O badgering/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
My/O question/O to/O you/O was/O whether/O or/O not/O there/O was/O within/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O a/O group/O which/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O relating/O to/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O still/O think/O it/O is/O a/O vague/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O seem/O to/O me/O to/O be/O an/O easy/O question/O for/O you/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O consider/O it/O a/O vague/O and/O airy/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O I/O will/O try/O to/O make/O it/O a/O little/O more/O specific/O for/O you/O ./O 
Were/O you/O interested/O ,/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O to/O the/O public/O relating/O to/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Either/O as/O a/O member/O or/O not/O as/O a/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
It/O seems/O to/O me/O you/O are/O just/O trying/O to/O connect/O me/O again/O with/O this/O organization/O ,/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O ,/O which/O you/O have/O declared/O or/O attempted/O to/O define/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O only/O endeavoring/O to/O get/O such/O facts/O from/O you/O as/O I/O am/O able/O to/O get/O concerning/O your/O experience/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION and/O the/O various/O organizations/O with/O which/O you/O were/O affiliated/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O an/O organization/O within/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O which/O interested/O itself/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O relating/O to/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
It/O seems/O to/O me/O this/O is/O the/O same/O type/O of/O question/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O asked/O the/O question/O of/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O admitted/O he/O was/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 307/O Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O understood/O he/O said/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O have/O misunderstood/O the/O question/O ./O 
You/O have/O stated/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O various/O positions/O you/O have/O held/O in/O the/O guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O I/O am/O very/O proud/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O are/O unwilling/O to/O state/O to/O this/O committee/O to/O what/O extent/O they/O were/O active/O or/O interested/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O relating/O to/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O declined/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O a/O committee/O known/O as/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Advisory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Before/O you/O get/O away/O from/O that/O ,/O what/O was/O the/O name/O of/O that/O organization/O ,/O Radio/O Writers/O `/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Radio/ORGANIZATION Advisory/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O to/O answer/O it/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
That/O organization/O has/O never/O been/O listed/O as/O a/O subver/O -/O sive/O ,/O Communist/O ,/O or/O Communist-front/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O was/O of/O a/O committee/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O and/O the/O Mobilization/O has/O been/O classified/O by/O this/O committee/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O POPPER/PERSON ./O 
If/O the/O chairman/O permits/O me/O to/O ,/O I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O refer/O you/O to/O the/O page/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O have/O an/O understanding/O so/O that/O we/O may/O avoid/O fur/O -/O ther/O interruptions/O ./O 
Counsel/O is/O privileged/O at/O this/O hearing/O to/O advise/O his/O client/O ,/O not/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O the/O official/O publication/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O known/O as/O Communique/O ,/O in/O its/O March/O 1945/O issue/O reported/O that/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O was/O planning/O a/O series/O of/O 26/O radio/O plays/O regarding/O the/O problems/O of/O returning/O soldiers/O ./O 
Were/O you/O on/O a/O board/O of/O five/O charged/O with/O the/O responsibility/O of/O getting/O scripts/O approved/O and/O into/O production/O relating/O to/O that/O series/O of/O radio/O programs/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O another/O question/O that/O would/O connect/O me/O with/O the/O Mobilization/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O as/O stated/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
May/O I/O interrupt/O at/O this/O point/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Your/O refusal/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O a/O while/O ago/O was/O predicated/O on/O the/O statement/O you/O made/O that/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O had/O been/O classified/O by/O this/O committee/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O ./O 
I/O call/O attention/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O that/O statement/O is/O not/O borne/O out/O by/O the/O facts/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Maybe/O it/O is/O n't/O this/O committee/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O in/O the/O list/O issued/O by/O the/O committee/O in/O March/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
WooD/O ./O 
It/O was/O cited/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Would/O that/O fact/O alter/O the/O witness/O '/O position/O on/O answering/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O it/O would/O not/O ./O 
308/O Mr./O COMMUNISM/O IN/O TAVENNER/O ./O 
MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O As/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O were/O you/O active/O in/O procuring/O the/O use/O of/O a/O broadcast/O station/O ,/O a/O radio/O station/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Could/O you/O make/O that/O question/O more/O specific/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O interested/O in/O obtaining/O the/O approval/O of/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Communications/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION to/O set/O up/O a/O radio/O station/O in/O behalf/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Community/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O know/O what/O you/O are/O referring/O to/O ,/O Mr./O Taven/PERSON -/O ner/O ./O 
I/O took/O part/O in/O a-may/O I/O see/O the/O book/O ?/O 
Are/O you/O referring/O to/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Community/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O suppose/O that/O is/O it/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O listed/O on/O page/O 56/O of/O this/O book/O as/O a/O subversive/O organization/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O questions/O relating/O to/O it/O for/O the/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O witness/O has/O given/O several/O reasons/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O these/O questions/O ,/O that/O they/O were/O vague/O and/O uncertain/O and/O that/O the/O organization/O about/O which/O they/O were/O asked/O was/O listed/O in/O this/O guide/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O get/O it/O clear/O ,/O what/O is/O your/O ground/O for/O refusal/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
The/O ground/O is/O the/O fear/O ,/O my/O fear/O ,/O that/O an/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
There/O has/O been/O testimony/O before/O this/O committee/O by/O Mr./O Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON to/O the/O effect/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O interested/O in/O the/O project/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O of/O disseminating/O information/O regarding/O atomic/O energy/O ./O 
To/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O was/O there/O a/O like/O interest/O ,/O or/O interest/O of/O any/O kind/O ,/O exhibited/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O the/O same/O type/O of/O information/O by/O means/O of/O radio/O ,/O through/O the/O help/O of/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O or/O any/O groups/O within/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
This/O question/O is/O the/O same/O type/O of/O question/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O as/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O might/O tend/O to/O incrimi/O -/O nate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O get/O it/O clear/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O :/O You/O have/O stated/O you/O belonged/O to/O an/O organization/O you/O say/O you/O are/O very/O proud/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O it/O is/O your/O contention/O that/O to/O answer/O ``/O yes/O ''/O or/O ``/O no/O ''/O to/O a/O question/O of/O whether/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION tried/O to/O use/O that/O organization/O ,/O would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O know/O whether/O there/O was/O a/O group/O within/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION known/O as/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION during/O the/O year/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O as/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Motion/ORGANIZATION Picture/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 309/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Democracy/ORGANIZATION is/O an/O organization/O that/O was/O cited/O by/O the/O Special/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O UnAmerican/O Activities/O on/O March/O 29/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O and/O by/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O UnAmerican/O Activities/O on/O April/O 17/O ,/O 1947/O ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O any/O substantial/O contribution/O to/O that/O organization/O after/O it/O was/O first/O cited/O and/O with/O knowledge/O that/O it/O had/O been/O cited/O as/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION front/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON left/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O see/O the/O point/O of/O asking/O me/O about/O these/O one/O after/O another/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O also/O on/O the/O same/O ground/O .1/O There/O are/O hundreds/O of/O organizations/O listed/O in/O your/O book/O ,/O and/O there/O are/O millions/O of/O members/O who/O have/O been/O proud/O to/O be/O members/O ,/O and/O this/O committee/O has/O made/O it/O impossible/O to/O answer/O this/O type/O of/O question/O with-i/O out/O the/O possibility/O of/O incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
DO/O you/O think/O the/O listing/O of/O these/O organizations/O has/O in/O anywise/O caused/O a/O decline/O of/O interest/O in/O the/O organizations/O and/O affected/O the/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O listing/O of/O such/O organization/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O intimidate/O members/O and/O nonmembers/O from/O joining/O that/O organization/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
WALTER/O ./O 
Has/O it/O had/O that/O effect/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O has/O tended/O to/O have/O that/O effect/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O your/O listing/O of/O a/O number/O of/O peace/O organizations/O was/O certainly/O not/O an/O encouragement/O to/O people/O -/O who/O organized/O for/O peace/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O through/O ?/O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O would/O like/O to/O follow/O it/O a/O little/O further/O ./O 
You/O think/O the/O release/O of/O the/O names/O of/O these/O organizations/O that/O purportedly/O are/O for/O the/O promotion/O of/O peace/O affected/O membership/O drives/O and/O perhaps/O affected/O the/O ability/O of/O the/O sponsors/O of/O those/O movements/O to/O raise/O funds/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O of/O my/O own/O knowledge/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O it/O would/O be/O probable/O that/O that/O would/O be/O the/O result/O ./O 
The/O result/O naturally/O would/O be/O to/O frighten/O people/O away/O from/O making/O any/O kind/O of/O organized/O effort/O for/O peace/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
If/O that/O is/O what/O was/O accomplished/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O committee/O has/O made/O a/O substantial/O contribution/O to/O peace/O in/O America/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O you/O mean/O by/O ``/O contribution/O ./O ''/O 
My/O idea/O is/O ,/O peace/O is/O peace/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Even/O if/O it/O means/O surrender/O and/O the/O peace/O of/O Alcatraz/LOCATION ?/O 
That/O is/O peace/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O have/O any/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
You/O stated/O an/O answer/O to/O various/O questions/O asked/O you/O would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ./O 
Has/O the/O committee/O ever/O ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O incriminated/O or/O caused/O incrimination/O of/O any/O witness/O who/O has/O come/O here/O and/O answered/O questions/O truthfully/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O tell/O you/O definitely/O ,/O if/O you/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O that/O it/O has/O not/O and/O never/O will/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O at/O one/O time/O on/O the/O editorial/O staff/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O magazine/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O a/O question/O in/O which/O the/O committee/O is/O tampering/O with/O the/O freedom/O of/O the/O -/O press/O ./O 
Hollywood/O Quarterly/O is/O listed/O also/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O as/O a/O subversive/O publication/O by/O your/O committee/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON and/O Ed/PERSON Dmytryk/PERSON also/O on/O the/O editorial/O staff/O of/O that/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O repeat/O that/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O strike/O ``/O also/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON and/O Ed/PERSON Dmytryk/PERSON on/O the/O editorial/O staff/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O stated/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O attend/O a/O meeting/O in/O 1945/O to/O discuss/O what/O is/O known/O as/O the/O Duclos/PERSON letter/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O as/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O has/O information/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1944/O and/O 1945/O ,/O and/O that/O you/O held/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ,/O registration/O card/O ,/O bearing/O No./O 47288/O for/O the/O year/O 1945/O ./O 
Is/O that/O information/O correct/O ?/O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O MOREo/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O are/O you/O a/O member/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
-/O Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O with/O reference/O to/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O think/O you/O volunteered/O the/O information/O that/O you/O were/O national/O president/O in/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O then/O that/O you/O were/O vice/O president/O a/O couple/O times/O ,/O and/O very/O proud/O of/O your/O membership/O ,/O and/O were/O elected/O to/O the/O council/O of/O the/O western/O and/O also/O the/O eastern/O region/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O looked/O in/O the/O book/O to/O which/O you/O referred/O ,/O both/O in/O the/O index/O ,/O at/O page/O 155/O ,/O and/O throughout/O this/O book/O I/O think/O you/O referred/O to/O as/O published/O in/O March/O of/O this/O year/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O find/O that/O organization/O listed/O ./O 
Is/O it/O your/O claim/O that/O it/O is/O listed/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O is/O a/O trade-union/O that/O is/O one/O of/O the/O best/O in/O the/O entertainment/O industry/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O very/O proud/O of/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O in/O your/O book/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O n't/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O refused/O to/O answer/O a/O ques/O -/O tion/O or/O two/O committee/O counsel/O asked/O you/O about/O the/O functioning/O of/O that/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION in/O connection/O with/O atomic/O energy/O ,/O if/O anything/O ,/O and/O you/O refused/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O same/O ground/O you/O had/O before/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O declined/O to/O answer/O a/O question/O that/O had/O to/O do/O with/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O misunderstood/O ,/O then/O ,/O counsel/O 's/O question/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O ,/O then/O :/O Did/O the/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member-I/O believe/O you/O said/O you/O still/O are/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DYLE/O ./O 
Did/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION have/O any/O committee/O which/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O dissemination/O of/O information/O about/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O such/O committee/O ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
INDUSTRY/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O 311/O Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O that/O Radio/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O make/O financial/O contributions/O to/O any/O organization/O which/O was/O interested/O in/O informing/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O on/O any/O subject/O in/O connection/O with/O atomic/O energy/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
That/O question/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
If/O the/O organization/O about/O which/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O is/O not/O listed/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O why/O would/O anything/O it/O did/O be/O ,/O in/O your/O judgment/O ,/O apt/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
It/O is/O not/O listed/O as/O subversive/O group/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O asking/O you/O about/O any/O other/O group/O ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O you/O about/O this/O one/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O asking/O a/O question/O that/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O is/O an/O at/O -/O tempt/O to/O tie/O me/O up/O with/O other/O organizations/O ./O 
this/O reason/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Maybe/O you/O are/O trying/O to/O anticipate/O what/O I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O ,/O but/O you/O might/O be/O mistaken/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O stand/O on/O my/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O trying/O to/O trap/O you/O ./O 
I/O am/O interested/O in/O trying/O to/O get/O your/O philosophy/O as/O to/O why/O you/O think/O answering/O a/O question/O as/O to/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION would/O incriminate/O you/O when/O it/O is/O not/O listed/O in/O any/O way/O in/O any/O subversive/O group/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Counsel/O has/O given/O me/O some/O kind/O of/O legal/O advice/O I/O do/O n't/O understand/O ,/O but/O I/O stand/O on/O my/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O heard/O your/O counsel/O and/O still/O do/O n't/O understand/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
I/O heard/O the/O finish/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Any/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
One/O more/O question/O ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O your/O position/O to/O be/O substantially/O this/O :/O That/O ,/O if/O you/O were/O asked/O any/O question/O by/O counsel/O or/O by/O one/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O with/O reference/O to/O any/O subject/O as/O to/O the/O activities/O or/O objectives/O or/O purposes/O or/O functioning/O of/O any/O group/O listed/O in/O this/O book/O published/O by/O the/O committee/O on/O March/O 3/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O you/O would/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O it/O might/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
I/O guess/O that/O is/O substantially/O right/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O reason/O I/O asked/O you/O that/O was/O not/O to/O trap/O you/O ./O 
I-notice/O you/O have/O refused/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O that/O was/O asked/O you/O about/O any/O organization/O or/O committee/O listed/O in/O this/O book/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O question/O :/O Do/O I/O understand/O then/O that/O you/O refusal/O to/O answer/O my/O question/O about/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O you/O have/O stated/O you/O this/O question/O :/O Do/O I/O understand/O then/O that/O your/O refusal/O to/O answer/O in/O 1945/O ,/O is/O because/O you/O feel/O that/O your/O answer/O to/O that-question/O might/O directly/O or/O indirectly/O lead/O you/O into/O being/O asked/O about/O the/O functioning/O of/O any/O of/O these/O groups/O that/O are/O listed/O as/O subversive/O in/O this/O book/O Mr./O MooRE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Walter/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moore/PERSON ,/O in/O the/O course/O of/O your/O preparation/O of/O scripts/O for/O radio/O ,/O television/O ,/O and/O the/O theater/O ,/O did/O you/O ever/O do/O anything/O on/O the/O atomic/O bomb/O or/O the/O horrors/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Did/O you/O write/O anything/O about/O the/O use/O of/O the/O atomic/O bomb/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O recall/O ;/O no/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ./O 
312/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Velde/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O notice/O you/O declined/O to/O answer/O some/O questions/O with/O reference/O to/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O it/O appeared/O in/O this/O guide/O the/O committee/O has/O issued/O ./O 
The/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O has/O been/O cited/O as/O a/O Communist-front/O organization/O by/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O in/O 1948/O ./O 
Does/O that/O information/O alter/O your/O position/O on/O answering/O the/O questions/O concerning/O its/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOORE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Any/O further/O questions/O ,/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Is/O there/O reason/O why/O this/O witness/O can/O not/O be/O excused/O from/O further/O attendance/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O of/O none/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Harold/PERSON Buchman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Buchman/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O testimony/O you/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O HAROLD/PERSON BUCHMAN/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O R./PERSON LAWRENCE/PERSON SIEGEL/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O Mr./O Harold/PERSON Buchman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O your/O full/O name/O ?/O 
Mr/O :/O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
R./PERSON Lawrence/PERSON Siegel/PERSON ,/O of/O Pepper/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Siegel/ORGANIZATION ,/O 55/O Liberty/O Street/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O N./O Y./O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O will/O you/O indulge/O me/O to/O make/O a/O motion/O for/O a/O few/O seconds/O ?/O 
I/O will/O be/O very/O brief/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
A/O motion/O ?/O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Of/O what/O nature/O ?/O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O move/O to/O vacate/O the/O subpena/O on/O several/O legal/O grounds/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
It/O will/O take/O about/O 2/O seconds/O if/O you/O want/O to/O indulge/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O inquire/O of/O the/O witness/O first/O if/O he/O has/O been/O subpenaed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O responded/O here/O today/O in/O answer/O to/O a/O subpena/O served/O on/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O has/O been/O subpenaed/O ./O 
This/O is/O not/O the/O proper/O forum/O in/O which/O to/O attack/O the/O validity/O of/O a/O subpena/O ./O 
The/O committee/O 's/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O only/O recourse/O in/O presenting/O witnesses/O is/O by/O its/O subpenas/O ./O 
313/O If/O it/O should/O become/O necessary/O in/O some/O future/O time/O to/O attack/O the/O validity/O of/O it/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O proper/O forum/O in/O which/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
My/O view/O of/O it/O is/O that/O this/O is/O not/O the/O proper/O forum/O ./O 
However/O ,/O if/O you/O have/O a/O written/O motion/O there/O you/O may/O file/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Buchman/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O state/O ,/O -/O please/O ,/O when/O and/O where/O you/O were/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Brainerd/LOCATION ,/O Minn./LOCATION ,/O June/O 24/O ,/O 1912/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O place/O of/O residence/O ?/O 
Mr./O BucHMAN/PERSON ./O 
607/O North/LOCATION Crescent/LOCATION Drive/LOCATION ,/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Screen/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Would/O the/O witness/O speak/O up/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCIMAN/PERSON ./O 
Screen/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O briefly/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O my/O family/O moved/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION when/O I/O was/O about/O 8/O ./O 
I/O went/O through/O the/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION public/O school/O system/O ./O 
I/O graduated/O from/O George/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O 1929/O ./O 
The/O fall/O of/O that/O year/O I/O entered/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Pennsylvania/ORGANIZATION and/O I/O stayed/O there/O 4/O years/O ,/O until/O I/O received/O an/O A./O B./O degree/O in/O 1933/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O briefly/O your/O employment/O record/O since/O the/O completion/O of/O your/O education/O ./O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O never/O known/O any/O other/O profession/O except/O screen/O writing/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O oh/O ,/O perhaps/O 6/O months/O after/O graduation/O from/O college/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O be/O in/O what/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Either/O the/O very/O end/O of/O 1933/O or/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1944/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1934/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O say/O 1944/O ?/O 
I/O mean/O 1934/O ./O 
And/O I/O wrote/O stories/O without/O success/O for/O a/O year/O or/O so/O ,/O finally/O sold/O a/O very/O important/O --/O unimportant/O ,/O I/O should/O say-story/O ,/O and/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O it/O I/O obtained/O a/O job/O at/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O I/O stayed/O for/O about/O 3/O years/O ,/O writing/O dozens/O and/O dozens/O of/O what/O we/O call/O program/O pictures/O in/O celluloid-low/O budget/O films/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O approximate/O dates/O ?/O 
You/O said/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 3/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O from/O about/O 1935/O through/O a/O good/O deal/O of/O 1938/O I/O worked/O exclusively/O at/O Columbia/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 1939/O I/O worked/O at/O Universal/O ./O 
At/O Universal/O I/O did/O several/O films/O ./O 
In/O 1940/O I/O went/O to/O Fox/PERSON ,/O 20th/O Century/O Fox/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O think/O all/O of/O my/O Hollywood/O employment/O for/O the/O next/O 4/O or/O 5/O years/O was/O at/O 20th/O Century/O Fox/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O under/O contract/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O living/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O from/O 1940/O up/O through/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
In/O a/O community/O not/O far/O from/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION called/O Westwood-called/O West/LOCATION Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
I/O think/O the/O exact/O street/O was/O Homedale/O Street/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O number/O of/O your/O residence/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
It/O had/O 5/O numbers/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O 11132/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O worked/O there/O until/O 1945/O ,/O and/O then/O from/O 1945/O what/O was/O your/O employment/O ?/O 
314/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O worked/O at/O Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer/ORGANIZATION following/O that/O ./O 
I/O worked/O at/O Metro/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O from/O December/O of/O 1945/O until/O about/O June/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
Possibly/O May/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
My/O next/O employment/O was/O at/O Twentieth/O Century/O Fox/O ./O 
In/O 1948/O I/O worked/O at/O Fox/PERSON for/O a/O brief/O time/O ./O 
I/O then/O had/O no/O employment/O for/O ,/O oh/O ,/O almost/O a/O year/O ./O 
My/O next/O job/O was/O at/O Paramount/O in/O 1949/O ./O 
I/O worked/O at/O Paramount/O from/O 1949/O ,/O September/O ,/O to/O I/O believe/O about/O March/O of/O 1950/O ./O 
I/O have/O not/O been/O employed/O since/O except/O for/O a/O couple/O of/O weeks/O at/O Columbia/LOCATION for/O my/O brother/O ,/O who/O produces/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O brother/O 's/O name/O is/O Sidney/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Sidney/PERSON Buchman/PERSON ./O 
And/O save/O for/O those/O few/O weeks/O ,/O I/O have/O not/O been/O employed/O since/O I/O left/O Paramount/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O NNER/O ./O 
Duringthis/PERSON period/O of/O time/O when/O you/O worked/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION as/O a/O screen/O writer/O ,/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAX/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O official/O positions/O have/O you/O held/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O and/O the/O approximate/O dates/O ?/O 
MJr/O ./O 
BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O I/O have/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O executive/O board/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O elevate/O your/O voice/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O executive/O board/O ./O 
What/O years/O ,/O I/O could/O not/O say/O ./O 
I/O have/O served/O in/O the/O guild/O for/O so/O many/O years/O on/O committees/O ,/O like/O credit/O union/O ,/O arbitration/O ,/O and/O what/O not/O ,/O that/O I/O would/O really/O be/O hard/O pressed/O to/O say/O ./O 
Possibly/O in/O 1945/O and/O 1946/O ,/O in/O those/O years/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O board/O ./O 
I/O know/O that/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O board/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O was/O treasurer/O for/O a/O couple/O of/O years/O of/O the/O guild/O ./O 
I/O was/O elected/O to/O the/O board/O in/O October/O of/O 1949/O and/O served/O until-served/O a/O full/O year/O until/O October/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O was/O the/O election/O date/O in/O the/O guild/O ,/O of/O 1950/O ./O 
I/O hold/O no/O office/O in/O the/O guild/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O apparently/O were/O on/O the/O executive/O board/O or/O possibly/O the/O treasurer/O at/O about/O the/O time/O that/O the/O issue/O arose/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O should/O continue/O to/O receive/O the/O support/O of/O the/O guild/O ./O 
What/O can/O you/O tell/O us/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O on/O the/O ground/O that/O it/O may/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O do/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O that/O I/O might/O ask/O you/O regarding/O your/O knowledge/O of/O the/O operations/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O merely/O feel/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O that/O in/O the/O context/O of/O this/O hearing/O ,/O in/O relation/O to/O certain/O matters/O which/O I/O feel/O I/O do/O n't/O have/O to/O acquaint/O you/O with/O ,/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O feel/O compelled/O ,/O or/O rather/O I/O feel/O that/O I/O can/O not/O in/O any/O way/O be/O asked/O to/O provide/O any/O kind/O of/O evidence/O against/O myself/O in/O terms/O of/O names/O or/O facts/O or/O any/O shred/O of/O evidence/O which/O might/O be/O used/O against/O me/O in/O a/O prosecution/O ./O 
I/O deplore/O theMr/O ./O 
WooD/O ./O 
Is/O it/O your/O thought/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O to/O answer/O questions/O involving/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O might/O have/O such/O a/O tendency/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O is/O it/O for/O that/O reason/O that/O you/O decline/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O concerning/O the/O operation/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 315/O ,/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O have/O occasion/O to/O travel/O outside/O the/O con/O -/O tinental/O limits/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O period/O you/O were/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION as/O a/O screen/O writer/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Europe/LOCATION for/O about/O 5/O months/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O countries/O did/O you/O visit/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O visited/O first/O England/LOCATION ./O 
From/O England/LOCATION I/O took/O a/O boat/O to/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
From/O there/O I/O went/O to/O Austria/LOCATION ./O 
From/O Austria/LOCATION I/O went/O to/O Italy/LOCATION ./O 
From/O Italy/LOCATION I/O went/O to/O France/LOCATION ./O 
From/O France/LOCATION I/O went/O to/O Switzerland/LOCATION ,/O back/O to/O Austria/LOCATION to/O ski/O ./O 
I/O then/O went/O to/O Paris/LOCATION ,/O back/O to/O London/LOCATION again/O ,/O and/O then/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O 5/O or/O 6/O weeks/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O you/O purpose/O in/O going/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O 'd/O describe/O it/O as/O a/O grand/O tour/O ,/O a/O trip/O throughout/O Europe/LOCATION that/O I/O was/O always/O wanting/O to/O make/O ./O 
I/O had/O saved/O just/O enough/O money/O to/O make/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O single/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O date/O of/O the/O trip/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O left/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION in/O August/O and/O returned/O in/O February/O ,/O althoughMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Of/O what/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
1937/O to/O 1938/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O your/O expenses/O paid/O entirely/O by/O yourself/O or/O was/O there/O a/O contribution/O from/O any/O source/O toward/O your/O expenses/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
None/O whatsoever/O ./O 
All/O my/O own/O ./O 
I/O was/O purely/O a/O tourist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O affiliated/O with/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O I/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Buchman/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O has/O information/O that/O you/O held/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION card/O No./O 46802/O for/O the/O year/O 1944/O ,/O and/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O for/O the/O year/O 1945/O bearing/O `/O the/O number/O 47174/O ,/O which/O bore/O the/O address/O 11232/O Homedale/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O any/O time/O ,/O and/O are/O you/O a/O member/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O it/O may/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYIE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Buchman/PERSON ,/O you/O related/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O it/O ,/O that/O group/O is/O not/O listed/O as/O subversive/O ,/O is/O it/O ,/O in/O the/O book/O issued/O March/O 3/O ,/O 1951/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O not/O asked/O any/O questions/O about/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O sir/O ,/O except/O in/O relation/O to/O a/O matter/O which/O gives/O me/O a/O sense/O of/O apprehension/O about/O incrimination/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O you/O do/O not/O find/O the/O Hollywood/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O listed/O ,/O do/O you/O ,/O in/O this/O book/O referred/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O find/O the/O Mobilization/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DonE/O ./O 
What/O page/O is/O that/O on/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Fifty-seven/O ./O 
81595-51-pt/O ./O 
2-2/O 316/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O is/O listed/O as/O the/O third/O item/O on/O page/O 57/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O asking/O you/O about/O that/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O you/O or/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O briefly/O about/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Screen/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Are/O they/O one/O and/O the/O same/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O why/O you/O do/O n't/O answer/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
It/O is/O merely/O the/O context/O of/O the/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
They/O are/O not/O the/O same/O ,/O except/O that/O I/O feel/O that/O very/O likely/O in/O the/O near/O future/O they/O could/O be/O the/O same/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Because/O of/O the/O similarity/O Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O because/O of/O certain/O testimony/O and/O a/O long/O history/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O which/O I/O feel/O because/O of/O my/O election/O in/O 1949that/O I/O feel/O like/O a/O candidate/O who/O is/O impervious/O to/O political/O winds/O ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O I/O was/O very/O honored/O in/O 1949/O that/O the/O guild/O looked/O upon/O me/O as/O an/O individual/O and/O considered/O that/O I/O owed/O no/O loyalty/O to/O any/O other/O organization/O except/O the/O guild/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O do/O you/O feel/O if/O I/O asked/O you/O any/O question/O about/O the/O functioning/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Screen/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION that/O you/O would/O be/O compelled/O to/O decline/O to/O answer/O because/O you/O think/O it/O might/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O waste/O your/O time/O and/O the/O committee/O 's/O time/O if/O that/O is/O going/O to/O be/O your/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O for/O clarification/O ,/O which/O I/O think/O may/O simplify/O it/O ./O 
When/O you/O say/O ``/O Hollywood/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O ''/O Congressman/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O mean/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O what/O is/O confusing/O the/O witness/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O refer/O to/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
What/O would/O be/O your/O answer/O to/O that/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O feel/O that/O if/O I/O asked/O you/O any/O question/O about/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O that/O you/O would/O be/O compelled/O in/O your/O own/O conscience/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O it/O might/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
It/O is/O not/O listed/O ,/O as/O near/O as/O I/O can/O see/O ,/O in/O this/O book/O ,/O is/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O just/O honestly/O feel/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O that/O it/O would/O be/O difficult/O for/O you/O to/O ask/O a/O question/O in/O which/O I/O could/O not/O sense/O a/O line/O of/O inquiry/O that/O I/O feel/O might/O lead/O to/O some/O future/O prosecution/O of/O myself/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O regrettable/O situation/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O did/O n't/O cause/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O read/O the/O law/O or/O has/O your/O counsel/O informed/O you/O of/O what/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O this/O committee/O is/O and/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O hearing/O ?/O 
Mr./O BucHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O a/O general/O understanding/O of/O it/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O understanding/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O understand/O my/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
-/O Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O you/O ,/O frankly/O ,/O as/O one/O American/O to/O another/O :/O What/O do/O you/O understand/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O this/O committee/O is/O at/O this/O sort/O of/O a/O hearing/O this/O morning/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O like/O many/O congressional/O committees/O ,/O a/O committee/O attempting/O to/O get/O information/O ,/O the/O end/O product/O of/O which/O is/O legislation/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Legislation/O for/O what/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O BTCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O big/O problem/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O this/O :/O I/O have/O known/O of/O you/O for/O a/O long/O time/O and/O applauded/O your/O election/O many/O years/O ago/O ,/O and/O sitting/O in/O this/O room/O was/O impressed/O with/O your/O own/O sincere/O desire/O to/O understand/O what/O is/O going/O on/O here/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O we/O have/O any/O argument/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O about/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O a/O political/O doctrine/O that/O is-well/O ,/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 317/O in/O a/O country/O that/O has/O had/O 150/O years/O of/O democratic/O processes/O ,/O I/O have/O never/O envisioned/O any/O change/O for/O this/O country/O which/O could/O not/O be/O achieved/O within/O that/O document/O ,/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O observation/O that/O you/O have/O just/O made/O -/O that/O you/O felt/O I/O was/O sincere/O in/O my/O committee/O approach/O to/O these/O problems-I/O wish/O to/O say/O that/O I/O think/O all/O members/O of/O this/O committee/O are/O sincere/O in/O trying/O to/O do/O the/O job/O we/O are/O assigned/O to/O do/O ./O 
I/O take/O it/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O you/O have/O n't/O had/O the/O time/O to/O read/O this/O assignment/O under/O the/O bill/O which/O the/O committee/O functions/O under/O ,/O which/O is/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O :/O Would/O n't/O you/O feel/O it/O is/O the/O duty/O and/O responsibility/O of/O this/O committee/O to/O examine/O into/O the/O extent/O and/O character/O and/O objectives/O of/O subversive/O conduct/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O if/O we/O were/O assigned/O to/O do/O that/O by/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
AMr/O ./O 
BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Sitting/O there/O last/O week/O I/O accepted/O your/O Webster/PERSON definition/O of/O ``/O subversive/O ,/O ''/O but/O beyond/O that/O point-and/O this/O is/O where/O we/O get/O into/O trouble/O ,/O and/O I/O speak/O as/O someone/O who/O considers/O himself/O no/O less/O loyal/O than/O any/O man/O in/O this/O room/O in/O combating/O a/O forceful/O overthrow/O of/O this/O country/O in/O an/O armed/O conflict/O ./O 
I/O would/O bear/O arms/O in/O defense/O of/O this/O country/O ./O 
But/O beyond/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O there/O are/O many/O questions/O of/O what/O this/O country/O is/O ./O 
I/O mean/O what/O it/O embodies/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O my/O opinion/O of/O this/O committee/O may/O not/O be/O worth/O anything/O because/O the/O accusation/O could/O be/O made/O that/O ,/O singled/O out/O by/O it/O ,/O I/O am/O very/O prejudiced/O and/O that/O my/O opinion/O is/O worth/O nothing/O ./O 
But/O I/O could/O find/O a/O stack/O of/O very/O conservative/O opinion/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O not/O a/O good/O committee/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON entered/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O question/O with/O reference/O to/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
From/O your/O answers/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O it/O is/O very/O apparent/O that/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O is/O not/O listed/O as/O subversive/O by/O this/O committee/O or/O any/O records/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O published/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O functioning/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O been/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O a/O number/O of/O weeks/O ./O 
I/O assume/O I/O am/O ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O been/O notified/O that/O my/O membership/O was/O terminated/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
At/O any/O time/O during/O the/O time/O you/O were/O active/O as/O a/O mem/O -/O ber/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O were/O you/O aware/O in/O your/O own/O belief/O ,/O from/O understanding/O the/O situation/O ,/O of/O any/O effort/O ,/O either/O direct/O or/O indirect/O ,/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O gain/O any/O control/O ,/O either/O by/O election/O of/O officers/O or/O committees/O ,/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O because/O of/O the/O obvious/O placing/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O I/O am/O deliberately/O placing/O it/O to/O find/O out/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O which/O is/O not/O listed/O as/O sub/O -/O versive/O ,/O was/O an/O object/O of/O desire/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION as/O one/O of/O the/O groups/O they/O wanted/O to/O control/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O purpose/O of/O my/O question/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O asking/O you/O whether/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O be/O a/O truthful/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O an/O honest/O declination/O to/O answer/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O is/O a/O very/O old/O and/O good/O answer/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O only/O one/O I/O can/O give/O ./O 
318/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O DOmiE/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Velde/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Whom/O did/O you/O go/O to/O work/O for/O in/O 1949/O at/O Paramount/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O '/O 
A/O man/O named/O Milton/PERSON Holmes/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Milton/PERSON Holmes/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
H-o-l-m-e-s/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O agency/O are/O you/O connected/O with/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O time/O it/O was/O the/O Willner-Goldstone/O agency/O ,/O which/O I/O had/O for/O about/O a/O year/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O it/O was/O the/O Mary/PERSON Baker/PERSON ,/O and/O for/O many/O years/O a/O man/O named/O Lucien/PERSON Swanson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Am/O I/O correct/O that/O in/O 1948/O you/O were/O at/O 20th/O Century/O Fox/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O scripts/O did/O you/O do/O during/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O BUCHMAN/PERSON ./O 
I/O wrote/O a/O story/O about/O psychosomatic/O medicine/O for/O a/O man/O named/O Kaufman-a/O comedy/O ./O 
We/O sold/O it/O to/O 20th/O ,/O and/O we/O went/O to/O work/O on/O the/O screen/O play/O ,/O which/O I/O hear/O is/O now/O on/O the/O shelf/O ./O 
There/O are/O so/O many/O ./O 
It/O has/O never/O been/O produced/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Any/O further/O questions/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O this/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
The/O next/O witness/O is/O Anne/PERSON Revere/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ./O 
You/O do/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O testimony/O you/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ANNE/PERSON REVERE/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HER/O COUNSEL/O ,/O R./PERSON LAWRENCE/PERSON SIEGEL/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Anne/PERSON Revere/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
R./PERSON Lawrence/PERSON Siegel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O your/O address/O too/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
Fifty-five/O Liberty/O Street/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION 5/O ,/O N./PERSON Y./PERSON Mr./PERSON Chairman/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O file/O a/O motion/O to/O vacate/O the/O subpena/O in/O behalf/O of/O this/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Miss/O Revere/O ,/O will/O you/O please/O state/O the/O place/O of/O your/O birth/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O for/O not/O asking/O me/O when/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Occasionally/O I/O play/O grandmothers/O ,/O and/O it/O might/O jeopardize/O my/O professional/O standing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O place/O of/O residence/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
2511/O Bowmont/O ,/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O Miss/O INDUSTRY/O 319/O IRVERE/O ./O 
I/O like/O to/O think/O of/O myself/O as/O an/O actress/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O in/O a/O general/O way/O your/O edu-cational/O background/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O educated/O in/O the/O grammar/O schools/O and/O high/O ./O 
schools/O of/O Westfield/ORGANIZATION ,/O N./PERSON J./PERSON ,/O and/O went/O rom/O there/O immediately/O to/O Wellesley/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ,/O from/O which/O I/O graduated/O ,/O receiving/O my/O B./O A./O -/O degree/O in/O 1926/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O record/O of/O engagements/O as/O an/O ./O 
actress/O ,/O briefly/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Spotty/O ,/O like/O all/O actresses/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
For/O whom/O have/O you/O worked/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O just/O interested/O in/O motion/O pictures/O ,/O or/O would/O ./O 
you/O like/O my/O theater/O history/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O began/O in/O the/O theater/O many/O years/O ago/O ./O 
I/O presume/O that/O my/O most/O successful/O plays/O were/O Double/O Door/O and/O The/O Children/O 's/O Hour/O ,/O in/O which/O I/O had/O an/O extended/O engagement/O ./O 
I/O also/O established/O or/O helped/O to/O establish/O a/O theater/O ,/O which/O I/O owned/O and/O operated/O ,/O in/O Surrey/LOCATION ,/O Maine/LOCATION ./O 
Subsequently/O ,/O in/O 1934/O ,/O I/O first/O came/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION to/O do/O the/O picture/O version/O of/O Double/O Door/O ,/O and/O then/O went/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O have/O for/O approximately/O 11/O years/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O been/O a/O resident/O `/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O during/O a/O great/O portion/O of/O that/O time/O ./O 
employed/O in/O the/O studios/O ./O 
./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
About/O what/O year/O did/O your/O residence/O in/O California/LOCATION begin/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O January/O 1940/O ,/O as/O nearly/O as/O I/O remember/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
While/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O Actors/O '/O Laboratory/O ,/O Inc./ORGANIZATION or/O affiliated/O with/O it/O in/O any/O way/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVE/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON and/O gentlemen/O ,/O this/O would/O seem/O to/O me/O ,/O ,/O based/O upon/O my/O observation/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O week/O in/O which/O I/O have/O listened/O to/O these/O testimonies/O ,/O to/O be/O the/O first/O in/O a/O possible/O series/O \*/O ofquestions/O which/O would/O attempt/O in/O some/O manner/O to/O link/O me/O with/O subversive/O organizations/O ;/O and/O as/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O a/O political/O ./O 
party-legal/O political/O party-in/O this/O country/O today/O ,/O and/O as/O I/O consider/O ./O 
any/O questioning/O regarding/O one/O 's/O political/O views/O or/O religious/O views/O as/O ./O 
a/O violation/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O a/O citizen/O under/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O as/O I/O would/O consider/O myself/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O contributing/O to/O the/O overthrow/O of/O -/O our/O form/O of/O government/O as/O I/O understand/O it/O if/O I/O were/O to/O assist/O you/O in/O violating/O this/O privilege/O of/O mine/O and/O other/O citizens/O of/O this/O country/O ,/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ,/O and/O also/O the/O first/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Miss/O Revere/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O you/O were/O the/O holder/O of/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION registration/O card/O for/O the/O year/O 1945/O ,/O bearing/O the/O number/O 47346/O ,/O and/O that/O you/O also/O held/O a/O card/O for/O the/O year/O 1944/O ,/O which/O bore/O the/O number/O 46937/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Could/O I/O see/O the/O card/O ,/O gentlemen/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recognize/O that/O card/O -LSB-/O handing/O document/O to/O witness/O -RSB-/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
As/O this/O would/O in/O effect/O constitute/O an/O answer/O to/O a/O question/O which/O I/O have/O already/O declined/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O reasons/O given/O ,/O namely/O ,/O that/O it/O is/O an/O invasion/O of/O the/O privileges/O and/O rights/O of/O a/O citizen/O ,/O 320/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O I/O would/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O possible/O self-inrimination/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O do/O notMr/O ./O 
WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O for/O that/O reason/O Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O SIEGEL/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O consult/O with/O the/O witness/O for/O a/O moment/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Miss/O Revere/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O also/O has/O information/O in/O the/O form/O of/O sworn/O testimony/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Do/O you/O desire/O to/O either/O affirm/O or/O deny/O that/O statement/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Again/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O claim/O my/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O and/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O such/O a/O question/O ,/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Is/O it/O on/O that/O basis/O that/O you/O decline/O to/O answer/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Could/O I/O enlarge/O upon/O that/O answer/O ,/O Mr./O Wood/PERSON ?/O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O just/O want/O to/O know/O if/O that/O is/O your/O reason/O for/O not/O answering/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O my/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O the/O committee/O is/O interested/O in/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVEX-NER/O ./O 
Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O seem/O to/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O that/O that/O is/O anotherMr/O ./O 
./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Just/O answer/O or/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O again/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/O `/O Party/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
That/O I/O also/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O ,/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O name/O Ann/PERSON Revere/PERSON is/O your/O professional/O name/O ,/O is/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O my/O professional/O name/O ./O '/O 
It/O is/O also/O the/O name/O which/O I/O was/O baptized/O with/O in/O the/O Presbyterian/ORGANIZATION Church/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Westfield/ORGANIZATION ,/O N./O J./O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O been/O married/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O at/O present/O married/O :/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O husband/O 's/O name/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Samuel/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O were/O you/O married/O ?/O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
1935/O ;/O April/O 11/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Walter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Velde/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O this/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 321/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Miss/O REVERE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Could/O I/O sayMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O testimony/O you/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O WILLIAM/PERSON A./PERSON WHEELER/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O employed/O as/O an/O investigator/O by/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O so/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
It/O will/O be/O 4/O years/O this/O coming/O August/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O were/O you/O directed/O to/O serve/O various/O subpenas/O in/O California/LOCATION for/O the/O attendance/O of/O prospective/O witnesses/O at/O this/O hearing/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O ``/O this/O hearing/O ''/O I/O do/O not/O necessarily/O confine/O it/O to/O today/O ,/O but/O I/O mean/O the/O Hollywood/O hearings/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O difficulty/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O you/O have/O had/O in/O serving/O those/O subpenas/O ,/O and/O be/O specific/O as/O to/O names/O and/O as/O to/O the/O circumstances/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O I/O were/O assigned/O by/O this/O committee/O to/O serve/O approximately/O 30/O subpenas/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O is/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Andrews/PERSON is/O also/O an/O investigator/O of/O this/O com/O -/O mittee-on/O approximately/O 30/O individuals/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O this/O assignment/O we/O were/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION on/O two/O separate/O occasions/O ,/O the/O first/O from/O February/O 21/O to/O March/O 17/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O and/O again/O from/O April/O 1/O to/O April/O 8/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
During-this/O period/O of/O time/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O I/O made/O a/O diligent/O effort/O in/O a/O search/O for/O these/O individuals/O ./O 
A/O number/O of/O subpenas/O were/O served/O ./O 
We/O also/O had/O the/O assistance/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O 's/O office/O in/O the/O serving/O of/O subpenas/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O bring/O to/O the/O committee/O 's/O attention/O the/O following/O cases/O in/O which/O we/O had/O difficulty/O ./O 
The/O first/O was/O the/O case/O of/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON ./O 
He/O resides/O at/O 3276/O DeRonda/PERSON Drive/PERSON ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O Uris/PERSON is/O not/O presently/O employed/O by/O any/O studio/O and/O is/O listed/O as/O a/O free/O lance/O screen/O writer/O ./O 
On/O the/O 24th/O of/O February/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON was/O contacted/O in/O an/O effort/O to/O serve/O the/O subpena/O ./O 
The/O maid/O answered/O the/O door/O and/O advised/O that/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON was/O ill/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mrs./O Uris/PERSON then/O came/O to/O the/O door/O and/O stated/O that/O her/O husband/O was/O sick/O with/O a/O virus/O infection/O ./O 
Mrs./O Uris/PERSON stated/O that/O she/O would/O go/O upstairs/O and/O talk/O the/O matter/O over/O with/O her/O husband/O ,/O which/O she/O did/O ./O 
She/O returned/O and/O stated/O that/O her/O husband/O was/O too/O ill/O to/O accept/O service/O and/O to/O call/O again/O on/O the/O following/O Monday/O ,/O ./O 
which/O would/O be/O February/O 26/O ./O 
She/O absolutely/O refused/O admittance/O 322/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O to/O see/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON and/O promised/O to/O see/O that/O the/O service/O of/O the/O subpena/O would/O be/O expedited/O the/O following/O Monday/O ./O 
On/O the/O following/O Monday/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON was/O again/O visited/O ,/O and/O Mrs./O Uris/PERSON advised/O that/O the/O doctors/O had/O sent/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON to/O the/O hospital/O and/O had/O instructed/O that/O he/O see/O no/O one/O ./O 
It/O was/O then/O requested/O that/O she/O obtain/O a/O statement/O from/O her/O doctor/O or/O doctors/O regarding/O the/O nature/O of/O her/O husband/O 's/O illness/O ./O 
She/O declined/O to/O name/O the/O name/O of/O the/O doctor/O or/O the/O hospital/O to/O which/O her/O husband/O was/O sent/O ./O 
She/O stated/O that/O she/O would/O contact/O the/O doctor/O and/O advise/O us/O the/O following/O day/O ./O 
The/O following/O day/O ,/O through/O the/O cooperation/O of/O a/O local/O law-enforcement/O agency/O ,/O all/O the/O hospitals/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION area/O were/O checked/O ,/O with/O negative/O results/O ./O 
The/O Uris/PERSON residence/O was/O again/O contacted/O ,/O and/O Mrs./O Uris/PERSON advised/O that/O she/O had/O sent/O her/O husband/O out/O of/O town/O to/O recuperate/O ,/O and/O he/O had/O not/O gone/O to/O a/O hospital/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O subpena/O for/O Mr./O Uris/PERSON originally/O called/O for/O his/O appearance/O here/O on/O the/O 21st/O day/O of/O March/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O leaving/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O we/O left/O the/O subpena/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O ./O 
On/O our/O second/O trip/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION we/O again/O contacted/O the/O home/O of/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON and/O found/O no/O one/O at/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O made/O any/O effort/O to/O serve/O the/O subpena/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O they/O did/O ./O 
I/O have/O some/O evidence/O that/O I/O would/O like/O to/O bring/O in/O at/O a/O later/O time/O regarding/O all/O these/O witnesses/O ./O 
The/O second/O person/O that/O we/O have/O had/O some/O difficulty/O with/O is/O Georgia/ORGANIZATION Backus/ORGANIZATION Alexander/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O individual/O is/O a/O radio/O writer/O and/O is/O known/O professionally/O as/O Georgia/ORGANIZATION Backus/ORGANIZATION ./O 
She/O resides/O with/O her/O husband/O at/O 6149/O Fulton/LOCATION Avenue/LOCATION ,/O Van/LOCATION Nuys/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
On/O the/O 24th/O of/O February/O the/O home/O of/O Georgia/ORGANIZATION Backus/ORGANIZATION was/O contacted/O ,/O at/O which/O time/O we/O talked/O to/O her/O husband/O ,/O Harmon/PERSON Alexander/PERSON ./O 
He/O refused/O to/O permit/O his/O wife/O to/O accept/O service/O of/O the/O subpena/O by/O not/O permitting/O her/O to/O leave/O the/O house/O ./O 
He/O stated/O that/O he/O wanted/O to/O discuss/O the/O matter/O with/O his/O lawyer/O ,/O and/O we/O requested/O that/O he/O do/O so/O at/O once/O ./O 
He/O made/O an/O effort/O to/O contact/O the/O lawyer/O but/O stated/O that/O he/O could/O not/O be/O located/O ,/O and/O wanted/O us/O to/O contact/O him/O again/O the/O following/O Monday/O ./O 
We/O contacted/O him/O the/O following/O Monday/O by/O telephone/O ,/O and/O he/O advised/O that/O his/O lawyer/O was/O a/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ,/O 6513/O Hollywood/LOCATION Boulevard/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON would/O arrange/O to/O accept/O service/O bf/O the/O subpena/O or/O make/O Mrs./O Backus/PERSON available/O ./O 
He/O was/O contacted/O ,/O and/O he/O stated/O that/O he/O had/O not/O been/O retained/O by/O the/O subject/O but/O would/O ascertain/O his/O position/O in/O the/O matter/O and/O let/O us/O know/O the/O following/O day/O ,/O on/O Tuesday/O ./O 
Mr./O Esterman/PERSON was/O again/O contacted/O ,/O and/O he/O advised/O that/O he/O did/O not/O represent/O the/O subject/O and/O for/O us/O to/O attempt/O to/O serve/O the/O subpena/O in/O the/O normal/O manner/O ./O 
Mr./O Alexander/PERSON was/O again/O contacted/O ,/O and/O he/O advised/O that/O his/O wife/O had/O gone/O out/O of/O town/O ,/O and/O he/O declined/O to/O give/O any/O information/O as/O to/O her/O whereabouts/O ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O 's/O office/O made/O an/O effort/O to/O serve/O this/O subpena/O and/O failed/O ./O 
The/O original/O subpena/O issued/O for/O her/O called/O for/O appearance/O before/O this/O committee/O on/O March/O 22/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O leaving/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O we/O left/O the/O subpena/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O 's/O office/O ,/O which/O is/O at/O the/O present/O time/O outstanding/O ./O 
The/O next/O individual/O is/O Fred/PERSON Rinaldo/PERSON ,/O of/O 14078/O Davana/O Terrace/O ,/O Sherman/LOCATION Oaks/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O also/O been/O successful/O in/O avoiding/O the/O service/O of/O a/O subpena/O ./O 
Mr./O Rinaldo/PERSON is/O a/O free-lance/O screen/O writer/O and/O at/O the/O present/O time/O unemployed/O ./O 
I/O personally/O called/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 323/O Rinaldo/PERSON on/O various/O occasions/O and/O discussed/O the/O matter/O with/O his/O wife/O ./O 
The/O second/O time/O we/O called/O there/O we/O identified/O ourselves/O and/O gave/O the/O purpose/O for/O our/O visit/O ./O 
She/O stated/O that/O Mr./O Rinaldo/PERSON was/O out/O on/O the/O desert/O ,/O that/O he/O had/O a/O virus/O infection/O and/O had/O gone/O out/O to/O recuperate/O ,/O but/O she/O did/O n't/O know/O where/O he/O was/O ,/O that/O he/O had/O n't/O called/O her/O and/O she/O had/O no/O way/O of/O getting/O in/O contact/O with/O him/O whatsoever/O ./O 
This/O continued/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 3/O weeks/O ,/O calling/O at/O the/O home/O and/O discussing/O the/O matter/O with/O Mrs./O Rinaldo/PERSON and/O also/O the/O maid/O ./O 
On/O April/O 6/O ,/O during/O our/O second/O visit/O to/O California/LOCATION ,/O we/O again/O called/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Rinaldo/PERSON ,/O and/O the/O maid/O answered/O the/O door/O ./O 
She/O stated/O that/O Mr./O Rinaldo/PERSON was/O still/O out/O on/O the/O desert/O ,/O that/O she/O did/O n't/O know/O where/O he/O was/O ,/O and/O that/O Mrs./O Rinaldo/PERSON was/O not/O home/O ./O 
The/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O 's/O office/O or/O deputy/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O representing/O that/O office/O has/O also/O called/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Rinaldo/PERSON on/O several/O occasions/O ./O 
The/O next/O individual/O is/O Mr./O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O a/O screen/O writer/O and/O also/O unemployed/O ./O 
He/O resides/O at/O 2002/O North/O Serrano/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O week/O of/O February/O 26/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O we/O visited/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON and/O were/O informed/O by/O his/O wife/O that/O Mr./O Butler/PERSON was/O expected/O home/O at/O 5:30/O ./O 
We/O did/O not/O identify/O ourselves/O at/O that/O time/O or/O the/O purpose/O of/O the/O visit/O ./O 
We/O called/O again/O the/O same/O day/O and/O were/O advised/O by/O his/O wife/O that/O she/O and/O Mr./O Butler/PERSON had/O some/O marital/O difficulty/O and/O that/O he/O had/O left/O the/O city/O ./O 
The/O marshal/O 's/O office/O has/O also/O called/O on/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Butler/PERSON on/O numerous/O occasions/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O myself/O ,/O without/O success/O ./O 
The/O last/O time/O we/O called/O was/O April/O 6/O ,/O and/O there/O was/O no/O response/O when/O we/O rang/O the/O bell/O ./O 
Butler/PERSON 's/O original/O subpena/O called/O for/O his/O appearance/O here/O in/O Washington/LOCATION on/O the/O 17th/O day/O of/O February/O ./O 
On/O February/O 14/O a/O subpena/O was/O left/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O ,/O calling/O for/O his/O appearance/O here/O at/O a/O later/O date/O ./O 
The/O next/O individual/O is/O Miss/O Karen/PERSON Morley/PERSON ,/O an/O actress/O who/O resides/O at/O 2723/O Laurel/LOCATION Canyon/LOCATION Boulevard/LOCATION ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
The/O home/O of/O Miss/O Morley/PERSON was/O lirst/O visited/O during/O the/O week/O of/O February/O 26/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
In/O response/O to/O the/O ringing/O of/O the/O door/O bell/O an/O individual/O ,/O also/O an/O actor/O ,/O named/O Lloyd/PERSON Gough/PERSON ,/O came/O to/O the/O door/O ,/O and/O we/O talked/O to/O him/O regarding/O Miss/O Morley/PERSON ./O 
He/O stated/O that/O she/O would/O be/O back/O later/O and/O to/O call/O later/O the/O same/O day/O ./O 
We/O did/O ,/O and/O we/O called/O back/O on/O various/O occasions/O during/O our/O period/O there/O and/O found/O absolutely/O no/O one/O at/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
About/O how/O many/O times/O did/O you/O call/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O we/O visited/O Miss/O Morley/PERSON 's/O house/O more/O than/O we/O did/O anybody/O else/O 's/O ./O 
She/O was/O closest/O to/O the/O hotel/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O we/O were/O up/O there/O at/O least/O 20/O times/O ,/O and/O maybe/O more/O ./O 
We/O called/O again/O on/O April/O 6/O and/O `/O she/O was/O not/O at/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O subpena/O left/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION mar/O -/O shal/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O we/O left/O the/O subpena/O with/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O ,/O and/O they/O also/O have/O attempted/O to/O serve/O Miss/O Morley/PERSON ,/O without/O result/O ./O 
The/O next/O individual/O ,/O Jack/PERSON Berry/PERSON ,/O is/O a/O motion-picture/O director/O ./O 
He/O resides/O at/O 935/O North/O Kings/O Road/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION Calif./LOCATION ./O 
On/O the/O day/O of/O February/O 24/O we/O called/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Berry/PERSON and/O talked/O '/O to/O his/O wife/O ./O 
On/O this/O occasion/O the/O identity/O of/O the/O investigator/O was/O disclosed/O to/O Mrs./O Berry/PERSON ./O 
She/O advised/O that/O her/O husband/O was/O out/O and/O would/O not/O be/O home/O until/O late/O at/O night/O ,/O and/O also/O that/O they/O were/O going/O away/O 324/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O fbr/O the/O week/O end/O ,/O but/O Mr./O Berry/PERSON would/O be/O available/O the/O following/O Monday/O to/O accept/O service/O ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O ,/O we/O called/O several/O times/O at/O the/O house/O that/O night/O ,/O but/O without/O finding/O them/O at/O home/O ./O 
On/O the/O following/O Monday/O Mrs./O Berry/PERSON was/O contacted/O ,/O and/O she/O advised/O that/O her/O husband/O was/O at/O home/O ,/O but/O would/O not/O accept/O service/O of/O the/O subpena/O until/O he/O had/O seen/O his/O lawyer/O ./O 
An/O appointment/O was/O arranged/O through/O Mrs./O Berry/PERSON to/O have/O Mr./O Berry/PERSON accept/O the/O service/O of/O the/O subpena/O the/O following/O day/O at/O 2/O p./O m./O ./O 
and/O it/O was/O understood/O that/O should/O there/O be/O any/O changes/O in/O plans/O she/O would/O notify/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON or/O myself/O at/O the/O hotel/O ./O 
Mr./O Berry/PERSON failed/O to/O keep/O the/O appointment/O and/O made/O no/O attempt/O to/O notify/O us/O of/O any/O change/O in/O plans/O ./O 
Subsequent/O attempts/O to/O contact/O the/O subject/O or/O his/O wife/O have/O met/O with/O no/O success/O ./O 
We/O visited/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Berry/PERSON on/O numerous/O occasions/O ./O 
The/O door/O was/O always/O answered/O by/O a/O lady/O who/O identified/O herself/O as/O a/O nurse/O ,/O taking/O care/O of/O the/O children/O ./O 
She/O stated/O that/O the/O Berrys/ORGANIZATION were/O out/O of/O town/O ,/O did/O n't/O know/O when/O they/O would/O be/O back/O ,/O or/O did/O not/O know/O how/O to/O locate/O them/O ./O 
On/O the/O 6th/O of/O April/O we/O again/O contacted/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Berry/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
About/O what/O age/O were/O the/O children/O ,/O if/O the/O nurse/O did/O n't/O know/O how/O to/O locate/O the/O parents/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O I/O actually/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ;/O but/O it/O is/O my/O understanding/O that/O they/O are/O small/O children/O ./O 
I/O believe/O they/O have/O two/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O DO/O LE/O ./O 
Did/O you/O leave/O that/O subpena/O with/O the/O marshal/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O subpena/O is/O with/O the/O marshal/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
On/O April/O 6/O the/O home/O was/O again/O contacted/O by/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O me/O ,/O and/O the/O maid/O related/O the/O same/O story/O ,/O that/O the/O Berrys/PERSON were/O out/O of/O town/O ,/O she/O did/O n't/O know/O where/O they/O were/O ,/O nor/O when/O she/O expected/O them/O back/O ./O 
The/O next/O individual/O ,/O Lew/PERSON Solomon/PERSON ,/O is/O a/O screen/O writer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O L-e-w/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O L-e-w/O S-o-l-o-m-o-n/O ./O 
He/O resides/O at/O 10513/O Holman/O Avenue/O ,/O West/LOCATION Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O Solomon/PERSON 's/O residence/O has/O been/O contacted/O repeatedly/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O talked/O both/O with/O Mrs./O Solomon/PERSON and/O the/O maid/O ,/O and/O Mr./O Solomon/PERSON is/O just/O out/O of/O town/O and/O has/O been/O out/O of/O town/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 4/O or/O 5/O weeks/O ,/O or/O left/O town/O shortly/O after/O Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O I/O arrived/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
The/O marshal/O has/O been/O unable/O to/O locate/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O Andrews/PERSON and/O I/O called/O at/O his/O home/O on/O April/O 6/O and/O were/O advised/O by/O the/O maid/O that/O Mr./O Solomon/PERSON was/O out/O of/O town/O ./O 
