COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 1/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-SECOND/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MARCH/O 8/O AND/O 21/O ;/O APRIL/O 10/O ,/O 11/O ,/O 12/O ,/O AND/O 13/O ,/O 1951/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 81595/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1951/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O JOHN/PERSON S./PERSON WOOD/PERSON ,/O Georgia/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION \*/O JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION HAROLD/LOCATION H./LOCATION VELDE/LOCATION ,/O Illinois/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CHARLES/PERSON E./PERSON POTTER/PERSON ,/O Michigan/LOCATION FRANK/LOCATION S./LOCATION TAVENNER/LOCATION ,/O Jr./O ,/O Counsel/O LouIs/O J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Senior/O Investigator/O JOHN/PERSON W./PERSON CARRINGTON/PERSON ,/O Clerk/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O Pug/O March/O 8/O ,/O 1951/O :/O 55/O Testimony/O of/O Victor/PERSON Jeremy/PERSON Jerome/PERSON --------------------------/O March/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of78/O Larry/PERSON Parks/PERSON -----------------------------------------/O 112/O Howard/PERSON Da/PERSON Silva/PERSON ---------------------------------/O 121/O Edith/PERSON Holm/PERSON -LRB-/O Gale/O -RRB-/O Sondergaard/PERSON -----------------------/O April/O 10/O ,/O 1951/O :/O 127/O Testimony/O of/O Sterling/O Hayden/PERSON -----------------------------/O April/O 11/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of177/O ./O 
------------------------------------------/O Will/O Geer/O 194/O Robert/PERSON Lees/PERSON ------------------------------------------/O April/O 12/O ,/O 1951/O :/O 217/O Testimony/O of/O Richard/PERSON J./PERSON Collins/PERSON ------------------------------/O April/O 13/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of259/O Waldo/LOCATION Salt/LOCATION -/O ------------------------------------------/O 274/O Paul/PERSON Jarrico/PERSON ---------------------------------------/O 284/O Meta/O Reis/PERSON Rosenberg/PERSON ----------------------------------/O Victor/PERSON Killian/PERSON ----------------------------------/O ,/O -/O -/O 296/O Fred/PERSON Graff/PERSON ./O 
-----------------------------/O ---------/O 298/O COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTIONPICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 1/O THURSDAY/O ,/O MARCH/O 8/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACrvITrES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/PERSON HEARING/O The/O committee/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 10:30/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O and/O '/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O Messrs./O Walter/PERSON ,/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Velde/O ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Potter/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/PERSON are/O present/O ,/O a/O quorum/O ./O 
Mr./O Attorney/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Whom/O do/O you/O have/O as/O a/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O as/O a/O witness/O this/O morning/O Mr./O V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON ./O 
Will/O Mr./O Jerome/PERSON come/O forward/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
You/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O take/O this/O opportunity/O to/O ask/O the/O committee/O to/O take/O notice/O of/O the/O presence/O at/O my/O side/O of/O Mr./O Powe/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O to/O represent/O me/O as/O counsel/O in/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Powe/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O give/O the/O reporter/O your/O full/O name/O and/O address/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O POWE/PERSON ./O 
Ralph/PERSON Powe/PERSON ,/O 23/O West/O Twenty-sixth/O Street/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O VICTOR/PERSON JEREMY/PERSON JEROME/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O RALPH/PERSON POWE/PERSON ,/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O and/O present/O address/O ?/O 
56/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Victor/PERSON Jeremy/PERSON Jerome/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O you/O need/O not/O stand/O unless/O you/O wish/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON -LRB-/O seating/O himself/O -RRB-/O ./O 
320/O Second/O Avenue/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O October/O 12/O ,/O 1896/O ,/O in/O Poland/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O naturalized/O American/O citizen/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O in/O what/O court/O were/O you/O naturalized/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O naturalized/O in/O January/O 1928/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O southern/O district/O court/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Under/O what/O name/O were/O you/O naturalized/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Jerome/PERSON Isaac/PERSON Romain/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O Romain/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
R-o-m-a-i-n/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O your/O name/O has/O been/O legally/O changed/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
My/O name/O has/O been/O legally/O changed/O in/O 1944/O ,/O Decem/LOCATION -/O ber/O 1/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O used/O any/O other/O name/O ,/O other/O than/O your/O present/O legal/O name/O and/O the/O name/O of/O Jerome/PERSON Isaac/PERSON Romain/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O the/O surname/O of/O Roman/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
R-o-m-a-n/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O where/O you/O have/O resided/O since/O 1930/O and/O for/O the/O approximate/O periods/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
My/O place/O of/O residence/O permanently/O has/O been/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION since/O 1930/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O reside/O temporarily/O at/O other/O places/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O in/O the/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
I/O base/O myself/O on/O the/O privilege/O afforded/O me/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O would/O your/O refusal/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O of/O where/O you/O had/O resided/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
It/O might/O lead/O to/O an/O area/O involving/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O to/O this/O committee/O your/O reasons/O for/O believing/O that/O it/O would/O bring/O you/O into/O such/O an/O area/O as/O you/O describe/O ,/O so/O that/O the/O committee/O may/O have/O some/O information/O upon/O which/O to/O act/O or/O to/O judge/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ,/O the/O answering/O of/O that/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O the/O answering/O of/O that/O question/O would/O violate/O my/O right/O to/O exercise/O the/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O you/O decline/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O it/O ,/O to/O advise/O the/O committee/O in/O what/O manner/O or/O any/O circumstances/O which/O would/O enable/O them/O to/O determine/O whether/O or/O not/O your/O refusal/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O of/O the/O places/O of/O your/O residence/O would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O motivated/O by/O any/O desire/O not/O to/O advise/O the/O committee/O ,/O but/O I/O feel/O that/O I/O have/O the/O right/O to/O exercise/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O briefly/O outline/O for/O the/O committee/O your/O educational/O background/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O my/O grammar/O school/O education/O and/O my/O sec/O -/O ondary/O school/O education/O in/O England/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O my/O college/O education/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
I/O am/O a/O graduate/O of/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 57/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O designate/O specifically/O the/O schools/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O here/O the/O College/O of/O the/O City/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O and/O later/O the/O Washington/LOCATION Square/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O where/O I/O graduated/O in/O 1930/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O outline/O briefly/O for/O the/O committee/O your/O occupational/O background/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O bookkeeper/O for/O years/O ./O 
I/O was/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Bookkeeper/O ,/O did/O you/O say/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O tutor/O ,/O private/O ./O 
For/O a/O time/O I/O taught/O in/O a/O high/O school/O ,/O Erasmus/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O a/O teacher/O in/O training/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O is/O that/O located/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Is/O the/O question/O relative/O to/O education/O or/O general/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O occupational/O background/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
For/O a/O brief/O while/O I/O was/O also/O printing/O salesman/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O soliciting/O printing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O whom/O were/O you/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O not/O employed/O ./O 
I/O was/O really/O self-employed/O ,/O on/O commission/O ,/O in/O the/O main/O ./O 
For/O a/O brief/O while/O I/O think/O perhaps-I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O was/O on/O salary/O ./O 
If/O I/O had/O a/O connection/O with/O a/O printer/O it/O was/O also/O on/O commission/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O so/O engaged/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O about/O 1929-30/O ./O 
Since/O then/O I/O also/O have/O been/O a/O writer/O and/O an/O editor/O ,/O which/O has/O been/O my/O major/O occupation/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Is/O that/O true/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Writer/O and/O editor/O for/O whom/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O I/O have/O previously/O given/O ,/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O but/O you/O voluntarily/O stated/O that/O you/O were/O a/O writer/O and/O ,/O as/O I/O understand/O the/O law/O ,/O you/O ca/O n't/O invoke/O privilege/O in/O order/O to/O avoid/O discussing/O the/O details/O of/O that/O which/O you/O volunteer/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O I/O am/O exercising/O my/O right/O as/O I/O see/O it/O and/O understand/O it/O in/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
And/O you/O still/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O reason/O given/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROM/LOCATION E./O For/O the/O reason/O given/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O engaged/O at/O any/O time/O in/O the/O teaching/O pro-/O fession/O other/O than/O the/O teaching/O in/O the/O high/O school/O and/O the/O tutoring/O which/O you/O have/O already/O described/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O against/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O you/O stated/O a/O while/O ago/O that/O you/O were/O engaged/O for/O a/O time/O in/O teaching/O ,/O tutoring/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Other/O than/O that/O I/O have/O described/O ,/O he/O said/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O subjects/O do/O you/O teach/O ,/O specialize/O in/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O teach/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O subjects/O did/O you/O teach/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O English/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
What/O subjects/O did/O you/O write/O on/O 58/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O answer/O the/O other/O question/O ,/O please/O ./O 
The/O sub/O -/O jects/O that/O I/O refer/O to/O involve/O the/O teaching/O of/O English/O ./O 
The/O subjects/O I/O wrote/O on/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O against/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O witness/O has/O already/O testified/O voluntarily/O that/O he/O is/O a/O writer/O and/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O what/O you/O are/O editor/O of/O ,/O what/O magazine/O ,/O what/O paper/O ,/O what/O pamphlet/O ,/O what/O book/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O my/O privilege/O afforded/O me/O by/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYE/O ./O 
When/O were/O you/O an/O editor/O ,/O what/O years/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O an/O editor/O ,/O what/O city/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O live/O when/O you/O were/O an/O editor/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O how/O could/O you/O possibly/O incriminate/O yourself/O by/O giving/O the/O committee/O the/O dates/O you/O were/O active/O as/O editor/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
The/O privilege/O I/O claim/O does/O not/O make/O it/O incumbent/O upon/O me/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O this/O :/O How/O could/O it/O possibly/O incriminate/O you/O to/O tell/O your/O fellow/O Americans-because/O you/O were/O naturalized/O in/O 1928how/O could/O it/O possibly/O incriminate/O you/O to/O tell/O us/O what/O books/O or/O papers/O you/O wrote/O ?/O 
You/O have/O said/O you/O were/O '/O an/O editor/O ./O 
I/O assume/O you/O were/O an/O editor/O in/O this/O country/O ./O 
How/O could/O it/O incriminate/O you/O to/O state/O what/O you/O wrote/O ?/O 
I/O assume/O you/O are/O proud/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
The/O situation/O is/O not/O of/O my/O creation/O ,/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
I/O feel/O there/O is/O justification/O in/O the/O statement/O made/O recently/O by/O Justice/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O to/O answer/O one/O question/O for/O the/O congressional/O committee/O is/O to/O rob/O yourself/O of/O the/O privilege/O afforded/O you/O by/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O in/O the/O position/O taken/O by/O Justice/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION the/O rest/O of/O the/O Court/O did/O not/O concur/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
True/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O a/O high/O regard/O for/O that/O position/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O like/O to/O identify/O myself/O with/O the/O recognition/O of/O that/O situation/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O a/O high/O regard/O for/O that/O position/O because/O ,/O in/O the/O first/O instance/O ,/O it/O covers/O your/O own/O course/O ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O written/O for/O any/O Communist/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O under/O the/O constitutional/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O any/O articles/O under/O any/O name/O other/O than/O your/O own/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O stated/O that/O you/O were/O an/O editor/O ./O 
Were/O you/O associated/O ,/O in/O the/O early/O 1930/O 's/O with/O the/O publication/O New/O Pioneer/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O in/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O associated/O in/O any/O capacity/O with/O the/O publication/O known/O as/O New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O the/O editor/O of/O the/O publication/O the/O Communist/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 59/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O associated/O with/O the/O publication/O Main/O Stream/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privi/O -/O lege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O official/O position/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O with/O the/O publication/O Political/O Affairs/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O priv/O -/O ilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O if/O Mr./O Joseph/PERSON Fields/PERSON was/O at/O any/O time/O editor/O of/O New/ORGANIZATION Century/ORGANIZATION Publishers/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O in/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Lement/O U./PERSON Harris/PERSON one/O of/O the/O editors/O of/O that/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O also/O an/O editor/O of/O that/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O given/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O the/O organization/O known/O as/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
And/O as/O I/O understand/O your/O reason/O ,/O it/O is/O because/O this/O organization/O is/O Communist/O ,/O and/O to/O admit/O association/O with/O it/O would/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O answered/O that/O to/O explain/O my/O reasons/O for/O in/O -/O voking/O the/O privilege/O represents/O a/O violation/O of/O the/O principle/O involved/O in/O that/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O was/O whether/O he/O was/O acquainted/O with/O that/O organization/O ,/O is/O that/O right/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O it/O is/O a/O Communist/O organization/O ,/O do/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O reason/O given/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O an/O organization/O known/O as/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O ground/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O know/O that/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O is/O an/O affiliate/O ,/O or/O was/O an/O affiliate/O ,/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O magazine/O Clipper/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O were/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O School/O for/O Writers/O which/O was/O operated/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O first/O by/O the/O Hollywood/O chapter/O of/O the/O League/O of/O American/O Writers/O ,/O and/O later/O by/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O under/O the/O Constitution/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION as/O an/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
60/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O THE/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION branch/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION took/O over/O the/O offices/O of/O the/O School/O for/O Writers/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O any/O such/O fact/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O with/O the/O officers/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O the/O turning/O over/O of/O its/O facilities/O to/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/O Center/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O any/O such/O fact/O ./O 
Mr./O MOTULDER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O knowledge/O concerning/O the/O activities/O of/O any/O of/O the/O organizations/O mentioned/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O given/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O in/O the/O business/O of/O solicitation/O on/O commission/O which/O you/O stated/O you/O had/O been/O engaged/O in/O ,/O was/O that/O business/O carried/O on/O in/O any/O manner/O in/O connection/O with/O any/O of/O these/O publications/O which/O I/O have/O asked/O you/O about/O ,/O or/O any/O of/O these/O organizations/O which/O I/O have/O asked/O you/O about/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
-/O To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ,/O no/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O I/O remember/O no/O such/O connection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O type/O of/O your/O connection/O with/O these/O publications/O which/O I/O have/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
For/O whom/O did/O you/O solicit/O printing/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O since/O it/O might/O entail/O the/O possibility/O of/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Elks/ORGANIZATION '/O Club/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O B'nai/O B'rith/O Lodge/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYE/O ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O of/O the/O Masonic/O fraternities/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O of/O the/O lodges/O identified/O with/O any/O religious/O organization/O in/O this/O country/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
If/O so/O ,/O what/O ones/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O lodge/O of/O any/O religious/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O of/O the/O established/O automobile/O clubs/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O AAA/O !/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O lodge/O having/O its/O headquarters/O in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O understand/O the/O meaning/O of/O the/O word/O ``/O lodge/O ,/O ''/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
A/O lodge/O as/O generally/O accepted/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O fraternal/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-inerimination/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O just/O answered/O that/O you/O were/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O other/O lodges/O identified/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 61/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O organization/O or/O group/O that/O might/O be/O termed/O ordinarily/O ,/O and/O is/O ordinarily/O termed/O ,/O as/O a/O secret/O organization/O ,/O in/O our/O country/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O further/O clarification/O on/O this/O question/O ,/O because/O to/O me/O I/O would/O have/O to/O have/O the/O definition/O of/O the/O word/O ``/O secret/O ./O ''/O 
It/O may/O be/O secret/O to/O X/O and/O not/O to/O Y/O and/O maybe/O to/O Z./O Therefore/O ,/O it/O is/O hard/O for/O me/O to/O know/O what/O the/O intent/O of/O your/O question/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Any/O organization/O that/O is/O secret/O to/O you/O ,/O in/O your/O esteem/O ,/O your/O judgment/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
General/O Kearney/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O any/O organization/O that/O has/O for/O its/O aims/O or/O objectives/O the/O overthrow/O of/O this/O Government/O by/O force/O or/O violence/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ./O 
JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WIOOD/PERSON ./O 
I/O understood/O in/O the/O early/O part/O of/O your/O testimony/O that/O at/O the/O time/O you/O were/O engaged/O in/O printing/O solicitation-was/O that/O around/O 1930/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Around/O that/O period/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
That/O has/O been/O 20/O years/O ago/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O 1929/O or/O 1930/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O understand/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O that/O the/O statute/O of/O limita/O -/O tions/O protects/O you/O after/O the/O expiration/O of/O 3/O years/O for/O any/O activity/O you/O may/O have/O engaged/O in/O that/O may/O be/O termed/O illegal/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O still/O stand/O on/O the/O claiming/O of/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
With/O reference/O to/O the/O question/O counsel/O asked/O you/O about/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O have/O you/O ever/O made/O any/O literary/O contribution/O of/O any/O character/O that/O could/O in/O any/O sense/O be/O termed/O subversive/O or/O anti-American/O to/O that/O periodical/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O name/O of/O the/O periodical/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O never/O written/O for/O that/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
At/O all/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
At/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O then/O ,/O why/O did/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O counsel/O 's/O ques/O -/O tion/O when/O he/O interrogated/O you/O about/O your/O connection/O with/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Have/O you/O ever/O had/O any/O financial/O connection/O with/O it/O in/O any/O way/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O never/O had/O any/O connections/O with/O that/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
At/O all/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
At/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O then/O ,/O your/O statement/O a/O while/O ago/O when/O you/O refused/O to/O answer/O counsel/O 's/O question/O as/O to/O that/O organization/O on/O the/O ground/O of/O self-incrimination/O was/O erroneous/O ,/O was/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
It/O would/O n't/O incriminate/O you/O ,/O would/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
The/O choice/O of/O that/O privilege/O is/O not/O an/O admission/O of/O incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O to/O say/O you/O can/O invoke/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O and/O refuse/O to/O answer/O a/O question/O as/O to/O an/O organiza/O -/O 62/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O tion/O ,/O the/O answer/O to/O which/O would/O be/O that/O you/O had/O no/O connection/O with/O it/O at/O all/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
When/O in/O my/O discretion/O it/O may/O lead/O into/O an/O area/O in/O which/O self-incrimination/O is/O possible/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O am/O glad/O we/O are/O getting/O ourselves/O identified/O ./O 
Then/O you/O take/O the/O position/O you/O can/O refuse/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O you/O wish/O by/O hiding/O behind/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
The/O fifth/O amendment/O is/O there/O to/O protect/O me/O against/O acting/O as/O a/O witness/O against/O myself/O ,/O and/O when/O in/O my/O discretion/O I/O feel/O that/O answering/O a/O question/O put/O to/O me/O represents/O acting/O as/O a/O witness/O against/O myself/O and/O involves/O the/O question/O of/O self-incrimination/O I/O invoke/O that/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O have/O invoked/O that/O right/O here/O today/O on/O a/O matter/O that/O can/O not/O incriminate/O you/O ,/O and/O you/O have/O just/O admitted/O it/O ,/O have/O n't/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O admitted/O what/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
As/O to/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O the/O name/O of/O a/O publication/O or/O an/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
This/O group/O has/O a/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O I/O have/O never/O written/O for/O that/O publication/O and/O I/O have/O no/O connection/O with/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O is/O the/O name/O of/O the/O publication/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O go/O by/O the/O name/O you/O mentioned/O to/O me/O and/O asked/O if/O I/O wrote/O for/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
How/O about/O the/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O that/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O connected/O with/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O new/O question/O to/O me/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O familiar/O with/O that/O publication/O ,/O Hollywood/O Quarterly/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
By/O ``/O familiar/O ''/O you/O mean/O have/O I/O ever/O seen/O it/O or/O read/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O seen/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O made/O any/O literary/O contribution/O to/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
To/O that/O quarterly/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O in/O answer/O to/O Mr./O Kearney/PERSON 's/O question/O ,/O you/O said/O you/O do/O not/O belong/O to/O any/O organization/O which/O believes/O in/O the/O overthrow/O of/O our/O Government/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
If/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION should/O become/O involved/O in/O a/O war/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O would/O you/O support/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION or/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O to/O answer/O that/O I/O consider/O this/O question/O no/O basis/O for/O any/O reply/O that/O I/O can/O make/O in/O the/O interests/O of/O truth/O and/O reality/O ./O 
I/O believe/O there/O is/O no/O basis/O in/O reality/O for/O that/O question/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O a/O suppositious/O ,/O hypothetical/O ,/O and/O provocative/O question/O that/O could/O only/O serve/O to/O romote/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Would/O it/O take/O you/O ,/O as/O an/O American/O ,/O to/O go/O into/O a/O long/O speech/O on/O a/O question/O like/O that/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 63/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O if/O the/O interests/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O would/O not/O be/O served/O by/O breaking/O down/O all/O possibilities/O of/O establishing/O a/O relationship/O of/O amity/O between/O countries/O ,/O and/O driving/O the/O mentality/O of/O our/O country/O into/O a/O war/O situation/O by/O that/O type/O of/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
So/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
My/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O is/O ,/O I/O am/O interested/O in/O helping/O bring/O about/O peaceful/O relationships/O between/O those/O countries/O and/O all/O countries/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
That/O does/O not/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O so/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O wish/O to/O be/O a/O party/O to/O answering/O a/O question/O that/O will/O just/O heighten/O a/O so-called/O war/O spirit/O in/O this/O country/O ./O 
I/O feel/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O when/O a/O meeting/O is/O taking/O place/O to/O bring/O the/O Four/O Powers/O together/O ,/O the/O hysteria/O raised/O by/O such/O a/O question/O can/O not/O serve/O the/O good/O interests/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O you/O are/O in/O rather/O poor/O position/O today/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O answers/O you/O have/O given/O to/O questions/O of/O counsel/O and/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O to/O take/O the/O position/O you/O take/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ./O 
I/O believe/O the/O position/O I/O take/O is/O joined/O by/O most/O of/O the/O people/O of/O the/O country/O ./O 
I/O think/O they/O want/O peace/O and/O not/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
None/O of/O us/O want/O war/O ./O 
If/O our/O security/O was/O at/O stake/O ,/O would/O you/O support/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION or/O would/O you/O support/O Soviet/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
You/O have/O refused/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
General/O Kearney/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O a/O proposed/O ``/O peace/O ''/O march/O on/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O I/O believe/O March/O 15/O ./O 
Are/O you/O connected/O with/O that/O movement/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chaiman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Velde/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O agree/O that/O this/O is/O a/O legally/O constituted/O committee/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O do/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O agree/O that/O we/O are/O attempting/O to/O determine/O what/O subversive/O forces/O exist/O in/O this/O country/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O refuse/O to/O cooperate/O by/O answering/O questions/O as/O to/O those/O subversive/O forces/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
My/O position/O is/O to/O cooperate/O as/O best/O I/O can/O ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O however/O ,/O I/O am/O entitled/O to/O invoke/O a/O constitutional/O privilege/O granted/O me/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O pertaining/O to/O any/O organizations/O that/O you/O belong/O to/O that/O you/O might/O think/O are/O subversive/O or/O incriminating/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O that/O in/O my/O opinion/O would/O put/O me/O in/O a/O position/O of/O possibly/O incriminating/O myself/O ,/O and/O inl/O this/O I/O believe/O I/O am/O constitutionally/O protected/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
What/O I/O ca/O n't/O understand/O about/O your/O testimony/O ,/O Mr./O Jerome-and/O I/O am/O not/O trying/O to/O embarrass/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O admit/O you/O are/O a/O writer/O ./O 
From/O that/O we/O are/O to/O assume/O that/O you/O have/O written/O material/O for/O public/O consumption/O ./O 
Yet/O you/O 64/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O decline/O to/O tell/O us/O to/O what/O publications/O you/O have/O made/O such/O literary/O contributions/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O objection/O to/O giving/O the/O committee/O the/O benefit/O of/O that/O information/O ?/O 
How/O can/O that/O possibly/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O only/O repeat/O my/O answer/O to/O a/O similar/O question/O be/O -/O fore/O ,/O that/O I/O must/O exercise/O my/O discretion/O in/O understanding/O the/O applicability/O of/O the/O privilege/O to/O the/O situation/O and/O the/O specific/O question/O put/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Of/O course/O we/O are/O going/O to/O have/O to/O accept/O that/O answer/O ,/O or/O that/O declination/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O you/O must/O realize/O it/O places/O the/O committee/O in/O a/O very/O peculiar/O position/O of/O not/O being/O able/O to/O understand/O what/O is/O in/O your/O mind/O in/O declining/O to/O answer/O it/O ./O 
As/O to/O most/O of/O the/O questions/O ,/O you/O would/O be/O protected/O under/O the/O statute/O of/O limitations/O ,/O anyhow/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O been/O a/O writer/O ,/O an/O editor/O ./O 
fact/O ,/O it/O was/O my/O main/O occupation/O ./O ''/O 
In/O Do/O you/O remember/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O answer/O to/O Mr./O Potter/PERSON 's/O question/O ,/O or/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON 's/O ques/O -/O tion/O ,/O you/O said/O you/O believe/O this/O is/O a/O legally/O constituted/O committee/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
You/O said/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
As/O one/O group/O of/O Americans/O talking/O to/O another/O American-even/O if/O you/O are/O naturalized/O --/O do/O n't/O you/O think/O it/O is/O within/O the/O province/O of/O the/O representatives/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O to/O go/O into/O the/O question/O of/O the/O main/O occupation/O of/O people/O as/O American/LOCATION citizens/O ?/O 
You/O testified/O that/O was/O your/O main/O occupation-writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Wherein/O ,/O then/O ,/O are/O we/O in/O error/O in/O asking/O you/O what/O you/O did/O during/O the/O time/O you/O were/O in/O your/O main/O occupation/O If/O so/O ,/O where/O are/O we/O in/O error/O ?/O 
How/O could/O it/O incriminate/O you/O to/O frankly/O and/O honestly/O tell/O us/O how/O you/O engaged/O yourself/O in/O your/O main/O occupation/O ,/O which/O you/O have/O told/O us/O was/O writing/O ?/O 
I/O am/O not/O assuming/O ,/O in/O asking/O you/O that/O question/O ,/O that/O you/O have/O been/O violating/O any/O law/O ./O 
I/O assume/O you/O have/O in/O all/O your/O writings/O been/O a/O patriotic/O American/O writer/O ./O 
But/O you/O do/O raise/O a/O question/O in/O my/O mind/O ,/O if/O you/O refuse/O to/O tell/O us/O as/O one/O American/O to/O another/O American/O group/O ,/O you/O cause/O a/O doubt/O in/O my/O mind/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O have/O told/O us/O the/O truth/O about/O what/O your/O main/O occupation/O was/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ashamed/O of/O it/O or/O is/O it/O because/O you/O have/O been/O in/O violation/O of/O law/O or/O committed/O some/O public/O wrong/O or/O what/O ?/O 
Have/O you/O been/O associated/O with/O men/O and/O women/O who/O have/O been/O trying/O to/O overthrow/O our/O Government/O in/O their/O writings/O ,/O have/O they/O been/O paying/O you/O ,/O or/O what/O ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O answer/O this/O way/O :/O Of/O course/O ,/O this/O committee/O is/O entitled/O to/O pursue/O its/O questioning/O in/O terms/O of/O its/O best/O understanding/O of/O how/O to/O carry/O through/O its/O set/O task/O of/O this/O morning/O or/O any/O other/O occasion/O ./O 
But/O this/O committee/O certainly/O also/O realizes/O that/O it/O does/O this/O within/O the/O framework/O of/O certain/O constitutional/O guarantees/O that/O are/O open/O to/O Americans/O ,/O and/O which/O we/O have/O a/O right/O to/O claim/O on/O certain/O bases/O ./O 
When/O I/O claim/O them/O I/O am/O not/O setting/O myself/O outside/O the/O range/O of/O Americanism/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O exercising/O a/O right/O afforded/O me/O by/O the/O American/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
That/O goes/O to/O the/O possibility/O of/O being/O prosecuted/O crimi/O -/O nally/O ./O 
If/O the/O statute/O of/O limitations/O has/O run/O ,/O what/O possible/O danger/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 65/O could/O you/O be/O in/O that/O would/O entitle/O you/O to/O invoke/O the/O provisions/O of/O the/O Constitution/O as/O a/O protection/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O feel/O called/O upon/O to/O go/O into/O an/O explanation/O of/O my/O understanding/O of/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O trying/O to/O refresh/O you/O on/O fundamental/O principles/O ,/O that/O is/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O should/O happen/O that/O later/O you/O were/O cited/O for/O con/O -/O tempt/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O would/O you/O still/O agree/O that/O this/O is/O a/O legally/O constituted/O committee/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O consult/O counsel/O on/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
You/O have/O the/O privilege/O of/O conferring/O with/O your/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O you/O desire/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O POWE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O have/O advised/O my/O client/O that/O in/O the/O light/O of/O the/O last/O answer/O -/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O rule/O of/O the/O committee/O is/O that/O you/O can/O advise/O your/O client/O and/O let/O your/O client/O give/O the/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O POWE/PERSON ./O 
I/O thought/O the/O committee/O would/O like/O to/O know/O the/O reason/O why/O I/O advised/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
We/O are/O not/O concerned/O with/O that/O ./O 
You/O advise/O him/O and/O let/O him/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Upon/O advice/O of/O my/O counsel/O I/O answer/O that/O question/O that/O an/O answer/O to/O this/O question/O involves/O legal/O opinion/O which/O I/O am/O not/O qualified/O at/O this/O time/O to/O answer/O ,/O but/O if/O such/O a/O situation/O should/O arise/O as/O was/O here/O indicated/O as/O a/O possibility/O ,/O I/O would/O then/O act/O upon/O the/O advice/O of/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
But/O your/O answer/O to/O my/O question/O originally/O that/O you/O agreed/O that/O this/O was/O a/O legally/O constituted/O committee/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION -/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON -LRB-/O continuing/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Was/O also/O on/O the/O advice/O of/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
This/O is/O my/O understanding/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O it/O would/O be/O the/O advice/O of/O counsel/O if/O I/O consulted/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O record/O should/O show/O that/O counsel/O was/O present/O at/O all/O times/O with/O the/O witness/O in/O all/O these/O questions/O and/O counsel/O made/O no/O objection/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O counsel/O is/O not/O supposed/O to/O make/O objections/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O did/O you/O assist/O in/O any/O manner/O in/O the/O formation/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possi/O -/O ble/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Gordon/PERSON Kahn/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O editorial/O board/O of/O the/O publication/O Clipper/O ,/O and/O who/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O faculty/O of/O the/O School/O of/O Writers/O ,/O now/O known/O as/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Branch/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ,/O who/O ,/O accord/O -/O ing/O to/O the/O August/O 1/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O Bulletin/O was/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O on/O radio/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
66/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Another/O individual/O attached/O to/O the/O publication/O Clipper/O was/O Waldo/PERSON Salt/PERSON ,/O S-a-l-t/O ,/O an/O associate/O editor/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Mr./O Salt/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O do/O you/O think/O it/O would/O incriminate/O you/O to/O admit/O you/O knew/O someone/O in/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O stand/O on/O my/O right/O to/O claim/O the/O privilege/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O my/O understanding/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O it/O is/O your/O understanding/O that/O you/O can/O decline/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O ,/O innocent/O as/O it/O may/O be/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O because/O you/O feel/O that/O the/O answer/O to/O that/O question/O might/O tend/O to/O in/O -/O criminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O consult/O counsel/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
My/O counsel/O advises/O me/O that/O in/O regard/O to/O any/O question/O where/O I/O honestly/O feel/O that/O the/O answer/O may/O tend/O to/O lead/O to/O self-incrimination/O ,/O I/O can/O avail/O myself/O of/O the/O constitutional/O right/O not/O to/O answer/O ./O 
I/O say/O this/O in/O the/O context/O of/O my/O desire/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O committee/O with/O this/O understanding/O of/O my/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O do/O you/O follow/O the/O advice/O of/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O 1946/O on/O the/O occasion/O of/O my/O mother/O 's/O death/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION again/O in/O 1948/O when/O my/O father/O was/O dying/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION prior/O to/O that/O in/O 1936/O ,/O part/O of/O 1936/O and/O part/O of/O 1937/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
To/O me/O Hollywood/O represents/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O yes/O ./O 
If/O I/O do/O n't/O call/O it/O city/O it/O is/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O understand/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O purpose/O of/O your/O visits/O on/O those/O occasions/O that/O which/O you/O mentioned/O ,/O to/O visit/O your/O mother/O and/O father/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O my/O visits/O in/O 1946/O and/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O any/O of/O the/O writers/O in/O Holly/LOCATION -/O wood/O ,/O any/O one/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
You/O were/O there/O in/O 1946/O and/O 1948/O on/O account/O of/O deaths/O in/O your/O family/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O your/O other/O visits/O in/O 1936/O and/O 1937/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self/O -/O incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Were/O those/O the/O only/O visits/O you/O made/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self/O -/O incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O work/O for/O any/O organization/O in/O Holly/LOCATION -/O wood/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 67/O Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O it/O true/O the/O purpose/O of/O those/O visits/O was/O to/O organize/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O help/O organize/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O spoke/O of/O the/O purpose/O of/O my/O visits/O in/O 1946/O and/O 1948/O ./O 
I/O stand/O by/O that/O explanation/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O visit/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION for/O the/O purpose/O of/O aiding/O in/O the/O organization/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION cell/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O you/O a/O few/O minutes/O ago/O to/O say/O that/O you/O wanted/O to/O be/O helpful/O to/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O will/O you/O tell/O us/O what/O you/O know/O about/O Actors/O '/O Laboratory/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O who/O the/O founders/O were/O of/O Actors/O '/O Laboratory/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Perhaps/O you/O could/O refresh/O his/O recollection/O by/O giving/O the/O names/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O J./PERSON Edward/PERSON Bromberg/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O associated/O with/O Actors/O '/O Laboratory/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Chapter/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Arts/ORGANIZATION ,/O Sciences/O ,/O and/O Professions/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O does/O ``/O acquainted/O ''/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O of/O the/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Of/O its/O existence/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O its/O existence/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
That/O is/O not/O my/O understanding/O of/O ``/O acquaintance/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
To/O what/O extent/O were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O aid/O or/O assist/O in/O any/O manner/O in/O the/O formation/O of/O that/O chapter/O ,/O or/O counsel/O or/O advise/O others/O in/O regard/O to/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Daily/O Worker/O of/O May/O 11/O ,/O 1934/O ,/O identifies/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Agit-Prop/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O the/O expression/O for/O the/O Agitation/O and/O Propaganda/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Was/O that/O a/O correct/O identification/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
If/O it/O were/O n't/O true/O it/O would/O n't/O incriminate/O you/O ,/O would/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ?/O 
81595-51-pt/O ./O 
1/O -/O 2/O 68/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O feel/O justified/O resting/O on/O my/O privilege/O against/O answer/O -/O ing/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O trying/O now/O to/O ascertain/O what/O your/O conception/O is/O of/O your/O privilege/O ./O 
Do/O you/O take/O the/O position/O that/O a/O question/O to/O which/O you/O could/O answer/O ,/O as/O in/O this/O instance/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O ''/O would/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O answered/O `/O with/O my/O explanation/O of/O the/O expres/O -/O sion/O given/O by/O Justice/O Black/PERSON in/O the/O Rogers/ORGANIZATION decision/O in/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O have/O it/O here/O before/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O only/O be/O reiterating/O what/O I/O said/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O in/O 1936/O connected/O in/O any/O capacity/O with/O the/O cultural/O commission/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O identified/O as/O chairman/O or/O head/O of/O the/O cul/O -/O tural/O commission/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION by/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O of/O August/O 7/O ,/O 1950/O ,/O and/O the/O Daily/O Peoples/O World/O of/O January/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O and/O February/O 8/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O whether/O that/O identification/O was/O wrong/O or/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O resting/O on/O my/O rights/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Again/O ,/O would/O you/O say/O that/O an/O answer/O that/O that/O identification/O is/O wrong/O ,/O if/O true/O ,/O would/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O stated/O my/O understanding/O ,/O that/O to/O answer/O that/O questionMr/O ./O 
WOOD/O ./O 
Would/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O knew/O subsequent/O to/O the/O publication/O of/O those/O papers/O ,/O those/O three/O occasions/O ,/O that/O you/O were/O listed/O as/O that/O ,/O did/O n't/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O grounds/O of/O possi/O -/O ble/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O was/O not/O true/O ,/O did/O you/O take/O any/O measures/O to/O correct/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O May/O 22/O ,/O 1950/O ,/O issue/O of/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ,/O at/O page/O 11/O ,/O there/O is/O contained/O a/O tribute/O from/O the/O national/O cultural/O commission/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O Bob/PERSON Reed/PERSON ,/O signed/O V./PERSON J./PERSON Jerome/PERSON ,/O chairman/O ,/O National/ORGANIZATION Cultural/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION ,/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O actually/O sign/O a/O tribute/O from/O that/O commission/O as/O its/O chairman/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O invoking/O my/O right/O against/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Bob/PERSON Reed/PERSON was/O a/O friend/O of/O yours/O ,/O was/O he/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O already/O stated/O to/O the/O committee/O that/O you/O went/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1936/O ./O 
Is/O it/O not/O true/O that/O the/O purpose/O of/O your/O trip/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1936/O was/O to/O organize/O a/O separate/O district/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O or/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O resting/O on/O my/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O not/O Stanley/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON in/O charge/O of/O Communist/O activities/O among/O the/O Hollywood/O group/O prior/O to/O your/O going/O there/O in/O 1936/O ?/O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 69/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O 1936/O when/O you/O went/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
All/O told/O I/O believe/O I/O was/O there/O about/O 9/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O live/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O while/O you/O were/O in/O Cali/LOCATION -/O fornia/O ,/O or/O immediately/O prior/O thereto/O ,/O was/O it/O determined/O by/O the/O national/O organization/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION funds/O derived/O from/O the/O California/LOCATION area/O were/O so/O large/O that/O it/O was/O considered/O advisable/O to/O have/O them/O sent/O directly/O to/O the/O national/O organization/O instead/O of/O to/O the/O State/O organization/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O was/O n't/O that/O the/O practice/O after/O your/O departure/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
While/O you/O were/O in/O California/LOCATION during/O this/O 9-month/O period/O ,/O were/O you/O known/O within/O Communist/O Party/O circles/O as/O the/O theatrical/O instructor/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION district/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O of/O no/O such/O designation/O ,/O nor/O do/O I/O lay/O claim/O to/O such/O title/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O an/O instructor/O of/O Stalinism/O and/O Leninism/O among/O the/O Hollywood/O group/O ,/O were/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O ground/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O state/O you/O were/O not/O the/O theatrical/O instructor/O ./O 
but/O did/O n't/O you/O engage/O in/O work/O as/O an/O instructor/O in/O the/O theory/O of/O communism/O while/O you/O were/O in/O California/LOCATION in/O 1936/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O you/O to/O define/O what/O you/O mean/O by/O ``/O theatrical/O instructor/O ./O ''/O 
Do/O you/O mean/O theatrical/O director/O ,/O or/O did/O I/O cast/O people/O into/O roles/O ?/O 
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O if/O you/O were/O known/O by/O that/O title/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
I/O recollect/O no/O such/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O if/O you/O were/O an/O instructor/O of/O a/O theatrical/O group/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O that/O title/O would/O be/O descriptive/O of/O your/O duties/O in/O that/O position/O ,/O would/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O engage/O in/O such/O activities/O while/O you/O were/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Instructing/O ,/O lecturing/O ,/O advising/O ,/O the/O Hollywood/O group/O on/O the/O question/O of/O communism/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O discharged/O the/O function/O I/O have/O described/O ,/O the/O term/O ``/O theatrical/O instructor/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ''/O would/O be/O an/O adequate/O description/O ,/O would/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O records/O of/O this/O committee/O reflect/O that/O the/O Holly/O -/O wood/O League/O Against/O Naziism/O was/O established/O in/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O that/O 70/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O the/O name/O was/O later/O changed/O to/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O the/O reason/O for/O that/O change/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O T./O \/O ENN-ER/O ./O 
Were/O you/O consulted/O with/O respect/O to/O the/O formation/O of/O the/O Hollwood/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION Against/O Nazism/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O that/O organization/O or/O the/O succeeding/O organization/O ,/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O it/O not/O true/O that/O efforts/O to/O link/O communism/O and/O fascism/O caused/O dissension/O in/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O which/O you/O were/O directed/O to/O straighten/O out/O the/O trouble/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O such/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O confer/O with/O members/O of/O the/O Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O purpose/O of/O settling/O the/O disputes/O they/O had/O within/O their/O own/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privi/O -/O lege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Dr./O Inez/PERSON Decker/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Dr./O Inez/PERSON Decker/PERSON was/O a/O mem/O -/O ber/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O James/PERSON Thorme/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privi/O -/O lege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Eva/PERSON Shaffron/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privi/O -/O lege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Rudy/PERSON Lambert/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O John/PERSON L./PERSON Leech/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privi/O -/O lege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O these/O individuals/O whose/O names/O I/O have/O just/O asked/O you/O about/O members/O of/O the/O executive/O committee/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O meet/O with/O these/O individuals/O in/O the/O home/O of/O Dr./O Inez/PERSON Decker/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 71/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O in/O the/O home/O of/O Dr./O Inez/PERSON Decker/PERSON ,/O discuss/O the/O reorganization/O of/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Anti-Nazi/O League/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O direct/O the/O executive/O committee/O of/O the/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION to/O carry/O out/O an/O extensive/O campaign/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION among/O the/O crafts/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O such/O as/O carpenters/O ,/O electricians/O ,/O technicians/O ,/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O Actors/O '/O Guild/O ,/O and/O other/O organizations/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O direct/O that/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION be/O used/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O bringing/O into/O contact/O with/O the/O -/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Hollywood/ORGANIZATION personalities/O who/O were/O not/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON Ogden/PERSON Stewart/PERSON was/O chairman/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
him/O ?/O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Marian/PERSON Spitzer/PERSON was/O vice/O chairman/O of/O the/O Holly/ORGANIZATION -/O wood/O Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O her/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Allen/PERSON Campbell/PERSON was/O secretary/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Have/O you/O talked/O to/O him/O about/O the/O affairs/O of/O the/O league/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O in/O the/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Bern/PERSON Bernard/PERSON W/PERSON \/O as/O treasurer/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O in/O any/O manner/O with/O the/O or/O -/O ganization/O known/O as/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/O Democratic/O Action/O ?/O 
`/O Thatis/O ,/O did/O you/O know/O of/O its/O existence/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O registered/O under/O the/O Internal/O Security/O Act/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O consult/O my/O attorney/O ,/O please/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O not/O registered/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Are/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O so-called/O Internal/O Security/O Act/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O in/O a/O way/O ./O 
I/O have/O read/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WoOD/O ./O 
You/O know/O in/O a/O general/O way/O about/O its/O provisions/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
In/O a/O general/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
And/O you/O have/O not/O registered/O under/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O not/O registered/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Potter/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O been/O very/O open/O about/O your/O affiliation/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O past/O ;/O is/O n't/O that/O true/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
72/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
The/O statement/O counsel/O made/O a/O little/O while/O ago/O concern/O -/O ing/O an/O article/O in/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O signed/O by/O you/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O Cultural/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O indicate/O you/O had/O been/O open/O about/O your/O affiliation/O in/O the/O past/O ./O 
That/O being/O so/O ,/O I/O will/O ask/O you/O now/O ,/O are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O present/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O have/O met/O that/O question/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O asked/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O POTTER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O answer/O is/O the/O same/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
The/O same/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Any/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O this/O question/O :/O Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O you/O made/O that/O award/O that/O has/O been/O referred/O to/O ,/O to/O Mr./O Reed/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O write/O that/O article/O that/O counsel/O cited/O from/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O for/O the/O same/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O demand/O a/O retraction/O from/O the/O Daily/O Worker/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O same/O basis/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O asking/O you/O about/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/O Democratic/O Action/O ./O 
Is/O it/O not/O true/O that/O Mr./O Fank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON was/O vice/O chairman/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O with/O Mr./O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON the/O activ/O -/O ities/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Dudley/PERSON Nichols/PERSON was/O secretary/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Action/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O the/O business/O of/O that/O organization/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Bern/PERSON Bernard/PERSON ,/O the/O same/O person/O about/O whom/O I/O asked/O you/O a/O moment/O ago/O ,/O was/O also/O treasurer/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/O Democratic/O Action/O ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O the/O business/O of/O that/O organization/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O priv/O -/O ilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON Garfield/PERSON is/O a/O person/O alleged/O to/O have/O been/O active/O in/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ,/O has/O that/O organization/O been/O cited/O as/O sub/O -/O versive/O by/O the/O Attorney/O General/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O has/O been/O cited/O by/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activies/O ,/O and/O was/O cited/O in/O 1948/O ./O 
We/O spoke/O of/O the/O School/O for/O Writers/O a/O little/O earlier/O in/O your/O testimony/O ,/O which/O later/O became/O a/O branch/O of/O the/O People/O 's/O Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ./O 
An/O individual/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Robert/PERSON Lees/PERSON is/O alleged/O to/O have/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O executive/O board/O of/O the/O School/O for/O Writers/O ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
73/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O the/O officers/O of/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O in/O 1942/O were/O Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ,/O chairman/O ;/O Paul/PERSON Franklin/PERSON ,/O vice/O chairman/O ;/O and/O Pauline/PERSON Lauber/PERSON Finn/PERSON ,/O executive/O secretary/O ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O any/O of/O these/O individuals/O ,/O and/O if/O so/O ,/O which/O ones/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Acquainted/O means/O have/O I/O known/O them/O or/O heard/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O known/O them/O personally/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O recollection/O ,/O none/O of/O those/O individuals/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O is/O it/O not/O true/O that/O the/O Politburo/O ordered/O the/O comrades/O who/O were/O in/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O organization/O to/O make/O plans/O for/O the/O holding/O of/O a/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Marc/PERSON Connelly/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Information/O is/O in/O the/O hands/O of/O the/O committee/O that/O the/O faculty/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION included/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Charles/PERSON J./PERSON Katz/PERSON ,/O attorney/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ;/O Herbert/PERSON Klein/PERSON ;/O Ben/PERSON Margolis/PERSON ;/O Earl/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ;/O and/O Revels/PERSON Cayton/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O any/O of/O those/O individuals/O ,/O and/O if/O so/O ,/O name/O those/O with/O whom/O you/O are/O acquainted/O ./O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Another/O member/O of/O the/O faculty/O of/O the/O People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION is/O alleged/O to/O be/O Carl/PERSON Winter/PERSON ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION secretary/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Mr./O Winter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Also/O on/O the/O faculty/O was/O Eva/PERSON Shaffron/PERSON ,/O alleged/O to/O be/O the/O director/O of/O the/O Workers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION for/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O her/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Viola/PERSON Brothers/PERSON Shore/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O appear/O as/O a/O speaker/O at/O the/O San/ORGANIZATION Francisco/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION held/O in/O October/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O in/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O suggestions/O ,/O or/O did/O you/O in/O any/O way/O assist/O in/O drawing/O up/O the/O plans/O for/O that/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O where/O the/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION was/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O claiming/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O it/O not/O true/O that/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O fellow-travelers/O in/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O ,/O acting/O under/O the/O directions/O of/O Alexander/PERSON Trachtenberg/PERSON and/O you/O ,/O persuaded/O Dr./O Robert/PERSON Sproul/PERSON ,/O president/O of/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O lend/O 74/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O you/O the/O campus/O for/O the/O meeting/O place/O for/O this/O Writers/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O also/O persuaded/O him/O to/O let/O you/O use/O the/O university/O 's/O name/O as/O cosponsor/O of/O the/O event/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O the/O Dr./O Sproul/PERSON who/O is/O connected/O with/O the/O Institute/ORGANIZATION of/O Pacific/O Relations/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O question/O directed/O to/O me/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O not/O like/O to/O state/O without/O definite/O knowledge/O ./O 
You/O state/O you/O had/O no/O knowledge/O of/O the/O making/O of/O those/O arrangements/O ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O knowledge/O you/O did/O have/O about/O the/O holding/O of/O that/O congress/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O and/O Alexander/PERSON Trachtenberg/PERSON ,/O Joseph/PERSON Fields/PERSON ,/O Lionel/PERSON Berman/PERSON ,/O and/O Louis/PERSON Budenz/PERSON were/O members/O of/O a/O committee/O ,/O were/O you/O not/O ,/O within/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O or/O were/O you/O at/O any/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Religious/ORGANIZATION Political/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O a/O conference/O of/O the/O School/O of/O Jewish/O Studies/O at/O the/O Jefferson/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Social/ORGANIZATION Science/ORGANIZATION auditorium/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O January/O 14/O and/O 15/O ,/O 1950/O ,/O at/O which/O time/O you/O were/O elected/O a/O member/O of/O the/O board/O of/O directors/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TATENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O or/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O International/O Workers/O '/O Order/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O conferred/O with/O Steve/PERSON Nelson/PERSON on/O Communist/O Party/O matters/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O October/O 1947/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O subpenaed/O before/O it/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION from/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O with/O the/O persons/O subpenaed/O ,/O their/O counsel/O or/O agents/O ,/O the/O strategy/O adopted/O by/O that/O group/O in/O refusing/O to/O answer/O questions/O propounded/O by/O the/O staff/O and/O members/O of/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Subsequent/O to/O these/O hearings/O a/O rally/O was/O held/O entitled/O ``/O Keep/O America/O Free/O ,/O ''/O which/O was/O sponsored/O by/O the/O Conference/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Cultural/ORGANIZATION Freedom/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Civil/ORGANIZATION Liberties/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Progressive/O Citizens/O of/O America/LOCATION ./O 
Did/O you/O discuss/O with/O anyone/O the/O formation/O of/O this/O rally/O prior/O to/O the/O holding/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O grounds/O of/O possible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O was/O the/O chairman/O of/O that/O rally/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O 75/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Committee/O information/O is/O it/O was/O Dr./O Harlow/PERSON Shap/PERSON -/O ley/O ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O days/O of/O the/O Hitler-Stalin/O pact/O ,/O did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION establish/O a/O commission/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O ascertaining/O the/O loyalty/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O during/O this/O period/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O pos/O -/O sible/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Has/O the/O Cultural/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION established/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O groups/O within/O the/O respective/O guilds/O or/O trades/O of/O the/O radio/O and/O television/O industry/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O invoking/O the/O privilege/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Norman/PERSON Louis/PERSON Corwin/PERSON assigned/O by/O the/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O to/O infiltrate/O and/O form/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION groups/O within/O the/O radio/O industry/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O take/O a/O recess/O until/O 2/O :/O 30/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Thereupon/O ,/O at/O 12:25/O p./O m./O ,/O a/O recess/O was/O taken/O until/O 2/O :/O 30/O p./O m./O of/O the/O same/O day/O ./O -RRB-/O 
AFTERNOON/O SESSION/O -LRB-/O The/O hearing/O was/O resumed/O at/O 2/O :/O 40/O p./O m./O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O there/O are/O present/O Messrs./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Frazier/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Potter/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/PERSON ,/O a/O quorum/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O question/O was/O asked/O this/O morning/O by/O a/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O about/O the/O citation/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O think/O I/O should/O state/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O record/O that/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/O Mobilization/O was/O cited/O as/O subversive/O and/O Communist/O by/O Attorney/O General/O Tom/PERSON Clark/PERSON on/O December/O 4/O ,/O 1947/O ,/O and/O again/O on/O September/O 21/O ,/O 1948/O ;/O and/O was/O also/O cited/O by/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O in/O 1945/O ./O 
The/O citation/O by/O the/O California/LOCATION committee/O is/O that/O it/O was/O a/O Communist-front/O organization/O whose/O ``/O true/O purpose/O ''/O was/O ``/O the/O creation/O of/O a/O clearing/O house/O for/O Communist/O propaganda/O ./O ''/O 
A/O publication/O which/O was/O referred/O to/O earlier/O in/O the/O testimony/O as/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Quarterly/ORGANIZATION was/O cited/O by/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O UnAmerican/O Activities/O in/O 1948/O as/O a/O ``/O Communist/O project/O ''/O sponsored/O jointly/O by/O the/O Communist/O front/O ,/O the/O Hollywood/O Writers/O '/O Mobilization/O ,/O and/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION at/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O VICTOR/PERSON JEREMY/PERSON JEROME/PERSON --/O Resumed/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jerome/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O knowledge/O of/O there/O having/O been/O in/O existence/O a/O list/O containing/O 300/O names/O of/O persons/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION which/O was/O used/O in/O obtaining/O funds/O for/O Spanish/O Aid/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O any/O list/O of/O 300/O such/O names/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O knowledge/O of/O any/O list/O compiled/O for/O that/O purpose/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O any/O list/O compiled/O for/O that/O purpose/O ./O 
76/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O Mr./O TAVENXER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O George/PERSON Pershing/PERSON ,/O the/O former/O field/O secretary/O of/O the/O Committee/O for/O Spanish/O Aid/O Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O present/O to/O him/O or/O transmit/O to/O him/O by/O any/O method/O a/O list/O containing/O names/O of/O persons/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O for/O him/O to/O use/O in/O obtaining/O funds/O for/O Spanish/O Aid/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O memory/O ;/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O such/O a/O list/O ,/O or/O any/O type/O of/O list/O ,/O avail/O -/O able/O to/O Paul/PERSON Crouch/PERSON for/O the/O purpose/O of/O soliciting/O funds/O for/O the/O publication/O of/O New/O South/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
What/O kind/O of/O list/O ?/O 
Will/O you/O repeat/O that/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVEXXER/PERSON ./O 
A/O list/O of/O names/O of/O individuals/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION to/O be/O used/O by/O Paul/PERSON Crouch/PERSON or/O any/O other/O person/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O soliciting/O funds/O for/O the/O publication/O of/O New/O South/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O in/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O acquainted/O with/O Paul/PERSON Crouch/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O furnish/O a/O list/O of/O names/O ,/O or/O cause/O a/O list/O of/O names/O to/O be/O furnished/O ,/O to/O Paul/PERSON Crouch/PERSON or/O any/O other/O person/O ,/O to/O be/O used/O as/O a/O list/O of/O secret/O contributors/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O JEROME/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O in/O exercise/O of/O my/O right/O against/O self-incrimination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O desire/O at/O this/O time/O to/O question/O the/O witness/O regarding/O the/O names/O of/O persons/O appearing/O on/O an/O alleged/O list/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O character/O of/O it/O ,/O it/O should/O be/O in/O executive/O session/O ,/O if/O you/O desire/O to/O consider/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
What/O is/O the/O pleasure/O of/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Members/O of/O the/O committee/O confer/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ,/O we/O will/O resolve/O the/O hearing/O into/O an/O executive/O session/O ./O 
We/O will/O ask/O the/O people/O other/O than/O the/O committee/O and/O the/O staff/O to/O retire/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Thereupon/O ,/O at/O 2:50/O p./O m./O ,/O the/O committee/O went/O into/O executive/O session/O ./O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNIST/O INFILTRATION/O OF/O HOLLYWOOD/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY-PART/O 1/O WEDNESDAY/O ,/O MARCH/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O CoMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIEs/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O pursuant/O to/O call/O at/O 10/O :/O 35/O a./O m./O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./O -LRB-/O appearance/O as/O noted/O in/O transcript/O -RRB-/O ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON H./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ;/O John/PERSON W./PERSON Carrington/PERSON ,/O clerk/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O disclose/O that/O there/O are/O present/O Messrs./O Walter/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Velde/PERSON ,/O Kearney/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O Potter/PERSON ,/O and/O Wood/PERSON ,/O constituting/O a/O quorum/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O make/O a/O brief/O statement/O regarding/O the/O general/O purpose/O of/O the/O hearing/O ?/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O is/O well/O known/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O has/O succeeded/O to/O a/O marked/O degree/O in/O exposing/O Communists/O '/O infiltration/O into/O labor/O organizations/O ,/O with/O the/O result/O in/O many/O instances/O that/O the/O organizations/O involved/O have/O rid/O themselves/O of/O Communist/O domination/O and/O influences/O ,/O and/O likewise/O with/O the/O result/O `/O that/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O informed/O of/O many/O important/O facts/O as/O the/O basis/O for/O legislative/O action/O ./O 
I/O need/O only/O remind/O you/O that/O the/O testimony/O of/O Matthew/PERSON Cvetic/PERSON virtually/O destroyed/O for/O the/O time/O being/O at/O least/O the/O power/O and/O influence/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O western/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ./O 
Then/O there/O have/O been/O many/O witnesses/O who/O have/O frankly/O and/O openly/O told/O this/O committee/O of/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O they/O were/O duped/O into/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O observed/O by/O them/O while/O they/O were/O members/O ,/O and/O the/O reasons/O for/O their/O breaking/O with/O the/O party/O ./O 
This/O has/O required/O courage/O on/O the/O part/O of/O these/O witnesses/O ./O 
But/O ,/O in/O so/O testifying/O ,/O they/O have/O performed/O a/O service/O of/O inestimable/O value/O to/O their/O country/O and/O in/O the/O end/O should/O and/O do/O receive/O the/O plaudits/O of/O their/O fellow/O citizens/O ./O 
78/O COMMUNISM/O IN/O MOTION-PICTURE/O INDUSTRY/O The/O hearing/O today/O is/O the/O first/O of/O a/O series/O designed/O by/O the/O committee/O to/O accomplish/O the/O same/O results/O in/O the/O entertainment/O field/O as/O have/O been/O accomplished/O in/O labor/O and/O other/O fields/O ./O 
In/O performing/O its/O statutory/O duty/O to/O investigate/O communism/O wherever/O it/O may/O be/O found/O ,/O we/O shall/O endeavor/O to/O ascertain/O the/O extent/O of/O past/O and/O present/O Communist/O infiltration/O in/O the/O field/O mentioned/O ./O 
It/O is/O hoped/O that/O any/O witness/O appearing/O during/O the/O course/O of/O these/O hearings/O ,/O who/O made/O the/O mistake/O of/O associating/O himself/O or/O herself/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O will/O have/O sufficient/O courage/O and/O loyalty/O to/O make/O an/O honest/O and/O complete/O disclosure/O of/O all/O they/O know/O about/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ./O 
These/O hearings/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O have/O not/O been/O hastily/O conceived/O ./O 
They/O are/O based/O upon/O investigative/O efforts/O by/O staff/O members/O extending/O over/O a/O number/O of/O years/O ./O 
As/O you/O will/O recall/O ,/O it/O was/O contemplated/O that/O these/O hearings/O be/O conducted/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION by/O the/O subcommittee/O which/O was/O chosen/O to/O conduct/O the/O hearings/O in/O Hawaii/LOCATION ;/O but/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O work/O required/O of/O the/O staff/O in/O the/O preparation/O of/O the/O Hawaiian/O hearings/O and/O other/O hearings/O ,/O this/O matter/O was/O postponed/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O ,/O as/O the/O first/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Larry/PERSON Parks/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Is/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON present/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Will/O you/O stand/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O evidence/O you/O give/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Have/O a/O seat/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O LARRY/O PARKS/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O LOUIS/PERSON MANDEL/PERSON Mr./O TAVEN/PERSON NER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Larry/PERSON Parks/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O am/O ./O 
My/O counsel/O is/O Mr./O Mandel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O identify/O himself/O ?/O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
