INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 7/O HEARING/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O APRIL/O 16/O ,/O 1956/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O Index/O in/O Part/O 10/O of/O This/O Series/O -RRB-/O 0/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 77436/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1956/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON E./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION RICHARD/PERSON ARENS/PERSON ,/O Director/O II/O CONTENTS/O PART/O 7/O April/O 16/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofWilliam/O Don/PERSON Waddilove/PERSON -----------------------------/O Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O George/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -RRB-/O ---------------------/O ./O 
Afternoon/O session/O :/O Rubin/PERSON Decker/PERSON ------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON Pass/PERSON --------------------------------------/O Samuel/PERSON Berland/PERSON -----------------------------------/O ./O 
Sylvia/PERSON Lardner/PERSON Darnell/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON -RRB-/O --------------/O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON --/O _/O -------------/O Milton/PERSON Kestenbaum/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Sidney/PERSON Greene/PERSON -----/O .../O .../O ---------------------/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON .../O ---------/O _/O ----------/O _/O ---------/O PART/O 8/O April/O 17/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Nikolai/PERSON Khokhlov/PERSON -/O .../O --/O ----------/O -/O PART/O 9/O April/O 19/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofAlbert/O Glasser/PERSON -/O .../O .../O ____/O ./O 
.../O ---------/O .../O Katherine/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -RRB-/O --------------------/O Herbert/PERSON Offner/PERSON ----------------/O ./O 
--------------------/O Sam/PERSON Fordis/PERSON -/O ____/O -/O _______/O --/O _/O --------/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ./O 
---------------/O ./O 
--/O ./O 
----------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O of/O :/O Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON _/O -------------------------/O Helen/PERSON Teverniti/PERSON -------------------------------/O Lewis/PERSON Elias/PERSON __/O --------------------/O ./O 
--------------/O ./O 
Leonard/PERSON H./PERSON Dahlsten/PERSON ___/O .../O .../O .../O .../O ---------/O .../O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -------------------------------/O Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --------------/O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -/O ./O 
-------------/O Manuel/PERSON L./PERSON Compinsky/PERSON ./O 
------------------------------/O Eudice/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -RRB-/O ------------------------------/O Milton/PERSON Feher/PERSON ./O 
./O 
------/O PART/O 10/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O ----------------------------/O Thomas/PERSON Walfrid/PERSON Nelson/ORGANIZATION Arthur/ORGANIZATION Globe/ORGANIZATION --------------------------------------------------------/O .../O ----------/O Don/PERSON Christlieb/PERSON Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofRamez/O Idriss/O --------------------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON DiFiore/PERSON ------/O ./O 
----------------------------/O Edgar/PERSON Lustgarten/PERSON .../O ./O 
Pae/O 3600/O 3676/O 3695/O 3711/O 3718/O 3726/O 3728/O 3733/O 3737/O 3749/O 756/O 3821/O 3837/O 3841/O 3850/O 3854/O 3862/O 3869/O 3870/O 3881/O 3885/O 3887/O 3887/O 3892/O 3896/O 3897/O 3901/O 3915/O 3918/O 3934/O 3937/O 3939/O IV/O CONTENTS/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956-Continued/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O of-Continued/O Morris/PERSON Boltuch/PERSON ___/O ./O 
___/O _________/O Philip/PERSON Goldberg/PERSON --/O _________/O __/O Joseph/PERSON Eger/PERSON _____/O __________/O Kalman/PERSON Bloch/PERSON --/O ____________/O --/O Jack/PERSON -LRB-/O L/O -RRB-/O Pepper/O --/O .../O Jean/ORGANIZATION C./ORGANIZATION Music/ORGANIZATION -/O __/O -/O ./O 
__________/O --/O Manuel/PERSON Newman/PERSON --/O Roy/PERSON Frankson/PERSON -/O __/O ./O 
_____________/O Herbert/PERSON Lessner/PERSON _______________/O George/PERSON Kast/PERSON --/O ______/O --/O April/O 21/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O :/O John/PERSON Walter/PERSON Porter/PERSON _/O --------------------------/O Jessica/PERSON Rhine/PERSON Wildman/PERSON -----------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofLouis/O R./PERSON Sherman/PERSON --------------------------/O William/PERSON Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON ----------------------/O ./O 
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------/O --/O --/O 3990/O -/O 4006/O --/O 4021/O ./O 
-----/O -/O 4026/O 4033/O Thomas/PERSON A./PERSON Chapman/PERSON ./O 
__/O --------------------/O _/O --/O -/O 4042/O Sidney/LOCATION London/LOCATION --/O .../O -/O ---------------/O ./O 
_/O ./O 
./O 
____/O --/O 4047/O Alfred/PERSON Hale/PERSON Caplan/PERSON ----------------/O 4053/O John/PERSON T./PERSON McTernan/PERSON ./O 
./O 
./O 
./O 
------------------/O .../O -/O ./O 
121/O ./O 
STANDINGCOMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O oeems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5,1955/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O wtinesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 7/O MONDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 16/O ,/O 1956/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUCOMMITrrEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O notice/O ,/O at/O 9/O :/O 30/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION ;/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ;/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O the/O Honorable/PERSON Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O of/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION ,/O pursuant/O to/O the/O provisions/O of/O law/O establishing/O this/O committee/O ,/O duly/O appointed/O Representative/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Representative/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ,/O and/O myself/O ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION ,/O chairman/O ,/O as/O a/O subcommittee/O to/O conduct/O hearings/O beginning/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION today/O ./O 
The/O full/O membership/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O is/O present/O ./O 
The/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O imposed/O upon/O this/O committee/O the/O duty/O of/O investigating/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O unAmerican/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O is/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O '/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
This/O committee/O has/O devoted/O much/O time/O in/O the/O past/O years/O to/O the/O investigation/O of/O the/O subject/O of/O communism/O ,/O and/O the/O committee/O has/O endeavored/O to/O keep/O Congress/ORGANIZATION well/O informed/O of/O the/O extent/O and/O the/O objects/O of/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O within/O this/O country/O ./O 
In/O the/O performance/O of/O this/O huge/O task/O the/O committee/O ,/O in/O its/O reports/O to/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O made/O in/O excess/O of/O 40/O recommendations/O for/O legislation/O by/O Congress/ORGANIZATION designed/O to/O aid/O in/O the/O fight/O against/O this/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ,/O all/O but/O a/O few/O of/O which/O have/O been/O enacted/O into/O law/O ./O 
3657/O 3658/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O In/O carrying/O out/O the/O statutory/O duties/O imposed/O upon/O this/O committee/O ,/O the/O committee/O proposes/O to/O continue/O its/O investigation/O of/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O Communist/O activities/O in/O this/O general/O area/O and/O in/O all/O other/O areas/O to/O which/O information/O developed/O may/O lead/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O to/O investigate/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O which/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
In/O 1951/O the/O committee/O began/O an/O investigation/O which/O resulted/O in/O a/O series/O of/O hearings/O related/O to/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ,/O of/O what/O is/O known/O as/O the/O northwest/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O usually/O referred/O to/O as/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O hearing/O will/O relate/O in/O part/O to/O a/O branch/O of/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION section/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O has/O not/O heretofore/O been/O the/O subject/O of/O investigation/O by/O this/O committee/O ./O 
This/O branch/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O committee/O is/O informed/O ,/O is/O composed/O exclusively/O of/O musicians/O ./O 
Inquiry/O will/O be/O made/O as/O to/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O members/O of/O this/O group/O with/O special/O reference/O to/O their/O activities/O in/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O the/O significance/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O that/O such/O activities/O import/O ./O 
The/O committee/O 's/O attention/O has/O been/O drawn/O to/O certain/O public/O interviews/O with/O a/O former/O Soviet/O intelligence/O officer/O which/O indicate/O a/O farreaching/O knowledge/O on/O his/O part/O of/O conditions/O within/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O believed/O that/O his/O background/O and/O experience/O has/O been/O such/O that/O his/O appearance/O as/O a/O witness/O should/O be/O a/O valuable/O aid/O to/O the/O committee/O in/O understanding/O in/O its/O proper/O perspective/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION control/O within/O the/O arts/O as/O practiced/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
This/O witness/O also/O will/O be/O asked/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O his/O analysis/O of/O the/O present/O Soviet/O policy/O as/O announced/O in/O the/O 20th/O Congress/O of/O the/O Soviet/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION held/O in/O Moscow/LOCATION in/O February/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
Here/O it/O should/O be/O noted/O that/O views/O of/O other/O leading/O authorities/O in/O this/O field/O will/O be/O the/O subject/O of/O a/O committee/O report/O which/O is/O expected/O to/O be/O ready/O for/O publication/O within/O the/O next/O few/O weeks/O ./O 
Several/O groups/O entirely/O unfamiliar/O with/O the/O investigative/O background/O of/O this/O hearing/O have/O protested/O against/O the/O holding/O of/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
In/O a/O communication/O from/O one/O of/O these/O groups/O it/O is/O stated/O :/O We/O believe/O ,/O as/O you/O have/O quite/O sincerely/O announced/O ,/O that/O the/O subpenaing/O of/O some/O 35/O local/O musicians/O is/O unrelated/O to/O the/O internal/O problems/O of/O the/O musicians/O union/O ./O 
Yet/O ,/O we/O believe/O ,/O the/O timing/O of/O the/O committee/O hearing/O is/O most/O unfortunate/O and/O certain/O to/O create/O public/O confusion/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O take/O this/O opportunity/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O state/O concretely/O and/O with/O emphasis/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O not/O interested/O in/O any/O dispute/O between/O employers/O and/O employees/O or/O between/O one/O union/O and/O another/O union/O ./O 
Neither/O is/O it/O interested/O in/O the/O internal/O affairs/O of/O any/O union/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O conclusive/O negation/O to/O the/O charge/O that/O this/O hearing/O is/O being/O held/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O interfering/O in/O the/O internal/O affairs/O of/O a/O union/O that/O this/O investigation/O was/O begun/O in/O June/O of/O 1955/O ,/O that/O the/O hearing/O was/O set/O for/O November/O of/O 1955/O ,/O that/O because/O of/O conflicts/O in/O appointments/O the/O hearings/O were/O continued/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O present/O date/O for/O the/O hearing/O was/O fixed/O by/O the/O committee/O at/O its/O first/O session/O in/O early/O January/O of/O this/O year/O ./O 
The/O only-and/O I/O quote/O from/O this/O communication/O -/O ``/O public/O confusion/O ''/O which/O could/O result/O is/O that/O which/O certain/O groups/O opposed/O to/O this/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3659/O committee/O seemed/O determined/O to/O create/O by/O the/O unfounded/O charges/O they/O persist/O in/O making/O ./O 
And/O that/O is/O the/O only/O public/O confusion/O that/O has/O been/O created/O ,/O and/O that/O has/O been/O created/O as/O a/O result/O of/O that/O ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O this/O investigation/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O of/O other/O individuals/O in/O the/O field/O of/O labor/O ,/O business/O ,/O and/O government/O have/O come/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O staff/O ,/O and/O will/O also/O be/O the/O subject/O of/O investigation/O and/O of/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
The/O committee/O took/O extensive/O testimony/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION during/O December/O of/O 1955/O ,/O and/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Washington/LOCATION in/O February/O and/O March/O ,/O relating/O to/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O of/O employees/O in/O various/O agencies/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O those/O hearings/O testimony/O was/O received/O divulging/O the/O existence/O of/O heretofore/O undisclosed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cells/O which/O operated/O in/O various/O Government/O agencies/O at/O various/O locations/O throughout/O the/O country/O ./O 
There/O will/O be/O heard/O ,/O before/O the/O conclusion/O of/O these/O hearings/O ,/O certain/O witnesses/O whose/O identity/O was/O disclosed/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O above/O hearings/O ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O received/O ,/O since/O its/O arrival/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O additional/O testimony/O touching/O on/O this/O subject/O from/O which/O it/O is/O apparent/O additional/O investigation/O will/O be/O required/O ,/O and/O in/O all/O probability/O future/O hearings/O will/O be/O held/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
It/O is/O a/O standing/O rule/O of/O this/O committee/O that/O any/O person/O who/O is/O named/O in/O the/O course/O of/O the/O conduct/O of/O the/O hearings/O of/O this/O committee/O and/O who/O is/O identified/O or/O referred/O to/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Conununist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION shall/O be/O given/O an/O opportunity/O to/O appear/O before/O this/O committee/O if/O he/O so/O desires/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O denying/O or/O explaining/O any/O testimony/O adversely/O affecting/O him/O or/O her/O ./O 
Should/O such/O an/O occasion/O arise/O such/O an/O individual/O concerned/O should/O communicate/O with/O any/O member/O of/O this/O committee/O or/O any/O member/O of/O the/O staff/O ./O 
Those/O present/O are/O reminded/O that/O they/O are/O guests/O of/O the/O committee/O as/O an/O agency/O of/O our/O Government/O ./O 
A/O disturbance/O of/O any/O kind/O or/O audible/O comment/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O ,/O either/O favorable/O or/O unfavorable/O to/O any/O witness/O or/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O will/O not/O be/O tolerated/O ./O 
For/O such/O infraction/O of/O this/O rule/O the/O offender/O immediately/O will/O be/O asked/O to/O leave/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O 
Under/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O televising/O and/O broadcasting/O of/O all/O House/ORGANIZATION committee/O hearings/O are/O prohibited/O ./O 
Still/O photographs/O are/O permitted/O while/O the/O witness/O is/O not/O testifying/O ./O 
I/O might/O also/O announce/O that/O the/O rules/O of/O those/O in/O control/O of/O this/O building/O prohibit/O smoking/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O Mr./O William/PERSON Don/PERSON Waddilove/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O come/O forward/O ,/O please/O ,/O and/O occupy/O the/O chair/O on/O my/O left/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O the/O testimony/O which/O you/O are/O about/O to/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOvE/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
3660/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O WILLIAM/O DON/O WADDILOVE/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
W-a-d-d-i-l-o-v-e/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O from/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Waddilove/PERSON ,/O it/O is/O noted/O that/O you/O are/O not/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O the/O practice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O advise/O all/O witnesses/O that/O they/O are/O entitled/O to/O counsel/O if/O they/O so/O desire/O ,/O and/O to/O confer/O with/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O during/O their/O testimony/O if/O the/O witness/O feels/O the/O occasion/O requires/O it/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Waddilove/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Ridgeway/PERSON ,/O Mo./LOCATION ,/O May/O 4/O ,/O 1919/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Secondary/O school/O and/O 1/O year/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Missouri/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O or/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O musician/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O practice/O your/O profession/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION between/O 1947/O and/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O engaged/O in/O that/O type/O of/O work/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
From/O 1942/O until/O 1952/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O reside/O in/O the/O general/O area/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O any/O time/O during/O that/O period/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Specifically/O ,/O during/O what/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDLOVE/PERSON ./O 
The/O latter/O half/O of/O 1947/O and/O all/O of/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Does/O that/O mean/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION early/O in/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Early/O in/O 1947/O I/O was/O engaged/O in/O a/O business/O venture/O which/O was/O on/O the/O verge/O of/O failing/O ,/O and/O eventually/O did/O ./O 
About-I/O am/O estimating-April/O or/O May/O of/O 1947/O ,/O I/O was/O engaged/O in/O a/O discussion/O group/O with/O several/O people/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O discussing/O political/O issues/O and/O economic/O issues/O in/O general/O on/O a/O social/O basis/O ./O 
At/O first/O only/O general/O issues/O were/O discussed/O ./O 
And/O this/O went/O on/O for/O some/O time/O ,/O and/O finally/O the/O people/O revealed/O themselves/O as/O Communists/O ,/O after/O a/O while/O ,/O after/O we/O agreed/O on/O the/O solution/O of/O certain/O issues/O ,/O and/O we/O were/O told/O that/O these/O issues/O could/O only/O be/O resolved/O through/O working/O through/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3661/O And/O that/O roughly/O are/O the/O circumstances/O surrounding/O my/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O have/O understood/O you/O correctly/O ,/O you/O were/O engaged/O in/O discussion/O groups/O with/O several/O people/O regarding/O political/O and/O economic/O issues/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O recess/O for/O 5/O minutes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O a/O short/O recess/O was/O taken/O ,/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Scherer/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O At/O the/O expiration/O of/O the/O recess/O ,/O the/O committee/O was/O reconvened/O ,/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O and/O Scherer/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Waddilove/PERSON ,/O I/O understood/O from/O your/O testimony/O that/O you/O had/O occasion/O to/O meet/O from/O time/O to/O time/O with/O a/O group/O of/O people/O who/O discussed/O political/O and/O economic/O issues/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILovE/O ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENER/PERSON ./O 
And/O that/O finally/O during/O those/O discussions/O several/O persons/O made/O themselves/O known/O to/O you/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O were/O advised/O by/O them/O that/O the/O only/O solution/O to/O the/O issues/O which/O you/O had/O been/O discussing/O was/O through/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O those/O individuals/O identifying/O themselves/O to/O you/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON and/O Sam/PERSON Albert/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O R-o-t-h/O ./O 
And/O what/O was/O the/O name/O of/O the/O other/O person/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Sam/PERSON Albert/PERSON ./O 
Were/O those/O individuals/O musicians/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O knew/O them/O at/O that/O time/O as/O being/O musiciansI/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O seek/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O mean/O by/O that/O ,/O did/O they/O ask/O you/O to/O join/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O so/O many/O words/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O the/O whole/O point/O of/O the/O discussion/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O what/O occurred/O and/O what/O you/O have/O just/O described/O ,/O did/O you/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Upon/O joining/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O group/O or/O unit/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
They/O were/O all/O musicians/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O one/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
You/O say/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
How/O did/O you/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
3662/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
By/O the/O members/O revealing/O themselves/O to/O me/O and/O being/O asked/O or/O permitted/O to/O attend/O party/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Nominal/O dues/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O issued/O any/O identification/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O persons/O composed/O the/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION with/O which/O you/O affiliated/O ,/O as/O nearly/O as/O you/O can/O now/O recall/O ?/O 
This/O was/O in/O 1947/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O exact/O number/O ,/O but/O I/O heard/O that/O there/O were/O roughly/O maybe/O 70/O or/O 75/O at/O one/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVEXXER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
He/O said/O members/O of/O the/O group/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O describe/O any/O particular/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Membership/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O know/O there/O were/O that/O many/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDLOVE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O figure/O was/O mentioned/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O reason/O I/O asked/O the/O question/O ./O 
Was/O it/O as/O a/O result/O of/O attending/O meetings/O or/O by/O examination/O of/O some/O records/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
By/O hearsay/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ,/O were/O meetings/O regularly/O held/O or/O at/O any/O stated/O intervals/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Weekly/O meetings/O were/O scheduled/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O frequently/O were/O they/O held/O ,/O generally/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Weekly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O the/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Many/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O during/O the/O entire/O period/O of/O your/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr/O VWADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O how/O many/O persons/O normally/O attended/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time/O ,/O maybe/O 10/O or/O 12/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O the/O meetings/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILovE/O ./O 
Various/O homes/O ,/O including/O my/O own/O ./O 
AMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O any/O persons/O in/O whose/O homes/O these/O meetings/O were/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O you/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O that/O information/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
The/O home/O of/O Anita/PERSON Short/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O that/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOvE/O ./O 
S-h-o-r-t/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Short/O ,/O Anita/PERSON Short/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
George/PERSON Sandell/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O it/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O S-a-n-d-e-l/O or/O two/O l/O 's/O ./O 
I/O amnot/O clear/O ./O 
Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O the/O correct/O spelling/O T-o-w-b-i-n/O or/O T-o-b-i-n/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3663/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O ,/O there/O was/O possibly/O a/O meeting/O at/O the/O house/O of/O Joe/PERSON Pass/PERSON ,/O Sam/PERSON Fordis/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O last/O name/O ?/O 
I/O did/O n't/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O WaDDILOVE/O ./O 
Fordis/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON Will/O you/O spell/O it/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O F-o-r-d-i-s/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O character/O of/O the/O meetings/O held/O in/O those/O homes/O and/O other/O homes/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Mainly/O they/O were/O study/O groups/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O meetings/O of/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O homes/O other/O than/O those/O that/O you/O have/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O exactly/O just/O whose/O ,/O but/O there/O were/O more/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O chief/O activity/O of/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O during/O your/O affiliation/O with/O this/O group/O ,/O what/O appeared/O to/O be/O its/O main/O objective/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Its/O main/O objective/O during/O that/O period/O was/O implementing/O the/O third/O party/O or/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O getting/O it/O on/O the/O ballot/O in/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O matter/O discussed/O in/O those/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Quite/O fully/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O occasions/O when/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functionaries/O came/O to/O your/O meeting/O ?/O 
That/O is/O functionaries/O on/O a/O higher/O level/O ,/O and/O told/O your/O membership/O what/O it/O was/O supposed/O to/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O IPP/ORGANIZATION was/O the/O target/O for/O 1948/O ./O 
All/O work/O was/O channeled/O in/O that/O direction/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O IPP/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O at/O this/O time/O the/O names/O of/O any/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functionaries/O who/O attended/O the/O meetings/O of/O your/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O one/O I/O could/O possibly/O recall/O would/O be/O Frank/PERSON Spector/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O only/O one/O I/O was/O aware/O of/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O position/O he/O held/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ,/O not/O exactly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O a/O member/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O what/O your/O group/O was/O advised/O or/O told/O to/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O we/O circulated/O petitions/O ,/O securing/O signatures/O ./O 
That/O was/O signatures/O to/O get/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O California/LOCATION ballot/O ./O 
And/O after/O this/O was/O done/O ,/O why/O ,/O then/O we/O did/O what/O we/O could/O to/O promote/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O ,/O in/O addition/O ,/O were/O requested/O to/O change/O our/O own/O registration/O from/O whatever/O it/O was/O to/O IPP/ORGANIZATION or/O Independent/O Progressive/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O follow/O the/O directions/O you/O received/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O both/O of/O those/O particulars/O ?/O 
That/O is/O ,/O in/O changing/O your/O registration/O and/O also/O in/O circulating/O petitions/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 2664/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O both/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O hand/O you/O a/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O an/O affidavit/O of/O registration/O showing/O your/O registration/O as/O an/O affiliate/O of/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O it/O is/O stated/O here/O ,/O under/O date/O of/O February/O 23/O ,/O 1948/O ./O 
I/O have/O another/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O an/O affidavit/O of/O registration/O indicating/O a/O change/O of/O residence/O ,/O with/O registration/O under/O the/O name/O of/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ,/O bearing/O date/O April/O 21/O ,/O 1948/O ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O these/O documents/O and/O state/O whether/O you/O recognize/O them/O as/O copies/O of/O your/O registrations/O ?/O 
-LSB-/O Documents/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RSB-/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O accept/O it/O as/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O offer/O both/O documents/O in/O evidence/O and/O ask/O that/O they/O be/O marked/O ``/O Waddilove/O Exhibits/O Nos./O 1/O and/O 2/O ''/O ,/O respectively/O ./O 
WADDILOVE/O EXHIBIT/O NO./O 1/O AIATMENT/O OPT/O ORCHANGE/O OSER/O OFNAME/O awte/O the/O ofi/O 4/O ,/O Myo/PERSON is/O jup1aton/O I/O h1eebyohosize/O the/O ancelatiooofaid/O egietrtion/O STATE/O OF/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION ./O 
9/O I/O intt/O ngioteeld/O -/O ORIGIAL/O LOSANOnUS/O CITYPRZc/O ErCT3O-fJ/O ./O 
i/O 6/O IN/O ./O 
AFFIDAATGoFREG/O OF.LOS/O ./O 
COUN/ORGANIZATION nB/O ry/O ThEuodeisnedaffiant/O ,/O beingdolyeo/O ,/O ./O 
sys/O :/O winbenatleasttwetyoneyea/O -/O ofsltbetimeaod/O sidenst/O of/O the/O State/O election/O ,/O a/O citizeno/O the/O UnitedSttes/O ninetyday/O prio/O thereto/O ,/O d/O e/O the/O nextsucceeding/O electionandw.i/O be/O mach/O ee/O yer/O ,/O of/O the/O Conotyninetydays.andof/O the/O Precinctfortydays/O ot/O preceding/O ''/O a/O electorofthl/O Countyatthe/O nextseeding/O elto/O ,/O 1/O ./O 
I/O havenot/O isteredeoe/O otherpreonctinthear/O S/O B/O e/O stat/O 1.1936/O I/O IILL.I/O ./O 
./O 
mY.k.TNSt/O 3/O ./O 
My/O My/O -/O g/O -/O ./O 
./O 
-/O 4l/O ./O 
./O 
-/O R/O t/O et/O s/O lng/O nad/O mShs/O ^/O -/O 3/O -/O yi/O _/O ./O 
d/O b/O 68/O .../O ./O 
.../O .../O .../O 1/O aOcbr/O 101911/O -/O \*/O =/O ,/O -/O '/O ''/O :/O l/O ''/O theCo/O s/O ttuton/O the/O E/O ty/O b/O -/O S7/O -/O _______/O withl/O _/O I/O tP.IJ/O '/O DE/O -/O H./O _/O -/O ----------/O r/O ./O ''/O 
li/O hlaIgUage/O ;/O Ic/O a/O '/O --/O at4Lo/O byDop/O o/O VotMitntesy/O ./O 
./O 
MyNighete/O -LRB-/O ./O 
by/O .../O witmyn/O --/O eg-sl/O of/O Vot/O ./O 
C111/O ;/O ./O 
R7/O DM/O q/O -/O ?/O 
^/O Date/O ,/O ./O 
__/O _/O t./O ~/O ol/O e/O ;/O Iam/O etitlcdto/O ote/O I/O -/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3665/O WADDILOVE/O EXHIBIT/O No./O 2/O STATEMENT/O OFTRAWSFNORCiANGE/O I/O OF/O AME/O o/O -/O nme/O I/O last/O registered/O derthe/O authorizethe/O ancelationoM/O I/O hereby/O ttgimtratifot/O gid/O STATEOFCALIFORNIA/O ./O 
-----/O -RCB-/O s/O CTY/ORGANIZATION O/ORGANIZATION LoSA/ORGANIZATION \*/ORGANIZATION W/ORGANIZATION n/O u/O 3/O ANoaUrI/O CIT/O Psculicr/O NOe/O AFFIDAVIT/O OF/O REGISTRATION/O ./O 
beingduly/O om/O ,/O y/O I/O wil/O be/O t/O lest/O twety/O e/O yea/O o/O at/O thetime/O The/O nndertigned.fItnt/O ./O 
thenextsuccedin/O election/O ,/O citi/O a/O of/O theUnited/O Ste/O niretyday/O priorthereto/O ./O 
adar/O idet/O theState/O one/O y/O of/O the/O Countyninetyday/O ,/O andof/O theP/O inct/O foty/O dayse/O t/O predig/O ah/O election/O ,/O Nd/O in/O o/O thisCountyat/O thenextsueedingeletio/O ./O 
nelector/O u/O 1ine/O Iy/O 1,936/O ./O 
otherp/O inctin/O theState/O 1/O ./O 
I/O ha-e/O t/O jgited/O ro/O anm/O 2/O u/O teu/O &/O a.ifaJ/O sf/O -/O \//O ./O 
./O 
hltM/O ____/O --/O ddre/O i/O ,/O .../O ig/O I./O ./O 
o./O ./O 
di/O l/O d9/O ./O 
,/O b/O --/O --/O &/O 1TVENN/O ./O 
CANCELLED/O ,/O h/O did/O s/O e/O sign/O that/O aeffidavitedt/O In/O what/O tcapacity/O Ou/O examine/O the/O signature/O at/O the/O bottom/O of/O oa/O t/O ,/O statement/O that/O N/O DONOGHIJ/O By-AIs/O -/O ./O 
./O 
s/O IL/O J./O itR/O ./O 
Mrlated/O at/O theea/O in4/O ./O 
p/O t/O y/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
h/O attheed/O d./O ao/O .../O .../O ./O 
a-y/O -/O there/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O whe/O _/O igo/O N-s/O l/O intend/O toN/O a/O ~/O \*/O ilte/O 7/O --/O ti/O ./O 
./O 
r/O Mii/O ^/O ./O 
,/O ,/O .6/O i/O __/O ,/O ./O 
k/O __/O eet/O a/O Sb/O i/O 4/O ./O 
_____/O tetup.Na/O .108/O dtI/O My/O oeNiden/O My/O SUS/O o/O were/O d/O -/O ./O 
-/O _/O ./O 
-/O 865418/O ``/O It/O ./O 
Regstar/O ofVotees/O lDepoty/O you/O a/O threxamine/O Will/O the/O signature/O at/O the/O bottom/O of/O exhibit/O No/O ./O 
and/O state/O who/O the/O registrar/O is/O ,/O what/O name/O you/O see/O signed/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O signed/O Mrs./O Esther/PERSON Roth/PERSON ./O 
there/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O signed/O Mrs./O Esther/PERSON Roth/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O capacity/O did/O she/O sign/O that/O affidavit/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O says/O Deputy/O Registrar/O of/O Voters/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O her/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Our/O investigation/O has/O disclosed/O a/O petition/O which/O shows/O ,/O at/O the/O end/O of/O it/O ,/O a/O statement/O that/O you/O were/O the/O one/O who/O circulated/O it/O ./O 
I/O hand/O you/O a/O three-page/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O it/O and/O ask/O you/O to/O examine/O it/O and/O state/O what/O it/O is/O ,/O please/O ./O 
3666/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O one/O I/O circulated/O in/O an/O effort/O to/O get/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O ballot/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION in/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O dated/O January/O 16/O ,/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O offer/O the/O document/O referred/O to/O above/O in/O evidence/O ,/O and/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O marked/O ``/O Waddilove/O Exhibit/O No./O 3/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O document/O so/O offered/O by/O counsel/O is/O admitted/O in/O evidence/O ./O 
-LRB-/O See/O p./O 3667/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O other/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O engage/O in/O the/O same/O type/O of/O activities/O which/O you/O described/O you/O pursued/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O we/O all/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ,/O on/O your/O level/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O advised/O why/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O taking/O such/O an/O active/O part/O in/O getting/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O ballot/O in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O quite/O sure/O I/O know/O exactly/O what/O you/O mean/O ./O 
However/O ,/O from/O an/O organizational/O standpoint/O ,/O I/O suppose/O it/O was/O logical/O because/O of/O the/O organization/O already/O set/O up/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O told/O that/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION offered/O the/O best/O vehicle/O for/O the/O advancement/O of/O the/O program/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O not/O as/O such/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
What/O did/O you/O understand/O to/O be/O the/O purpose/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O infiltrating/O the/O Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Why/O was/O it/O done/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O ,/O rather/O than/O infiltrate/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O spearheaded/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O the/O Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION would/O have/O reached/O a/O place/O on/O the/O ballot/O had/O it/O not/O been/O for/O the/O organization/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION behind/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION spearhead/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O so/O certainMr/O ./O 
SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION feel/O that/O it/O had/O more/O chance/O of/O success/O by/O using/O the/O name/O Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION rather/O than/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Undoubtedly/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O the/O reason/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O that/O is/O a/O good/O reason/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mentioned/O the/O name/O of/O Frank/PERSON Spector/PERSON as/O a/O Communist/O who/O attended/O some/O of/O your/O meetings/O and/O discussed/O activities/O relating/O to/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O what/O position/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O he/O held/O in/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
A/O moment/O ago/O you/O said/O that/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O ,/O in/O your/O judgment/O ,/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O spearheading/O the/O circulation/O of/O these/O petitions/O to/O qualify/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O to/O make/O it/O a/O legal/O party/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O was/O because/O you/O felt/O the/O party/O had/O more/O chance/O of/O success/O through/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O stating/O that/O substantially/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
3667/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O WADDILOVE/O EXHIBIT/O NO./O 3/O IPPC/O 6425/O INDEPENDENT/O PROGRESSIVE/O PARTY/O OF/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION PETITION/O TO/O PARTICIPATE/O IN/O THE/O PRIMARY/O ELECTION/O JUNE/O 1/O ,/O 1948/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION CialItd/O fl/O the/O County/O -LRB-/O or/O CityandCounty/O -RRB-/O of/O STATE/O OF/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION LOS/O _/O _/O ANGEL/LOCATION County/LOCATION or/LOCATION City/LOCATION snd/O Co.uty/O -RRB-/O of/O TO/O THE/O HONORABLE/O SECRETARY/O OF/O STATEOF/O THE/O STATE/O OF/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION :/O We/O ./O 
the/O underlgn/O ./O 
inhterd/O ./O 
-LRB-/O or/O quafludeletorsof/O the/O Stateof/O CEolorla/O ./O 
roaldents/O of/O the/O CLOS/O county/O Cy/O ./O 
./O 
d/O Cou.ty/O -RRB-/O ofc.llo/O .../O .../O ./O 
./O 
to/O h.s.O/O ./O 
AN/O GELE/O &/O i./O of/O Stto/O of/O th/O State/O of/O Californiath/LOCATION ./O 
Petitionand/O declarethatwe/O regret/O potcal/O P/O pay/O ,/O the/O nm/O of/O which/O i/O INDEPENDENT/O PROGRESSIVE/O PARTY/O OF/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION ,/O whichparty/O mid/O ./O 
eltor/O dr/O sIn/O to/O h.av/O partlcipate/O I/O the/O PrimnryEl/O to/O be/O held/O on/O Juno/O I./O 194/O ./O 
ecion/O -/O L/O SRESIDENCEr/O ./O 
_/O 3/O ./O 
./O 
./O 
-/O ./O 
-/O .../O P/O --/O ./O 
;/O .11/O ol/O .../O .../O .../O .../O .../O -/O --/O hW/O C/O ~/O ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O anddrmg/O all/O e/O time/O while/O soltm/O shownafter/O each/O sInature/O ,/O andat/O thetie/O each/O |/O -/O d/O bmg/O Irt/O gnatur/O dt-t/O ./O 
duly/O wcn/O ./O 
dopot/O ./O 
ndno/O ./O 
./O 
as/O herematterset/O tot/O th/O andregterd/O electorol/O the/O abovenamedCounty/O or/O Ct/O and/O Countyloandof/O theSlate/O ol/O California/LOCATION I/O am/O the/O personwho/O sohciledthe/O ignalures/O iotat/O going/O Petiton/LOCATION a/O ithe/O signaturesto/O theattach/O .../O inmy/O seton/O weremade/O aqid/O ador/O presence/O andupon/O the/O date/O sonersigned/O his/O nameto/O saidPetiton/O he/O alsoaftix/O theretohis/O redence/O as/O above/O stated/O ,/O and/O the/O dateof/O said/O sign/O ,/O and/O said/O agnatureswere/O cited/O by/O mewithhte/O abovenamed/O County/LOCATION -LRB-/O or/O City/LOCATION nd/LOCATION County/LOCATION afH/O L/O nh/O end/O to/O the/O beht/O of/O my/O knowledgeand/O belief.each/O to/O Ihe/O ad/O section/O i/O the/O genuine/O ignaure/O of/O the/O /O personwhosenameit/O purportto/O he/O ./O 
signature/O SohoooAm/O d/O andswornto/O beforemethin/O \//O .../O Notry/O Ptublic/O in/O andr/O 1/O ./O 
</O 4/O day/O of/O -/O ./O 
-/O ./O 
./O 
77436-56/O --/O Pt/O ./O 
7-2/O ./O 
6/O \//O Y/O ./O 
A/O '/O 6/O ^/O -/O nt/O '/O -/O G./O th/O ./O 
Coty/O or/O ty/O Cr4/O \//O of/O ./O 
oCos/O ./O 
</O 4Cooty/O -RRB-/O City/O d/O Sta/O ./O 
of/O CtIlool/O ./O 
./O 
Sa/O MoCommion/O ./O 
Epire/PERSON MarchtO/PERSON ,/O I/O n/O w/O ./O 
./O 
Lc/O -/O 3668/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O Do/O L./O Do/O I/O understand/O by/O that/O ,/O in/O your/O judgment/O ,/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member/O and/O for/O which/O you/O were/O circulating/O the/O petition/O to/O qualify/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O therefore/O considering/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O front/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Did/O it/O go/O to/O that/O extent/O in/O your/O judgment/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O why/O you/O were/O doing/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
In/O actuality/O that/O is/O what/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
In/O order/O to/O clarify/O the/O record/O ,/O and/O probably/O give/O you/O an/O opportunity/O to/O explain/O your/O testimony/O in/O that/O respect/O :/O Do/O you/O mean/O to/O infer/O that/O all/O people/O who/O signed/O or/O whose/O signatures/O were/O secured/O on/O the/O petition/O to/O place/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O the/O ballot/O as/O a/O legal/O party/O ,/O were/O Communists/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
By/O no/O means/O ,/O by/O no/O means/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION did/O you/O discover/O that/O the/O two/O persons/O ,/O whose/O names/O you/O first/O gave/O us/O ,/O were/O members/O of/O the/O same/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O their/O names/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON and/O Sam/PERSON Albert/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O been/O asked/O to/O list/O as/O many/O of/O the/O members/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O you/O could/O recall/O ./O 
Have/O you/O done/O that/O ?/O 
Mr/O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O given/O us/O the/O names/O of/O those/O two/O persons/O -/O Roth/PERSON and/O Albert-and/O the/O names/O of/O a/O number/O of/O persons/O in/O whose/O homes/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION met/O ./O 
Now/O will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O names/O ,/O please/O ,/O of/O all/O of/O the/O other/O persons/O that/O you/O can/O recall/O who/O were/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O members/O of/O that/O same/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
Joe/PERSON Eger/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Due/O to/O the/O difficulty/O of/O hearing/O ,/O I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O to/O spell/O that/O last/O name/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O hear/O it/O pronounced/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Eger/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O E-g-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O the/O name/O should/O be/O spelled/O against/O any/O possible/O error/O in/O identification/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
And/O you/O could/O hear/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Witness/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Spell/O the/O names/O in/O all/O instances/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVANNER/PERSON ./O 
Give/O us/O the/O name/O again/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Joe/PERSON Eger/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Spell/O the/O name/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O G-o-t-t-l-i-e-b/O ./O 
Some/O of/O these/O spellings/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O know/O the/O names/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O the/O spelling/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O as/O to/O your/O knowledge/O of/O an/O individual/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O although/O you/O may/O not/O have/O the/O precise/O spelling/O of/O the/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3669/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O does/O the/O staff/O investigation/O reveal/O the/O correct/O spelling/O of/O the/O names/O of/O the/O persons/O the/O witness/O is/O identifying/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O does/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O suggest/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O that/O you/O request/O the/O spelling/O of/O the/O name/O if/O there/O is/O any/O question/O about/O it/O ,/O and/O also/O that/O you/O identify/O the/O person/O as/O carefully/O as/O possible/O so/O that/O the/O person/O named/O will/O not/O be/O confused/O with/O some/O other/O person/O who/O might/O have/O the/O same/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O ask/O you/O again/O ,/O Were/O all/O of/O these/O individuals/O whose/O names/O you/O are/O now/O giving/O us/O musicians/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOV/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O that/O would/O identify/O them/O by/O occupation/O ./O 
If/O there/O is/O any/O other/O identifying/O information/O you/O can/O furnish/O regarding/O the/O individual/O ,/O I/O wish/O you/O would/O do/O so/O as/O you/O give/O the/O name/O ./O 
According/O to/O the/O committee/O 's/O investigation/O ,/O the/O spelling/O of/O Gottlieb/PERSON that/O you/O gave/O is/O the/O correct/O spelling/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Morris/PERSON Browda/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O is/O B-r-o-w-d-a/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENER/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O name/O is/O what/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Morris/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O Morris/PERSON ?/O 
MI/O ./O 
W.DDILOVE/O ./O 
M-o-r-r-i-s/O ./O 
Herb/PERSON Offener/PERSON ,/O O-f-f-n-e-r/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Wayne/PERSON Ronka/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O it/O R-o-n-k-a/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O first/O name/O ./O 
Wayne/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
W-a-y-n-e/O ./O 
Milt/PERSON Kestenbaum/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O K-e-s-t-e-n-b-a-u-m/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
TWhat/O is/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Milt/PERSON ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Milt/PERSON is/O an/O abbreviation/O for/O Milton/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Rubin/PERSON Decker/PERSON ,/O D-e-c-k-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O spelling/O of/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
R-u-b-i-n/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Herb/PERSON Lessner/PERSON ./O 
Herbert/PERSON ,/O I/O guess/O ./O 
L-e-s-s-n-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Herb/PERSON ./O 
George/PERSON Kast/PERSON ,/O K-a-s-t/O ./O 
That/O is/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O musician/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
P-o-w-e-1-1/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O our/O investigation/O discloses/O that/O there/O are/O 2/O musicians/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON ,/O 1/O living/O in/O Oregon/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O other/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Which/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON is/O it/O to/O whom/O you/O refer/O ?/O 
Mr./O WVADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O probably/O the/O one/O that/O lives/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION at/O the/O moment/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O know/O ,/O he/O has/O not/O identified/O either/O one/O of/O these/O persons/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
3670/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
All/O of/O these/O persons/O were/O members/O ./O 
He/O is/O now/O identifying/O persons/O who/O were/O known/O to/O him/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O his/O professional/O group/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O for/O clarity/O of/O the/O record/O ,/O we/O should/O state/O at/O this/O time/O that/O as/O far/O as/O the/O committee/O knows/O ,/O the/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON in/O Oregon/LOCATION is/O not/O the/O one/O who/O is/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O the/O committee/O has/O no/O knowledge/O of/O the/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON in/O Oregon/LOCATION as/O having/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O to/O what/O period/O of/O time/O you/O are/O referring/O when/O you/O say/O that/O some/O person/O is/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O referring/O to/O nothing/O later/O than/O the/O first/O or/O early/O part/O of/O 1949/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O no/O knowledge/O past/O that/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O since/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Since/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDLOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O identifying/O those/O persons/O as/O of/O that/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
As/O of/O that/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O give/O us/O specific/O information/O as/O to/O why/O you/O know/O they/O were/O at/O that/O time/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O meetings/O with/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O give/O more/O specific/O information/O as/O to/O what/O the/O meetings/O were/O ?/O 
Were/O they/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O they/O closed/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Confined/O strictly/O to/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Seymour/PERSON Sheklow/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O spelling/O of/O that/O name/O is/O S-e-y-m-o-u-r/O ./O 
The/O last/O name/O is/O S-h-e-k-l-o-w/O ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Sidney/PERSON Greene/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O spelling/O is/O S-i-d-n-e-y/O G-r-e-e-n-e/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Sidney/PERSON Greene/PERSON known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O a/O member/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O attended/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O with/O all/O of/O these/O individuals/O whose/O names/O you/O have/O given/O us/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O was/O the/O practice/O in/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O which/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3671/O you/O were/O affiliated/O ,/O to/O study/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION doctrine/O and/O philosophy/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O literature/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O was/O that/O carried/O out/O ?/O 
How/O was/O that/O instruction/O given/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOE/PERSON ./O 
From/O week/O to/O week/O a/O new/O topic/O would/O be/O chosen/O ,/O and/O the/O discussion/O would/O be/O held/O the/O following/O week/O of/O the/O material/O -/O covered/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O membership/O furnished/O with/O books/O and/O other/O materials/O on/O the/O subjects/O which/O you/O discussed/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O available/O ./O 
We/O paid/O for/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O those/O books/O made/O available/O to/O the/O membership/O at/O the/O meetings/O which/O you/O have/O described/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O proportion/O of/O the/O meetings/O was/O usually/O devoted/O to/O the/O study/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION doctrine/O and/O principles/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Anywhere/O from/O one-half/O to/O one-third/O possibly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O fairly/O constant/O during/O your/O entire/O membership/O from/O 1947/O to/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADLILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O why/O the/O membership/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O composed/O solely/O of/O musicians/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILVE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O it/O was/O probably/O set/O up/O on/O a/O trade/O basis/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O suppose/O it/O was/O required/O that/O all/O of/O these/O musicians/O be/O members/O of/O a/O union/O in/O order/O to/O work/O in/O their/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Basically/O ,/O yes/O ;/O to/O be/O gainfully/O employed/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O period/O of/O your/O membership/O in/O 1947/O and/O 1948/O ,/O did/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O endeavor/O to/O interest/O itself/O in/O the/O election/O of/O any/O particular/O slate/O in/O your/O union/O ,/O to/O act/O as/O a/O unit/O in/O doing/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
We/O sponsored/O a/O slate/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O in/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O ``/O we/O sponsored/O a/O slate/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O say/O ``/O we/O ''/O to/O whom/O are/O you/O referring/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDmOVE/O ./O 
The/O Communist/O Party/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O your/O opinion/O ,/O succeed/O in/O any/O substantial/O way/O to/O control/O any/O of/O the/O offices/O of/O your/O local/O union/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O slate/O you/O sponsored/O comprised/O of/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
It/O was/O people/O who/O they/O thought/O could/O ,/O by/O virtue/O of/O their/O popularity/O ,/O win/O the/O election/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O n't/O necessarily/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O an/O antiadministration/O slate/O rather/O than/O proanything/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O get/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
You/O understand/O what/O I/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Antiadministration/O ?/O 
Anti/O union/O administration/O slate/O ?/O 
3672/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
And/O they/O supported/O the/O antiadministration/O faction/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
The/O antiadministration/O faction/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
So/O ,/O regardless/O in/O what/O activities/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION engaged/O ,/O it/O was/O not/O successful/O within/O your/O local/O union/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILoVE/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O from/O your/O testimony/O the/O fact/O to/O be/O then/O ,/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O ,/O the/O members/O of/O which/O were/O also/O members/O of/O the/O musicians/O '/O union/O ,/O put/O up/O a/O slate/O which/O was/O antiunion/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O antiunion/O ;/O no/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O it/O was/O in/O opposition/O to/O the/O incumbents/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O successful/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O caucus/O on/O the/O slate/O as/O to/O who/O they/O would/O put/O up/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILovE/O ./O 
Not/O as/O a/O cell/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O endeavor/O on/O the/O part/O of/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O ,/O as/O a/O cell/O ,/O to/O shape/O the/O policies/O of/O the/O union/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O probably/O had/O quite/O a/O bit/O to/O do/O with/O the/O platform/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
It/O probably/O had/O a/O good/O deal/O to/O do/O with/O the/O platform/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
To/O understand/O my/O question/O ,/O let/O me/O ask/O it/O this/O way/O :/O Did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member/O ,/O within/O the/O union/O ,/O undertake/O to/O act/O in/O concert/O and/O influence/O the/O platform/O of/O the/O union/O as/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O acting/O as/O a/O unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O per/O se/O ./O 
I/O mean/O the/O whole/O opposition/O ,/O again/O as/O in/O the/O case/O of/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O not/O all/O Communist/O ./O 
It/O was/O more/O or/O less/O guided/O by/O them/O ,/O or/O spearheaded/O ,/O if/O you/O wish/O ,/O but/O not/O in/O toto/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O quite/O hear/O ./O 
More/O or/O less/O guided/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O policy/O ./O 
Is/O that/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
In/O cooperation/O with/O the/O other/O people/O in/O the/O same/O slate/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O understood/O you/O to/O say/O that/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O end/O of/O 1948/O or/O very/O early/O in/O 1949/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O reason/O for/O leaving/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O several/O reasons/O ./O 
The/O failure/O of/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1948/O made/O me/O see/O ,/O or/O led/O me/O to/O believe/O ,/O that/O the/O majority/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O had/O rejected/O it/O and/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O it/O was/O not/O the/O right/O thing/O to/O do/O ./O 
And/O also/O I/O was/O raised/O in/O a/O very/O religious/O household/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O voice/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O hard/O to/O throw/O off/O a/O religious/O background/O and/O ,/O sooner/O or/O later/O ,/O it/O crops/O up/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O vernacular/O ,/O and/O you/O have/O to/O live/O with/O it/O ./O 
The/O main/O reason/O :/O my/O main/O disagreement/O with/O the/O party/O was/O objectingMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
The/O reporter/O is/O having/O difficulty/O hearing/O you/O ./O 
Would/O you/O repeat/O that/O ,/O please/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3673/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O can/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O speaking/O of/O your/O religious/O background/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
The/O Communist/O Party/O chooses/O to/O ignore/O God/O in/O the/O scheme/O of/O things/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O say/O they/O deny/O God/O ,/O but/O they/O choose/O to/O ignore/O it/O in/O the/O scheme/O of/O human/O events/O ./O 
And/O that/O was/O a/O basic/O disagreement/O as/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O ./O 
And/O ,/O thirdly/O ,/O it/O is/O n't/O pleasant/O to/O work/O ,/O what/O you/O might/O say/O ,/O underground/O for/O any/O length/O of/O time/O ./O 
I/O mean/O I/O like/O to/O be/O able/O to/O look/O people/O in/O the/O eye/O once/O in/O a/O while/O ./O 
And/O I/O was/O tired/O of/O being/O a/O fugitive/O from/O the/O human/O race/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O you/O rebelled/O at/O the/O secret/O methods/O used/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O one/O point/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
It/O finally/O got/O to/O be/O quite/O a/O task/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O that/O you/O ,/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O in/O 1947,1948/O and/O 1949-I/O wish/O to/O specify/O not/O as/O a/O union/O man-were/O finding/O yourself/O obligated/O to/O work/O in/O secret/O and/O underground/O ?/O 
You/O just/O used/O the/O word/O ``/O underground/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O and/O is/O very/O ,/O very/O unpopular/O ,/O and/O you/O just-I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O else/O to/O put/O it/O ,/O frankly/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O ca/O n't/O describe/O it/O any/O other/O way/O than/O ``/O underground/O ,/O ''/O if/O that/O is/O what/O you/O were/O required/O to/O do/O ./O 
That/O is/O where/O rats/O and/O mice/O hide/O generally/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O your/O reaction/O to/O those/O matters/O ,/O what/O did/O you/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O dropped/O out/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O give/O any/O notice/O of/O any/O kind/O of/O your/O contemplated/O action/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O just/O quit/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILovE/O ./O 
I/O just/O dropped/O out/O ;/O quit/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O effort/O made/O at/O any/O later/O period/O to/O get/O you/O back/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Nothing/O very/O serious/O ;/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O severed/O all/O connections/O with/O the/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O the/O action/O that/O you/O took/O in/O 1949/O final/O and/O complete/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O knowledge/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O on/O the/O part/O of/O any/O of/O the/O members/O of/O your/O group/O since/O the/O time/O you/O withdrew/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
None/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O any/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O inquire/O on/O a/O few/O points/O ?/O 
I/O think/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O my/O recollection/O is/O that/O in/O connection/O with/O the/O circulation/O of/O petitions/O ,/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O others/O possibly/O ,/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION to/O qualify/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O legal/O party/O in/O my/O State/O ,/O there/O were/O some/O 11,000/O signatures/O on/O the/O IPP/ORGANIZATION petitions/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
Did/O you/O as/O one/O of/O the/O circulators/O ,/O as/O a/O Communist/O ,/O tell/O any/O of/O the/O people/O who/O signed/O the/O petition/O for/O you/O that/O you/O were/O a/O Communist/O and/O that/O your/O Comminist/O cell/O was/O circulating/O this/O petition/O ?/O 
3674/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Why/O not/O ?/O 
Why/O did/O n't/O you/O reveal/O that/O it/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O was/O circulating/O the/O IPP/ORGANIZATION petition/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O n't/O the/O way/O it/O worked/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O we/O were/O doing/O it/O apparently/O as/O private/O citizens/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O doing/O it/O secretly/O and/O as/O an/O underground/O operation/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
In/O essence/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYE/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O record/O will/O show/O that/O in/O former/O hearings/O in/O California/LOCATION we/O have/O an/O abundance/O of/O testimony/O under/O oath/O by/O former/O leaders/O in/O the/O IPP/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION who/O were/O also/O top/O leaders/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O California/LOCATION not/O only/O circulated/O these/O petitions/O ,/O but/O they/O dictated/O the/O leadership/O of/O the/O IPP/ORGANIZATION in/O many/O ,/O many/O cases/O in/O California/LOCATION during/O that/O campaign/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O the/O record/O will/O reveal/O that/O fact/O in/O our/O previous/O hearings/O ./O 
I/O wish/O to/O thank/O the/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O have/O here/O a/O communication/O allegedly/O signed/O by/O some/O 22/O people/O who/O indicate/O that/O they/O are/O members/O of/O Local/O 47/O ,/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Musicians/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O the/O witness/O if/O he/O has/O seen/O this/O letter/O ./O 
It/O constitutes/O a/O protest/O against/O the/O hearings/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Document/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O saw/O a/O copy/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O read/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O very/O difficult/O for/O me/O to/O believe/O that/O this/O letter/O ,/O signed/O by/O 22/O members/O ,/O constitutes/O an/O expression/O of/O what/O I/O understand/O is/O a/O union/O membership/O of/O 15,000/O musicians/O in/O this/O area/O ./O 
I/O should/O like/O to/O ask/O the/O witness/O after/O he/O reads/O the/O letter/O if/O he/O feels/O ,/O from/O his/O own/O association/O within/O the/O musician/O 's/O organization/O ,/O that/O the/O letter/O constitutes/O a/O majority/O opinion/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Since/O you/O received/O your/O subpena/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O have/O you/O been/O approached/O by/O any/O person/O ,/O other/O than/O investigators/O for/O this/O committee/O ,/O relative/O to/O your/O appearance/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Waddilove/PERSON ,/O I/O have/O 1/O or/O 2/O questions/O to/O ask/O you/O ./O 
First/O ,/O as/O to/O the/O name/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O that/O you/O belonged/O to/O :/O What/O was/O its/O name/O ,/O if/O it/O had/O a/O name/O or/O designation/O as/O a/O group/O ?/O 
You/O have/O referred/O to/O it/O as/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O ,/O and/O I/O assume/O that/O it/O had/O some/O identification/O other/O than/O just/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O called/O the/O Steinmetz/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O ?/O 
Mr./O TADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Steinmetz/PERSON ,/O as/O I/O recall/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
And/O ,/O also/O ,/O according/O to/O your/O information-and/O I/O believe/O you/O referred/O to/O it/O as/O hearsay/O information-that/O the/O total/O membership/O totaled/O approximately/O 70/O or/O 75/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3675/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O heard/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
You/O understood/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O that/O number/O ,/O how/O many/O have/O you/O identified/O during/O your/O testimony/O as/O having/O been/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Roughly/O 20/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O named/O 20/O ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O recall/O your/O testimony/O that/O Mrs./O Esther/PERSON Roth/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Was/O she/O a/O musician/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
And/O also/O a/O registrar/O ,/O or/O deputy/O registrar/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVELNER/PERSON ./O 
Deputy/O registrar/O of/O voters/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O do/O you/O base/O your/O opinion/O about/O her/O being/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O W/O ~/O ADDILOVE/O ./O 
She/O attended/O meetings/O of/O our/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Participated/O in/O Communist/O Party/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O VWADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O referred/O to/O by/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O closed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O understand/O your/O testimony/O no/O other/O person/O could/O attend/O those/O meetings/O ,/O unless/O he/O was/O a/O bona/O fide/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O stated/O by/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O anyone/O can/O become/O a/O deputy/O registrar/O ./O 
It/O has/O no/O official/O significance/O other/O than/O that/O every/O citizen/O has/O authority/O to/O take/O a/O form/O and/O have/O someone/O else/O sign/O it/O and/O refer/O to/O themselves/O as/O being/O a/O deputy/O registrar/O ./O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Right/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O Mrs./O Roth/PERSON was/O a/O musician/O ,/O instead/O of/O a/O public/O official/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O WADDILOVE/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O understand/O ./O 
On/O behalf/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O Mr./O Waddilove/PERSON ,/O we/O wish/O to/O express/O our/O gratitude/O and/O appreciation/O for/O your/O sincere/O and/O honest/O cooperation/O with/O this/O committee/O in/O giving/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O as/O a/O witness/O ,/O and/O you/O may/O claim/O your/O witness/O fees/O from/O the/O deputy/O clerk/O who/O sits/O just/O behind/O you/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 5/O minutes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O a/O short/O recess/O was/O taken/O ,/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Scherer/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O At/O the/O expiration/O of/O the/O recess/O the/O committee/O was/O reconvened/O ,/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O and/O Scherer/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O hearing/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
All/O conversation/O will/O cease/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O with/O another/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVNNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ,/O please/O come/O forward/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
My/O attorney/O is/O not/O with/O me/O ./O 
I/O am/O waiting/O for/O my/O attorney/O ./O 
3676/O COMAMTOIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O will/O take/O the/O witness/O stand/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Are/O you/O Mrs./O Fidith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O testimony/O which/O you/O are/O about/O to/O give/O before/O the/O committee/O will/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O ,/O God/O Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O photographers/O will/O please/O be/O seated/O ./O 
You/O may/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O EDITH/O RAPPORT/O -LRB-/O MRS./O GEORGE/O RAPPORT/O -RRB-/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O DANIEL/PERSON G./PERSON MARSHALL/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O will/O have/O to/O wait/O until/O my/O attorney/O is/O seated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O attorney/O is/O now/O seated/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O your/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O your/O last/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
How/O do/O you/O have/O it/O spelled/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O waste/O of/O time/O and/O duplication/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O will/O spell/O it-R-a-p-p-o-r-t/O ./O 
Mr./O MARSHALL/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O address/O you/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O inquire/O ,/O is/O any/O recording/O being/O made/O of/O these/O proceedings/O other/O than/O the/O stenographic/O reporting/O of/O the/O hearing/O ?/O 
Mr./O '/O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O no/O knowledge/O of/O any/O recordings/O being/O made/O of/O the/O proceedings/O ./O 
Mr./O MARSHALL/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O no/O tape/O recording/O is/O being/O made/O of/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Please/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O who/O just/O addressed/O the/O chairman/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O MARSHALL/PERSON ./O 
Daniel/PERSON G./PERSON Marshall/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O appearing/O with/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O MARSHALL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mrs./O Rapport/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O December/O 18/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O rather/O not/O tell/O my/O age/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O directed/O to/O give/O the/O date/O of/O her/O birth/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
In/O reading/O some/O of/O the/O other/O testimony/O I/O notice/O that/O you/O gave/O the/O actresses/O or/O people/O in/O the/O acting/O profession/O preferences/O as/O to/O answering/O their/O age/O or/O telling/O their/O age/O ,/O and/O I/O ,/O being/O a/O professional/O person/O ,/O would/O rather/O not/O disclose/O my/O age/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Chair/O will/O speak/O for/O the/O committee/O ,/O in/O stating/O that/O the/O purpose/O of/O directing/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O is/O to/O inform/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS-ANGELES/O ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3677/O you/O of/O the/O dangers/O which/O you/O might/O be/O confronted/O with/O in/O connection/O with/O being/O in/O contempt/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O ,/O in/O so/O advising/O you/O and/O directing/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O in/O the/O nature/O of/O or/O spirit/O of/O a/O threat/O ,/O but/O for/O your/O own/O interest/O in/O order/O to/O protect/O you/O from/O such/O future/O proceedings/O in/O the/O nature/O of/O contempt/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O the/O committee/O directs/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ,/O December/O 18/O ,/O 1912/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Minsk/LOCATION ,/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O come/O to/O this/O country/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O quite/O remember/O the/O date/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O say/O approximately/O 1923/O or/O 1924/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O naturalized/O American/O citizen/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O citizen/O by/O derivation/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Through/O your/O mother/O or/O your/O father/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Through/O my/O father/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O father/O 's/O name/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O to/O drag/O my/O father/O into/O this/O ,/O too/O ?/O 
You/O find/O that/O it/O is/O necessary/O to/O drag/O my/O entire/O family/O into/O this/O hearing/O Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O ./O 
I/O can/O see/O in/O no/O manner/O how/O that/O would/O be/O a/O reflection/O upon/O your/O father/O for/O you/O to/O admit/O that/O you/O are/O his/O daughter/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O think/O anyone/O who/O is/O mentioned/O by/O the/O committee/O is/O enough/O to/O drag/O him/O through/O the/O mud/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O proper/O identification/O ,/O I/O ask/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O am/O identified/O sufficiently/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O directed/O -/O Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O assure/O you/O that/O I/O am/O the/O person/O who/O has/O been/O subpenaed/O ./O 
My/O name/O is/O Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ./O 
I/O received/O your/O subpena/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O we/O have/O a/O right/O to/O determine/O whether/O this/O person/O is/O a/O naturalized/O citizen/O by/O derivation/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O ,/O therefore/O ,/O as/O to/O her/O father/O 's/O name/O ,/O is/O perfectly/O proper/O to/O determine/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O citizenship/O as/O she/O indicated/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O reasons/O stated/O by/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON and/O by/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O you/O are/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
My/O father/O 's/O name/O is/O Max/PERSON Rubin/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O was/O he/O naturalized/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O know/O the/O exact/O date/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O in/O approximately/O 1927/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O living/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
3678/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O come/O to/O California/LOCATION to/O reside/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O California/LOCATION twice/O ./O 
Which/O time/O are/O you/O referring/O to/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O us/O begin/O with/O the/O first/O time/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
The/O first/O time/O ,/O approximately/O 1930/O or/O 1929/O ./O 
tell/O you/O the/O exact/O year/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O live/O in/O California/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
You/O are/O making/O me/O go/O back/O an/O awfully/O long/O time/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O have/O that/O recollection/O ./O 
I/O believe/O just/O a/O couple/O of/O years/O ,/O approximately/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O married/O at/O the/O time/O you/O came/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O 1929/O or/O 1930/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O married/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O husband/O 's/O name/O is/O George/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O her/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Are/O you/O familiar/O with/O the/O rules/O of/O procedure/O that/O you/O sent/O me/O ?/O 
I/O think/O this/O was/O sent/O to/O me/O by/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON 's/O office/O ,/O representing/O this/O committee/O ./O 
I/O was/O asked/O a/O question/O ./O 
Will/O you/O permit/O me/O to/O finish/O this/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCmERER/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O it/O is/O obvious/O that/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON is/O not/O asking/O her/O to/O testify/O against/O her/O husband/O ./O 
He/O wants/O to/O know/O the/O identity/O of/O her/O husband/O ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Obviously/O you/O ca/O n't/O seem/O to/O get/O together/O on/O this/O ,/O can/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O trying/O to/O be/O very/O respectful/O ./O 
We/O will/O be/O respectful/O to/O you/O as/O a/O witness/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O kindly/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O merely/O asked/O a/O question/O ./O 
Because/O of/O the/O sound/O effects/O I/O could/O n't/O understand/O what/O it/O was/O ./O 
Please/O repeat/O the/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O asked/O her/O if/O her/O husband/O 's/O name/O was/O George/PERSON Rapport/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
A/O perfectly/O proper/O question/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O identification/O ./O 
Certainly/O it/O is/O not/O violating/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
May/O I/O read/O this/O little/O Rules/O of/O Procedure/O ,/O this/O little/O booklet/O ,/O as/O to/O how/O a/O witness/O should/O behave/O ?/O 
I/O quote/O :/O The/O confidential/O relationship/O between/O husband/O and/O wife/O shall/O be/O respected/O ,/O and/O ,/O for/O reasons/O of/O public/O policy/O ,/O one/O spouse/O shall/O not/O be/O questioned/O concerning/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O other/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O nothing/O confidential/O about/O one/O 's/O marriage/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O she/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mrs./O RAPPORT/O ./O 
