INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 6/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-THIRD/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MARCH/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O ,/O AND/O JUNE/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activitie/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 31747/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1953/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O l/O N-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON YELDE/PERSON ./O 
Illinois/LOCATION ,/O Charmaon/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD-L/O ./O 
JACKSON/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O MIssopr/O CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION KIT/LOCATION CLARDY/LOCATION ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR/O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION ROBERT/PERSON L./PERSON KUNZG/PERSON ,/O Coasel/PERSON FRANK/PERSON S/PERSON TAVeNNrER/PERSON Jr./PERSON ,/O Counsel/O Lours/PERSON J./PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Chief/O Investigator/O THOMAS/O W/O BEALK/LOCATION ,/O Sr./O ,/O Chief/O Cle/O k/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O II/O CONTENTS/O March/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Larry/PERSON Parks/PERSON .../O .../O ./O 
----------------------/O ./O 
./O 
./O 
June/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Statement/O ofCharlotte/O Darling/O Adams/O _/O ----------------------------/O Roland/PERSON William/PERSON Kibbee/PERSON --------------------------------/O .../O Babbette/PERSON Lang/PERSON .../O .../O .../O ----------------------/O ./O 
LeeJ/O ./O 
Cobb/O ----------------------------/O ./O 
121/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O i/O STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O mnay/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 83D/O CONGRESS/O \*/O \*/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 3/O ,/O 1953/O \*/O \*/O ./O 
RULE/O X/O \*/O \*/O E/O STANDING/O COMMITTI/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIESOF/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 6/O WEDNESDAY/O ,/O MARCH/O 21/O ,/O 1951/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITrEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTTIITTES/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./ORGANIZATION C./ORGANIZATION EXECUTIVE/ORGANIZATION SESSION/ORGANIZATION 1/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O in/O executive/O session/O at/O 4/O p./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 226/O ,/O Old/O House/O Office/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O John/PERSON S./PERSON Wood/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ,/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON J./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Charles/PERSON E./PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O senior/O investigator/O ;/O William/PERSON H./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O assistant/O counsel/O ;/O and/O A./PERSON S./PERSON Poore/PERSON ,/O editor/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O LARRY/O PARKS/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O LOUIS/PERSON MANDEL/PERSON Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Parks/PERSON ,/O at/O the/O conclusion/O of/O the/O morning/O session/O ,/O the/O committee/O had/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O the/O unanimous/O expression/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O that/O we/O were/O going/O to/O seek/O your/O further/O cooperation/O in/O an/O executive/O session/O ,/O for/O further/O testimony/O that/O will/O not/O be/O publicized/O until/O such/O time/O ,/O if/O at/O all/O ,/O as/O the/O committee/O itself/O may/O deem/O expedient/O ./O 
It/O may/O never/O happen/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O only/O fair/O to/O say/O to/O you/O that/O it/O is/O in/O the/O discretion/O of/O the/O committee/O at/O any/O time/O to/O make/O public/O any/O information/O that/O you/O may/O see/O fit/O to/O give/O in/O this/O executive/O session/O ./O 
Until/O such/O time/O ,/O if/O it/O does/O happen/O ,/O it/O will/O be/O kept/O in/O the/O confidential/O files/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
With/O that/O statement/O ,/O counsel/O will/O now/O propound/O additional/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
So/O that/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON will/O be/O fully/O aware/O of/O where/O he/O is/O going/O ,/O is/O it/O the/O intention/O of/O the/O committee/O that/O unless/O he/O answers/O these/O questions/O in/O private/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O in/O executive/O session/O ,/O they/O intend/O to/O cite/O him/O for/O contempt/O of/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Thle/O committee/O makes/O no/O threats/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O n't/O approached/O it/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O threat/O ,/O just/O to/O clear/O his/O thinking/O so/O that/O he/O is/O fully/O informed/O in/O his/O own/O mind/O of/O the/O consequences/O of/O following/O that/O path/O ./O 
SThis/O testimony/O ,/O taken/O in/O executive/O session/O during/O the/O 82d/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O has/O been/O examined/O and/O released/O by/O the/O full/O committee/O ./O 
2299/O 2300/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Counselor/O ,/O you/O have/O asked/O a/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O will/O answer/O it/O as/O frankly/O as/O I/O can/O ./O 
The/O committee/O did/O not/O discuss/O that/O phase/O of/O it/O and/O has/O n't/O discussed/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O entirely/O possible/O ,/O if/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON placed/O himself/O in/O the/O position/O here/O of/O being/O in/O contempt/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O the/O committee/O may/O request/O a/O citation/O for/O that/O purpose/O ./O 
On/O the/O other/O hand/O ,/O it/O may/O not/O ./O 
I/O can/O not/O speak/O for/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Does/O that/O answer/O your/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O not/O quite/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O spend/O another/O minute/O on/O it/O ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O also/O realize/O the/O position/O of/O the/O committee/O not/O to/O commit/O themselves/O to/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON ,/O but/O im/O view/O of/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON '/O general/O attitude/O of/O being/O cooperative/O ,/O and/O everyone/O easily/O understands/O here/O what/O is/O motivating/O him-he/O feels/O so/O bad/O about/O what/O he/O has/O to/O do/O ,/O and/O if/O he/O thought/O in/O his/O own/O judgment/O there/O was/O any/O chance/O at/O all/O that/O you/O would/O elicit/O from/O him/O information/O that/O was/O important/O to/O you/O ,/O that/O he/O would/O very/O gladly/O give/O it/O to/O you/O voluntarily/O ./O 
It/O is/O only/O saving/O that/O little/O bit/O of/O something/O that/O you/O live/O with/O ./O 
You/O have/O to/O see/O and/O walk/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION with/O that/O ./O 
You/O have/O to/O meet/O your/O children/O and/O your/O wife/O with/O it/O and/O your/O friends/O ./O 
It/O is/O that/O little/O bit/O that/O you/O want/O to/O save/O ./O 
Although/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O ask/O the/O committee/O to/O commit/O itself/O ,/O in/O fairness/O to/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON ,/O he/O may/O have/O to/O sacrifice/O the/O arm/O with/O gangrene/O in/O order/O to/O save/O the/O body/O ./O 
Even/O though/O he/O does/O n't/O like/O it/O ,/O he/O will/O walk/O around/O the/O rest/O of/O his/O life/O without/O an/O arm/O ./O 
I/O realize/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O committee/O ,/O and/O our/O attitude/O has/O been/O one/O of/O cooperation/O ./O 
We/O want/O to/O go/O right/O through/O with/O that/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O going/O to/O be/O the/O penalty/O that/O he/O eventually/O will/O have/O to/O pay/O ,/O then/O I/O have/O to/O help/O him/O think/O a/O different/O way/O ./O 
I/O have/O to/O urge/O him/O a/O different/O way/O ./O 
His/O honest/O and/O sincere/O opinion/O is/O that/O what/O he/O is/O going/O to/O give/O you/O will/O only/O eat/O up/O his/O insides/O and/O you/O will/O get/O nothing/O ,/O no/O more/O than/O you/O have/O today/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O conviction/O of/O this/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Mr./O Attorney/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O has/O to/O be/O the/O judge/O of/O what/O information/O has/O pertinency/O and/O relevancy/O ./O 
It/O ca/O n't/O take/O the/O opinions/O of/O other/O people/O ./O 
I/O have/O tried/O to/O be/O frank/O about/O it/O ,/O and/O the/O committee/O is/O very/O anxious-I/O think/O you/O will/O agree-to/O be/O considerate/O of/O this/O man/O ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O no/O sense/O responsible/O for/O the/O position/O he/O finds/O himself/O in/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O responsible/O for/O the/O position/O we/O find/O ourselves/O in/O ./O 
We/O have/O a/O responsibility/O and/O duty/O that/O is/O on/O us/O as/O public/O officials/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O answer/O any/O further/O inquiries/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ./O 
I/O was/O wondering/O if/O I/O could/O get/O the/O opinion/O of/O the/O committee/O before/O ,/O because/O the/O direction/O will/O have/O to/O come/O to/O him/O ``/O If/O youl/O do/O n't/O answer/O ,/O then/O we/O will/O cite/O you/O for/O tempt/O ./O ''/O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O part/O of/O the/O law/O ,/O for/O the/O man/O to/O know/O conthe/O price/O ./O 
So/O it/O would/O have/O to/O come/O anyhow/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O law/O ./O 
I/O am/O urging/O it/O now/O so/O that/O I/O can/O sit/O down/O with/O him/O ./O 
I/O know/O how/O it/O is/O biting/O on/O the/O inside/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O put/O the/O committee/O in/O a/O position/O here/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O any/O of/O them/O want/O to/O be/O placed/O in/O the/O position/O ,/O of/O making/O any/O compromising/O statements/O about/O what/O they/O will/O do/O here/O in/O any/O given/O set/O of/O circumstances/O ./O 
I/O think/O they/O can/O cross/O that/O when/O they/O arrive/O at/O that/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O intend/O to/O argue/O with/O the/O committee/O any/O further/O ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O made/O my/O point/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2301/O Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Parks/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O an/O effort/O made/O to/O raise/O funds/O for/O the/O New/O Masses/O magazine/O ,/O which/O was/O in/O the/O form/O of/O a/O party/O held/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON on/O June/O 8/O ,/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O such/O party/O at/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON 's/O house/O ./O 
I/O was/O at/O his/O house/O I/O believe/O only/O once/O ,/O and/O as/O I/O remember/O it/O there/O were/O maybe/O 2/O or/O 3/O people/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O purely/O a/O social/O evening/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O to/O the/O very/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O of/O having/O attended/O such/O a/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O just/O learned/O there/O are/O two/O Frank/PERSON Tuttles/PERSON in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O that/O fact/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKs/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O only/O know/O one/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O a/O director/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O the/O one/O that/O I/O had/O reference/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O one/O that/O I/O am/O acquainted/O with/O ,/O was/O acquainted/O with/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O he/O is/O out/O there/O now/O at/O this/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O a/O Comnmumst/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O of/O a/O cultural/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O home/O of/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O to/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON 's/O house/O twice/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
One/O was/O on/O a/O matter/O of-I/O believe/O I/O read/O a/O script/O of/O his/O ./O 
The/O other/O time/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O was/O a/O party/O given/O for-as/O I/O recall/O ,/O it/O was/O given/O for/O the/O people/O who/O had/O come/O before/O your/O committee/O in/O 1947/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O going/O to/O a/O party/O for-what/O was/O it/O ?/O 
New/O Masses/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
This/O party/O that/O I/O am/O speaking/O of/O now/O did/O not/O necessarily/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O New/O Masses/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O different/O meeting/O that/O I/O am/O referring/O to/O now/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O alleged/O to/O have/O taken/O place/O on/O January/O 3/O ,/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O going/O there/O for/O a/O party/O at/O that/O time/O at/O all/O ./O 
I/O am/O being/O very/O honest/O when/O I/O say/O that/O ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O know/O where/O he/O lives/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O I/O have/O been/O there/O twice/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O or/O from/O information/O made/O available/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O Hugo/PERSON Butler/PERSON at/O all/O being/O a/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O attend/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O at/O which/O he/O was/O present/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
I/O never/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
This/O ,/O counsel/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O know/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O have/O ever/O heard/O that/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O that/O I/O have/O ever/O to/O the/O very/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ever/O attended/O any/O meeting/O of/O such/O a/O nature/O with/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O members/O of/O the/O cell/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O during/O the/O period/O from/O 1941/O on/O up/O to/O the/O time/O you/O disassociated/O yourself/O from/O the/O party/O about/O 1945/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Tlns/O is/O what/O I/O have/O been/O talking/O about/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O thing/O that/O I/O am/O no/O longer/O fighting/O for/O myself/O ,/O because/O I/O tell/O you/O frankly/O that/O 1/O am/O probably/O the/O most/O completely/O ruined/O man/O that/O you/O have/O ever/O seen/O ./O 
I/O am/O fighting/O for/O a/O principle/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O if/O Americanism/O is/O involved/O in/O this/O particular/O case/O ./O 
This/O is/O what/O I/O have/O been/O talking/O 31747-53-pt/O 6/O --/O 2/O 2302/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O about/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O it/O befits/O this/O committee/O to/O force/O me/O to/O do/O this/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O it/O befits/O this/O committee/O or/O its/O purposes/O to/O force/O me/O to/O do/O this/O ./O 
This/O is/O my/O honest/O feeling/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O this/O is/O fair/O play/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O it/O is/O in/O the/O spirit/O of/O real/O Americanism/O ,/O as/O we/O know/O it/O ./O 
These/O are/O not/O people/O that/O are/O a/O danger/O to/O this/O country/O ,/O gentlemen/O ,/O the/O people/O that/O I/O knew/O ./O 
These/O are/O people/O like/O myself/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O if/O the/O witness/O refuses/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O I/O see/O very/O little/O use/O in/O my/O asking/O him/O about/O other/O individuals/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O has/O got/O to/O make/O up/O his/O own/O mind/O as/O to/O whether/O he/O will/O or/O will/O not/O do/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O n't/O sufficient/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O this/O committee/O is/O concerned/O ,/O to/O say/O that/O in/O your/O opinion/O it/O is/O unfair/O or/O unAmerican/O in/O the/O proper/O administration/O of/O justice/O ./O 
The/O question/O is/O :/O Do/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O or/O will/O you/O answer/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
At/O this/O point/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O the/O chairman/O whether/O he/O is/O directing/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O has/O been/O asked/O ./O 
He/O must/O answer/O or/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O a/O little/O more/O is/O needed/O ./O 
He/O must/O be/O directed/O to/O answer/O ,/O and/O if/O he/O refuses/O to/O answer/O ,/O just/O merely/O asking/O him/O and/O not/O going/O beyond/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O under/O law/O is/O sufficient/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O has/O to/O be/O directed/O and/O told/O ``/O You/O have/O got/O to/O answer/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WOOD/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O any/O such/O rule/O ,/O but/O in/O order/O to/O avoid/O any/O controversy/O I/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O feel/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O doing/O a/O really/O dreadful/O thing/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O will/O look/O kindly/O on/O ./O 
This/O is/O my/O opinion/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O they/O will/O consider/O this/O as/O honest/O ,/O just/O ,/O and/O in/O the/O spirit/O of/O fair/O play/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O might/O I/O interpose/O at/O this/O point/O ?/O 
Mr./O Parks/PERSON ,/O we/O are/O ,/O each/O one/O of/O us/O ,/O individually/O responsible/O to/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O our/O concept/O of/O our/O responsibility/O or/O of/O the/O extent/O to/O which/O we/O must/O answer/O is/O a/O thing/O which/O we/O ourselves/O are/O fully/O conscious/O of/O ./O 
That/O determination/O must/O rest/O with/O the/O individual/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O and/O the/O committee/O as/O a/O whole/O ./O 
I/O for/O one/O resent/O having/O my/O duties/O pointed/O out/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O pointing/O the/O duty/O out/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O inference/O is/O that/O we/O are/O doing/O something/O which/O is/O un-American/O in/O nature/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O personal/O opinion/O of/O yours/O ,/O and/O I/O merely/O think/O that/O it/O should/O be/O in/O the/O record/O ./O 
We/O have/O accountability/O for/O which/O we/O must/O account/O and/O for/O which/O we/O must/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
The/O witness/O has/O said/O he/O does/O n't/O refuse/O to/O answer/O ,/O so/O I/O assume/O he/O is/O ready/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O may/O say/O this/O at/O this/O point/O :/O I/O think/O the/O committee/O and/O the/O individual/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O are/O all/O seeking/O within/O themselves/O to/O do/O the/O right/O thing/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O about/O that/O ./O 
I/O think/O in/O the/O same/O spirit/O ,/O no/O one/O can/O ,/O with/O the/O heritage/O that/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON has/O to/O uphold/O ,/O think/O that/O he/O is/O n't/O as/O loyal/O as/O any/O member/O of/O this/O committee/O ,/O individually/O or/O collectively/O ,/O and/O that/O he/O in/O his/O own/O mind/O has/O to/O do/O the/O right/O thing/O as/O we/O Americans/O in/O our/O elections/O do/O and/O choose/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O when/O the/O final/O gong/O goes/O down/O ,/O he/O intends/O as/O he/O indicated/O to/O respect/O the/O will/O of/O this/O committee/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O justly/O he/O reserves/O the/O right/O to/O talk/O to/O you/O gentlemen/O and/O possibly/O persuade/O you/O to/O think/O differently/O and/O express/O his/O opinions/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2303/O Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O took/O the/O view/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O perhaps/O there/O might/O be/O some/O merit/O in/O your/O contention/O if/O we/O were/O still/O in/O an/O open/O hearing/O ,/O but/O we/O are/O not/O ./O 
It/O is/O an/O executive/O session/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O want/O to/O thank/O the/O committee/O for/O this/O consideration/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O should/O have/O been/O done/O first/O before/O we/O started/O here/O ,/O but/O this/O session/O is/O a/O very/O private/O session/O or/O executive/O session/O ,/O which/O is/O very/O considerate/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O and/O the/O record/O should/O so/O state/O ./O 
May/O I/O have/O a/O minute/O to/O talk/O to/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
You/O may/O retire/O if/O you/O like/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O make/O this/O request/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
I/O want/O no/O promise/O from/O you/O ,/O but/O just/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O finding/O what/O is/O the/O sportsmanlike/O attitude/O ,/O that/O what/O lie/O gives/O you/O will/O not/O be/O used/O in/O that/O way/O if/O it/O can/O be/O helped/O ,/O without/O embarrassing/O these/O people/O in/O the/O same/O position/O he/O finds/O himself/O in/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O Woon/PERSON ./O 
Nobody/O on/O this/O committee/O has/O any/O desire/O to/O smear/O the/O name/O of/O anybody/O ./O 
That/O is/O n't/O of/O benefit/O to/O this/O committee/O in/O the/O discharge/O of/O its/O duties/O ./O 
It/O has/O been/O a/O uniform/O custom/O of/O the/O committee/O since/O I/O have/O been/O connected/O with/O it/O ./O 
I/O think/O all/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O who/O have/O viewed/O the/O work/O of/O the/O committee/O dispassionately/O and/O impartially/O will/O agree/O with/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O asked/O is/O because/O in/O the/O struggle/O that/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON is/O going/O through/O I/O think/O the/O internal/O struggle/O would/O go/O a/O little/O lighter/O ,/O having/O that/O statement/O from/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O will/O just/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ./O 
The/O question/O was/O :/O Who/O were/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cell/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O during/O the/O period/O from/O 1941/O until/O 1945/O ,/O or/O the/O period/O when/O you/O dissolved/O your/O membership/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O Morris/PERSON Carnovsky/PERSON ,/O Joe-Mr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O that/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O possibly/O spell/O it/O ./O 
Carnovsky/PERSON ,/O Joe/PERSON Bromberg/PERSON ,/O Sam/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ,/O Anne/PERSON Revere/PERSON ,/O Lee/PERSON Cobb/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Cobb/PERSON ./O 
Gale/PERSON Sondergaard/PERSON ,/O Dorothy/PERSON Tree/PERSON ./O 
Those/O are/O the/O principal/O names/O that/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O name/O of/O Dorothy/PERSON Tree/PERSON 's/O husband/O ?/O 
Was/O it/O not/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O Michael/PERSON Uris/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O any/O other/O cell/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O this/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O he/O was/O a/O writer/O ,/O was/O he/O not/O ,/O as/O distinguished/O from/O an/O actor/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O was/O a/O writer/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O persons/O whose/O names/O you/O have/O mentioned/O were/O all/O actors/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O that/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O others/O who/O were/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O that/O cell/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
That/O 's/O about/O all/O I/O recall/O right/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Howard/PERSON Da/PERSON Silva/PERSON a/O member/O ?/O 
2304/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O that/O I/O ever/O attended/O a/O meeting/O with/O Howard/PERSON Da/PERSON Silva/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Howard/PERSON Da/PERSON Silva/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O ability/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O attended/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O having/O attended/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O Roman/O Bohman/PERSON a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O now/O deceased/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
He/O is/O dead/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O James/PERSON Cagney/PERSON a/O member/O at/O any/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O or/O from/O information/O made/O available/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O hearing/O that/O he/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Sam/PERSON Jaffe/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Sam/PERSON Jaffe/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAXENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O lie/O a/O llember/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O or/O from/O information/O made/O available/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O knowledge/O that/O Sam/PERSON Jaffe/PERSON was/O ever/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON Garfield/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O at/O a/O meeting/O with/O Jolm/PERSON Garfield/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O whether/O John/PERSON Garfield/PERSON ever/O addressed/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O when/O you/O were/O present/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O such/O occasion/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Marc/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON ,/O was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O that/O cell/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O beheve/O he/O was/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O say/O with/O certainty/O ./O 
I/O believe/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O there/O in/O your/O memory/O that/O leads/O you/O to/O believe/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O told/O you/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O attend/O very/O many/O meetings/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O I/O recall/O that/O lie/O was/O there/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O swear/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O It/O during/O the/O early/O part/O or/O the/O latter/O part/O of/O your/O membership/O that/O you/O have/O that/O recollection/O of/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O thli/O I/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O suggest/O to/O counsel/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O general/O feeling/O of/O the/O witness-I/O do/O n't/O mean/O to/O rush/O you/O ,/O but/O this/O whole/O thing/O being/O so/O distasteful/O ,/O I/O wonder/O if/O we/O can/O proceed/O a/O little/O faster/O so/O he/O does/O n't/O suffer/O so/O much/O while/O this/O is/O going/O on/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O hmu/O to/O be/O accurate/O on/O it/O ./O 
I/O purposely/O do/O not/O want/O to/O rush/O him/O into/O answering/O about/O matters/O as/O important/O as/O these/O ./O 
Mr./O MANDEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O infer/O that/O and/O mean/O that/O ./O 
I/O am/O just/O trying/O to/O be/O considerate/O of/O the/O man/O 's/O feelings/O ,/O doing/O something/O thatMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O this/O morning/O about/O Karen/PERSON Morley/PERSON ./O 
Was/O she/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O she/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O she/O in/O this/O particular/O cell/O that/O you/O have/O described/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O she/O was/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2305/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON ,/O were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O know/O Richard/PERSON Collins/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Representative/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O asked/O you/O whether/O or/O not/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION from/O the/O eastern/O part/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION had/O appeared/O before/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O ./O 
You/O said/O you/O did/O not/O recall/O that/O any/O had/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
That/O 's/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O did/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION organizers/O from/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION appear/O before/O your/O committee/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Not/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O met/O any/O of/O them/O or/O ever/O saw/O any/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENKER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O lectures/O given/O at/O any/O time/O or/O study/O courses/O given/O in/O your/O cell/O in/O which/O persons/O outside/O of/O your/O cell/O took/O part/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O believe/O on/O one/O occasion/O ./O 
The/O only/O one/O that/O I/O recall/O at/O this/O time/O was/O a/O talk/O by/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON 's/O connection/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O really/O know/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O really/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEL/PERSON ./O 
Fred/PERSON Graff/PERSON ,/O was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
G-r-a-f-f/O ./O 
Fred/PERSON Graff/PERSON ,/O usually/O referred/O to/O as/O Freddie/PERSON Graff/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
The/O name/O does/O n't/O ring/O a/O bell/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Georgia/PERSON Backus/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O at/O a/O meeting/O with/O Georgia/ORGANIZATION Backus/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Meta/O Reis/PERSON Rosenberg/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O know/O the/O lady/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O at/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O your/O cell/O ,/O even/O if/O you/O were/O not/O in/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O 1/O have/O no/O information/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Philip/PERSON Loeb-L-o-e-b/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Who/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Philip/PERSON Loeb/PERSON I/O believe/O is/O the/O correct/O pronunciation/O ./O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O I/O know/O the/O gentleman/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Lloyd/PERSON Gough/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O believe/O he/O was/O a-I/O saw/O him/O at/O a/O couple/O of/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Sterling/O Hayden/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O at/O a/O meeting/O with/O Sterling/PERSON Hayden/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O T/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O being/O in/O a/O meeting/O with/O Will/PERSON Geer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Victor/PERSON Killian/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O recall/O that/O he/O attended/O at/O least/O one/O meeting/O where/O I/O was/O present/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Victor/PERSON Killian/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O am/O acquainted/O with/O the/O gentleman/O at/O all/O ./O 
2306/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Lionel/PERSON Stander/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O have/O met/O him/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Andy/PERSON Devine/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Andy/PERSON Devine/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Edward/PERSON G./PERSON Robinson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKs/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O -/O ttending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Edward/PERSON G./PERSON Robinson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mi/O ./O 
Chairman/O ,/O I/O think/O nearly/O all/O of/O these/O people/O have/O either/O been/O subpenaed/O or/O we/O have/O tried/O to/O find/O them/O ./O 
Some/O of/O them/O unquestionably/O are/O attempting/O to/O avoid/O service/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Hester/PERSON Sondergaard/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O meeting/O her/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O is/O Gale/PERSON Sondergaard/PERSON 's/O sister/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O she/O is/O married/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Francis/PERSON Edwards/PERSON Faragoh/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Vera/PERSON Caspary/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O that/O I/O know/O the/O woman/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Madelaine/PERSON Carroll/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKs/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Madelaine/PERSON Carroll/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O she/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O knowledge/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Gregory/PERSON Peck/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O remembrance/O of/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Gregory/PERSON Peck/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Humphrey/PERSON Bogart/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ever/O attending/O a/O meeting/O with/O Humphrey/PERSON Bogart/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O you/O could/O get/O some/O comfort/O out/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O people/O whose/O names/O have/O been/O mentioned/O have/O been/O subpoenaed/O ,/O so/O that/O if/O they/O ever/O do/O appear/O here/O it/O wo/O n't/O be/O as/O a/O result/O of/O anything/O that/O you/O have/O testified/O to/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Repiesentative/O Bernard/PERSON W/PERSON Kearney/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
It/O is/O no/O comfort/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O of/O any/O other/O person/O now/O whose/O name/O comes/O to/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O PARKS/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O anyone/O else/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O PoaTER/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O say/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O that/O Mr./O Parks/PERSON '/O testimony/O has/O certainly/O been/O refreshing/O in/O comparison/O with/O the/O other/O witnesses/O that/O we/O have/O had/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
I/O am/O bure/O you/O reflect/O the/O sentiments/O of/O the/O entire/O committee/O ./O 
We/O appreciate/O your/O cooperation/O ,/O and/O subject/O to/O call/O ,/O the/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Yon/O do/O not/O have/O to/O i/O main/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O MANuEL/PERSON ./O 
We/O canl/O go/O home/O now/O ?/O 
He/O call/O go/O back/O to/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2307/O Mr./O WooD/O ./O 
Any/O time/O you/O like/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 4/O :/O 40/O p./O m./O ,/O the/O hearing/O was/O recessed/O ,/O subject/O to/O call/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O By/O order/O of/O the/O committee/O the/O following/O letters/O are/O being/O included/O in/O the/O record/O at/O this/O point/O :-RRB-/O JULY/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O Hon./O IIAROLD/O VELDE/LOCATION ,/O Chatrmwn/O ,/O House/ORGANIZATION Commtitte/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-Amerwan/O Activities/O ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON DEAR/PERSON CHAIRMAN/O VELDi/O :/O I/O ha/O \/O e/O your/O letter/O of/O July/O 17/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O so/O good/O to/O hear/O from/O you/O ./O 
Pursuant/O to/O your/O suggestion/O ,/O I/O 'm/O enclosing/O a/O sworn/O copy/O of/O the/O letter/O I/O sent/O you/O and/O also/O authorize/O you/O and/O your/O committee/O to/O release/O the/O testimony/O I/O gave/O Sou/PERSON in/O executive/O session/O ./O 
Again/O let/O me/O take/O this/O opportunity/O to/O thank/O you/O for/O your/O consideration/O ,/O I/O remain/O Respectfully/O ,/O LARY/O PARKS/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Sworn/O letter/O mentioned/O by/O Larry/PERSON Parks/PERSON in/O his/O letter/O dated/O July/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O :-RRB-/O JLY/O 15/O ,/O 1953/O ./O 
Hon./O HAROLD/PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Chairman/O ,/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION L/ORGANIZATION n/O -/O ./O 
nwrican/O Actiirties/O ,/O sWashinUgto/O ,/O D./O C./O DI.A/O CHAIRMAN/O VELDE/O :/O After/O careful/O consideration/O ,/O I/O wish/O to/O file/O a/O clarifying/O statement/O of/O my/O point/O of/O view/O on/O the/O Communist/O problem/O with/O your/O comimittee/O ./O 
In/O re-reading/O my/O public/O testimony/O before/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O I/O am/O now/O convinced/O that/O it/O improperly/O reflects/O my/O true/O attitude/O toward/O the/O malignancy/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
If/O there/O is/O any/O way/O in/O which/O I/O can/O further/O aid/O in/O exposing/O the/O methods/O of/O entrapment/O and/O deceit/O through/O which/O Communist/O conspirators/O have/O gained/O the/O adherence/O of/O Ameican/O idealists/O and/O liberals/O ,/O I/O hope/O the/O committee/O will/O so/O advise/O me/O Perhaps/O some/O of/O the/O confusion/O now/O apparent/O to/O me/O in/O my/O testimony/O before/O ./O 
\/O ourcommittee/O can/O best/O be/O explained/O by/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O was/O the/O first/O cooperative/O witness/O from/O Hollywood/LOCATION to/O appear/O before/O your/O committee/O and/O at/O the/O time/O I/O was/O under/O really/O great/O strain/O and/O tension/O Upon/O reflection/O ,/O I/O see/O that/O I/O did/O not/O adequately/O express/O my/O true/O beliefs-beliefs/O which/O have/O even/O deepened/O and/O strengthened/O since/O my/O appearance/O Above/O all/O I/O wish/O to/O make/O it/O clear/O that/O I/O support/O completely/O the/O objectives/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
I/O believe/O fully/O that/O Communists/O nod/O Communist/O intrigues/O should/O be/O thoroughly/O exposed/O and/O isolated/O and/O thus/O rendered/O impotent/O ./O 
In/O the/O light/O of/O events/O which/O have/O transpired/O since/O I/O appeared/O as/O a/O witness/O before/O your/O committee/O ,/O it/O is/O crystal/O clear/O that/O no/O one/O w/O `/O io/O really/O bell/O vP/O 'n/O a/O progressive/O program/O for/O humanity/O can/O support/O any/O part/O of/O the/O Communist/O program/O ./O 
No/O true/O liber.il/O can/O doubt/O that/O Soviet/O communism/O constitutes/O as/O grave/O a/O threat/O to/O the/O rights/O of/O man/O today/O as/O once/O did/O Hitler/PERSON fascism/O ./O 
The/O most/O recent/O attack/O by/O the/O Soviet/O Army/O on/O unarmed/O German/O workers/O makes/O it/O crystal/O clear/O that/O fheir/O interest/O in/O labor/O is/O only/O to/O increase/O their/O power/O ./O 
Liberals/O must/O now/O embrace/O the/O cause/O of/O anticommunism/O with/O the/O same/O dedication/O and/O zeal/O as/O we/O once/O did/O that/O of/O antinnzism/O ./O 
The/O enemy/O is/O the/O same/O though/O the/O labels/O have/O changed/O ./O 
It/O is/O my/O conviction/O that/O to/O assist/O your/O committee/O in/O obtaining/O full/O information/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O activities/O is/O the/O duty/O of/O all/O who/O possess/O such/O evidence/O ./O 
Certainly/O ,/O if/O I/O were/O to/O testify/O today/O I/O would/O not/O testify/O as/O I/O did/O in/O 1951-that/O to/O aive/O such/O testimony/O is/O to/O ``/O wallow/O in/O the/O mud/O ./O ''/O 
but/O on/O the/O contrary/O I/O would/O recognize/O that/O such/O cooperationn/O would/O help/O further/O the/O cause/O in/O which/O many/O of/O us/O were/O sincerely/O interested/O when/O we/O were/O duped/O into/O joining/O and/O taking/O part/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
My/O statement/O about/O not/O wanting/O my/O sons/O to/O become/O ``/O cows/O in/O the/O pasture/O ''/O obviously/O needs/O clarification/O ./O 
The/O thought/O I/O really/O meant/O to/O convey/O was/O that/O my/O sons/O should/O not/O become/O indifferent/O to/O the/O plight/O of/O the/O people/O less/O fortunate/O than/O themselves/O ./O 
It/O is/O my/O conviction/O that/O through/O sympathetic/O understanding/O and/O aid/O to/O the/O repressed/O peoples/O we/O Americans/O can/O not/O only/O best/O represent/O Ameriian/O traditions/O ./O 
but/O also/O effectively/O aid/O in/O combating/O the/O false/O power/O of/O commu/O -/O 2308/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O nism/O ./O 
I/O want/O my/O sons/O to/O participate/O fully/O in/O the/O search/O for/O democratic/O answers/O to/O the/O continuing/O threat/O of/O totalitananism-Communist/O or/O Fascist/O ./O 
To/O that/O end/O ,/O I/O will/O do/O all/O within/O my/O power/O as/O one/O who/O once/O was/O duped/O but/O has/O since/O learned/O the/O hard/O way/O about/O the/O guileful/O traps/O which/O communism/O can/O set/O for/O an/O unwary/O idealist/O or/O liberal/O ./O 
I/O sincerely/O hope/O that/O the/O committee/O will/O publish/O the/O statement/O of/O my/O militant/O anti-Communist/O beliefs/O at/O the/O earliest/O possible/O date/O ./O 
Sincerely/O ,/O LARBYPARKS/O ./O 
VIOLA/PERSON W./PERSON JOHNSON/PERSON ,/O Notary/O Public/O in/O and/O for/O said/O County/LOCATION and/O State/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 6/O TUESDAY/O ,/O JUNE/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O AcTIvrrEs/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O STATEMENT/O '/O An/O executive/O statement/O ,/O given/O at/O 10/O a./O m./O ,/O June/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O at/O room/O 1107/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION Roosevelt/LOCATION Hotel/LOCATION ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
STATEMENT/O OF/O CHARLOTTE/O DARLING/O ADAMS/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O Charlotte/PERSON Darling/PERSON Adams/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O the/O same/O person/O who/O testified/O before/O the/O committee/O on/O March/O 26/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O desire/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O under/O subpena/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O giving/O this/O statement/O voluntarily/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O appearance/O before/O the/O committee/O on/O March/O 26/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O you/O testified/O you/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O approximately/O 1936/O and/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1946/O ./O 
In/O your/O appearance/O of/O March/O you/O were/O not/O asked/O in/O detail/O the/O identity/O of/O individuals/O you/O met/O as/O Communists/O ./O 
At/O this/O time/O we/O will/O begin/O in/O 1936/O ,/O and/O if/O possible/O ,/O in/O chronological/O order/O ,/O list/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION groups/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O and/O identify/O the/O individuals/O you/O met/O as/O Communists/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O to/O what/O group/O you/O were/O first/O assigned/O in/O 1936/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O assigned/O to/O a/O mixed/O group/O of/O studio/O workers/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O type/O of/O employment/O did/O the/O members/O of/O this/O group/O engage/O in/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O all/O sorts/O of/O people/O ./O 
Mostly/O craft/O workers/O and/O technicians/O and/O musicians/O ./O 
I/O really/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O complete/O setup/O of/O it/O because/O I/O attended/O only/O two/O meetings/O ./O 
2Released/O by/O the/O full/O committee/O 2309/O 31747-53-pt/O 6-3/O 2310/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O who/O recruited/O you/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Ed/PERSON Gilbert/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O the/O individuals/O of/O this/O first/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Not/O very/O many/O of/O them/O ./O 
There/O was/O Ed/PERSON Gilbert/PERSON ,/O of/O course/O ,/O and/O Frank/PERSON Drdrlik/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O Mr./O Gilbert/PERSON 's/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O set/O designer/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O Mr./O Drdrlik/PERSON 's/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O also/O a/O set/O designer/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Those/O are/O the/O two/O individuals/O you/O recall/O in/O this/O first/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O subsequently/O transferred/O to/O another/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
The/O three/O of/O us/O were/O transferred/O to/O another/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O type/O of/O group/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O a/O group/O of/O what/O were/O considered/O craft/O workers/O ,/O set/O designers/O ,/O and/O cartoonists/O ,/O supposed/O to/O be/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O there/O were/O some/O teamsters/O ./O 
This/O was/O supposed/O to/O be/O all/O of/O the/O back-lot/O workers/O who/O were/O not/O technicians/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O with/O the/O second/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
About/O 2/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O the/O Identity/O of/O the/O individuals/O that/O comprised/O this/O thing/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON Well/O ,/O there/O was/O Don/PERSON Gordon/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
A/O reader/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
And/O Drdrlik/PERSON and/O Gilbert/PERSON ,/O Henry/PERSON Peterson/PERSON ,/O a/O carpenter/O ./O 
Hjalman/PERSON Peterson/PERSON ;/O also/O a/O carpenter/O ./O 
Father/O and/O son/O ,/O and/O the/O father/O is/O Hjalmar/PERSON ./O 
Joe/PERSON Kromberger/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O an/O electrician/O ./O 
Sam/PERSON Cloner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O his/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
A/O laborer/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O approximately/O how/O many/O individuals/O comprised/O the/O second/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O about/O 6/O or/O 7/O ;/O it/O varied/O ./O 
One/O or/O two/O people/O would/O come/O in/O and/O maybe/O so/O many/O would/O leave/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O group/O or/O the/O main/O program/O set/O forth/O by/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O a/O trade/O union/O group/O ./O 
Most/O everyone/O in/O it/O was/O working/O in/O organization/O of/O unions/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Most/O individuals/O were/O members/O of/O the/O IATSE/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAiS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
These/O were/O people/O outside/O of/O the/O IATSE/O ./O 
Kromberger/PERSON ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O IBEW/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Cloner/O ,/O the/O laborers/O ,/O while/O they/O were/O in/O the/O IA/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O union/O did/O you/O belong/O to/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O ours/O was/O an/O independent/O guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O hold/O any/O office/O in/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O secretary/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
1936-37/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2311/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O president/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O presidential/O material/O ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O after/O you/O left/O the/O second/O group/O in/O 1939/O ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O third/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O third/O group/O was/O cartoonists/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Cartoonists/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O in/O approximately/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mrs./O AnDAs/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O very/O small/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O a/O member/O of/O this/O cartoonists/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Until/O I/O got/O married/O in/O 1941/O ;/O it/O was/O several/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O it/O up/O to/O 1941/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAu.s/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ,/O through/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O WIEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O individuals/O were/O members/O of/O the/O cartoonists/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Four/O or/O five/O or/O six/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O few/O wives/O ,/O Libby/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON ./O 
and/O Dave/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON ./O 
Mr/O ./O 
WiIEELER/O ./O 
Were/O all/O the/O members/O of/O this/O group/O also/O members/O of/O tile/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Cartoonists/ORGANIZATION '/O Guild/O Mrs./O ADANMS.Well/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Part/O of/O them/O were/O ./O 
The/O wives/O were/O also/O members/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O hold/O any/O position/O in/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAs/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O from/O time/O to/O time/O I/O did/O things/O ,/O like/O literature/O and/O membership/O and/O dues/O ,/O organization/O for/O a/O little/O while/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O n't/O very/O good/O at/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WHIFELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O group/O active/O in/O formulating/O the/O policy/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ,/O in/O a/O way/O ./O 
It/O was/O mainly/O in/O support/O of/O the/O organization/O ./O 
We/O influenced/O what/O policy/O we/O could/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
During/O this/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O did/O you/O ever/O have/O occasion/O to/O meet/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O his/O position/O at/O that/O time/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O he/O was/O called/O ,/O but/O I/O rather/O imagine/O he/O was/O the/O organizer/O for/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION studios/O ./O 
I/O would/O think/O that/O is/O what/O his/O title/O would/O be/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O he/O was/O organizer/O of/O the/O labor/O groups/O in/O the/O studios/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADArs/O ./O 
He/O also/O apparently/O ,/O although/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O this/O of/O my/O own/O knowledge/O he/O apparently/O also/O worked/O with/O the/O talent/O groups/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON Did/O he/O ever/O attend/O any/O meetings/O of/O your/O group/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartooni/O its/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
He/O met/O with/O a/O fraction/O ./O 
This/O was/O probably/O in/O about/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O else/O were/O members/O of/O this/O cartoonists/O '/O group/O ,/O other/O than/O Libby/PERSON and/O David/PERSON Hilbernan/PERSON ?/O 
2312/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
They/O did/O not/O ever/O meet/O with/O Kibre/PERSON while/O I/O was/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O were/O the/O other/O members/O of/O the/O cartoonists/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O a/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Phil/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O where/O he/O was/O employed/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O him/O very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Anyone/O else/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O any/O others/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O your/O testimony/O you/O mentioned/O you/O attended/O fraction/O meetings/O ,/O at/O which/O time/O you/O met/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O go/O into/O greater/O detail/O with/O reference/O to/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O seems/O that/O one/O incident/O I/O remember/O very/O well/O because/O it/O caused/O me/O a/O lot/O of/O trouble/O ,/O was/O that/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O had/O an/O attorney/O named/O Leonard/PERSON Janofsky/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O way/O did/O this/O Leonard/PERSON Janofsky/PERSON cause/O you/O trouble/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON opposed/O Leonard/PERSON Janofsky/PERSON as/O attorney/O for/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O because/O he/O did/O n't/O go/O along/O with/O the/O party/O line/O in/O relation/O to/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O policy/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O effort/O made/O by/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON to/O remove/O Janofsky/PERSON from/O his/O position/O with/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O Janofsky/PERSON took/O a/O position/O as/O attorney/O for/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Union/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Cartoonists/ORGANIZATION at/O Disney/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Kibre/PERSON was/O opposed/O to/O this/O union/O because/O it/O was/O considered/O an/O outlaw/O union/O and/O would/O n't/O affiliate/O with/O the/O existing/O union/O in/O the/O cartoonists/O ,/O and/O took/O steps/O to/O eliminate/O Janofsky/PERSON from/O his/O position/O as/O attorney/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O steps/O did/O Kibre/PERSON take/O in/O eliminating/O or/O having/O Janofsky/PERSON fired/O from/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O wrote/O a/O letter/O and/O I/O signed/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O text/O of/O this/O letter/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O you/O remember/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
It/O pointed/O out/O to/O the/O board/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O that/O Janofsky/PERSON was/O not/O a/O suitable/O representative/O for/O them/O ,/O was/O not/O a/O good/O trade/O unionist/O because/O he/O was/O representing/O an/O outlaw/O union/O ,/O which/O was/O organizing/O opposition/O to/O what/O we/O considered/O a/O legitimate/O union/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O state/O that/O you/O signed/O this/O letter/O ./O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O signed/O it/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O at/O that/O time/O secretary/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O position/O did/O Kibre/PERSON have/O with/O the/O Screen/O Cartonnists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O position/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O ,/O in/O your/O opinion/O ,/O a/O direct/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION directive/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O considered/O to/O the/O best/O interest/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O I/O considered/O it/O that/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2313/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O because/O it/O alienated/O a/O large/O group/O of/O cartoonists/O at/O Disney/ORGANIZATION 's/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O place/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION over/O your/O position/O as/O secretary/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O hard/O to/O say/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O really/O did/O ,/O although/O that/O is/O looking/O at/O it/O in/O retrospect/O ./O 
My/O reason/O for/O joining/O the/O party/O was/O to/O organize/O the/O union/O ./O 
Consequently/O ,/O I/O believe/O that/O the/O union/O was/O more/O important/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
But/O yet/O you/O would/O lend/O yourself/O to/O directives/O of/O the/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O I/O believe/O in/O my/O testimony/O downtown/O ,/O my/O previous/O testimony/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O I/O joined/O the/O party/O because/O I/O knew/O nothing/O about/O organization/O and/O it/O was/O the/O place/O to/O get/O information/O ./O 
Since/O my/O basic/O reason/O for/O joining/O was/O to/O organize/O cartoonists/O ,/O I/O do/O feel/O that/O the/O cartoonists/O '/O union/O was/O more/O important/O to/O me/O than/O the/O party/O itself/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O was/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O first/O organized/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O organization/O was/O in/O 1936/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON have/O any/O voice/O in/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O he/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O subsequently/O have/O a/O voice/O in/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
Very/O little/O ,/O because/O his/O attitude/O was/O a/O little/O too/O extreme/O to/O us/O to/O direct/O cartoonists/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O confer/O with/O Kibre/PERSON on/O problems/O that/O arose/O in/O the/O industry/O ,/O in/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O conferred/O with/O him/O and/O I/O took/O nonparty/O members/O with/O me/O to/O confer/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O occasion/O where/O you/O took/O opposition/O to/O Mr./O Kibre/PERSON 's/O decision/O in/O a/O matter/O ,/O or/O his/O advice/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
I/O can/O remember/O occasions/O on/O which/O it/O was/O necessary/O ,/O because/O his/O point/O of/O view/O was/O n't/O practical/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O specific/O instance/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
I/O just/O remember/O that/O very/O often/O his/O advice/O was/O confusing/O ./O 
When/O issues/O came/O up/O in/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O they/O were/O acted/O upon/O very/O often/O from/O the/O floor/O or/O by/O the/O executive/O board/O ./O 
And/O while/O I/O influenced/O them/O where/O I/O could/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O give/O too/O much/O opposition/O to/O the/O democratic/O processes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
DO/O you/O recall/O any/O other/O instances/O in/O which/O you/O lent/O yourself/O as/O secretary/O of/O the/O Screen/ORGANIZATION Cartoonists/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION to/O carry/O out/O other/O decisions/O or/O directives/O of/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O participated/O in/O an/O unemployment/O conference/O within/O the/O studios/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O further/O explain/O what/O the/O unemployment/O conference/O was/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O a/O legitimate/O organization/O ,/O to/O do/O research/O into/O the/O unemployment/O situation/O in/O the/O studios/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O officers/O of/O this/O organization/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O Herbert/PERSON Sorrell/PERSON was/O president/O ./O 
It/O seems/O to/O me/O he/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O this/O ?/O 
2314/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
1939/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON have/O a/O voice/O in/O this/O organization/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O he/O was/O representative/O from/O the/O prop/O makers/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O representative/O from/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O representative/O from/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
We/O had/O two/O delegates/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O other/O one/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O the/O other/O was/O Ted/PERSON Pierce/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O a/O party/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O other/O delegates/O from/O the/O other/O various/O unions?l/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O Frank/PERSON Drdrhk/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a/O delegate/O ,/O and/O Ed/PERSON Mussa/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O Communist/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O believe/O Ed/PERSON Gilbert/PERSON was/O a/O delegate/O ;/O Ben/PERSON Martinez/PERSON ,/O of/O the/O plasterers/O ./O 
These/O are/O not/O Communists/O ;/O Jules/PERSON Scacerieux/PERSON ,/O a/O plasterer/O ./O 
There/O were/O several/O writers/O ./O 
Francis/PERSON Goodrich/PERSON and/O Albert/PERSON Hackett/PERSON were/O writers/O ./O 
There/O were/O some/O people/O from/O the/O office/O employees/O ./O 
Virginia/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ,/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON 's/O wife/O ,/O was/O there/O ./O 
There/O were/O several/O directors/O ,/O Harry/PERSON Herrick/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O Herbert/PERSON Biberman/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O that/O conference/O ,/O of/O the/O directors/O ./O 
I/O knew/O none/O of/O these/O individuals/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O except/O the/O ones/O I/O previously/O testified/O to/O ./O 
Most/O of/O them/O were/O simply/O interested/O in/O solving/O the/O unemployment/O problem/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O elected/O a/O delegate/O to/O this-what/O was/O the/O name/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Studio/O Unemployment/O Conference/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O elected/O from/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O elected/O a/O delegate/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O were/O also/O delegates/O to/O this/O Studio/O Unemployment/O Conference/O ,/O have/O fraction/O meetings/O or/O discuss/O what/O policies/O should/O be/O formulated/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O able/O to/O control/O the/O Studio/O Unemployment/O Conference/O to/O any/O degree/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O controlled/O it/O to/O the/O degree/O that/O the/O policies/O were/O so/O fantastic/O it/O fell/O apart/O ./O 
We/O did/O make/O a/O survey/O of/O the/O unemployment/O situation/O in/O the/O studios/O ,/O and/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON ,/O at/O a/O fraction/O meeting/O ,/O suggested/O we/O have/O a/O mass/O meeting/O at/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION Bowl/LOCATION ./O 
Most/O of/O us/O thought/O that/O was/O a/O little/O fantastic/O ,/O those/O of/O us/O in/O the/O fraction/O ./O 
He/O prevailed/O on/O us/O to/O do/O it/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O a/O collossal/O flop/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O other/O policies/O were/O set/O forth/O by/O the/O fraction/O that/O you/O considered/O to/O be/O fantastic/O that/O led/O to/O the/O falling/O apart/O of/O this/O conference/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O generally/O say/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O Hollywood/O Bowl/O fiasco/O was/O the/O last/O straw/O ,/O actually/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O able/O to/O get/O the/O non-Communist/O members/O of/O this/O conference/O to/O agree/O to/O the/O policies/O as/O set/O forth/O by/O the/O fraction/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Drdrlik/PERSON brought/O the/O question/O up/O ./O 
He/O was/O the/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2315/O one/O who/O was/O to/O bring/O it/O up/O ./O 
He/O had/O a/O lot/O of/O friends/O in/O the/O conference/O meeting/O ,/O as/O he/O has/O a/O lot/O of/O friends/O every/O place/O usually/O ./O 
He/O made/O it/O seem/O like/O it/O would/O be/O a/O very/O good/O Hollywood/LOCATION thing/O to/O do/O ,/O it/O would/O appeal/O to/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O is/O it/O that/O a/O small/O group/O of/O Communists/O are/O able/O to/O control/O a/O whole/O body/O where/O they/O are/O outnumbered/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O because/O Communists/O are/O the/O most/O active/O members/O of/O the/O union/O ,/O usually/O ./O 
They/O work/O the/O hardest/O ,/O and/O they/O give/O more/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O the/O other/O members/O of/O this/O unemployment/O conference/O conscious/O of/O the/O Communist/O infiltration/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O ,/O to/O any/O degree/O ./O 
I/O would/O think/O some/O of/O them/O might/O have/O suspected/O it/O ,/O but/O where/O you/O feel/O that/O people/O agree/O with/O you/O ,/O you/O are/O inclined/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O so/O what/O do/O their/O politics/O matter/O ?/O ''/O 
At/O least/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O that/O was/O the/O feeling/O ./O 
Mr./O WHIEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O overall/O objective/O of/O the/O conference/O was/O for/O the/O good/O of/O the-Mrs/O ./O 
ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O good/O of/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ,/O the/O working/O people/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O ./O 
It/O could/O have/O done/O some/O good/O but/O was/O badly/O directed/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O n't/O attain/O any/O positive/O results/O from/O the/O conference/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O because/O we/O could/O n't/O get/O any/O agreement/O on/O what/O to/O do/O about/O it/O ./O 
The/O feeling/O was/O that/O maybe/O the/O work/O could/O be/O spread/O out/O so/O there/O would/O n't/O be/O so/O much/O unemployment/O ,/O people/O who/O were/O employed/O could/O work/O less/O and/O those/O who/O were/O unemployed/O could/O get/O a/O few/O days/O '/O work/O instead/O of/O no/O work/O at/O all/O ./O 
But/O that/O is/O a/O very/O hard/O thing/O to/O get/O the/O membership/O of/O the/O union/O to/O agree/O upon/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
TO/O get/O back/O to/O the/O former/O attorney/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O Mr./O Janofsky/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O recall/O what/O action/O was/O taken/O by/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O after/O the/O receipt/O of/O the/O letter/O that/O Jeff/PERSON Kibre/PERSON wrote/O and/O you/O signed/O and/O sent/O to/O the/O guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
They/O fired/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O who/O was/O on/O the/O board/O of/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O anyone/O on/O the/O board/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Actually/O what/O this/O amounts/O to/O in/O the/O Communist/O PartyMrs/O ./O 
ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Kibre/PERSON was/O actually/O a/O sort/O of/O liaison/O person/O between/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O and/O the/O talent/O guilds/O and/O the/O craft/O unions/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O liaison/O between/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O these/O guilds/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAsts/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O mean/O he/O was/O important/O to/O the/O other/O people/O besides/O Communists/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Kibre/PERSON ,/O then/O ,/O as/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O able/O to/O remove/O this/O attorney/O because/O he/O was/O in/O opposition/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
During/O this/O period/O of/O time/O that/O we/O are/O presently/O talking/O about/O ,/O 1939/O ,/O Germany/LOCATION and/O Russia/LOCATION entered/O into/O a/O nonaggression/O pact/O ;/O do/O you/O recall/O that/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O your/O reaction/O to/O the/O nonagression/O pact/O ?/O 
2316/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O chagrin/O ,/O because/O as/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O at/O the/O time/O I/O felt/O that/O there/O were/O no/O two/O ideologies/O more/O diametrically/O opposed/O than/O nazism/O and/O communism/O ./O 
The/O whole/O party/O line/O had/O been/O in/O opposition/O to/O Hitler/PERSON and/O to/O Mussolini/PERSON and/O to/O Franco/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O bring/O yourself/O in/O a/O position/O to/O accept/O it/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O we/O felt/O that/O because/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION was/O a/O country/O surrounded/O by/O capitalist/O countries/O that/O this/O pact/O with/O Germany/LOCATION was/O an/O expedient/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O explained/O this/O sudden/O twist/O in/O party/O line/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O who/O did/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O you/O did/O accept/O fully/O this/O change/O in/O the/O line/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O also/O recall/O several/O years/O later/O that/O when/O Ger/PERSON -/O many/O attacked/O Russia/LOCATION there/O was/O again/O a/O sudden/O change/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O you/O reacted/O to/O the/O breaking/O of/O the/O pact/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
As/O far/O as/O I/O was/O concerned/O ,/O I/O got/O the/O feeling/O that/O other/O people/O felt/O the/O same/O way/O ./O 
There/O was/O never/O a/O feeling/O of/O trust/O for/O the/O Nazis/ORGANIZATION simply/O because/O there/O was/O a/O nonaggression/O pact/O ,/O that/O it/O was/O a/O kind/O of/O a/O holding/O off/O ./O 
Further/O ,/O that/O whoever/O discussed/O this/O in/O 1939/O ,/O to/O us/O ,/O this/O was/O to/O stall/O the/O present/O danger/O ,/O and/O only/O proved/O that/O they/O were/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELE/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Adams/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O we/O have/O discussed/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O up/O to/O approximately/O 1942/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O if/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O you/O were/O transferred/O to/O another/O unit/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
At/O about/O this/O time/O I/O got/O married/O ,/O in/O the/O fall/O of/O 1941/O ./O 
I/O continued/O on/O with/O the/O cartoonists/O until/O ,/O oh/O ,/O about/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1942/O ./O 
Then/O I/O quit/O work/O and/O I/O continued/O for/O a/O little/O while/O ,/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O ,/O in/O the/O cartoonists/O ,/O and/O I/O met/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O with/O the/O lab/O technicians/O because/O my/O husband/O was/O a/O lab/O technician/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O go/O into/O the/O party/O and/O it/O was/O a/O very/O unhappy/O period/O ./O 
I/O introduced/O him/O to/O a/O couple/O of/O members/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O like/O them/O and/O we/O had/O lots/O of/O arguments/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O was/O transferred/O a/O little/O bit/O later/O to/O a/O group/O in/O Burbank/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O this/O lab/O technicians/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
A/O couple/O of/O months/O or/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O how/O many/O individuals/O were/O in/O the/O technicians/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O n't/O a/O very/O big/O group/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O mostly/O technicolor/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEsLER/O ./O 
DO/O you/O recall/O who/O these/O individuals/O were/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O because/O I/O did/O n't/O work/O with/O them/O and/O they/O used/O party/O names/O ./O 
I/O remember/O a/O Hank/PERSON Morley/PERSON because/O he/O used/O his/O right/O s/O g/O name/O ./O 
Most/O of/O them/O used/O party/O names/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O of/O the/O individuals/O '/O party/O names/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O was/O chairman/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2317/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O individuals/O you/O introduced/O your/O husband/O to/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Norville/PERSON Crutcher/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Anybody/O else/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O a/O big/O obnoxious/O guy/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O what/O his/O name/O was/O ./O 
He/O was/O the/O last/O straw/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O my/O husband/O was/O concerned/O ;/O just/O could/O n't/O stand/O him/O ./O 
He/O was/O with/O technicolor/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O individuals/O were/O members/O of/O this/O lab/O technicians/O '/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O 5/O or/O 6/O or/O 7/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O Julian/PERSON Gordon/PERSON being/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O him/O ./O 
He/O may/O have/O been/O a/O member/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O remember/O when/O I/O saw/O him/O at/O the/O hearing/O ./O 
Mr.WHEELER/O ./O 
Were/O you/O subsequently/O transferred/O to/O another/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O at/O a/O neighborhood/O group/O in/O Burbank/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O neighborhood/O group/O in/O Burbank/LOCATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O member/O for/O ,/O oh/O ,/O well/O ,/O 6/O months/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O attend/O meetings/O regularly/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O of/O the/O individuals/O who/O were/O members/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O remember/O a/O girl/O named/O Thelma/PERSON Bachelis/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Mrs./O Bachelis/PERSON '/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
She/O was/O an/O attorney/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O did/O you/O attend/O while/O assigned/O to/O the/O Burbank/LOCATION group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ,/O about/O 4/O or/O 5/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O individuals/O were/O members/O of/O this/O club/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
There/O must/O have/O been/O 10/O or/O 12/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O any/O of/O the/O other/O individuals/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O at/O whose/O homes/O you/O met/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
We/O alternated/O ,/O I/O remember/O ./O 
It/O was/O always/O at/O a/O different/O place/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O employed/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O industry/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O was/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O left/O the/O Burbank/LOCATION group/O ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O another/O club/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Late/O in/O 1943/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O I/O went/O back/O to/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O employed/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
At/O Universal/ORGANIZATION Pictures/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O reaffiliate/O with/O a/O motion-picture/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/O Part/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
es/O ;/O I/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Until/O I/O dropped/O out/O in/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O the/O members/O were/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O Kate/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O the/O wife/O of/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ./O 
Edward/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ,/O a/O painter/O ./O 
Eugene/PERSON 31747-53-pt/O ./O 
6-4/O 2318/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Fleury/PERSON ,/O a/O teacher/O and/O artist/O ./O 
Bernice/PERSON Fleury/PERSON ./O 
also/O a/O teacher/O and/O artist/O ./O 
David/PERSON Hilberiman/PERSON ,/O Libby/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON ./O 
David/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON was/O a/O cartoonist/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Libby/PERSON Hilberman/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
His/O wife/O ./O 
John/PERSON Hubley/PERSON ,/O a/O cartoonist/O ./O 
Cecil/PERSON Beard/PERSON ,/O cartoonist/O ./O 
Edwina/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ,/O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O only/O in/O briefly/O ./O 
Zachery/PERSON Schwartz/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O only/O in/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O the/O record/O to/O show/O at/O this/O point/O Eugene/PERSON Fluery/PERSON ,/O Bernice/PERSON Fluery/PERSON ,/O and/O Zachery/PERSON Schwartz/PERSON have/O all/O testified/O before/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O as/O cooperative/O witnesses/O ./O 
You/O mentioned/O the/O name/O of/O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O he/O at/O one/O time/O have/O an/O official/O position/O with/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O business/O agent/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION have/O any/O voice/O in/O the/O appointment/O of/O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON as/O business/O agent/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAM/PERSON ./O 
Indirectly/O ,/O I/O suppose/O ,/O but/O lie/O was/O actually/O recommended/O by/O the/O Pacific/ORGANIZATION Coast/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who-Mrs/O ./O 
ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O board/O examiner/O for/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION Relations/ORGANIZATION Board/ORGANIZATION at/O one/O time/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
When/O he/O stopped/O working/O with/O the/O Board/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O any/O other/O business/O agents/O of/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O Morrie/PERSON Howard/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Maurice/PERSON Howard/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
He/O succeeded/O William/PERSON Pomerance/PERSON ;/O is/O that/O right/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O meet/O Maurice/PERSON Howard/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O cartoonist/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O in/O one/O of/O your/O groups/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O group/O would/O you/O place/O him/O in/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O in/O this/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O in/O the/O last/O group/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Later/O on/O that/O was/O ,/O I/O mean/O he/O was/O n'tMr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O when/O you/O left/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O he/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O anyone/O else/O who/O was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O later/O group/O or/O any/O group/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O dues/O secretary/O at/O any/O time/O of/O the/O last/O group/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O was/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O collected/O dues/O from/O all/O these/O individuals/O you/O have/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 2319/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O to/O whom/O you/O gave/O the/O dues/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O gave/O them/O to/O Naomi/PERSON Robison/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O time/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O ever/O have/O occasion/O to/O meet/O Paul/PERSON Perlin/PERSON as/O a/O Communist/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O in/O which/O group/O I/O met/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O W/O \/O IEELER/O ./O 
It/O was/O in/O one/O of/O your/O groups/O ?/O 
Mrs./O AD/O ./O 
\/O is/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O it/O was/O in/O one/O of/O the/O groups/O ?/O 
Mrs./O AuAss/O ./O 
It/O was/O very/O early/O ./O 
It/O may/O have/O been/O in/O this/O first/O group/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O quite/O sure/O whether/O I/O met/O him/O in/O the/O beginninghe/O used/O to/O take/O me/O to/O parties/O and/O things/O once/O in/O a/O while/O ./O 
So/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O whether/O I/O met/O him/O at/O parties/O or/O where/O I/O met/O him/O ,/O actually/O ,/O within/O the/O party/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O have/O occasion/O to/O meet/O Mary/PERSON Nolan/PERSON as/O a/O meiibler/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
She/O may/O have/O come/O along/O with/O Ed/PERSON ./O 
Was/O n't/O that/O the/O husband/O 's/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Frank/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
She/O may/O have/O come/O along/O with/O hun/O ./O 
I/O remember/O I/O saw/O her/O at/O union/O meetings/O quite/O often/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
But/O not/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O she/O was/O a/O member/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O and/O dropped/O out/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1946/O ,/O did/O anyone/O endeavor/O to/O resolicit/O your/O membership/O ?/O 
Mrs./O AnD/O s./O No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEEIER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O had/O no/O contact/O with/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION since/O that/O date/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O have/O n't/O ;/O casually/O ,/O to/O say/O hello/O ,/O perhaps/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O specific/O reason/O why/O you/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O got/O tired/O of/O being/O told/O what/O to/O do/O ./O 
For/O an/O example/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O I/O was/O secretary/O of/O the/O Community/O Homes/O ,/O a/O housing/O co-op/O ,/O which/O I/O considered/O an/O important/O activity/O ./O 
After/O I/O quit/O work/O it/O was/O suggested/O to/O me/O that/O I/O should/O resign/O as/O secretary/O of/O the/O Community/O Homes/O and/O come/O back/O into/O the/O Screen/O Cartoonists/O '/O Guild/O ./O 
It/O was/O suggested/O to/O me/O by/O someone/O in/O the/O party/O that/O I/O should/O go/O back/O to/O work/O and/O rejoin/O the/O cartoonists/O '/O union/O and/O drop/O out/O of/O the/O Community/O Homes/O ,/O because/O they/O did/O not/O consider/O it/O an/O important/O enough/O activity/O for/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O a/O little/O more/O than/O a/O suggestion/O by/O this/O party/O person/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O no/O intention/O of/O going/O back/O to/O work/O ./O 
I/O have/O my/O family/O to/O consider/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O asked/O you/O to/O resume/O your/O work/O in/O the/O studios/O and/O stop/O your/O work/O in/O the/O Community/O Homes/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMs/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O it/O was/O a/O woman/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O just/O sure/O who/O ./O 
It/O was/O someone/O from/O the/O group/O ./O 
It/O may/O have/O been/O Mrs./O Howard/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O Mrs./O Maurice/PERSON Howard/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O her/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Evelyn/PERSON ./O 
2320/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Evelyn/PERSON Howard/PERSON was/O also/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O what/O your/O reaction/O was/O to/O this/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O no/O intention/O on/O going/O back/O to/O work/O ./O 
I/O have/O too/O much/O to/O do/O at/O home/O and/O I/O feel/O that/O Community/O Homes/O is/O a/O good/O activity/O that/O is/O related/O to/O my/O family/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O You/O will/O go/O back/O to/O work/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O I/O wo/O n't/O ./O ''/O 
That/O was/O all/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O am/O through/O with/O the/O party/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O it/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O call/O me/O again/O ./O 
I/O am/O through/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O anything/O additional/O you/O would/O like/O to/O add/O for/O the/O record/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O just/O that/O dropping/O out/O of/O the/O party/O was/O not/O a/O sudden/O thing/O ./O 
Over/O the/O last/O year/O or/O two/O that/O I/O was/O a/O member/O I/O had/O become/O increasingly/O disillusioned/O with/O it/O ,/O actually/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O at/O this/O time/O any/O other/O individual/O you/O met/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O whether/O it/O was/O a/O fraction/O meeting/O ,/O group/O meeting/O ,/O or/O any/O other/O type/O of/O meeting/O ,/O that/O could/O be/O construed/O as/O pure/O Communist/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O really/O do/O n't/O ./O 
There/O were/O many/O meetings/O where/O there/O was/O a/O mixture/O of/O people/O who/O were/O communistic/O people/O ,/O who/O were/O not/O Communists/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O be/O sure/O enough/O to/O name/O any/O of/O those/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O anything/O additional/O you/O want/O to/O put/O in/O ?/O 
Mrs./O ADAMS/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O that/O the/O committee/O will/O find/O your/O statement/O of/O great/O interest/O ,/O Mrs./O Adams/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O interrogation/O of/O Charlotte/LOCATION Darling/O Adams/PERSON was/O concluded/O ./O -RRB-/O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 6/O TUESDAY/O ,/O JUNE/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMIrrEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVrTES/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O STATEMENT/O An/O executive/O statement/O given/O at/O 1/O :/O 30/O p./O m./O ,/O June/O 2/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O at/O room/O 117/O Hollywood/LOCATION Roosevelt/LOCATION Hotel/LOCATION ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
STATEMENT/O OF/O ROLAND/PERSON WILLIAM/PERSON KIBBEE/PERSON Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
Roland/PERSON William/PERSON Kibbee/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O born/O and/O when/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
February/O 15/O ,/O 1941/O ;/O Monongahela/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O under/O subpena/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O giving/O this/O statement/O of/O your/O own/O free/O will/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O realize/O that/O by/O giving/O this/O statement/O does/O not/O eliminate/O the/O possibility/O of/O your/O being/O called/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O the/O future/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Mr./O Kibbee/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O KImBEE/O ./O 
I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O first/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1937/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O memory/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O KIBBEE/PERSON ./O 
For/O a/O period/O of/O approximately/O 2/O years/O ./O 
