INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 10/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O APRIL/O 20/O AND/O 21/O ,/O 1956/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O -RRB-/O 77436/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1956/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON E./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION RICHARDARENS/LOCATION ,/O Director/O 31/O CONTENTS/O PART/O 7/O April/O 16/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofWilliam/O Don/PERSON Waddilove/PERSON .../O ./O 
./O 
-------------------------/O Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O George/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -RRB-/O ---------------/O Afternoon/O sessionRubin/O Decker/O ------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON Pass/PERSON -------------------------------/O Samuel/PERSON Berland/PERSON --------------/O Sylvia/PERSON Lardner/PERSON Darnell/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON -RRB-/O --------------/O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON ---------------------------/O Milton/PERSON Kestenbaum/PERSON ./O 
./O 
-/O ./O 
--------/O .../O Sidney/PERSON Greene/PERSON -----------/O Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON ---------------------------/O PART/O 8/O April/O 17/O ./O 
1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Nikolai/PERSON Khokhlov/PERSON -------------------/O --/O Pae/ORGANIZATION 3/O 60/O 3676/O 3695/O 3711/O 3718/O 3726/O 3728/O 3733/O 3737/O 3749/O 3756/O PART/O 9/O April/O 19/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofAlbert/O Glasser/PERSON ----------------------/O 3821/O Katherine/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -RRB-/O --/O ----------/O 3837/O Herbert/PERSON Offner/PERSON -----------------------/O 3841/O Sam/PERSON Fordis/PERSON ----------------------------/O 385/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ----------------------------/O 3854/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofCyril/O Towbin/PERSON ---------/O -----------------/O 3862/O Helen/PERSON Teverniti/PERSON --------------/O 3869/O Lewis/PERSON Elias/PERSON ------------------------------/O 3870/O Leonard/PERSON H./PERSON Dahlsten/PERSON -------------------------/O 3881/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --------------------/O 3885/O Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -----------------/O 3887/O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON ----------------/O -----------/O 3887/O Manuel/PERSON L./PERSON Compinsky/PERSON -----------------------/O 3892/O Eudice/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -RRB-/O ----------------------/O 3896/O Milton/PERSON Feher/PERSON --------------------------/O 3897/O PART/O 10/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofThomas/O Walfrid/PERSON Nelson/PERSON ------------------------/O Arthur/ORGANIZATION Globe/ORGANIZATION ----------------------------------/O Don/PERSON Christlieb/PERSON -----------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofRamez/O Idriss/PERSON ----------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON DiFiore/PERSON -------/O ./O 
---------------------------/O Edgar/PERSON Lustgarten/PERSON -----------------------------------/O 3901/O 3915/O 3918/O 3934/O 3937/O 3939/O IV/O CONTENTS/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956-Continued/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O of-Continued/O Morris/PERSON Boltuch/PERSON ./O 
./O 
.../O ----------------------------------/O Philip/PERSON Goldberg/PERSON --/O ./O 
------------------/O Joseph/PERSON Eger/PERSON _/O -----------------/O ./O 
------/O Kalman/PERSON Bloch/PERSON Jack/PERSON -LRB-/O L/O -RRB-/O Pepper/O ------------------------------------------------------------/O Jean/O C./O Music/O --------------------------------/O Manuel/PERSON Newman/PERSON -/O ./O 
-/O ----------------------------/O Roy/PERSON Frankson/PERSON --/O Herbert/PERSON Lessner/PERSON ----------------------------------------/O George/PERSON Kast/PERSON ----------------------------------------------/O April/O 21/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O ---------------------/O John/PERSON Walter/PERSON Porter/PERSON ./O 
Jessica/PERSON Rhine/PERSON Wildman/PERSON ---------------------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofLouis/O R./PERSON Sherman/PERSON ------------------------------------/O William/PERSON Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON --------------------------------/O Louis/PERSON R./PERSON Sherman/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -----------------------------------------------/O Thomas/PERSON A./PERSON Chapman/PERSON -----------------------/O Sidney/LOCATION London/LOCATION -/O Alfred/PERSON Hale/PERSON Caplan-John/PERSON T./PERSON MeTernan/PERSON ./O 
121/O ./O 
STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O to/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O `/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authoized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O \*/O \*/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5,1955/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O \*/O \*/O POWERSANDDUTIESOFCOMMITTEES/O \*/O v/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O invesi/O gation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 10/O FRIDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 20/O ,/O 1956/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O C0/O IrrrTTEEON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O -/O at/O 9/O :/O 30/O a./O m./O ,/O pursuant/O to/O recess/O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION -LRB-/O presiding/O -RRB-/O ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O would/O you/O call/O your/O first/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Nelson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O so/O affirm/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O THOMAS/PERSON WALFRID/PERSON NELSON/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROSE/O S./O ROSENBERG/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Nelson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O accompanying/O the/O witness/O please/O identify/O herself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
Rose/PERSON S./PERSON Rosenberg/PERSON ,/O b-e-r-g/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O February/O 24/O ,/O 1913/O ,/O in/O Little/LOCATION Rock/LOCATION ,/O Wash./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O resided/O in/O Long/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O 4/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O educated/O in/O the/O public/O schools/O of/O the/O State/O of/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O graduated/O from/O the/O Washington/LOCATION schools/O in/O 3901/O 3902/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Olympia/LOCATION ,/O Wash./LOCATION ./O 
In/O my/O grammar/O school/O education/O I/O was/O valedictorian/O of/O my/O class/O ./O 
From/O Olympia/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION I/O was/O salutatorian/O of/O a/O class/O of/O 160/O pupils/O ./O 
I/O have/O a/O bachelor/O 's/O degree/O from/O Western/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Education/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O have/O had/O 1/O year/O of/O graduate/O training/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O receive/O your/O bachelor/O 's/O degree/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1937/O ./O 
The/O graduate/O training/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION completes/O my/O formal/O education/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O complete/O your/O graduate/O training/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O employment/O has/O been/O since/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O from/O 1941/O to/O 1945/O ./O 
I/O was/O employed/O by/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION from/O 1945/O to/O 1947/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O from/O 1947/O to/O 1949/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION in/O 1949/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O the/O Monrovia-Duarte/ORGANIZATION Evening/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION 1949-51/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O is/O that/O located/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O located/O in/O Monrovia/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O employed/O as/O a/O teacher/O there/O ?/O 
Is/O that/O what/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O that/O is/O what/O I/O mean/O ./O 
From/O 1951/O to/O 1952/O I/O was/O employed/O by/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 1952/O I/O was/O employed/O by/O the/O Arcadia/ORGANIZATION Unified/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION District/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Since/O 1952/O I/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O mean/O that/O your/O employment/O between/O 1951/O and/O 1952/O by/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION was/O in/O the/O teaching/O profession/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O that/O employment/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O State/O parole/O officer/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O employment/O since/O 1952/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
With/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
A/O medical/O social/O worker/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O understood/O you/O to/O say/O that/O from/O 1941/O to/O 1945/O you/O were/O employed/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O that/O employment/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
For/O some/O months/O I/O was/O employed/O as/O a/O field/O grant/O supervisor/O at/O Yakima/LOCATION ,/O Wash./LOCATION ,/O where/O I/O was/O assigned/O to/O the/O administration/O of/O the/O Federal/O grant/O program/O administering/O relief/O to/O migratory/O farm/O laborers/O ./O 
Later/O I/O was/O promoted/O to/O regional/O grant/O supervisor/O ,/O supervising/O the/O program/O throughout/O the/O States/O of/O Oregon/LOCATION ,/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O and/O Idaho/LOCATION ,/O with/O headquarters/O at/O Portland/LOCATION ,/O Oreg/LOCATION ./O 
When/O the/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Agriculture/ORGANIZATION Farm/ORGANIZATION Security/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION program/O was/O transferred/O to/O the/O War/ORGANIZATION Food/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ,/O Office/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O transferred/O to/O that/O agency/O in/O 1943/O ,/O and/O continued/O with/O it/O until/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O have/O any/O assignment/O in/O the/O Agriculture/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ./O 
COMiMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF/LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3903/O ,/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O said/O that/O from/O 1945/O to/O 1947/O you/O were/O employed/O by/O UNRRA/ORGANIZATION ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O your/O employment/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O welfare/O officer/O in/O the/O displaced/O persons/O program/O ,/O assigned/O to/O the/O American/O Zone/O of/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O general/O nature/O of/O your/O duties/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O general/O nature/O of/O my/O duties/O was/O to/O set/O up/O and/O supervise/O the/O welfare/O programs/O for/O the/O victims/O of/O Nazi/O terror/O who/O were/O housed/O in/O displaced/O persons/O '/O camps/O as/O a/O military/O measure/O until/O until/O such/O time/O as/O they/O might/O be/O returned/O to/O their/O lands/O of/O origin/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O told/O us/O that/O from/O 1947/O to/O 1949/O you/O were/O again/O employed/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O ,/O please/O ,/O in/O what/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELsON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O welfare/O officer/O with/O military/O government/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O stationed/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O stationed/O at/O Nagoya/LOCATION ,/O spelled/O N-a-g-o-y-a/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O reason/O for/O the/O termination/O of/O your/O services/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELsON/PERSON ./O 
Chairman/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O introductory/O remark/O which/O you/O made/O to/O this/O group/O on/O last/O Monday/O ,/O wherein/O you/O stated/O that/O it/O was/O not/O the/O intention/O of/O this/O committee/O to/O delve/O into/O the/O relationship/O between/O employer/O and/O employee/O ,/O I/O wonder/O if/O you/O would/O ask/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON to/O kindly/O withdraw/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O request/O is/O denied/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O repeat/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O read/O him/O the/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O pending/O question/O was/O read/O by/O the/O reporter/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O ,/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O date/O of/O the/O termination/O of/O your/O services/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O response/O to/O the/O question/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O ,/O in/O my/O opinion/O ,/O that/O question/O is/O beyond/O the/O area/O of/O jurisdiction/O of/O this/O committee/O as/O set/O up/O by/O your/O function/O ,/O according/O to/O my/O understanding/O ,/O and/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O we/O can/O not/O investigate/O Communist/O sub/O -/O version/O even/O in/O Allied/O military/O government/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O there/O is/O anything/O in/O the/O record/O with/O regard/O to/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
There/O may/O be/O before/O we/O get/O through/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O released/O from/O military/O service/O under/O the/O provisions/O of/O Public/O Law/O 808/O as/O a/O security/O risk/O and/O returned/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION from/O Japan/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O never/O in/O military/O service/O ./O 
I/O was/O classified/O 2-B/O because/O of/O the/O essential/O nature/O of/O my/O work/O at/O War/ORGANIZATION Food/ORGANIZATION Administration/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O subject/O to/O military/O authority/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O were/O you/O not/O ?/O 
3904/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O civilian/O employee/O of/O the/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O military/O government/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O but/O you/O were/O subject/O to/O military/O authority/O while/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O ?/O 
I/O did/O n't/O understand/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
He/O said/O he/O was/O ;/O certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O then/O ./O 
Were/O you/O returned/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION under/O the/O provisions/O of/O Public/O Law/O 808/O from/O Japan/LOCATION as/O a/O security/O risk/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O were/O you/O returned/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O as/O to/O why/O he/O was/O returned/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O requested/O by/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O the/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O privileges/O allowed/O me/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O ,/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O to/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Public/O Law/O 808/O provides/O that/O ,/O within/O 30/O days/O after/O removal/O ,/O any/O person/O shall/O have/O opportunity/O personally/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O official/O designated/O by/O the/O Secretary/O concerned/O ,/O and/O be/O fully/O informed/O of/O the/O reasons/O for/O such/O removal/O ,/O and/O to/O submit/O ,/O within/O 30/O days/O thereafter/O ,/O such/O statements/O or/O affidavits/O or/O both/O as/O he/O may/O desire/O to/O show/O why/O he/O should/O be/O retained/O and/O not/O removed/O ./O 
Did/O you/O resort/O to/O that/O remedy/O provided/O by/O Public/O Law/O 808/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Regardless/O of/O in/O which/O manner/O this/O matter/O is/O approached/O ,/O I/O shall/O continue/O to/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
With/O respect/O to/O this/O specific/O question/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Actually/O ,/O you/O did/O not/O appeal/O from/O the/O decision/O removing/O you/O ,/O or/O take/O any/O steps/O to/O avoid/O it/O ,/O did/O you/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O any/O time/O between/O 1947/O and/O 1949/O ?/O 
That/O was/O the/O period/O you/O were/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O response/O to/O that/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O assert/O that/O the/O only/O purpose/O of/O your/O asking/O that/O question/O is/O to/O intimidate/O me/O by/O putting/O out/O words/O such/O as/O communism/O and/O Communist/O and/O subversive/O with/O the/O idea/O of/O causing/O citizens/O to/O refrain/O from/O attending/O any/O sort/O of/O meetings/O or/O joining/O any/O sort/O of/O organizations/O for/O fear/O that/O at/O some/O time/O they/O may/O be/O labeled/O as/O subversive/O or/O un-American/O ,/O and/O ,/O thereby/O ,/O causing/O a/O person/O to/O lose/O his/O employment/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O that/O is/O an/O unjust/O question/O to/O put/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3905/O Mr./O SCHERE/PERSON ./O 
Since/O you/O raise/O the/O question/O ,/O I/O am/O surprised/O that/O and/O you/O have/O been/O employed/O by/O the/O Government-true/O ,/O it/O is/O State/O and/O county/O and/O city/O government-since/O your/O dismissal/O from/O Japan/LOCATION under/O the/O circumstances/O ./O 
That/O does/O interest/O me/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O consider/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O be/O an/O organization/O which/O one/O should/O feel/O free/O to/O join/O and/O with/O the/O membership/O of/O which/O one/O should/O feel/O free/O to/O associate/O I/O Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O in/O response/O to/O that/O question/O ,/O I/O would/O repeat/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O out/O of/O its/O jurisdiction/O in/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O already/O told/O you/O fellows/O that/O you/O may/O not/O investigate/O where/O you/O do/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O legislate/O ./O 
And/O ,/O since/O you/O do/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O legislate/O in/O the/O field/O of/O associations/O of/O citizens/O ,/O I/O feel/O that/O the/O question/O is/O out/O of/O order/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O it/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O one/O thing/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O :/O If/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O or/O any/O of/O its/O committees/O ,/O does/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O legislate/O with/O respect/O to/O Federal/O employees/O ,/O or/O to/O make/O inquiry/O into/O matters/O concerning/O Federal/O employees/O ,/O past/O and/O present/O ,/O who/O are/O members/O or/O have/O been/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O then/O there/O is/O certainly/O something/O very/O awry/O as/O far/O as/O the/O investigating/O power/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION is/O concerned/O ./O 
This/O is/O one/O area/O in/O which/O there/O should/O be/O absolutely/O no/O question/O as/O to/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Congress/ORGANIZATION would/O be/O derelict/O indeed/O if/O it/O permitted/O a/O situation/O to/O go/O unnoticed/O in/O which/O there/O were/O past/O or/O present/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION employed/O ,/O especially/O in/O light/O of/O the/O action/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O outlawing/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O I/O understand/O ,/O Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ,/O that/O you/O are/O contending/O that/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION can/O not/O legislate/O in/O the/O field/O of/O military/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O in/O Japan/LOCATION or/O foreign/O countries/O ,/O in/O the/O American/O military/O ?/O 
Do/O I/O understand/O that/O is/O your/O contention/O ,/O that/O that/O is/O not/O in/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
I/O so/O understood/O ./O 
I/O was/O quite/O shocked/O to/O hear/O you/O say/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O wonder/O if/O you/O would/O kindly/O ask/O the/O man/O to/O read/O my/O answer/O back/O to/O Mr./O What/O is/O the/O name/O of/O the/O gentleman/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O who/O I/O am/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O Doyle/PERSON of/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O 's/O proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O want/O the/O answer/O ,/O please/O ,/O to/O that/O ./O 
The/O gentleman/O wanted/O his/O answer/O read/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O would/O be/O good/O to/O have/O it/O read/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O requested/O by/O the/O witness/O and/O by/O Congressman/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O will/O the/O reporter/O please/O read/O the/O answer/O requested/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O the/O record/O was/O read/O by/O the/O reporter/O ,/O as/O follows/O :-RRB-/O In/O response/O to/O that/O question/O ,/O I/O would/O repeat/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O out/O of/O its/O jurisdiction/O in/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O already/O told/O you/O fellows/O that/O you/O may/O not/O investigate/O where/O you/O do/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O legislate/O ./O 
And/O ,/O since/O you/O do/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O legislate/O in/O the/O field/O of/O associations/O of/O citizens/O ,/O I/O feel/O that/O the/O question/O is/O out/O of/O order/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O it/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
3906/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O wondering/O if/O the/O gentleman/O cared/O to/O answer/O my/O question/O ,/O if/O he/O still/O contended/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION did/O not/O have/O power/O and/O jurisdiction/O to/O legislate/O in/O the/O field/O of/O the/O American/O military/O wherever/O it/O was/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
I/O understood/O the/O gentleman/O to/O say/O he/O was/O subject/O to/O American/O military/O discipline/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ./O 
I/O am/O on/O the/O Armed/ORGANIZATION Services/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O too/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O we/O have/O the/O power/O to/O legislate/O regarding/O the/O American/O military/O wherever/O it/O is/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O of/O the/O opinion/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O that/O by/O the/O mere/O fact/O that/O you/O are/O a/O civilian/O employee/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O you/O do/O not/O lose/O your/O civil/O rights/O ./O 
I/O still/O say/O that/O this/O committee/O does/O not/O have/O the/O jurisdiction/O to/O probe/O into/O my/O thoughts/O or/O my/O associations/O ./O 
And/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O your/O taking/O a/O position/O in/O Japan/LOCATION ,/O did/O you/O prepare/O an/O application/O for/O Government/O service/O in/O which/O you/O set/O forth/O your/O personal/O history/O and/O certain/O other/O matters/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O presume/O that/O I/O did/O because/O it/O is/O a/O general/O routine/O for/O Federal/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O hand/O you/O a/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O a/O so-called/O application/O for/O employment/O ,/O and/O ask/O you/O to/O look/O at/O the/O last/O page/O and/O see/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O signature/O appearing/O at/O the/O bottom/O of/O it/O ,/O on/O the/O reverse/O side/O of/O that/O sheet/O ,/O is/O your/O signature/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O the/O usual/O Government/O form/O ?/O 
Has/O it/O a/O number/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O number/O has/O been/O covered/O and/O I/O am/O unable/O to/O see/O it/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Document/O handed/O to/O counsel/O for/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O equivalent/O to/O form/O 57/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O it/O is/O exactly/O form/O 57/O ./O 
The/O sheet/O which/O I/O asked/O the/O witness/O to/O examine/O is/O the/O back/O page/O of/O the/O document/O on/O which/O his/O name/O appears/O ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O signature/O appearing/O at/O the/O bottom/O of/O the/O last/O page/O ,/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O is/O your/O signature/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O my/O employment/O history/O has/O always/O been/O commented/O upon/O by/O my/O various/O employers/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O not/O responsive/O to/O my/O question/O ./O 
The/O question/O simply/O was/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O signature/O appearing/O at/O the/O end/O of/O the/O document/O is/O your/O signature/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
With/O respect/O to/O this/O question/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O the/O question/O by/O counsel/O ,/O you/O were/O first/O asked/O if/O you/O signed/O an/O application/O for/O employment/O ./O 
Is/O n't/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O MoULDER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O witness/O answered/O ``/O Yes/O ''/O that/O he/O probably/O did/O ,/O or/O he/O assumed/O that/O he/O had/O signed/O such/O application/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O it/O is/O my/O opinion/O that/O you/O probably/O have/O opened/O the/O door/O and/O waived/O your/O right/O to/O claim/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3907/O The/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O response/O to/O the/O direction/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O based/O upon/O the/O privilege/O provided/O me/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ,/O I/O note/O on/O this/O application/O also/O ,/O on/O the/O last/O page/O ,/O question/O No./O 26/O :/O Do/O you/O advocate/O or/O have/O you/O ever/O advocated/O ,/O or/O are/O you/O now/O or/O have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O any/O organization/O that/O advocates/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION by/O force/O or/O violence/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O in/O the/O column/O where/O an/O answer/O is/O required/O there/O is/O an/O X-mark/O under/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
Was/O that/O statement/O a/O true/O statement/O at/O the/O time/O this/O application/O was/O executed/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O record/O will/O show/O that/O the/O witness/O has/O not/O identified/O this/O document/O ./O 
However/O ,/O with/O respect/O to/O the/O question/O ,/O I/O will/O state/O that/O at/O no/O time/O have/O I/O advocated/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Now/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION have/O defined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O an/O organization/O which/O does/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O advocate/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O say/O again/O that/O to/O toss/O such/O a/O word/O as/O Communist/O and/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O force/O and/O violence/O ,/O associated/O with/O the/O name/O of/O the/O witness/O ,/O is/O not/O good/O ./O 
And/O I/O say/O it/O is/O out/O of/O line/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O is/O out/O of/O line/O it/O was/O entirely/O out/O of/O line/O ,/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O ,/O for/O you/O to/O have/O signed/O this/O statement/O ,/O or/O indicated/O on/O this/O statement-and/O I/O am/O taking/O it/O for/O granted/O that/O this/O is/O your/O application-for/O you/O to/O have/O indicated/O that/O you/O were/O never/O a/O member/O of/O any/O organization/O that/O advocated/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ,/O and/O now/O ,/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O decline/O to/O state/O whether/O you/O are/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O has/O been/O officially/O designated/O by/O your/O Government/O as/O an/O organization/O which/O does/O precisely/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O a/O comment/O or/O a/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O I/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O comment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O give/O me/O the/O date/O ,/O please/O ,/O of/O that/O document/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
August/O 12/O ,/O 1947/O ,/O by/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Nelson/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O middle/O name/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
My/O middle/O name/O is/O Walfrid/PERSON ,/O spelled/O W-a-l-f-r-i-d/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O date/O indicated/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O again/O ,/O is/O an/O invasion/O of/O my/O rights/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O ,/O in/O which/O a/O citizen/O is/O guaranteed/O freedom/O from/O inquiry/O with/O respect/O to/O his/O beliefs/O and/O associations/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O no/O right/O to/O belong/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
You/O are/O speaking/O in/O terms/O that/O imply/O that/O you/O have/O a/O constitutional/O 3908/O COM1VUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O right/O to/O belong/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION which/O has/O been/O outlawed/O by/O the/O Government/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
You/O certainly/O have/O no/O right/O to/O belong/O to/O what/O has/O been/O judicially/O described/O as/O an/O international/O conspiracy/O ./O 
You/O have/O certain/O rights/O under/O the/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O ,/O but/O you/O have/O no/O right/O to/O enter/O into/O a/O conspiracy/O any/O more/O than/O you/O have/O a/O right/O to/O peddle/O narcotics/O ./O 
Or/O more/O than/O you/O have/O a/O right/O to/O violate/O any/O Federal/O statute/O ./O 
This/O business/O of/O rights/O of/O individuals/O to/O do/O whatever/O they/O see/O fit/O under/O any/O circumstances/O is/O a/O little/O far-fetched/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O record/O will/O not/O show/O any/O organizations/O to/O which/O I/O may/O have/O belonged/O or/O any/O narcotics/O I/O may/O have/O peddled/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O information/O on/O the/O narcotics/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O period/O 1945/O to/O 1947/O when/O you/O were/O serving/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION in/O Germany/LOCATION were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION we/O Americans/O worked/O alongside/O of/O our/O Allies/O in/O an/O attempt/O to/O rehabilitate/O the/O damage/O done/O by/O thought/O control/O and/O terroristic/O measures/O of/O the/O Hitler/PERSON regime/O ./O 
And/O I/O do/O not/O ,/O again/O ,/O feel/O that/O you/O have/O any/O right/O to/O infringe/O upon/O my/O rights/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O consider/O the/O Hitler/PERSON regime/O any/O worse/O or/O any/O better/O than/O the/O Communist/O regime/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O some/O rather/O positive/O opinions/O about/O the/O Hitler/PERSON regime/O ,/O based/O upon/O my/O observations/O there/O ./O 
I/O actually/O talked/O with/O some/O of/O the/O former/O concentration/O camp/O victims/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O heard/O about/O the/O concentration/O camps/O in/O Russia/LOCATION and/O Siberia/LOCATION ,/O and/O persecution/O of/O the/O Jews/O by/O the/O Russians/O and/O Communists/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O actually/O saw/O some/O of/O the/O bones/O of/O Buchenwald/LOCATION ,/O and/O some/O of/O the/O victims/O who/O I/O am/O sure/O would/O agree/O with/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION Justice/O Rutledge/PERSON when/O he/O stated/O that/O these/O folks/O would/O certainly/O have/O appreciated/O the/O worthwhileness/O of/O a/O fifth/O amendment/O in/O their/O country/O when/O they/O were/O being/O harassed/O by/O their/O own/O government/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O answer/O my/O question/O ./O 
Would/O you/O consider/O the/O Hitler/PERSON regime/O any/O worse/O or/O any/O betterthat/O was/O my/O question-than/O the/O Communist-Stalin/O regime/O which/O now/O even/O the/O Communists/O condemn/O as/O murderous/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O my/O opinion/O ,/O the/O reason/O why/O this/O committee/O brings/O out/O these/O terms/O of/O communism/O and/O nazismMr/O ./O 
SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
You/O brought/O up/O nazism/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O to/O infer/O that/O the/O witness/O can/O be/O tied/O in/O with/O them/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O not/O care/O to/O express/O my/O opinion/O on/O this/O matter/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O deny/O at/O this/O very/O moment/O that/O while/O you/O were/O working/O for/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Nations/ORGANIZATION and/O while/O you/O were/O an/O employee/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O allied/O military/O government/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O deny/O that/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3909/O Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O record/O will/O show/O that/O question/O has/O already/O been/O put/O and/O answered/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O 's/O answer/O it/O again/O ,/O now/O ./O 
Do/O you/O deny/O it/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
My/O record/O has/O been/O a/O dedication/O to/O upholding/O and/O defending/O the/O rights/O guaranteed/O under/O the/O American/O Constitution/O ,/O both/O as/O a/O schoolteacher/O where/O I/O taught/O that/O the/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O is/O something/O that/O should/O be/O used/O every/O day/O and/O not/O merely/O honored/O on/O the/O Fourth/O of/O July/O ,/O and/O in/O my/O work/O as/O a/O social/O worker/O where/O we/O work/O on/O a/O democratic/O basis/O ./O 
Recognizing/O every/O individual/O as/O important/O ,/O and/O his/O own/O dignity/O :/O he/O has/O the/O right/O to/O grow/O without/O Government/O oppression/O ./O 
I/O feel/O that/O my/O record/O will/O stand/O with/O anyone/O 's/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O the/O reason/O General/O MacArthur/PERSON discharged/O you/O and/O sent/O you/O back/O from/O Japan/LOCATION as/O a/O security/O risk/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O matter/O has/O already/O been/O handled/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O has/O it/O not/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O answer/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O n't/O you/O sent/O back/O as/O a/O security/O risk/O by/O this/O Government/O Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O first/O employment/O by/O the/O Government/O was/O between/O 1941/O and/O 1945/O ,/O in/O the/O State/O of/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O speaking/O of/O the/O Federal/O Government/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O while/O in/O the/O State/O of/O Washington/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O approaching/O the/O same/O matter/O from/O a/O different/O angle/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O continue/O to/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O privilege/O permitted/O me/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION during/O the/O period/O you/O were/O teaching/O school/O from/O 1949/O to/O 1951/O ,/O inclusive/O ?/O '/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O say/O that/O a/O schoolteacher/O should/O not/O be/O subjected/O by/O a/O congressional/O committee/O as/O to/O his/O political/O opinions/O ./O 
In/O my/O viewpoint/O ,/O a/O schoolteacher/O should/O be/O judged/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O his/O competence/O and/O his/O truthfulness/O in/O teaching/O his/O classes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O take/O it/O then/O that/O you/O are/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O a/O person/O who/O is/O subject/O to/O the/O directives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION should/O be/O permitted/O to/O teach/O in/O our/O public/O schools/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O repeat/O it/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O take/O it/O ,/O from/O what/O you/O have/O stated/O ,/O that/O you/O are/O of/O the/O opinion/O that/O a/O person/O who/O is/O subject/O to/O the/O directives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION should/O be/O permitted/O to/O teach/O in/O our/O public/O schools/O ./O 
Is/O that/O your/O view/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O asking/O for/O my/O opinion/O ./O 
I/O shall/O give/O it/O to/O you/O ./O 
In/O my/O opinion/O ,/O a/O schoolteacher-just/O as/O any/O other/O employee-should/O 3910/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O not/O be/O responsible/O to/O his/O employer/O for/O his/O political/O opinions/O or/O his/O private/O thoughts/O ./O 
A/O schoolteacher/O ,/O especially/O ,/O must/O be/O free/O to/O explore/O all/O knowledge/O and/O to/O expose/O his/O students/O to/O the/O facts/O so/O that/O the/O students/O themselves/O may/O form/O their/O opinions/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O a/O person/O subject/O to/O the/O directives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION free/O to/O do/O those/O things/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Still/O going/O on/O my/O own/O opinion/O ,/O I/O have/O seen/O in/O recent/O years/O statements/O where/O teachers/O have/O been/O discharged/O from/O their/O work/O after/O having/O been/O employed/O for/O sometimes/O 10/O ,/O 15/O ,/O and/O 20/O years/O ./O 
I/O must/O believe/O that/O this/O teacher/O must/O have/O been/O competent/O if/O he/O was/O held/O on/O his/O position/O through/O all/O this/O length/O of/O time/O ./O 
So/O I/O can/O not/O say/O whether/O these/O specific/O teachers/O were/O subject/O to/O anybody/O directing/O from/O outside/O ./O 
But/O I/O do/O say/O that/O these/O teachers/O who/O have/O been/O charged/O by/O this/O committee/O and/O similar/O committees/O as/O being/O under/O the/O subjugation/O of/O somebody/O else/O ,/O I/O submit/O that/O the/O fact/O that/O they/O did/O teach/O for/O such/O a/O long/O time/O and/O had/O such/O very/O fine/O records/O must/O be/O an/O indication/O that/O they/O were/O competent/O to/O teach/O and/O were/O retained/O by/O their/O administration/O as/O good/O teachers/O until/O such/O time/O as/O such/O committees/O as/O these/O came/O around/O and/O tried/O to/O bring/O in/O other/O factors/O rather/O than/O academic/O competence/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O not/O necessarily/O true/O ./O 
I/O know/O of/O some/O cases/O before/O this/O committee/O where/O teachers/O were/O released/O ,/O not/O because/O of/O their/O competency/O or/O lack/O of/O competency/O ,/O but/O because/O they/O lied/O on/O official/O documents/O ./O 
I/O think/O personally/O that/O a/O Communist/O teacher/O has/O got/O as/O much/O right/O in/O close/O contact/O with/O a/O young/O mind/O as/O a/O rattlesnake/O has/O in/O a/O baby/O 's/O crib/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION be/O -/O tween/O 1951/O and/O 1952/O when/O you/O served/O as/O an/O officer/O of/O the/O State/O parole/O system/O for/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O was/O with/O the/O State/O only/O a/O brief/O time/O ,/O but/O even/O in/O that/O short/O time/O I/O was/O commended/O by/O my/O superior/O as/O being/O one/O of/O the/O very/O promising/O officers/O ./O 
However/O ,/O with/O respect/O to/O this/O particular/O question/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O privilege/O provided/O to/O me/O under/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O tell/O your/O superior/O who/O commended/O you/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O signed/O your/O application/O form/O for/O employment/O with/O the/O State/O and/O were/O asked/O the/O question/O whether/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O not/O ,/O did/O you/O disclose/O that/O on/O that/O application/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O the/O application/O here/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
I/O think/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON would/O like/O to/O examine/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O sign/O such/O an/O application/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O your/O knowledge/O Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION Personnel/O Department/O has/O application/O forms/O as/O other/O public/O agencies/O do/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O it/O would/O be/O of/O value/O to/O the/O committee/O to/O let/O them/O examine/O it/O if/O it/O is/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O phrase/O it/O this/O way/O :/O OO/O IMUJNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 8911/O If/O you/O were/O required/O today/O to/O sign/O such/O an/O affidavit/O would/O you/O do/O so/O ,/O stating/O that/O you/O were/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O apparent/O intent/O of/O these/O remarks/O is/O to/O drive/O home/O the/O inference/O that/O this/O witness/O has/O done/O something/O that/O he/O should/O not/O have/O done/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O an/O attempt/O to/O find/O out/O from/O you/O whether/O you/O are/O depending/O upon/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O in/O good/O faith/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O only/O intent/O ./O 
And/O to/O also/O attempt/O to/O find/O out/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O sought/O the/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O good/O faith/O in/O the/O Constitution/O and/O all/O of/O the/O amendments/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
Pardon/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O a/O question/O before/O this/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDE/PERSON ./O 
The/O last/O question/O was/O would/O you/O sign/O such/O an/O application/O today/O ,/O or/O affidavit/O ,/O that/O you/O were/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O is/O the/O question/O propounded/O by/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDFR/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O his/O question/O was/O :/O If/O you/O were/O signing/O an/O application/O for/O employment/O with/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O which/O provided/O or/O asked/O the/O question/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O would/O you/O sign/O such/O an/O affidavit/O ./O 
I/O believe/O substantially/O that/O is/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O substantially/O it/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O would/O make/O a/O statement/O today/O on/O an/O official/O form/O which/O was/O a/O requisite/O of/O employment/O that/O he/O was/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O put/O the/O question/O ,/O and/O the/O form/O is/O not/O before/O this/O committee/O ,/O and/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O conjecture/O ./O 
And/O I/O would/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O it/O a/O matter/O of/O conjecture/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O matter/O of/O past/O history/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O sign/O it/O ?/O 
If/O you/O are/O ,/O as/O you/O say/O ,/O a/O good/O loyal/O American/O citizen/O with/O nothing/O in/O your/O background/O of/O which/O to/O be/O ashamed/O ,/O do/O you/O feel/O that/O you/O can/O not/O tell/O the/O committee/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION whether/O or/O not/O you/O would/O state/O affirmatively/O that/O you/O were/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O I/O have/O been/O and/O I/O am/O now/O a/O good/O loyal/O American/LOCATION citizen/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O I/O am/O not/O required/O to/O answer/O such/O question/O as/O the/O one/O just/O now/O put/O to/O me/O by/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O shall/O put/O a/O similar/O one/O ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION today/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O told/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O this/O matter/O may/O be/O approached/O from/O various/O angles/O ,/O but/O I/O still/O say/O that/O the/O Constitution/O is/O in/O effect/O ,/O and/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O supplemented/O by/O the/O fifth/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
77436-56-pt/O ./O 
10-2/O 3912/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O a/O question/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O just/O a/O couple/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O made/O a/O record/O of/O the/O witness/O '/O testimony/O of/O the/O agencies/O in/O Government/O in/O which/O he/O worked/O ,/O and/O manifestly/O he/O has/O had/O a/O very/O rich/O and/O varied/O experience/O and/O a/O very/O valuable/O experience/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O agree/O with/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O think/O the/O Government/O has/O had/O ,/O though/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O apparently/O he/O is/O very/O well/O informed/O on/O the/O history/O of/O nations/O and/O of/O government/O ,/O including/O the/O history/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O is/O very/O evident/O ./O 
I/O notice/O ,/O Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ,/O that/O you/O worked/O in/O the/O State/O of/O Washington/LOCATION in/O 1941/O to/O 1945/O for/O the/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Agriculture/ORGANIZATION in/O relief/O work/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O you/O know/O that/O in/O April/O of/O 1945/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON was/O kicked/O out/O of/O the/O American/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Shortly/O thereafter/O certainly/O every/O thinking/O adult/O ,/O American/LOCATION citizens/O ,/O should/O have/O been/O charged/O with/O knowledge/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION program/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O in/O the/O world/O was/O a/O conspiracy/O ,/O subversively/O ./O 
Certainly/O for/O the/O last/O several/O years/O it/O has/O been/O a/O matter/O of/O knowledge/O to/O you/O as/O a/O schoolteacher/O and/O a/O student/O of/O government/O that/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION courts/O and/O Congress/ORGANIZATION have/O declared/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O America/LOCATION to/O be/O an/O international/O conspiracy/O based/O upon/O the/O use/O ,/O if/O necessary/O in/O their/O judgment/O ,/O of/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O mentioned/O that/O is/O I/O know/O that/O you/O know/O history/O perhaps/O as/O well/O as/O I/O do/O or/O better/O ./O 
But/O I/O know/O that/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O history/O ,/O and/O so/O do/O you/O ./O 
Very/O frankly/O ,/O the/O thing/O that/O amazes/O me/O ,/O even/O recognizing/O your/O rights/O to/O plead/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments-which/O we/O all/O certainly/O do/O ,/O if/O it/O is/O done/O in/O good/O faith/O and/O honestly-is/O that/O you/O would/O come/O here/O this/O morning/O ,/O and/O not/O be/O in/O a/O position/O where/O you/O could/O honestly/O say/O you/O are/O not/O today/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O is/O the/O thing/O that/O amazes/O me/O ./O 
I/O can/O make/O allowance/O for/O thinking/O ,/O patriotic/O American/LOCATION citizens/O who/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION back/O in/O 1941/O ,/O 1942/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O 1944/O ,/O 1945/O ,/O and/O some/O of/O them/O in/O 1946/O before/O it/O was/O known/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O conspiracy/O founded/O upon/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Before/O it/O was/O generally/O known/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Before/O it/O was/O generally/O known/O ./O 
But/O you/O ,/O sir/O ,/O from/O your/O training/O ,/O knew/O it/O ahead/O of/O most/O of/O us/O ./O 
From/O your/O education/O and/O from/O your/O statements/O I/O can/O draw/O certain/O deductions/O based/O upon/O my/O own/O experience/O ./O 
And/O so/O there/O came/O a/O time/O ,/O in/O my/O book/O ,/O when/O you/O ,/O as/O a/O schoolteacher/O and/O a/O patriotic/O American/LOCATION citizen/O ,/O should/O have/O withdrawn/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
By/O that/O I/O am/O inferring/O what/O I/O know/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O practical/O experience/O ,/O that/O there/O was/O a/O time/O when/O you/O were/O pretty/O close/O to/O it/O ./O 
You/O have/O n't/O admitted/O ever/O joining/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O inferring/O it/O ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O under/O the/O law/O there/O is/O no/O inference/O to/O be/O drawn/O ;/O there/O is/O no/O presumption/O to/O be/O drawn/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O am/O glad/O you/O said/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O know/O what/O the/O decisions/O of/O the/O courts/O are/O as/O well/O as/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3913/O Mr./O SCHEER/PERSON ./O 
That/O does/O n't/O prevent/O us/O from/O relying/O on/O other/O sworn/O testimony/O ,/O however/O ,/O in/O arriving/O at/O a/O conclusion/O of/O this/O man/O 's/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O about/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O n't/O have/O to/O have/O an/O inference/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O thing/O that/O amazes/O me/O is/O that/O you/O ,/O as/O a/O schoolteacher/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O a/O State/O official/O and/O former/O Government/O official/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O in/O foreign/O countries/O as/O well/O as/O in/O this/O country/O ,/O have/O not/O as/O yet/O put/O yourself/O in/O the/O position/O where/O you/O could/O frankly/O say/O to/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Congress-about/O which/O you/O have/O been/O teaching/O schoolchildren-it/O might/O have/O been/O some/O of/O my/O children/O ,/O which/O makes/O me/O shiver/O to/O think/O of/O it/O -/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ''/O if/O you/O were/O ``/O back/O in/O 1942/O until/O 1946/O even/O ,/O but/O I/O got/O my/O fill/O and/O I/O got/O out/O ./O ''/O 
That/O is/O the/O thing/O that/O amazes/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Nelson/PERSON ,/O that/O a/O man/O with/O your/O background/O is/O n't/O able/O to/O say/O this/O morning/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O ''/O 
You/O may/O think/O that/O is/O an/O invasion/O by/O us/O to/O make/O that/O inquiry/O ./O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O you/O do/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O amazes/O me/O ,/O to/O be/O frank/O with/O you/O ,/O because/O I/O used/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O California/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Board/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Education/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O know/O some/O of/O the/O problems/O we/O had/O ./O 
One/O more/O statement/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
And/O may/O I/O make/O this/O observationMr/O ./O 
NELSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O express/O my/O amazement/O also/O ,/O Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ?/O 
I/O am/O really/O amazed/O at/O the/O activities/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O understand/O the/O temptation/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O witness/O to/O reply/O to/O a/O lecture/O ./O 
Each/O member/O has/O a/O right/O to/O conduct/O himself/O as/O he/O pleases/O ./O 
I/O do/O the/O best/O I/O can/O to/O keep/O order/O and/O an/O orderly/O procedure/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O respectfully/O request/O that/O the/O witness/O be/O permitted/O to/O answer/O an/O argument/O that/O was/O put/O to/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O arguing/O ,/O Madam/O Attorney/O ./O 
I/O am/O making/O a/O statement/O of/O my/O position/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O this/O witness/O would/O have/O a/O like/O privilege/O ./O 
I/O respectfully/O urge/O that/O you/O give/O him/O the/O privilege/O that/O your/O colleagues/O have/O been/O given/O all/O morning/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON will/O proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O just/O wish/O this/O witness/O would/O understand/O my/O position/O as/O a/O mere/O Congressman/O ./O 
I/O recognize/O your/O right/O and/O every/O American/LOCATION citizen/O 's/O right/O to/O think/O what/O he/O pleases/O and/O to/O preach/O what/O he/O pleases/O and/O to/O write/O what/O he/O pleases/O and/O to/O live/O the/O way/O he/O pleases/O ./O 
But/O he/O has/O to/O do/O it/O within/O the/O four/O corners/O of/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
And/O I/O do/O n't/O recognize/O your/O right/O ,/O nor/O the/O right/O of/O any/O other/O American/LOCATION citizen/O to/O continue/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O any/O organization/O or/O any/O association/O that/O has/O been/O declared/O a/O conspiracy/O by/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O because/O that/O makes/O it/O illegal/O ./O 
So/O I/O say/O to/O you/O ,/O sir/O ,/O as/O one/O American/O to/O another/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O recognize/O your/O right/O to/O come/O before/O any/O group/O of/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Congressmen/ORGANIZATION ,/O lawfully/O on/O an/O investigation/O ,/O and/O claim/O it/O is/O your/O right-if/O you/O want/O to/O claim/O it-to/O still/O be/O a/O member/O ,/O if/O you/O ever/O have/O been/O ,/O of/O a/O conspiracy/O that/O has/O been/O declared/O illegal/O by/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION the/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION 3914/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O States/O ./O 
And/O I/O hope/O you/O will/O get/O into/O a/O position/O where/O you/O do/O not/O disagree/O with/O me/O ,/O at/O least/O on/O that/O one/O point/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O must/O say/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O that/O we/O will/O agree/O that/O you/O have/O the/O right/O to/O claim/O the/O privilege/O ,/O as/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON says/O ,/O and/O decline/O to/O answer/O under/O the/O provisions/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O his/O point/O is/O that/O he/O is/O criticizing/O your/O decision/O and/O judgment/O in/O so/O proceeding/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
Which/O he/O has/O no/O right/O to/O do/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O say/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
And/O he/O has/O no/O right/O to/O draw/O inferences/O ,/O which/O he/O has/O consistently/O drawn/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Now/O what/O do/O you/O have/O to/O say/O ?/O 
Mr./O NELSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O certainly/O like/O to/O express/O my/O amazement/O also/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Only/O a/O few/O days/O ago/O I/O was/O sitting/O in/O this/O room/O when/O I/O heard/O the/O Congressman/O speak/O of/O some/O of/O the/O eminent/O citizens/O of/O this/O community/O as/O rats/O and/O mice/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O deny/O it/O ./O 
You/O heard/O nothing/O of/O the/O kind/O ./O 
Mr./O NELsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O heard/O it/O ./O 
And/O I/O must/O say/O that/O if/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON fancies/O himself/O as/O a/O political/O pied/O piper/O who/O is/O going/O to/O take/O the/O mice/O out/O of/O the/O city/O of/O Hamlin/LOCATION ,/O constitutional/O liberties/O ,/O he/O had/O better/O take/O a/O second/O look/O ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O not/O accept/O the/O inferences/O that/O have/O been/O made/O that/O because/O a/O citizen/O ,/O in/O his/O own/O protection/O ,/O from/O having/O observed/O how/O this/O committee/O operates/O ,/O answers/O the/O questions/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O and/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O that/O any/O inference/O unfair/O to/O him/O should/O be/O drawn/O ./O 
The/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O spoken/O on/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O that/O should/O be/O enough/O to/O silence/O this/O sort/O of/O activity/O ./O 
And/O I/O hope/O that/O my/O opportunity/O of/O being/O here/O today/O can/O help/O to/O hasten/O the/O day/O when/O this/O committee/O will/O no/O longer/O be/O in/O existence/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
If/O the/O officer/O can/O identify/O any/O person/O responsible/O for/O that/O demonstration/O ,/O they/O will/O be/O removed/O from/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O a/O question/O before/O the/O witness/O ,/O Mr./O Chair/O -/O man/O ?/O 
Is/O there/O a/O question/O before/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O pending/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O additional/O questions/O ?/O '/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mrs./O ROSENBERG/PERSON ./O 
Is/O the/O witness/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Arthur/PERSON Globe/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O testimony/O which/O you/O are/O about/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3915/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O ARTHUR/O GLOBE/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ESTHER/PERSON SHANDLER/PERSON Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O request/O the/O committee/O to/O keep/O these/O photographers/O away/O from/O me/O ,/O if/O you/O do/O n't/O mind/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O object/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
The/O press/O has/O every/O right/O to/O operate/O ./O 
It/O is/O one/O of/O the/O freedoms/O contained/O in/O the/O famous/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O ,/O upon/O which/O the/O witnesses/O propound/O at/O length/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Arthur/PERSON Globe/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O accompanying/O the/O witness/O please/O identify/O herself/O for/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mrs./O SHANDLER/PERSON ./O 
Esther/PERSON Shandler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Globe/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Chicago/LOCATION ,/O 11/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
February/O 26,1918/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
In/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O lived/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Something/O over/O 30/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O took/O a/O bachelor/O of/O arts/O degree/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O in/O 1942/O ,/O and/O after/O my/O Army/O service/O of/O 40/O months/O ,/O I/O returned/O to/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O graduate/O work/O ,/O and/O completed/O 65/O units/O in/O clinical/O psychology/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O period/O of/O your/O military/O service/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
From/O September/O of/O 1942/O until/O January/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O your/O additional/O graduate/O training/O after/O you/O returned/O from/O the/O service/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O again/O state/O what/O that/O was/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Three/O to/O four/O years/O of/O study/O in/O the/O field/O of/O clinical/O psychology/O and/O related/O fields/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O completed/O your/O course/O of/O formal/O training/O then/O about/O what/O date/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O quite/O complete/O my/O formal/O training/O ./O 
I/O took/O the/O course/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O approximate/O date/O when/O you/O finished/O your/O formal/O training/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
It/O extended/O over/O a/O period/O of/O approximately/O 4/O to/O 4/O :/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O what/O time/O was/O that/O work/O terminated/O ?/O 
I/O have/O asked/O that/O three/O times/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
You/O asked/O the/O actual/O day/O ,/O hour/O ,/O and/O minute/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O ask/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O can/O give/O it/O to/O you/O as/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O :/O From/O 1946/O to/O 1950/O approximately/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O first/O time/O you/O have/O done/O that/O ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O profession/O since/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
My/O profession/O has/O been/O that/O of/O a/O psychologist/O and/O that/O of/O a/O social/O worker/O ,/O both/O areas/O concerned/O with/O mental/O health/O ./O 
3916/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O have/O you/O been/O employed/O in/O your/O work/O as/O a/O social/O worker/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Would/O you/O be/O more/O specific/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O employment/O as/O a/O social/O worker/O since/O 1950/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O find/O the/O questioning/O as/O to/O my/O employment/O a/O little/O difficult/O to/O accept/O under/O the/O circumstances/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O quite/O see/O how/O my/O employment/O ,/O my/O employment/O experience/O ,/O present/O or/O past/O ,/O can/O be/O the/O concern/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
I/O do/O my/O work/O and/O I/O do/O it/O as/O well/O as/O I/O can/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O situation/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O understand/O the/O line/O of/O your/O questioning/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ScHERER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON 's/O question/O with/O reference/O to/O his/O employment/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O proper/O identification/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O request/O of/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O the/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O have/O been/O employed/O as/O a/O social/O worker/O ,/O or/O at/O least/O in/O social/O agencies/O twice/O ./O 
The/O present/O employment/O is/O that/O of/O a/O social/O worker/O ,/O and/O the/O past/O employment/O was/O also/O ./O 
In/O 1950/O I/O worked/O as/O a/O social/O worker/O in/O a/O social/O agency/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
In/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
By/O whom/O are/O you/O presently/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
By/O the/O County/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O social/O worker/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O attend/O school/O between/O 1946/O and/O 1950/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O answered/O that/O question/O already/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEB/PERSON ./O 
You/O said/O you/O attended/O school/O ,/O but/O you/O did/O n't/O state/O where/O ,/O according/O to/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O period/O that/O you/O were/O taking/O graduate/O work/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O '/O Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O familiar/O with/O an/O organization/O in/O that/O school/O composed/O largely/O of/O graduate/O students/O known/O as/O the/O John/ORGANIZATION Reed/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
My/O familiarity/O or/O lack/O of/O familiarity/O with/O any/O organization/O that/O might/O exist/O in/O the/O country/O today/O is/O entirely/O my/O own/O business/O ,/O and/O termed/O under/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
This/O is/O a/O matter/O of/O personal/O knowledge/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O any/O right/O to/O inquire/O into/O my/O personal/O knowledge/O in/O this/O or/O any/O other/O respect/O since/O they/O can/O not/O legislate/O what/O I/O do/O nor/O what/O I/O do/O not/O know/O ,/O or/O what/O I/O intend/O to/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O ScHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O directed/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
Finding/O the/O question/O completely/O out/O of/O line/O as/O far/O as/O my/O rights/O as/O a/O citizen/O are/O concerned/O ,/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3917/O under/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O of/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O John/ORGANIZATION Reed/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION while/O in/O attendance/O at/O the/O university/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
This/O question/O is/O even/O more/O objectionable/O than/O the/O first/O one/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O I/O previously/O stated/O ,/O and/O I/O object/O to/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O acquainted/O with/O any/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O a/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION known/O as/O the/O John/ORGANIZATION Reed/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O observe/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O since/O 1950/O of/O any/O persons/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O John/ORGANIZATION Reed/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION while/O you/O were/O at/O the/O university/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O feel/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O if/O you/O want/O information/O about/O names/O ,/O people/O ,/O and/O anything/O else/O that/O you/O might/O be/O concerned/O with/O ,/O I/O suggest/O that/O you/O get/O one/O of/O your/O trained/O seals/O up/O here/O and/O ask/O them/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O ./O 
Anyone/O or/O any/O associations/O I/O may/O have/O had/O in/O the/O past/O or/O expect/O to/O have/O in/O the/O future/O are/O entirely/O my/O own/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O ,/O as/O it/O is/O an/O invasion/O of/O my/O rights/O ,/O invasion/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O all/O the/O American/O citizens/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ,/O both/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O ,/O as/O previously/O stated/O ,/O for/O previous/O reasons/O ,/O and/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O this/O witness/O say/O he/O served/O in/O the/O Armed/O Forces/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
While/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Armed/O Forces/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O Witness/O ,/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O ./O 
First/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ./O 
You/O have/O no/O right/O to/O ask/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O one/O question/O ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O knowledge/O or/O information/O of/O subversive/O or/O communistic/O activities/O of/O any/O person/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O not/O funny/O ,/O Witness/O ,/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O rather/O difficult/O question/O to/O answer/O ,/O since/O it/O contains/O so/O many/O elements/O that/O are/O implied/O and/O have/O not/O been/O established/O since/O I/O have/O been/O on/O the/O stand/O ./O 
As/O far/O as/O I/O am/O concerned/O ,/O these/O implications/O have/O not/O been/O established/O in/O the/O country/O at/O all/O ./O 
The/O whole/O ideaMr/O ./O 
SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O there/O has/O been/O no/O establishment/O in/O this/O country/O of/O subversive/O activities/O when/O our/O atomic/O secrets/O were/O stolen/O and/O 3918/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O now/O rest/O in/O the/O archives/O of/O the/O Kremlin/O because/O of/O subversives/O in/O Government/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O confers/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
I/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O discuss/O this/O or/O any/O other/O question/O you/O might/O ask/O meMr/O ./O 
SCITEREn/O ./O 
When/O you/O are/O not/O under/O oath/O ./O 
Mr./O GLOBE/O ./O 
When/O I/O am/O not/O on/O the/O stand/O under/O the/O circumstances/O of/O this/O committee/O ;/O where/O I/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O discuss/O it/O under/O oath/O if/O you/O ,/O too/O ,/O were/O under/O oath/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Under/O the/O circumstances/O I/O feel/O that/O I/O am/O ,/O since/O I/O am/O a/O target/O for/O what/O seems/O to/O be/O and/O has/O been/O proved/O to/O be/O quite/O unprincipled/O attacks/O that/O are/O aimed/O at/O maligning/O and/O destroying/O a/O person/O 's/O working/O ability/O ,/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O as/O previously/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O excused/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O stand/O in/O recess/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 5/O minutes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O a/O short/O recess/O was/O taken/O ,/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Jackson/PERSON and/O Scherer/PERSON being/O present/O ./O -RRB-/O 
-LRB-/O The/O committee/O was/O reconvened/O upon/O the/O expiration/O of/O the/O recess/O ;/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O and/O Jackson/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Call/O your/O next/O witness/O ,/O please/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Don/PERSON Ohristlieb/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDE/PERSON ./O 
Please/O be/O seated/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O DON/PERSON CHRISTLIEB/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Don/PERSON Christlieb/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
That/O is/O C-h-r-i-s-t-l-i-e-b/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O the/O practice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O advise/O all/O wit/O -/O nesses/O who/O appear/O before/O it/O that/O they/O have/O the/O right/O to/O have/O counsel/O with/O them/O if/O they/O desire/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O CHRISTLnEB/O ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O right/O to/O confer/O with/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O during/O the/O period/O of/O their/O questioning/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Fullerton/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O October/O 10/O ,/O 1912/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
In/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O profession/O or/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Musician/O ,/O instrumentalist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O professionally/O engaged/O as/O an/O instrumentalist/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1936/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3919/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLRB/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O the/O public/O schools/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION through/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION Junior/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O employment/O record/O since/O completion/O of/O your/O school/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1937/O I/O have/O been/O employed/O as/O a/O musician/O in/O studio/O recording/O orchestras/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O worked/O in/O every/O studio/O at/O one/O time/O or/O other/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
Was/O your/O employment/O interrupted/O by/O military/O service/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRIBTIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
In/O 1934-1935/O I/O enlisted/O for/O 2/O years/O and/O 2/O months/O in/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O have/O an/O honorable/O discharge/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O as/O a/O musician/O you/O were/O requested/O to/O affiliate/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O become/O affiliated/O ?/O 
Mr./O CaISTunEB/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O did/O ./O 
In/O ,/O I/O think-before/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ,/O in/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O remain/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLEB/PERSON ./O 
As/O nearly/O as/O I/O can/O determine/O it/O was/O about/O the/O end/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O not/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION since/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O have/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O circumstances/O of/O your/O affiliation/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O first/O place/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O I/O hoped/O for/O a/O form/O of/O society/O which/O could/O avoid/O the/O extremes/O of/O depression/O and/O war/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O that/O the/O threat/O of/O fascism/O at/O that/O time/O involving/O the/O world/O was/O a/O period/O of/O cynicism/O and/O pessimism/O in/O late/O 1939/O and/O the/O late/O 1940/O 's/O ./O 
And/O I/O believe/O while/O many/O people/O were/O window-shopping/O for/O socialism/O here/O ,/O I/O went/O in/O and/O made/O a/O purchase/O of/O merchandise/O I/O considered/O unreturnable/O and/O too/O hot/O to/O handle/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O been/O returning/O small/O pieces/O painfully/O year/O after/O year/O ,/O and/O I/O hope/O I/O can/O return/O a/O small/O piece/O today/O that/O is/O left/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O how/O were/O you/O recruited/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Would/O you/O tell/O us/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTmEB/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O it/O is/O a/O very/O individualistic/O thing/O with/O musicians/O ,/O in/O the/O Musicians/O Branch/O ./O 
It/O is/O one/O of/O the/O few/O times/O when/O party/O work/O is/O such/O ,/O musicians/O '/O work/O in/O the/O branch/O is/O such/O ,/O that/O the/O individual/O personality/O and/O ingenuity/O and/O training/O and/O talent/O is/O given/O full/O play/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O usually/O made/O by/O contact/O of/O an/O individual/O seeking/O to/O recruit/O a/O person/O they/O may/O consider/O eligible/O ./O 
That/O person/O is/O usually/O asked/O to/O read/O at/O that/O time/O the/O Daily/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION and/O many/O articles/O of/O that/O sort/O ,/O which/O I/O was/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O describing/O now/O what/O happened/O in/O your/O own/O case/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O similar/O cases/O around/O me/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O that/O after/O reading/O of/O such/O articles/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O we/O were/O approached/O by/O members/O that/O were/O in/O the/O party/O and/O asked/O how/O we/O felt/O about/O what/O we/O were/O reading/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ,/O and/O if/O we/O would/O care/O to/O attend/O Marxist/O classes/O ./O 
3920/O coMMVUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ;/O CAL/ORGANIZATION F./ORGANIZATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O Marxist/O classes/O ?/O 
Mr./O CIRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
For/O how/O long/O a/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTIEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O only/O attended/O about/O four/O sessions/O ,/O as/O such/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O teachers/O of/O those/O sessions/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
I/O could/O only/O guess/O that/O it/O was/O someone/O sent/O from/O the/O section/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O saw/O him/O after/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O ``/O section/O ,/O ''/O do/O you/O mean/O a/O section/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLrEB/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O called/O the/O Northwest/ORGANIZATION Section/ORGANIZATION ,/O under/O which/O the/O branches/O ,/O the/O musicians/O particular/O branch/O came/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O just/O what/O happened/O when/O you/O completed/O that/O course/O of/O study/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
After/O the/O completion/O of/O the/O four/O sessions/O I/O was/O asked/O if/O I/O still/O wished/O to/O join/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O did-which/O I/O did-the/O branch/O would/O then/O meet/O and/O vote/O on/O my/O acceptance/O ,/O which/O they/O did/O ./O 
And/O that/O was/O all/O the/O formality/O needed/O to/O attend/O the/O first/O meeting/O of/O the/O branch/O as/O such/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O person/O by/O whom/O you/O were/O recruited/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O where/O Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON is/O now/O Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O he/O is/O in/O Europe/LOCATION at/O the/O present/O time-I/O think/O France/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O other/O persons/O who/O had/O taken/O this/O course/O with/O you/O ,/O or/O this/O reading/O ,/O this/O study/O course/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O there/O were/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O who/O were/O also/O recruited/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O their/O names/O Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
There/O were/O Haakon/PERSON Berg-Mr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O both/O names/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRSTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
H-a-a-k-o-n/O B-e-r-g/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O had/O taken/O this/O study/O course/O with/O you/O and/O went/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRSTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O he/O withdrew/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION before/O you/O did/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O he/O went/O into/O defense/O work/O and/O then/O into/O the/O Army/O quite/O soon/O afterward/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O the/O other/O persons/O from/O your/O study/O group/O who/O went/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
There/O were/O George/PERSON PepperMr/PERSON ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Was/O George/O Pepper/O a/O musician/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O that/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O there/O any/O others/O that/O you/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
There/O were/O their/O wives/O also/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O the/O name/O of/O the/O wife/O of/O George/PERSON Pepper/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLEB/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O Joy/O ./O 
And/O with/O Mr./O Berg/PERSON it/O was/O Ann/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O were/O taken/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION were/O you/O assigned/O to/O an/O organized/O group/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIfITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O AN/O GLES/O ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3921/O Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
That/O particular/O branch/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O called/O branch/O O./O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Branch/O O./O Was/O that/O the/O musicians/O '/O branch/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHOPITLIEB/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O remain/O a/O member/O of/O that/O same/O branch/O during/O your/O entire/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O were/O you/O at/O any/O time/O transferred/O to/O another/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O CHRISTLIEB/PERSON ./O 
I/O never/O knew/O it/O to/O be/O under/O any/O other/O title/O ,/O in/O my/O experience/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O how/O frequently/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION met/O ?/O 
