1463-2/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O INTHE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 8/O HEARING/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-THIRD/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O NOVEMBER/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 81747/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1934/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-ASIERICAN/O ACrIVITIES/O Ur/O `/O lizn/O STATES/O Houst/O ovr/O REI'RErXTATI/O 1/O %/O 8/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Illinoi/O ,/O Chairman/O BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION FRANCIS/O &/O W./O ~/O ALTER/O ./O 
Pennslvania/PERSON DONALD/PERSON L/PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION MLOROANMi.MOUJLDER/O ./O 
Missouri/O KIT/O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Michigan/LOCATION CLYDE/PERSON DOTLE/PERSON ./O 
Californaa/PERSON GORDON/PERSON HL/PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FUAZIER/PERSON ./O 
JaL/O ,/O Tennse/O ROBRT/O L/O ,/O KC10zig/O ,/O COuNSel/O FSANX/O 8/O ./O 
TAYRUNCR/O ./O 
Jr./PERSON ,/O Covatl/PERSON LouIS/PERSON J./PERSON HR88ueLL/PERSON ,/O Chief/O Inreatigofor/O THoMAB/O W./O i19AL1/O ./O 
Sr./O ./O 
ChifE/O Clerk/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON Nixox/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Resarch/O CONTENTS/O November/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O testimony/O of/O -/O -----/O --/O --/O --/O --/O -/O Max/PERSON N./PERSON Benoit/PERSON 850/O -RRB-/O 8/O --------/O John/PERSON Brown/PERSON W/O illllam/O It/O ./O 
AllazmL/O --/O ./O 
./O 
-------/O ./O 
-/O ./O 
./O 
--/O ./O 
./O 
-/O ./O 
--/O ./O 
--/O 3511/O Wton/O -/O eln/O -/O ./O 
--------/O .../O -/O 8S/O 1061Z/O -----/O -------/O &/O -LSB-/O PuLTo/O LAw/O 601/O ,/O 79TH/O CONGRESS/O The/O legislation/O under/O which/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O operates/O is/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ,/O 79th/O Congress/ORGANIZATION -LSB-/O 1946/O -RSB-/O ,/O chapter/O 753/O ,/O 2d/O session/O ,/O which/O provides/O :/O Be/O it/O enacted/O by/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION and/O House/ORGANIZATION of/O Repre/O #entative/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION in/O Congress/ORGANIZATION assembled/O ,/O \*/O 0/O 0/O PART/O 2-RULES/O OF/O THE/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O RuLz/O X/O aSE/O ,121/O ./O 
STANDING/O ooMMrTIZ5s/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O lOWERS/O AND/O DtXU/O O/O 0oMUrTEMS/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O Investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 11/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O Instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O il/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O In/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/O In/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/O Is/O not/O In/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O lnvestgation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O It/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O Investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Aetvitles/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/O Is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O bearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O It/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O Issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULEM/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 83D/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 8/O ,/O 193/O Ruma/PERSON X/O cOMMuZIuB/O TANDWNO/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O S/O S/O S/O S/O 5/O 5/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O S/O S/O S/O S/O S/O Rucz/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIM/O Or/O COUMrrTE/O 1/O ?/O 
./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O Investigntions/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O In/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propuganda/O that/O Is/O Instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O In/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/O In/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/O If/O the/O House/O Is/O not/O In/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O Investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O Issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
vt/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 8/O MONDAY/O ,/O NOVEMBER/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O UNITmD/O STATES/O CommT-r/O ./O 
IOUsE/O OF/O REPRFsENTATlVZ/O -/O ,/O ON/O Ux-AMMEICAN/O Acriv/O '/O T/O s/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Anyeoe/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O '/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 9/O :/O 30/O a/O in/O in/O room/O G-39/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O lion/O ./O 
Donald/PERSON L/PERSON Jackson/PERSON presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON and/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsON/PERSON ./O 
By/O direction/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O there/O is/O convened/O herewith/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O that/O committee/O ,/O the/O subcommittee/O consisting/O of/O Congressman/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O with/O Congressman/O Jackson/PERSON as/O acting/O chairman/O ./O 
Areyou/PERSON ready/O to/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavennerl/PERSON Mr./O `/O AVENNFMt/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O MAX/O N./O DEIIOFF/O Mr./O TAvENNZR/O ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O nameI/O Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
Max/PERSON Benoff/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O testified/O before/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION on/O March/O 24,1953/O ,/O did/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O BENorF/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O air/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNIM/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O been/O informed/O that/O you/O desire/O to/O appear/O again/O before/O the/O committee/O this/O morning/O ./O 
Mr./O BENoFr/O ./O 
Ye/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNF.R/O ./O 
Wili/PERSON you/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O pleaIse/O the/O reason/O for/O your/O desire/O to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O and/O proceed/O to/O make/O such/O statements/O as/O you/O desire/O ./O 
Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O thank/O you/O first/O for/O allowing/O me/O to/O appear/O here/O `/O Released/O by/O tie/O fall/O committee/O ./O 
3Mo/O 3502/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O DomLw/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O witness/O is/O here/O without/O legal/O counsel/O ./O 
I/O wonder/O if/O that/O is/O entirely/O at/O your/O own/O choice/O ./O 
Mr./O BcwOF/PERSON ?/O 
./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DoylE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O willing/O to/O proceed/O without/O private/O counsel/O with/O youI/O Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O read/O a/O statement/O which/O I/O have/O prepared/O ?/O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O appeared/O before/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O I/O was/O motivated/O by/O only/O one/O desire/O :/O To/O draw/O a/O distinct/O line/O between/O my/O confused/O past/O and/O my/O clear/O knowledge/O and/O distinction/O of/O the/O truth/O which/O I/O see/O today/O ./O 
I/O not/O only/O wanted/O to/O make/O amends/O for/O personal/O mistakes/O and/O misassociations/O ,/O but/O overcoming/O personal/O pride/O and/O false/O consideration/O which/O tied/O me/O to/O an/O untenable/O position/O ,/O I/O wanted/O to/O be/O accepted/O by/O the/O movement/O which/O is/O now/O afoot/O and/O which/O I/O have/O now/O learned/O to/O respect/O as/O the/O only/O salvation/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O movement/O to/O stamp/O out/O communism/O ./O 
I/O used/O the/O privilege/O of/O appearing/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O order/O to/O make/O a/O public/O break/O and/O declare/O myself/O as/O an/O ally/O of/O the/O anti-Communist/O forces/O ./O 
Unknowingly/O I/O have/O been/O drawn/O into/O a/O movement/O ,/O the/O true/O nature/O of/O which/O I/O never/O understood/O ,/O which/O now/O turns/O out/O to/O have/O been/O part/O of/O a/O subversive/O activity/O which/O can/O not/O be/O tolerated/O by/O anyone/O who/O calls/O himself/O an/O American/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O has/O become/O clear/O to/O me/O that/O the/O Communists/O have/O declared/O war/O on/O us/O and/O they/O intend/O to/O win/O this/O war/O with/O every/O means/O at/O their/O disposal/O ,/O aboveboard/O or/O underground/O ./O 
After/O my/O testimony/O I/O have/O found/O that/O the/O impression/O created/O by/O me/O on/O the/O stand/O was/O not/O what/O I/O intended/O ./O 
Where/O I/O thought/O that/O I/O had/O been/O 100/O percent/O cooperative/O ,/O some/O people/O whose/O patriotism/O has/O been/O above/O reproach/O ,/O have/O expressed/O their/O disappointment/O in/O the/O manner/O and/O contents/O of/O my/O statements/O ./O 
Looking/O back/O ,/O I/O must/O say/O that/O I/O could/O have/O been/O more/O definite/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O like/O to/O submit/O that/O at/O that/O time/O I/O was/O only/O intent/O upon/O declaring/O myself/O as/O a/O cooperative/O witness/O and/O had/O left/O the/O manner/O and/O extent/O of/O the/O questioning/O to/O the/O committee/O ./O 
It/O was/O only/O human/O of/O me/O to/O try/O and/O make/O my/O appearance/O as/O short/O as/O possible/O ./O 
When/O the/O committee/O had/O no/O more/O questions/O and/O I/O was/O thanked/O for/O my/O testimony/O ,/O I/O stepped/O off/O the/O stand/O ,/O relieved/O and/O convinced/O that/O I/O had/O done/O my/O duty/O and/O accomplished/O my/O purpose/O ./O 
However/O ,/O as/O long/O as/O even/O one/O doubt/O remains/O among/O people/O whose/O fight/O against/O communism/O I/O admire/O and/O eagerly/O support/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O I/O have/O not/O done/O enough/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O what/O else/O I/O can/O do/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O some/O of/O the/O facts/O that/O unfortunately/O seem/O to/O be/O on/O record/O against/O me/O ,/O and/O which/O I/O can/O less/O explain/O than/O some/O people/O who/O may/O be/O experts/O in/O the/O structure/O ,/O organization/O ,/O and/O workings/O of/O the/O Communist/O menace/O and/O disease/O ./O 
But/O I/O want/O to/O reiterate/O that/O I/O would/O go/O to/O any/O extent/O to/O help/O uncover/O facts/O that/O I/O may/O not/O be/O aware/O of/O if/O ,/O with/O the/O help/O of/O more/O competent/O People/O ,/O I/O would/O be/O assisted/O in/O remembering/O ./O 
The/O basic/O facts/O ;/O as/O given/O in/O my/O short/O testimony/O ,/O are/O still/O ,/O to/O my/O best/O recollection/O ,/O the/O sum/O total/O of/O my/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION affiliations/O ./O 
The/O names/O mentioned/O by/O me/O are/O still/O more/O or/O less/O all/O the/O names/O that/O I/O can/O identify/O with/O the/O degree/O of/O certainty/O required/O under/O oath/O ./O 
CoMUnST/O avrrIs/O iN/O TH/O LOS/O ANaELES/O AnzA/O 3503/O However/O ,/O a/O great/O deal/O can/O sometimes/O be/O achieved/O if/O good/O people/O get/O together/O and/O cooperate/O ./O 
I/O would/O be/O happy/O and/O privileged/O in/O doing/O my/O duty/O as/O a/O citizen/O if/O I/O were/O permitted/O to/O dig/O into/O my/O past/O ,/O with/O the/O help/O of/O the/O investigator/O or/O even/O a/O group/O of/O citizens/O whom/O I/O respect/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O unearth/O any/O more/O clues/O that/O might/O be/O of/O any/O value/O in/O our/O fight/O against/O the/O common/O enemy/O Do/O I/O need/O to/O add/O that/O I/O am/O ,/O aove/O and/O beyond/O my/O above/O statements/O ,/O ready/O ,/O willing/O ,/O and/O eager/O to/O take/O up/O arms/O ,/O literally/O or/O any/O other/O way/O ,/O to/O do/O my/O little/O share/O as/O a/O citizen/O ?/O 
Mr./O JAcKsox/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O TANT/O -RSB-/O NTE/O ./O 
Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ,/O you/O testified/O when/O before/O the/O committee/O previously/O of/O the/O character/O of/O work/O in/O which/O you/O had/O been/O engaged/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION prior/O to/O your/O coming/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION in/O the/O year/O 1943/O ./O 
You/O were/O asked/O the/O question/O at/O that/O time/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O had/O been/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O manner/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION prior/O to/O your/O coming/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O and/O your/O reply/O was/O that/O you/O had/O not/O ./O 
You/O were/O also/O asked/O the/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O had/O been/O approached/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION by/O anyone/O and/O requested/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O you/O replied/O that/O you/O had/O not/O ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O in/O possession/O of/O information/O indicating/O that/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O was/O transferred/O in/O November/O 1943/O from/O the/O city/O of/O Rew/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
That/O is/O the/O only/O matter/O that/O comes/O Wvithin/O my/O knowledge/O as/O to/O which/O you/O could/O be/O further/O interrogated/O with/O the/O prospect/O of/O accomplishing/O any/O further/O purpose/O ./O 
So/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O you/O now/O whether/O you/O desire/O in/O any/O way/O to/O enlarge/O upon/O your/O former/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O BENOF/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O do/O very/O much/O want/O to/O enlarge/O upon/O that/O ./O 
When/O I/O gave/O that/O answer/O it/O was/O a/O truthful/O answer/O ,/O and/O this/O is/O my/O enlargement/O upon/O it/O ./O 
When/O we/O worked/O on/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O 2/O men/O came/O from/O Hollywood-one/LOCATION was/O Jack/PERSON Moss/PERSON --/O to/O produce/O a/O picture/O show/O out/O of/O tho/O road/O show/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ./O 
The/O other/O fellow/O was/O a/O writer/O whose/O name/O was/O Lou/PERSON Soloian/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JcKsox/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O spell/O that/O ,/O please/O !/O 
Mr./O BF.NOF/O ./O 
L-o-u/O S-o-l-o-m-a-n/O ./O 
And/O now/O I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O that/O he/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O Will/O you/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O ''/O 
If/O he/O did/O ,/O I/O would/O be/O more/O than/O happy/O to/O say/O so/O ,/O that/O he/O did/O ,/O if/O he/O signed/O me/O ./O 
If/O I/O actually/O had/O a/O clear/O recollection/O ,/O or/O even/O a/O hazy/O recollectionalthough/O you/O want/O me/O to/O say/O only/O what/O I/O recall/O ,/O I/O know/O ./O 
1/O would/O tell/O you/O so/O ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O to/O hide/O and/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O hide/O anything/O from/O the/O committee/O ./O 
But/O I/O can/O only/O say/O this/O :/O This/O is/O what/O it/O must/O have/O been-and/O in/O retrospect/O it/O exp/O -RRB-/O aini/O a/O lot/O of/O things/O that/O do/O n't/O seem/O quite/O right-I/O am/O sure/O that/O he/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O Would/O you/O like/O to/O meet/O big/O writers/O like/O myself/O '/O I/O thought/O he/O was/O a/O big/O writer/O ./O 
He/O was/O n't/O very'Mr/O ./O 
TvENN-R/O ./O 
To/O whom/O are/O you/O referring/O I/O Mr./O Borr/O ./O 
To/O Mr./O Lou/PERSON ./O 
Solonmun/O ;/O not/O to/O Mr./O Mosm/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O this/O type/O of/O conversation/O with/O Mr./O Moss/PERSON ./O 
Ile/O must/O have/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O Would/O you/O like/O to/O meet/O with/O big/O writers/O I/O ''/O And/O in/O those/O days/O discussions/O of/O communism/O was/O not/O like/O it/O ,/O Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O this/O ?/O 
81741-54/O --/O pt/O ./O 
8-2/O 350/O COMMUST/O \*/O criVffm/O DI/O TEN/O Mr./O Bjoraq/PERSON ./O 
1948/O ./O 
L40B/O AKGNLNS/O AMN/O They/O came/O out-I/O do/O n't/O remember/O exactly/O ./O 
I/O left/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O June/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O they/O were/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION for/O about/O a/O month/O with/O us/O ,/O in/O which/O time/O they/O signed/O us/O to/O write/O the/O screenplay/O with/O Lou/PERSON Soloman/PERSON ,/O and/O to/O come/O back/O to/O Hollywood/LOCATION with/O a/O kind/O ofscreenplay/O ;/O that/O is/O ,/O he/O came/O to/O get/O the/O title/O and/O he/O got/O it/O and/O we/O were/O brought/O back/O ./O 
He/O may/O have/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O Would/O you/O like/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/O Partyl/O ''/O at/O which/O time/O it/O would/O n't/O have/O seemed/O so/O out/O of/O line/O for/O me/O to/O say/O ,/O and/O possibly/O .1/O told/O him/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
I/O may/O have/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O did/O ;/O but/O possibly/O I/O did/O ./O 
I/O know/O one/O thing/O ,/O it/O was/O always/O the/O mark/O of/O a/O ood/O Communist/O to/O grab/O a/O recruit/O whenever/O you/O can/O ;/O even/O if/O he/O was/O n't/O very/O good/O you/O got/O him/O and/O worked/O with/O him/O ./O 
I/O remember/O once/O walking/O alon/O $/O the/O street/O with/O Jack/PERSON Moss/PERSON ,/O walking/O and/O talking/O along/O ,/O and/O he/O walked-into/O a/O drugstore/O and/O bought/O me/O a/O copy/O of/O Mother/LOCATION Russia/LOCATION ,/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Here/O ,/O this/O will/O teach/O you/O more/O about/O Russia/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
That/O is/O all/O r/O can/O remember/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O even/O going/O to/O one/O meeting/O ./O 
If/O there/O was/O any/O kind/O of/O activity/O there/O ,/O there/O never/O was/O any/O kind/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activity/O on/O my/O part/O ./O 
o/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O speaking/O now/O of/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O Bzo/PERSON \*/O 7/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
And/O I/O would/O have/O no/O reason/O to/O --/O believe/O me/O ,/O gentlemen/O ,/O I/O '/O do/O n't/O want-there/O is/O no/O reason/O why/O I/O wouid/O want/O to/O tell/O about/O California/LOCATION and/O not/O this/O part/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
It/O did/O n't/O seem/O very/O important/O ./O 
I/O discussed/O with/O my/O attorneys/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O how/O the/O committee-I/O know/O from/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON you/O have/O to/O be/O pretty/O definite/O before/O you/O can/O say/O anything/O that/O will/O incriminate/O on/O the/O stand/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O the/O high/O purpose/O of/O the/O committee/O is/O not/O to/O say/O things/O that/O have/O no/O real/O backing/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O general/O nature/O of/O the/O representations/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O that/O were/O made/O to/O you/O by/O Mr./O Soloman/PERSON ,/O or/O your/O general/O impression/O as/O to/O his/O political/O philosophy/O I/O Mr./O Barrow/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O you/O know/O in/O retrospect/O now/O ,/O that/O Mr./O Soloman/PERSON has/O been/O identified/O a/O number/O oi/O times/O as/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
You/O know/O you/O are/O bound/O to/O be/O affected/O by/O things/O that/O are/O spoken/O ,/O but/O ,/O honestly/O ,/O here/O is/O what/O really/O went/O on/O :/O `/O He/O came/O there/O with/O the/O treatment/O for/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O ./O 
Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O was/O not/O anything/O that/O had/O to/O do/O with/O communism/O ;/O completely/O opposite/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O -/O that/O is/O ,/O opposite/O in/O that/O it/O was/O free/O and/O democratic/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
And/O our/O discussions/O were/O mainly/O upon/O this/O thing/O ,/O because/O we/O had/O all/O worked/O very/O hard/O on/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O for/O 2/O years/O ,/O day/O and/O night/O ,/O and/O it/O meant/O very/O much/O to/O us/O ./O 
First/O ,/O when/O they/O came/O they/O had/O to/O make/O a/O deal/O ./O 
So/O really/O it/O was/O a/O very/O short/O period/O ./O 
First/O they/O came/O they/O had/O to/O make/O the/O deal-it/O was/O n't/O made/O yet/O --/O then/O the/O time/O had/O to/O be/O spent/O to/O make/O the/O deal/O ./O 
Then/O it/O was/O to/O hire/O the/O writers/O ,/O and/O we/O were/O naturally/O selected/O to/O be/O the/O writers/O ./O 
And/O that/O was/O kind/O of/O a/O shaking/O thing/O ,/O because/O it/O was/O so/O much/O money/O we/O were/O getting/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
There/O really/O was/O n't/O much/O time/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O might/O add/O that/O Lou.Soloman/O did/O n't/O take/O very/O much/O to/O me/O ./O 
Whatever/O it/O was/O ,/O our/O personalities/O were/O not/O of/O the/O same/O type/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O much/O more/O serious/O fellow/O than/O I/O am/O ;/O was/O a/O different/O type/O fellow/O than/O I/O am/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O what/O happened/O was/O when/O we/O came/O out/O here/O I/O 0mMST/O Ac/O TU/O Im/O TH/O LOs/O AxGmE/O Am/O 3505/O left/O Duffy/PERSON 's/O Tavern/O and/O went/O into/O picture/O work/O ,/O and/O I/O never/O even/O talked/O to/O Lou/PERSON Soloman/PERSON ./O 
He/O never/O called/O me/O up/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Come/O to/O meetingn/O ''/O and/O he/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O at/O all/O with/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activity/O here/O ./O 
I/O never/O saw/O him/O at/O a/O meeting/O ./O 
That/O 's/O hard/O to/O say/O becaue/O --/O in/O fact/O ,/O I/O will/O take/O that/O back/O ,/O because/O that/O is/O hard/O to/O say/O because/O you/O get/O everything/O confused/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O it/O is/O 10/O years/O or/O so/O ,/O and/O what/O you/O think/O you/O saw/O at/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O or/O Veterans/O Committee/O meeting/O ,/O maybe/O you/O are/O now/O mistaken/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcxsoN/O ./O 
Well/O now/O ,/O today/O ,/O under/O the/O compulsion/O of/O your/O oath/O ,/O you/O are/O prepared/O ,/O Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ,/O without/O equivocation/O ,/O to/O say/O that/O you/O have/O told/O the/O committee/O everything/O within/O your/O recollection/O or/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O Bnxonm/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcxso/PERSON ./O 
As/O to/O your/O activities/O in/O and/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O also/O the/O names/O of/O all/O the/O individuals/O with/O whom/O you/O attended/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O or/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION functions/O Mr./O Bnrow/PERSON ./O 
In/O New/O Y/O I/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Bzxow/PERSON ./O 
Y/O -/O ir/O ,/O absolutely/O so/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvzNNRi/O I/O have/O no/O furtherq1estions/O ./O 
Mr.J/O ~/O cxso/O ~/O '/O ./O 
Is/O there/O anything/O ,/O Mr/O :/O Dole/PERSON !/O 
Mr./O Dovi/PERSON ./O 
./O 
Let/O 's/O see/O ,/O you/O a/O howold/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O BFrv/O ./O 
Thirtylcght/O ./O 
\/O Mr.Doli/O ./O 
Dun/PERSON thistim/O ,10/O yeegragoyouwere281/O \/O Mr./O iskorzn/O ./O 
That/O is/O i/O \*/O htd9/O -/O --/O ./O 
Mr./O ./O 
I/O ~/O rn/O ./O 
I/O notice/O At/O Anentdened/O ,/O though/O ,/O that/O Ar/O ./O 
Mon/O stopped/O at/O astore/O and/O bougo/O Ou/O a/O book/O boat/O Russia/LOCATION and/O said/O ``/O Here/O is/O morelabout/O Rtka/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O 1zO/O ./O 
yel.iI/O ~/O T/O rent/O l/O y/O you/O had/O been/O discussing/O Uussia/LOCATION ./O 
C/O Mr./O In/O \*/O hat/O way/O withM.iUo/O Mr./O Btrof/PERSON ,/O ./O 
J/O tstasanybody/O wouid/O di/O 6ujs/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O think/O we/O wer/O together/O the/O -LRB-/O var/O then/O ,/O I/O belliwe/O `/O ww-were/O ./O 
I/O doift/O know/O how/O the/O nversatlon.ould/O h/O `/O arte/O ./O 
./O 
,/O ./O 
It/O would/O n't/O be/O that/O startling/O ,/O to/O e/O me/O reim/O ember/O ,/O but/O V/O -/O remeniber/O him/O buying/O n/O ;/O '/O o/O a/O book/O ./O 
But/O it/O co/O d/O have/O started/O about/O wy/O they/O were'our/O allied/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O wheth/O tere/O wst/O a/O second/O front/O tho/O ./O 
Any/O oas/O of/O those/O things/O ./O 
-/O ./O 
./O 
-/O \//O Mr./O DormuWhat/O I/O Mr./O Bzvor/PERSON ./O 
Oekainly/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O it/O had/O nothing/O to/O do-I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
It/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O the/O nature/O of/O `/O the/O material/O in/O the/O screen/O play/O ./O 
in-e/O ,/O ./O 
Mr.Dohx.I/O am/O interested/O seei-g/O if/O you/O could/O help/O me/O understand/O more/O what/O it/O is/O that/O impels/O you/O now/O to/O be/O so/O desirous/O of/O doing/O everything/O you/O can/O to/O do/O what/O you/O said/O you/O want/O to/O do/O in/O the/O state/O ./O 
ment.you/O just/O read/O to/O us/O ,/O to/O the/O committee/O ;/O that/O is/O ,/O to/O cooperate/O in/O defeating/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ./O 
What/O is/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ,/O that/O im/O is/O ou/O to/O that/O position/O I/O It/O \*/O Nso/O ./O 
Well/O you/O know/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O hard/O thing/O to/O say/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O ithas/O to/O do/O with/O work/O ./O 
But/O that/O is/O not/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O hard/O thing/O to/O say/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O stand/O the/O thought/O that/O people/O are/O saying/O ,/O ``/O What/O 's/O the/O matter/O with/O Benoff/PERSON ,/O ''/O you/O know/O ./O 
``/O Is/O he/O still/O a/O CommuxustV/O ''/O For/O instance/O ,/O a/O man/O who/O I/O respect/O very/O much/O said/O to/O me/O ,/O ``/O Let/O your/O conscience/O be/O your/O guide/O ./O ''/O 
Now/O ,/O that/O is/O terrible/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O go/O 3506/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O ./O 
LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Iirough/PERSON life/O with/O people/O thinking/O I/O am/O not/O an/O American/O or/O there/O ./O 
a/O some/O kind/O of/O spy/O kind/O of/O thing/O ,/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
The/O rumors/O that/O get/O around/O are/O just/O terrible/O ./O 
These/O things/O kill/O me/O ./O 
I/O have/O to/O clear/O that/O up/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O what/O happened/O last/O time/O ,/O if/O the/O testimony/O got/O around/O to/O being/O too/O flippant/O ,/O that/O I/O have/O led/O some/O people/O to/O believe/O that-that/O 's/O what/O I/O want/O to/O erase/O ./O 
I/O mean/O I/O am/O deadly/O serious/O about/O this/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O have/O people/O say/O these/O things/O about/O me/O ./O 
If/O I/O may/O I/O would/O like-for/O instance/O ,/O it/O has/O been/O brought/O to/O my/O attention-i/O did/O n't/O know/O this/O thing/O was/O going/O on/O aboutMr/O ./O 
DoY/O ./O 
What/O Mr./O BzEOFF/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O people/O saying/O ,/O or/O a/O man/O who/O I/O had/O admired/O and/O respected/O ,/O saying/O ,/O ``/O Let/O your/O conscience/O be/O your/O guide/O ./O ''/O 
What/O 's/O going/O on/O ?/O 
Then/O I/O found/O out/O there/O is/O a/O rumor/O aflight/O that/O I/O worked/O in/O the/O Russian/O Embassy/O ,/O that/O my/O father/O worked/O in/O the/O Russian/O Embassy/O ./O 
That/O is/O not/O so/O ./O 
The/O simple/O fact/O of/O the/O story/O is/O that/O way/O back/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O about/O 19/O I/O worked/O for/O Torgsin/PERSON ,/O who/O may/O have/O been/O a/O part/O of/O the/O Amtorg/ORGANIZATION Wrading/ORGANIZATION Corp./ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O a/O 7/O ./O 
assian/O subsidiary/O ./O 
I/O worked/O as/O a/O shipping/O clerk/O ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O $/O 18/O a/O week/O ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O k.months/O ./O 
I/O was/O happy/O to/O have/O the/O job/O ./O 
They/O fired/O me/O ,/O or/O I/O quit/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O which/O it/O was/O ,/O what/O happened/O ./O 
Mr./O Doymz/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O get/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O BENoFF/PERSON ./O 
My/O father/O did/O some/O insurance/O --/O he/O spoke/O Russian/O ./O 
I/O went/O back/O and/O asked/O my/O father/O ,/O and/O he/O says/O ,/O ``/O You/O can/O go/O back/O to/O your/O children/O and/O everybody/O and/O say/O ,/O '/O I/O was/O not/O a/O member/O and/O am/O not/O ./O '/O ''/O 
He/O is/O retired/O now/O ,/O and/O does/O n't/O do/O any/O business/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O kind/O of/O rumor/O I/O want/O to/O dispel/O ./O 
Then/O I/O hear/O that/O when/O I/O got/O on/O the/O Life/O with/O Luigi/PERSON ,/O there/O was/O a/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Hy/PERSON Kraft/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O identified/O ,/O been/O brought/O up/O as/O a/O Communist/O ,/O and/O that/O there/O was/O something/O indicated/O of/O a/O contact/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O kind/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION contact/O was/O alluded/O to/O ./O 
That/O is/O not/O so/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O brought/O on/O to/O see/O if/O I/O could/O help/O that/O show/O ./O 
I/O was/O such/O a/O great/O aid/O that/O in/O 3/O weeks/O Mr./O Kraft/PERSON was/O taken/O off/O the/O show/O ./O 
So/O how/O could/O there/O have/O been/O any/O connection/O ,/O any/O kind/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION connection/O between/O Mr./O Kraft/PERSON and/O myself/O ?/O 
I/O mean/O ,/O I/O think/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O make/O my/O position/O clear/O enough/O at/O the/O time/O ;/O I/O think/O I/O did/O n't/O quite/O understand/O `/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O I/O have/O to/O make/O my/O position/O evident/O ./O 
There/O has/O to/O be/O definiteness/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O anybody/O to/O have/O any/O idea/O that/O I/O am/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communists/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O terrible/O ./O 
Mr./O DoymE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O wrong/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION propaganda/O program/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O our/O Nation/O is/O concerned/O with/O it/O ,/O what/O is/O there/O ,/O in/O your/O judgment/O ,/O that/O makes/O you/O so/O anxious/O to/O divorce/O yourself/O of/O the/O possibility/O that/O at/O any/O time/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Suppose/O you/O had/O been/O I/O Suppose/O you/O were/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Communism/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O it/O is/O a/O disease/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O menace/O ,/O and/O ,/O well/O ,/O it/O 's/O taken/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O and/O been/O a/O hard/O lesson/O to/O learn/O ;/O against/O every/O interest/O of/O our/O country/O ./O 
It/O hasto/O be/O destroyed/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O Dom/PERSON ./O 
I/O agree/O with/O you/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O but/O I/O want/O to/O see/O if/O part/O of/O your/O motive/O in/O coming/O here/O this/O morning/O was/O to/O come/O out/O against/O the/O Communist/O propaganda/O program/O ,/O rather/O than/O just/O entirely/O to/O clear/O up/O your/O own/O status/O in/O the/O community/O ;/O if/O you/O get/O my/O point/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 3507/O Mr./O BENoF/PERSON '/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O do/O ./O 
If/O I/O have/O n't/O made/O myself/O clearMr/O ./O 
DOYm/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O the/O reason/O Don/PERSON Jackson/PERSON and/O I/O are/O here/O this/O morning/O is/O because/O there/O is/O a/O real/O threat/O to/O our/O whole/O constitutional/O existence/O by/O reason/O of/O the/O proven/O subversive/O Communist/O conspiracy/O to/O overthrow/O it/O by/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
Mr./O BENOFF/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O had/O that/O in/O my/O statement/O ./O 
I/O sat/O down/O and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Put/O down/O what/O you/O think/O ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O do/O want/O to/O join/O with/O the/O forcesMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O one/O more/O question/O :/O Since/O you/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O before/O ,/O you/O are/O adding/O this/O supplementary/O statement-in/O the/O interim/O has/O it/O come/O to/O you/O that/O anything/O that/O this/O committee/O could/O do/O or/O should/O do/O in/O connection/O with/O our/O hearings/O ,/O public/O hearings/O ,/O such/O as/O you/O appeared/O in/O before/O ,/O that/O we/O did/O not/O do/O beforeI/O Is/O there/O any/O way/O we/O could/O make/O that/O sort/O of/O hearing/O more/O efficient/O and/O of/O an/O aid/O in/O any/O way/O against/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ?/O 
You/O have/O had/O several/O months/O to/O think/O it/O over/O ./O 
Mr./O BE/O orF/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O think/O the/O committee/O is/O doing/O a/O fine/O job/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O can/O help/O because/O I/O think/O you/O see/O it/O is/O a/O frightening/O thing/O to/O appear/O in/O public/O ./O 
It/O is/O tough/O for/O people/O to/O appear/O in/O public/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O that/O persons/O like/O myself/O who/O have/O been/O through/O this/O ,/O wherever/O he/O finds/O anybody/O who/O is/O in/O a/O similar/O spot/O ,/O and/O either/O ca/O n't/O make/O the/O break/O or/O has/O some/O doubts/O ,/O or/O is/O being/O duped/O and/O does/O n't/O recognize/O it/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O can/O do/O a/O lot/O of/O good/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyms/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O feel/O the/O committee/O has/O done/O and/O is/O doing/O a/O good/O jobI/O Mr./O BF.orr/O ./O 
Wonderful/O ./O 
Mr./O Doym/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Areyou/PERSON presently/O employed/O ,/O Mr./O Benoff/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BEoFF/O ./O 
No/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
But/O your/O occupation/O is/O that/O of/O screen/O and/O radio/O writer/O I/O Mr./O Bzaoru/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O and/O television/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
In/O connection/O with/O the/O supplemental/O appearance/O of/O yourself/O ,/O has/O any/O person/O made/O any/O promises/O orMr/O ./O 
B/O oFF/O ./O 
On/O no/O n/O iirMr/O ./O 
JACKSWN/PERSON ./O 
This/O isa/O voluntary/O appearance/O in/O order/O to/O supplement/O your/O previous/O testimony/O ?/O 
Mr./O BzworF/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O requested/O this/O and/O I/O appreciate/O being/O granted/O an/O opportunity/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O say/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O committee/O we/O are/O very/O glad/O to/O have/O the/O supplemental/O testimony/O ./O 
We/O appreciate/O your/O desire/O to/O clear/O this/O matter/O up/O entirely/O ./O 
Tho/O subcommittee/O appreciates/O your/O cooperation/O ./O 
Tsthere/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O Mr./O TAvr.NSER/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O Brown/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Ido/O ./O 
Mr.JAcxwso/O ./O 
Be/O seated/O ,/O please/O ./O 
3508/O CO/O -RRB-/O MUNIST/O AIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANGLES/O AE/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O SOHN/PERSON BROWN/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O Z./PERSON B./PERSON TIETZ/PERSON ./O 
Whatisyour/O namely/O Mr./O Tavw/PERSON Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON Brown/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvExNR/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O giveyournamel/O Mr./O Twmi/PERSON J./PERSON B./PERSON Tietz/PERSON ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVT.NEn/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O wereyou/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Brown/PERSON Mr./O BRoww/PERSON ./O 
Yorkshire/LOCATION ,/O England/LOCATION ,/O April/O 4,1904/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvzNNER/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O come/O to/O this/O country/O I/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
1915/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/O Are/O you/O a/O naturalized/O American/O citizen/O I/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O through/O my/O father/O 's/O naturalization/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENZR/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O was/O he/O naturalized/O ?/O 
Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
1923/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAvNr.xE/O ./O 
What/O was/O your/O father/O 's/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Julius/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAv/O zrnm/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupation/O ,/O Mr./O Brown/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Actor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNIR/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O briefly/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O grade/O school/O in/O England/LOCATION ,/O Australia/LOCATION ,/O and/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O think/O about/O one/O term/O of/O hih/O school/O ,/O and/O ,/O oh/O ,/O a/O few/O weeks/O at/O night/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O record/O of/O employment/O has/O been/O since/O 1941/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1940/O I/O have/O been/O a/O free-lance/O actor/O ,/O working/O mostly/O in/O radio/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O a/O few/O pictures/O ,/O small/O parts/O ,/O and/O a/O little/O television/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O more/O fully/O what/O your/O employment/O in/O the/O moving/O picture/O industry/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O difficult/O thing/O to/O describe/O ,/O since/O I/O am/O what/O is/O called/O a/O bit/O actor/O in/O pictures/O ;/O called/O for/O whatever/O thing/O they/O happen/O to/O think/O I/O can/O do/O ./O 
Most/O bf/O my/O employment/O has/O been/O no/O more/O than/O a/O day/O or/O 2/O days/O '/O duration/O ./O 
I/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Extending/O over/O Jhat/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O Mr./O Brown/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O came/O here/O in/O 1943/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O my/O first/O picture/O work/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O or/O in/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O Twrz/PERSON ./O 
By/O here/O ,/O you/O mean/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O more/O fully/O what/O your/O connection/O has/O been/O with/O the/O radio/O industry/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O radio/O industry/O I/O am/O also/O a/O free-lance/O actor/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O a/O great/O deal/O more/O work/O in/O radio/O than/O pictures/O ./O 
I/O have/O played/O mostly/O comedy/O parts/O ,/O as/O a/O straight/O man/O or/O comedian/O ./O 
I/O have/O also/O played/O dramatic/O roles/O in/O dramatic/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O you/O know/O the/O situation/O ./O 
An/O actor/O is/O called/O for/O practically/O everything/O that/O is/O going/O -/O on/O ./O 
Im/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O there/O are/O a/O great/O many/O so-calle-d/O soap/O operas/O ,/O which/O I/O did/O a/O good/O deal/O of/O ,/O and/O out/O here/O on/O the/O coast/O I/O have/O done/O mostly/O comedy/O shows/O ./O 
communwr/O AC1vrrIs/O iN/O TH/O LOS/O A/O maGLS/O AREA/O 8509/O Mr./O TAvz/O Nr/O How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O engaged/O in/O that/O type/O of/O radio/O entertainment/O I/O Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O began/O in/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENN/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O come/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION I/O Mr./O Bnow2r/O ./O 
Late/O 1943/O ;/O I/O think/O either/O very/O late/O in/O October/O or/O very/O late/O in/O November/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvWENNR/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O time/O where/O did/O you/O reside/O I/O Mr.BRowN/O ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENwxi/O ./O 
How/O were/O you/O employed/O at/O the/O time/O you/O left/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O radio/O actor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNRE/O ./O 
Mr./O Brown/PERSON ,/O have/O you/O had/O the/O opportunity/O ,/O either/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION or/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O to/O observe/O any/O of/O the/O workings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O that/O my/O answer/O might/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENm/O ./O 
Were/O you/O at/O any/O time/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O city/O of/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvNNzRL/O Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O been/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/O AngelesI/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O R/O Are/O you/O now/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/O PartyI/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O any/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O Donz/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O registered/O voter/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O continuously/O registered/O as/O a/O voter/O in/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION since/O you/O came/O here/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Do-E/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O question/O your/O right/O to/O raise/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O lawyer/O ,/O too/O ,/O I/O wish/O to/O say/O to/O counsel/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O disappointed/O in/O your/O doing/O it/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O make/O that/O very/O clear/O to/O you/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O criticize/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O disappointed/O ./O 
Because/O we/O are/O here/O as/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O your/O own/O Congress/ORGANIZATION on/O a/O very/O difficult/O assignment/O We/O are/O trying/O to/O help/O uncover/O the/O subversive/O elements/O in/O our/O Nation/O ./O 
./O 
I/O have/O just/O come/O back/O from/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O been/O there/O 30/O days/O ./O 
And/O again/O I/O find/O the/O best/O evidence/O we/O can/O get/O that/O there/O is/O a/O conspiracy/O over/O there/O emanating/O directly/O from/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O and/O it/O is/O sulstantially/O the/O same/O as/O it/O is/O in/O your/O country/O and/O mine/O ./O 
I/O hope/O the/O time/O will/O come/O before/O you/O are/O much/O older/O ,/O Mr./O Brown/PERSON ,/O that/O with/O the/O advice/O of/O your/O counsel/O ,/O you/O will/O feel/O the/O protection/O of/O your/O country/O ,/O and/O to/O help/O the/O committee/O uncover/O whatever/O there/O is/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O anything/O ,/O about/O subversive/O conspiracy/O in/O our/O Nation/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O all/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
DiA/O you/O have/O anything/O further/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAvgNEmrl/O Yes/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O should/O ask/O the/O witness/O 1/O or/O 2/O more/O questions/O ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O Mr./O Houseley/PERSON Stevenson/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ?/O 
8510/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIViES/O IN/O THS/O LOB/O ANUELS/O AREA/O Mr./O BmowN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that.question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O l1AVY/O ./O 
NNFJI/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
Stevenson/PERSON testified/O in/O an/O executive/O session/O ,/O or/O nmtde/O a/O sworn/O statement/O ./O 
for/O use/O by/O this/O conuinitlee/O ,/O under/O date/O of/O September/O 11/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O in/O which/O ho/O sftLes/O that/O lio/O was/O a/O member/O of/O a/O neighborhood/O group/O of/O the/O Conmnist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Now/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION in/O 1930/O or/O 1937/O and/O hi/O identified/O you/O as/O a/O nember/O of/O that/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/O ilarty/O ./O 
1/O desire/O to/O give/O you/O anl/O opportunity/O to/O make/O nty/O explanation/O that/O may/O be/O in/O keeping/O with/O the/O facts/O regarding/O that/O testimony/O ,/O or/O to/O deny/O it/O or/O to/O confirm/O it/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
BrowN/O ./O 
Is/O that/O a/O question/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O `/O rAVFNNEII/O ./O 
Ye/O ./O 
Mr./O INowN/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O '/O ,/O AvENWNit/O ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Mr./O Robert/PERSON Shayne/PERSON Daweo/PERSON Mr./O BrowN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O ,/O sir/O ,/O onl/O tho/O sane/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O rAVENNrt/O ./O 
Mr./O 1/O -RRB-/O atwe/O testified/O before/O this/O committee/O on/O the/O sante/O day/O ,/O ellemilwir/O 11/O ,/O 19153/O ,/O 1m/O stilted/O that/O he/O had/O been/O a/O member/O of/O thie/O -LRB-/O onmumist/O Party/O in/O the/O cily/O of/O New/LOCATION YVork/LOCATION and/O identleild/O yel/O as/O having/O been/O a/O metmtlwr/O Co/O t/O he/O -LRB-/O Oommunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O of/O w/O ;/O ich/O hie/O was/O a/O nenber/O ./O 
Ie/O further/O testifed/O that/O at/O that/O f/O ime/O you/O welt/O ativi/O inl/O r/O 11/O prin1io/O cipallv/O ,/O ond/O that/O later/O you/O lcame/O an/O imlmrtant/O supporting/O Ilayer/O with/O Pred/PERSON Allen/PERSON 's/O show/O ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O give/O you/O the/O opportunity/O to/O make/O such/O explanation/O as/O the/O faets/O m11ay/O justify/O reg,-ditiug/O the/O testinmony/O of/O Mr./O Shiiynm/PERSON ,/O ,/O and/O to/O either/O deny/O or/O confirm/O this/O statement/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O -LRB-/O Counmnist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O Broww/PERSON ./O 
If/O thua/O is/O a/O -LRB-/O luestion/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O it/O on/O the/O sWeI/O grounds/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
l/O -RRB-/O oyI.x/O ./O 
Ma/O I/O lisk/O you/O ,/O were/O you/O it/O nenber/O of/O Fred/PERSON Allen/PERSON 's/O show/O in/O New/O Yorlf/O Mr./O BROwN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Doavv/PERSON ./O 
VhOt/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Froin/O about/O 19.34/O to/O 19.13/O ./O 
Mr./O DoyYL/O You/O were/O a/O menllber/O of/O the/O cast/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O l/O -RRB-/O ovygx/O ./O 
And/O all/O that/O time/O was/O the/O show/O performing/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION I/O Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O not/O all/O the/O time/O ./O 
We/O came/O to/O the/O coast/O twice/O for/O very/O short/O periods/O while/O Mr./O Allen/PERSON was/O making/O a/O moving/O picture/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyie/PERSON ./O 
Ios/O Angelts/O ?/O 
Mr./O BROWN/PERSON ./O 
Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyir/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O were/O with/O that/O show/O all/O during/O that/O period/O that/O you/O relate/O d/O Mr./O BRowN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excusedI/O Mr./O TAvENNF.R/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O excused/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
COMMUNrST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANOELES/O AREA/O 3511/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O WILLIAM/PERSON L./PERSON ALLAND/PERSON Mr./O TAvWENNr.R/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O nano/O ,/O please/O ,/O sirl/O Mr./O ALLANS/O -RRB-/O ./O 
William/PERSON L./PERSON Alland/PERSON ,/O A-I-1-a-n-d/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O I/O `/O AVENNER/O ./O 
Are/O you/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ,/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON I/O Mr./O ALAND/PERSON ./O 
No/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O I/O `/O ATNNFR/O ./O 
it/O is/O the/O practice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O inform/O every/O wilem/O that/O ho/O has/O the/O right/O to/O counel/O -/O ,/O and/O we/O give/O him/O an/O olportunity/O to/O have/O counsel/O present/O ,/O with/O him/O if/O he/O desires/O ./O 
Mr./O AI.IJ.ANi/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O feel/O I/O need/O voiinsel/O ,/O siico/O I/O wish/O to/O speak/O freely/O and/O of/O my/O own/O conscience/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O I/O `/O AVENNP/O .1/O I./O When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O AL/PERSON ,/O AND/O ./O 
Dolinar/PERSON ,/O I/O -RRB-/O el./O ;/O March/O 4/O ,/O 1916/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
`/O i/O `/O AVSNNER/O ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O rosidel/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O reside/O in/O Canoga/LOCATION Park/LOCATION ,/O Cilif/LOCATION ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
TAv.NNrR/O ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O resided/O in/O Californial/O Mr./O AL.LND/O ./O 
Since/O the/O end/O of/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O l'AVENNEI/O cents/O ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O reside/O prior/O to/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mir/O ./O 
AIJAND/O ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O time/O I/O lived/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Before/O that/O in/O Blotinore/LOCATION ,/O Md./LOCATION ,/O where/O I/O was/O brought/O ns/O a/O young/O child/O fromt/O Delaware/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O `/O lWhensNn/O ./O 
Wheu/PERSON did/O you/O leave/O Baltimore/LOCATION to/O take/O up/O your/O residence/O in/O Now/LOCATION York/LOCATION I/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O the/O into/O ./O 
I/O was/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O 18/O years/O Mr./O AUJI/PERSON ./O 
N./O old/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvr/O Nrit/O ./O 
And/O you/O lived/O continuously/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION intil/O yoe/O caneto/O Califoriin/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O went/O there/O to/O go/O on/O the/O stage/O ;/O or/O try/O ./O 
Mr./O TAV/O :/O NNVR/O ./O 
WhIlt/O is/O ollr/O occupat/O ion/O ?/O 
Mr./O A.AND/O ./O 
I/O have/O b2een/O for/O the/O last/O 3/O years/O a/O motion-picture/O producer/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O rAvPNNF.R/O ./O 
Will/O yon/O tell/O the/O committee/O at/O this/O point/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O yoreducatinaml/O training/O has/O ieen/O ?/O 
Mr./O Ar.rin/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O went/O partially/O through/O high/O school/O ./O 
I/O also/O ,/O while/O in/O Now/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O took/O various/O courses/O in/O the/O history/O of/O the/O American/O theater/O ;/O courses/O in/O stage/O design/O ,/O courses/O in/O acting/O ,/O and/O all/O the/O various/O courses/O that/O oee/O should/O take/O if/O one/O is/O interested/O in/O the/O theater/O ,/O in/O a/O full/O career/O in/O the/O theater/O ./O 
Mr./O T'AV/O ./O 
NNVR/O ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O for/O the/O past/O 8/O years/O you/O have/O been/O a/O producer/O I/O Mr./O A/O ,/O ANm/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O TAVENN/O i./O Moving-picture/O producer/O Mr./O ALANDn/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O %/O `/O FNNR/O ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O just/O what/O your/O record/O of/O employment/O has/O been/O up/O to/O and/O including/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O A/O ,/O ,/O AND/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O after/O going/O to/O dramatic/O school/O and/O acting/O in/O sumnmer/O theater/O I/O joined/O the/O Mercury/O Theater/O ,/O which/O is/O an/O acting/O group/O in/O Now/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O professional/O group/O ./O 
I/O was/O employed/O as/O an/O actor/O and/O stage/O manager/O ./O 
This/O group/O also/O did/O radio/O shows/O ,/O and/O I/O acted/O and/O helped/O produce/O those/O radio/O shows/O ./O 
Mr./O TA/O F/O NNPR/O ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O those/O radio/O shows/O more/O fully/O I/O 3,,47-54/O --/O p/O ,/O ,/O 8-3/O 510/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOB/O ANGELES/O MFA/O Mr./O AiLND/O ./O 
They/O were/O our/O entertainment/O &/O One/O of/O the/O most/O familiar/O ones/O was/O the/O ``/O War/O of/O the/O Worlds/O ''/O broadcast/O the/O frightening/O one/O ./O 
You/O probably/O remember/O that/O ./O 
Then/O this/O organization/O came/O to/O California/LOCATION ./O 
The/O head/O of/O it/O was/O Orson/LOCATION Welles/LOCATION ./O 
And/O we/O got/O a/O contract/O at/O RKO/O to/O make/O pictures/O ./O 
And/O I/O was/O taken/O along/O on/O a/O salary/O ./O 
We/O spent/O some/O time/O at/O RKO/O learning/O how/O to/O make/O movies/O ,/O and/O this/O period/O resulted/O in/O our/O making/O the/O picture/O called/O Citizen/O Kane/PERSON ./O 
After/O Citizen/O Kane/PERSON we/O went/O back/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O put/O on/O a/O play/O called/O Native/O Son/O ./O 
After/O Mr./O Welles/PERSON left/O first/O and/O went/O back/O and/O got/O it/O organized/O ,/O when/O he/O got/O to/O the/O final/O staging/O ,/O I/O was/O sent/O for/O and/O I/O was/O one/O of/O the/O stae/O managers/O of/O that/O production/O ./O 
We/O returned-I/O am/O not/O giving/O dates/O ./O 
Is/O that/O all/O rightI/O Mr./O TAvENxNR/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O for/O you/O to/O give/O them/O approximately/O ,/O if/O you/O can/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
AULAND/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O Citizen/PERSON Kane/PERSON was/O in/O 1940/O ./O 
The/O trip/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION for/O Native/O Son/O was/O the/O winter/O of/O 1940-41/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1911/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O these/O are/O approximate/O dates/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsom/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O your/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O Au/O N./O N/O Yes/O ./O 
I/O might/O be/O quite/O off/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O bad/O at/O dates/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O California/LOCATION in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1941/O ,/O and/O I/O left/O the/O Mercury/O Theater/O shortly/O thereafter/O ./O 
I/O lelt/O after/O a/O disagreement/O with/O Mr./O Welles/PERSON regarding/O salary/O ./O 
I/O thenl/O did/O odd/O jobs/O around/O the/O motion-picture/O business/O ,/O little/O bits/O here/O ,/O and/O collected/O unemployment/O insurance/O ./O 
I/O just/O sort/O of/O got/O by/O with/O odd/O jobs/O in/O the/O industry/O ,/O until/O Pearl/O harbor/O ./O 
A/O few/O weeks/O after/O Pearl/O Harbor/O I/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O went/O to/O work/O for/O the/O Office/O of/O War/O Information/O ./O 
We/O did/O radio/O propaganda/O broadcasts/O to/O all/O the/O foreign/O countries/O ,/O and/O I/O helped/O produce/O them/O ,/O stage/O them/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O write/O them/O ./O 
I/O merely-I/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O them/O except/O to-most/O of/O these/O people/O were/O foreigners/O ,/O did/O n't/O understand/O microphones/O ,/O and/O I/O staged/O the/O shows/O ,/O helped/O them/O ptit/O them/O on/O ./O 
I/O also/O developed/O my/O own/O program/O ,/O which/O was/O athistory/O of/O jazz/O program/O which/O was/O beamed/O to/O our/O troops/O all/O over/O the/O world/O ;/O which/O I/O am/O quite/O proud/O of/O ./O 
So/O this/O was/O in/O the/O year/O after/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O the/O Office/O of/O War/O Information/O for/O 6/O or/O 7/O months/O or/O so/O ,/O and/O in/O August/O of/O that/O year/O I/O enlisted/O ./O 
I/O resigned/O to/O enlist/O in/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O became/O an/O aviation/O cadet/O and/O I/O was/O sent/O to/O Texas/LOCATION and/O spent/O a/O year/O training/O as/O a/O pilot/O ./O 
Then/O I/O was/O a/O combat/O pilot/O in/O the/O Pacific/LOCATION theater/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O mustered/O out/O in/O August/O of/O 1945/O ./O 
I/O got/O back/O to/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O fi/O ly/O ./O 
tat/O the/O end/O of/O 1945/O 1/O developed/O an/O idea/O for/O a/O radio/O program/O called/O `/O Doorway/O to/O Life/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O dramatization/O of/O problems/O in/O child/O psychology/O ./O 
The/O attempt/O there/O was/O to/O help/O parents/O to/O understand/O how/O ~/O to/O handle/O their/O children/O so/O as/O to/O prevent/O them/O from/O becoming/O neurotic/O and/O delinquent/O ;/O which/O is/O relatively/O a/O new/O science/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O anything/O about/O it/O when/O I/O got/O back/O but/O I/O met/O some/O neighbors/O who/O had/O a/O little/O child/O and/O it/O seemed/O to/O me/O t/O t/O t/O e/O a/O his/O hild/O improperly/O ;/O never/O knew/O the/O differnc/O between/O right/O and/O wrong/O ,/O and/O I/O read/O a/O couple/O of/O books/O by/O Gesell/PERSON of/O Yale/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O it/O opened/O up/O quite/O a/O thing/O ,/O opened/O up/O my/O own/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANOELES/O AREA/O 3513/O eyes/O to/O my/O own/O childhood/O ,/O and/O I/O began/O to/O realize/O what/O my/O own/O problems/O were/O ,/O and/O this/O interested/O me/O ./O 
And/O eventually/O we/O got/O to/O a/O psychoanalyst/O ,/O child/O experts/O ,/O and/O got/O them/O to/O cooperate/O ,/O give/O us/O case/O histories/O which/O we/O dramatized/O and/O put/O on/O the/O air/O ,/O and/O sold/O this/O show/O to/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION Broadcasting/ORGANIZATION System/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O it/O was/O on/O the/O air/O for/O little/O over/O a/O year/O ./O 
Then/O the/O program/O went/O off/O the/O air/O ./O 
I/O had/O hopes/O that/O I/O could/O sell/O a/O few/O of/O these/O for/O motion-pictures/O films/O ,/O and/O there/O was/O a/O delay/O ./O 
I/O think/O we/O did/O not/O have/O the/O right/O to/O sell/O these/O programs/O for/O films/O until/O 6/O months/O after/O they/O were/O off/O the/O air/O ,/O and/O so/O for/O a/O 6-month/O period/O I/O did/O n't/O do/O very/O much/O ,/O just/O getting/O by/O --/O could/O n't/O sell/O them/O ./O 
In/O March/O of/O 1946/O I/O opened/O a/O model/O airplane/O store/O ,/O hobby/O shop/O ./O 
Strange/O thing/O ,/O I/O had/O always/O been/O interested/O in/O model/O airplanes/O and/O I/O built/O these/O radio-controlled/O jobs/O and/O ,/O and/O actually/O was/O kind/O of/O psychological/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O seem/O to/O be/O able/O to/O find/O my/O way/O ,/O and/O I/O retreated/O to/O childhood/O ,/O playing/O with/O toys/O ,/O what/O you/O might/O say/O it/O was/O ./O 
We/O submitted/O the/O show/O at/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1940/O to/O CBS/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O it/O took/O months/O to/O decide/O whether/O they/O wanted/O it/O or/O not/O ./O 
During/O this/O perio/O -LRB-/O l/O I/O opened/O up/O this/O model/O airplane/O shop/O ,/O within/O the/O period/O from/O March/O through/O to/O around/O September/O 1946/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O CBS/ORGANIZATION said/O ``/O We/O will/O buy/O the/O show/O and/O -/O o/O to/O work/O ''/O which/O I/O closed/O the/O mode/O anyway/O ,/O and/O we/O started/O by/O toen/O ,/O barupt/O practicallyAnd/O shop/O ,/O program/O ./O 
then/O were/O on/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O the/O program/O writing/O airidlane/O this/O continued/O through/O the/O end/O of/O 1947/O ,/O somewhere/O in/O there/O ./O 
Then/O again/O a/O bleak/O period/O ,/O waiting/O for/O the/O 0/O monthis-t4hat/O is/O ,/O when/O the/O 6/O months/O were/O up/O we/O did/O n't/O sell/O the/O show/O to/O films/O as/O we/O had/O hoped/O to/O do/O ./O 
But/O I/O did/O manage/O to/O play/O the/O records/O of/O a/O couple/O of/O them/O for/O a/O producer/O at/O Universal/O ,/O and/O lie/O was/O very/O impressed/O with/O them/O and/O said/O that/O while/O lie/O did/O n't/O feel/O it/O was/O the/O kind/O of/O thing/O suitable/O for/O his/O type/O of/O operation/O ,/O lie/O did/O like/O the/O shows/O and/O he/O did/O like/O my/O work/O ,/O and/O lie/O said/O ,/O ``/O How/O would/O you/O like/O to/O come/O to/O work/O for/O me/O as/O an/O assistant/O working/O with/O writers/O ?/O '/O 
I/O accepted/O ,/O but/O the/O job/O did/O n't/O materialize/O until/O March/O of/O 1950/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
And/O I/O worked/O as/O an/O assistant/O and/O began/O to/O bring/O in/O story/O ideas/O that/O they/O liked/O ,/O and/O eventually/O was/O made/O a/O full/O producer/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O 's/O the/O story/O of/O my/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O date/O was/O when/O Mr/O Alland/PERSON I/O Mr./O AU.AND/O ./O 
The/O date/O I/O became/O a/O full/O producer/O f/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O AIAND/PERSON ./O 
About/O 3/O years/O ago/O ,/O November/O 1950/O I/O would/O say/O ./O 
I/O was/O actually/O associate/O producer/O with/O Leonard/PERSON Goldstein/PERSON ,/O really/O producing/O ,/O but/O did/O n't/O get/O the/O credit/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O a/O full/O producer/O getting/O credit/O myself/O until/O 22/O years/O ,/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNF/O ./O 
./O 
What/O are/O some/O of/O the/O principal/O pictures/O you/O have/O w/O received/O credits/O for/O as/O a/O producer/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Well/O what/O you/O call/O the/O Lawless/O Breed/O ,/O a/O western/O ,/O based/O on/O the/O life/O of/O John/PERSON Wesey/PERSON Hardin/PERSON ./O 
Also/O ,/O a/O horror/O picture/O calledthe/O Black/O Castlei/O The/O Raiders/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O a/O western/O ./O 
Stand/O at/O Apache/LOCATION River/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O a/O western/O ,/O and/O It/O Came/O From/O Outer/O Space/O ,/O science/O fiction/O that/O was/O finally/O produced/O ,/O the/O first/O 3-D/O picture/O at/O the/O studio/O ./O 
And/O I/O have/O just/O completed/O two/O others/O ./O 
One/O is/O sort/O of/O a/O horror/O picture/O ,/O Black/O Lagoon/O ./O 
This/O is/O about/O a/O hypothetical/O monster/O in/O human/O form/O but/O with/O quills/O ,/O who/O lives/O under/O the/O sea/O ./O 
3514/O COMMUMST/O ACrvIzS/O im/O T/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O And/O I/O have/O just/O completed/O another/O one/O called/O Johnny/PERSON Dark/PERSON ,/O which/O is/O the/O story/O of/O road/O racing/O ,/O which/O I/O think/O is/O going/O to/O be/O very/O good/O ./O 
y/O the/O way/O ,/O it/O has/O a/O race/O in/O it/O from/O Canada/LOCATION to/O Mexico/LOCATION ,/O across/O the/O whole/O breadth/O and/O width/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O on/O wide/O screen/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Alland/PERSON ,/O information/O has/O come/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O committee/O indicating/O that/O you/O are/O in/O a/O position/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O information/O reiarding/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
My/O first/O question/O then/O is/O to/O ask/O you/O what/O opportunities/O you/O have/O had/O to/O observe/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O AuAxN/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O the/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION phase/O of/O my/O life/O there/O may/O have/O been/O opportunities/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O completely/O unaware/O ,/O really/O ,/O of/O politics/O ./O 
I/O was/O very/O much/O interested/O in/O the/O theater/O ,/O and/O I/O really/O can/O tell/O you/O nothing/O about/O Communist/O activity/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O because/O I/O was/O a/O youngster/O and/O very/O much/O in/O love/O with/O the/O theater/O ./O 
And/O I/O am/O very/O happy/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O anything/O about/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
In/O California/LOCATION is/O where/O my/O first/O contacts/O with/O this/O organization/O began/O ;/O during/O the/O making/O of/O Citizen/O Kane/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAV/O NNER/O ./O 
That/O would/O have/O been/O about/O 1041/O or/O 19421/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
1940/O ./O 
Through/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O became/O engaged/O and/O married/O someone/O at/O that/O time/O who/O had/O been/O active/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION earlier/O ,/O and/O I/O got/O my/O first/O sort/O of/O inkling/O about/O it/O ./O 
But/O I/O did/O n't/O personally/O engage/O in/O any/O activity/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION until/O after/O the/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvFNNICR/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O would/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O what/O you/O observed/O of/O the/O activity/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION prior/O to/O the/O war/O and/O during/O the/O period/O that/O you/O were/O shooting/O the/O picture/O Citizen/O Kane/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ALtAwD/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O during/O that/O period/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O my/O first/O wife/O ,/O whom/O I/O met/O ,/O took/O me/O around/O and/O introduced/O me/O to/O some/O people/O ./O 
I/O recall/O one/O person/O that/O she/O introduced/O me/O to/O at/O that/O time/O was/O -LRB-/O -/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvXNNzR/O ./O 
Let/O me/O ask/O you/O ,/O did/O you/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O AuAND/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
T/O mentioned/O this/O man/O 's/O name/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O mean/O necessarily/O to/O identify/O him/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O JAcKso/O ./O 
I/O wish/O ,/O in/O the/O mentioning/O of/O any/O names/O ,/O you/O would/O be/O very/O careful/O unless/O you/O very/O definitely/O can/O identify/O them/O as/O membervof/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O our/O own/O knowledge/O ./O 
And/O your/O stiplation/O onMr/O ./O 
--/O will/O be/O note/O ./O 
rAL/O n./O All/O right/O ./O 
The/O only/O thing/O of/O significance/O during/O that/O period/O was/O that/O I/O was/O taken/O to/O a/O school/O where/O courses/O ,/O various/O course/O in/O Communist/O philosophy/O ,/O Marxism/O ,/O were/O being/O taught/O ,/O wide/O open/O ,/O downtown/O on/O the/O second/O floor/O of/O the/O building/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O at/O the/O moment/O recall/O the/O address/O of/O the/O street/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O same/O street/O that/O Angel/PERSON 's/O Flight/O is/O on/O ,/O I/O believe/O and/O then/O the/O whole/O second/O floor/O of/O this/O building/O there/O were/O courses/O being/O taught/O ./O 
I/O attended/O a/O couple/O of/O these/O ./O 
Mr./O Doiu/PERSON ./O 
A/O couple/O of/O the/O courses/O ?/O 
Mr./O AL/PERSON ,/O w./O Yes/O ./O 
These/O were/O being/O taught/O ./O 
I/O attended/O one/O course/O being/O t/O ,/O ,/O ught/O by/O a/O woman/O named/O Eva/PERSON Shafron/PERSON ./O 
8Tb/O ./O 
person/O saved/O by/O thewitness/O was/O not/O satisfaetori/O Identifed/O as/O having/O bees/O a/O member/O 49/O the/O Corrnuakt/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O for/O that/O resom/O th/O ./O 
namewas/O deleted/O b/O -/O the/O con/O Mitte/LOCATION ,/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 3515/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Spell/O the/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O ALLNn/O ./O 
This/O was/O justMr/O ./O 
Winrt/O ./O 
R./O S-h-a-f-r-o-n/O ./O 
Mr./O AL.AND/O ./O 
But/O I/O say/O this/O is/O just/O a/O short/O time/O before/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION and/O was/O n't/O pursuedlbeyont/O that/O point/O ./O 
Then/O ,/O s/O I/O told/O vo/O ,/O I/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O went/O to/O work/O ,/O and/O subsequently/O enlisted/O in/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Corps/ORGANIZATION and/O went/O to/O Texas/LOCATION and/O then/O overseas/O ./O 
And/O then/O I/O returned/O to/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O with/O the/O exception/O of/O a/O couple/O of/O lectures/O that/O I/O attended/O at/O the/O so-called/O school/O ,/O I/O engaged/O in/O no/O Communist/O activity/O ,/O per/O se/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O these/O individual/O lectures/O ,/O or/O were/O they/O lecture/O courses/O ?/O 
Mr./O AULAND/PERSON ./O 
Lecture/O courses/O ,/O classroom/O ,/O large/O group/O of/O people/O attending/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O attended/O the/O entire/O courses/O or/O lectures/O in/O the/O course/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Lectures/O in/O the/O course/O ./O 
I/O forget/O ./O 
how/O many/O weeks/O the/O session/O was/O stipposed/O to/O continue/O ,/O but/O ;/O I/O only/O attended/O a/O couple/O of/O them/O ,/O 2/O or/O 3/O ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O remember/O the/O name-it/O was/O absolutely/O elenientary/O courses/O ./O 
I/O recall/O the/O blackboard/O ,/O the/O old/O illustration/O that/O the/O man/O who/O makes/O 50/O pairs/O of/O shoes/O in/O a/O factory/O ,/O he/O does/O n't/O get/O back/O all/O the/O 50/O ,/O he/O only/O gets/O back/O part/O of/O what/O he/O makes/O ,/O and/O therefore/O he/O is/O being/O cheated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVrFNNF.R/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O the/O name/O of/O the/O school/O was/O the/O Los/O A/O ngeles/O Labor/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION I/O Mr.AxxAND/O ./O 
It/O could/O very/O well/O be/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O say/O for/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O rAV1FNNFR/O ./O 
Was/O it/O through/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION associations/O that/O you/O attended/O that/O school/O ?/O 
Mr./O AmANn/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O through/O riy/O first/O wife/O that/O I/O attended/O ./O 
She/O took/O some/O courses/O and/O invited/O me/O to/O take/O some/O and/O I/O readily/O took/O them/O ;/O although/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O I/O found/O it/O difficult/O to/O stick/O at/O it/O ha/O and/O fast/O ./O 
Only/O attended/O a/O few/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVF.N/O NKU/ORGANIZATION ./O 
When/O did/O you/O become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O at/O all/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALAxND/O ./O 
I/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party-let/O 's/O see/O ,/O the/O exact/O date-I/O have/O been/O going/O through/O ,/O trying/O to/O construct/O this/O in/O my/O mind/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ,/O in/O February/O or/O March/O of/O 19461/O was/O included/O into/O a/O neighborhood/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvrN.r/O How/O were/O you/O employed/O at/O that/O timo/O Mr./O ArjAmn/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O time/O we/O were/O just/O opening/O this/O hobby/O shop/O ./O 
We/O submitted/O this/O radio/O show/O to/O CBS/ORGANIZATION for/O their/O consideration/O ,/O and/O while/O waiting/O I/O had/O opened/O this/O hobby/O shop/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O this/O Communist/O Party/O in/O 1946/O ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O group/O or/O cell/O of/O the/O party/O I/O Mr./O ALtre/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVFXNER/PERSON ./O 
By/O what/O name/O was/O the/O cell/O known/O I/O Mr./O AUAND/PERSON ./O 
The/O Echo/O Park/O branch/O ,/O which/O ,/O however/O ,/O was/O divided/O into/O smaller/O units/O of/O the/O rThho/O Park/O branch/O ./O 
I/O was/O in-I/O forget/O it/O ./O 
It/O was/O ven/O another/O name/O ./O 
Each/O of/O the/O various/O units/O of/O the/O Echo/O Park/O branch/O were/O given/O another/O name/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O in/O one/O of/O the/O units/O of/O the/O Echo/O Park/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNF.FJ/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O membership/O of/O the/O various/O units/O of/O he/O branch/O ,/O and/O of/O the/O branch/O ?/O 
3516/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O A.LAND/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O the/O membership/O varied/O from/O 15/O to/O 45/O people/O ./O 
The/O entire/O branch/O could/O have/O been/O a/O very/O large/O number/O of/O people/O ,/O as/O much/O as/O maybe/O 200/O or/O 300/O ,/O 1/O imagine/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvwNNER/O ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O hold/O a/O position/O in/O your/O group/O or/O cell/O of/O the/O party/O I/O Mr./O ALLANn/O ./O 
No/O official/O position/O ,/O beyond/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O was/O asked1/O to/O pick/O up/O literature/O at/O the/O bookstore/O and/O bring/O it/O to/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
We/O were/O all/O given/O assiginents/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ,/O to/O discuss/O particular/O i/O sues/O at/O the/O next/O meeting/O ,/O read/O the/O paper/O or/O read/O such/O ndsuch/O an/O article/O in/O one/O of/O the/O Communist/O magazines/O and/O discuss/O it/O ./O 
and/O this/O kind/O of/O thing/O ./O 
But/O I/O never/O ,/O to/O my/O recollection/O ,/O held/O a/O further/O position/O than/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVF.NNFR/O ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O leaders/O among/O the/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALIAND/PERSON ./O 
In/O this/O neighborhood/O branch/O I/O have/O great/O difficulty/O in/O recalling/O the/O names/O ./O 
I/O am/O hoping/O ,/O through/O some/O help/O ,/O to/O get/O this/O down/O ./O 
But/O Virginia/PERSON Mullen/PERSON was/O chairman/O of/O this/O group/O for/O a/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O this/O individual/O appeared/O as/O a/O witness/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O refused/O to/O answer/O material/O questions/O in/O reliance/O upon/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
She/O was/O an/O actress/O ./O 
Mr./O AL/PERSON AND/O ./O 
She/O was/O more/O than/O that/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O should/O know/O that/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O when/O I/O started/O the/O idea/O for/O this/O child-psychology/O program/O I/O developed/O it/O to/O a/O certain/O point/O myself/O ./O 
At/O this/O point/O my/O first/O wife/O ,/O who/O I/O was/O living/O with/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O know/O someone/O ,/O ''/O and/O also/O at/O this/O point/O I/O was/O not/O in/O the/O party/O yet-but/O this/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O be/O mistaken/O ./O 
I/O knew/O the/O people/O ./O 
They/O were/O in/O and/O out/O ./O 
It/O was/O very/O friendly/O ./O 
She/O told/O me/O that/O she/O knew/O someone/O who/O had/O studied/O some/O child/O psychology/O ,/O worked/O with/O children/O ,/O been/O a/O nursery/O ./O 
schoolteacher/O and/O had/O some/O children/O of/O her/O own/O ,/O and/O that/O she/O might/O be/O helpful/O ./O 
And/O I/O said/O fine/O ,/O and/O she/O introduced/O me/O to/O Virginia/PERSON Mullen/PERSON ./O 
She/O supplied/O me/O with/O some/O technical/O information/O ,/O certain/O source/O material/O that/O I/O needed/O ,/O and/O having/O children/O of/O her/O own/O ,/O which/O I/O did/O n't/O have/O it/O was/O very/O helpful/O in/O trying/O to/O dramatize/O these/O particular/O eases/O o/O #/O children/O ,/O the/O habits/O of/O children/O ,/O having/O a/O practice/O experience/O ,/O and/O then/O you/O could/O apply/O the/O problem/O ,/O and/O she/O was/O very/O helpful/O ./O 
And/O while/O I/O wrote/O the/O show/O ,/O I/O did/O at/O the/O same/O time/O give/O her/O cocredit/O with/O me/O ,/O and/O this/O Doorway/O to/O Life/O series/O was/O presented/O on/O the/O air/O ,/O and/O presented/O as/O the/O writers/O were/O William/PERSON Alland/PERSON and/O Virginia/PERSON Mullen/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O was/O a/O while/O after/O I/O started/O working/O with/O her/O on/O this/O show/O that/O I/O eventually/O went/O into/O her/O neighborhood/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVWNNzEr/O ./O 
Did/O she/O play/O any/O part/O in/O your-becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION I/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
She/O certainly/O did/O ./O 
Although/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O you/O have/O to/O be/O willing/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O nice/O to/O say-and/O I/O think/O this/O is/O the/O important/O thing/O ,/O been/O very/O difficult/O for/O me/O to/O face/O --/O I/O always/O have/O been/O tempted/O to/O say/O these/O people/O did/O it/O to/O me/O ./O 
They/O do/O ./O 
JutI/O think/O Americans/O must/O not/O be/O vulnerable/O ./O 
If/O you/O are/O vulnerable/O it/O is/O because/O ou/O have/O n't/O been/O thinking/O clearly/O or/O fully/O appreciating/O what/O your/O life/O nere/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O JACBSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Miss/O Mullen/PERSON suggest/O to/O you/O in/O so/O many/O words/O at/O the/O time/O extend/O an/O invitation/O to/O you/O ,/O or/O offer/O the/O suggestion/O that/O you/O should/O be/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALjLAD/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O judge/O that/O this/O was/O not/O only/O in/O one/O instance/O !/O 
Mr./O Au/O ./O 
ND/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
COMMUNI/ORGANIZATION T/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O TIE/O LO/ORGANIZATION ANGELER/ORGANIZATION AREA/O 3517/O Mr./O TAvFNNFR/O ./O 
duringg/O the/O pro-re/O ./O 
ss/O of/O your/O work/O with/O her/O did/O she/O at/O any/O time/O indicate/O to/O you/O the/O advisabilit/O y/O of/O coloring/O your/O production/O with/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION prolagandt/O I/O Mr./O ALLrAN/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
And/O let/O me/O say/O that/O I/O would/O have/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O I/O think/O been/O amlenable/O to/O doing/O so/O myself/O ./O 
It/O so/O happened/O that/O it/O was/O a/O kind/O of/O show/O which/O is/O like/O medical/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O you/O can/O take/O medicine/O anl/O inject/O propaganda/O into/O it/O ./O 
That/O is/O in/O terms/O of/O a/O diagnosis/O ./O 
`/O I/O `/O hese/O ease/O hIstories/O were/O given/O to/O u.s/O by/O bona/O fide/O doctors/O and/O -RRB-/O sychoanalysts/O here/O ,/O and/O the/O Psychoanalytical/ORGANIZATION Society/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O is/O the/O top/O and/O respected/O organization/O here/O ,/O when/O the/O script/O was/O finished/O ,/O it/O had/O to/O be/O submitted/O to/O them/O for/O their/O approval/O ,/O because/O when/O these/O went/O on/O the/O air/O ,/O coast/O to/O coast/O ,/O it/O was/O CJS/O who/O insisted/O on/O this/O that/O it/O was/O with/O the/O full/O backing/O and/O approval/O of/O an/O important/O and/O bona/O ide/O medical/O organization/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
So/O there/O was/O n't/O the/O opportunity/O ./O 
But/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O had/O there/O been/O ,/O I/O certainly/O th.nk/O I/O would/O have/O bied/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVF.NNFR/O ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O other/O persons/O who/O were/O active/O in/O the/O work/O of/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ArJ.AND/O ./O 
In/O the/O neighborhood/O branch/O ,/O which/O is/O the/O first/O group/O that/O I/O was/O in/O ,/O there/O was/O Ruth/PERSON Myerson/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O my/O first/O wife/O ;/O Virginia/PERSON Mullen/PERSON ,/O and/O there/O was/O a/O man/O ,/O r-s/PERSON Bryant/PERSON ,/O and/O his/O wife/O ./O 
Mr./O ,/O JACK/O ON/O ./O -RRB-/O 
o/O you/O know/O what/O her/O name/O was/O ,/O her/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Then/O a/O woman/O named/O Anita/PERSON ,/O her/O last/O name/O is/O Hay/O ./O 
Mr./O ,/O JAcKSON/PERSON ./O 
If/O possible/O ,/O will/O you/O give/O the/O occupation/O orMr/O ./O 
AIJ.AND/O ./O 
Les/PERSON Bryant/PERSON was/O at/O that/O time/O a/O soap/O manufacturer/O ,/O small/O soap/O manufacturer/O ./O 
He/O later/O became/O a/O small/O building/O contractor/O ./O 
Anita/PERSON Hay/PERSON was/O a/O housewife/O ,/O and/O her/O husband/O was/O a/O cost/O controller/O in/O some/O foundry/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O the/O particular/O place/O ./O 
As/O I/O said/O ,/O the/O members/O of/O the/O branch/O at/O the/O moment/O are/O very/O hazy/O to/O tie/O ,/O and/O I/O hope/O to/O ,/O with/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON 's/O help/O ,/O go/O through/O this/O again/O ./O 
I/O do/O recall/O persons/O coming/O to/O this/O branch/O to/O give/O lectures/O and/O so/O on/O ,/O and/O one/O was/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Paul/PERSON Perlin/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
Perlin/PERSON was/O a/O witness/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O refused/O to/O answer/O pertinent/O questions/O ,/O relying/O upon/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
He/O was/O one/O of/O the/O back-lot/O workers/O in/O the/O motion-picture/O indtstrv/O ./O 
Mr./O ALLANt/O ./O 
This/O man/O ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O had/O been/O introduced/O to/O me/O by/O my/O wife/O before/O the/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O Doiusr/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O times/O did/O lie/O come/O ,/O approximately/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLm/O ./O 
Before/O the/O war/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O Doyr/PERSON ,/O ./O 
Before/O your/O group-Perlin/O ./O 
Mr./O A/O ,/O TAim/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O several/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYmr/O ,/O ./O 
Five/O or/O sixI/O Mr./O ATT.AwNn/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O that/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAITNNF11/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O appearance/O before/O your/O group/O ?/O 
1/O Mr./O ALL/O ./O 
D.Well/O ./O 
he/O evidently/O occupied/O an/O important/O position/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O because/O he/O would/O come/O and/O conduct/O a/O series/O of/O lectures/O on/O party/O lines/O ,/O and/O he/O mainly/O kept/O the/O group/O straight/O on/O how/O to/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O DomuE/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O would/O attend/O these/O group/O meetings/O ?/O 
0518/O coim/O SmuACTrVrms/O iN/O TH/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O AuLAiw/PERSON ./O 
This/O branch/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O consisted/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O of/O about/O 20/O to/O 25/O people/O ./O 
But/O the/O attendance/O would/O vary/O from/O 10/O ,/O 15/O ,/O or/O 20/O sometimes/O ./O 
These/O were/O weekly/O meetings/O held/O at/O private/O homes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvNNE/O ./O 
Well/O you/O were/O giving/O us/O the/O names/O of/O persons/O who/O had/O appeared/O in/O the/O role/O of/O lecturers/O before/O your/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O -/O AuAi/O That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O continue/O ,/O please/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Perlin/PERSON is/O the/O person/O that/O appeared/O as/O a/O lecturer/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O others/O at/O the/O moment/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O is/O the/O most/O that/O I/O can/O recollect/O at/O the/O moment/O about/O this/O neighborhood/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvwzm/O ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O neighborhood/O branch/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALT/O Am/O ./O 
For/O several/O months/O ,/O from-well/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O from/O March/O of/O 1946/O or/O the/O date/O that/O I/O was/O recruited/O ,/O until/O the/O beginning/O of/O 1947/O ./O 
by/O this/O time/O the/O radio/O program/O was/O on/O the/O air/O Doorway/O to/O Life/O ,/O and/O doing/O well/O ./O 
And/O at/O this/O time/O I/O was/O ordered/O to/O transfer/O to/O a/O radio/O group/O Mr./O TAVE2NNR/O ./O 
How/O didyou/O receive/O that/O direction/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAN/PERSON ;D/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNR/PERSON ./O 
By/O whom/O and/O under/O whatcircumstancesI/O Mr./O A/O AND/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O was/O visited/O at/O home/O by/O Alvin/PERSON Hammer/PERSON ,/O who/O ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O I/O had/O never/O attended/O any/O meetings/O with/O ,/O but/O who/O visited/O me/O ,/O speaking/O in/O the/O name/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVNNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O he/O was/O a/O functionary/O in/O the/O Communist/O Part/O I/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
assumed/O that/O he/O was/O ,/O because/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O he/O came/O and/O told/O me/O that/O I/O should/O transfer/O to/O a/O radio/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O state/O for/O the/O record/O that/O Alvin/PERSON Hammer/PERSON was/O subpenaed/O to/O Washington/LOCATION to/O appear/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O refused/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O relating/O to/O his/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O alleged/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ,/O relying/O upon/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O A/O AND/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to-I/O did/O n't/O read/O or/O hear/O the/O testimony/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O but/O I/O understand/O that/O Mr./O Hammer/PERSON was/O asked/O if/O he/O knew/O a/O Ruth/PERSON Alland/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O you/O recall/O thisMr/O ./O 
Doyz/PERSON ./O 
Had/O he/O met/O her/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
She/O had/O lived/O with/O the/O Hammers/O while/O I/O was/O overseas/O and/O I/O had/O met/O them/O when/O I/O first/O came/O home/O ,/O and/O we/O rented/O rigt/O across/O the/O street/O from/O them/O ./O 
r./O TAVZNiNE/O ./O 
Was/O any/O reason/O assigned/O by/O Mr./O Hammer/PERSON as/O to/O why/O you/O should/O transfer/O to/O the/O radio/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
He/O felt/O that/O I/O could/O work/O for/O the/O party/O more/O efficiently/O in/O the/O radio/O group/O and/O I/O could/O gain/O some/O understanding/O ,/O perhaps/O of/O the/O radio/O writer/O in/O relation/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
./O 
Would/O you/O describe/O what/O he/O indicated/O your/O role/O should/O be/O ?/O 
Mr./O AmAw/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O did/O n't/O go/O any/O further/O ;/O in/O a/O sense/O ,/O he/O did/O n't/O have/O to/O ./O 
I/O understood/O what/O he/O meant/O ,/O you/O might/O say/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O got/O briefed/O much/O more/O thoroughly/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O after/O I/O transferred/O into/O the/O radio/O group/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O given/O my/O education/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
Mr.TAvawxu/O ./O 
Would/O you/O expand/O on/O that/O ,/O please/O ,/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O and/O tell/O the/O committeejust/O what/O your/O experiences/O were/O in/O the/O radio/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION I/O COMM/O `/O CNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 3519/O 31r/O ./O 
ALL/O ,/O 'D/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O you/O must/O understand/O in/O terms/O of/O the/O kind/O of/O show/O I/O was/O doing/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION wishes/O to/O pin/O all/O failings/O of/O people/O ,/O any/O kindof/O trouble/O a/O person/O might/O have/O ,/O on/O capitalism/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
If/O you/O break/O a/O leg/O ,/O they/O figure/O that/O you/O should/O ,/O by/O applying/O Marxist/O philosophy/O ,/O you/O can/O blame/O capitalism/O of/O the/O Unite/O States/O because/O you/O broke/O your/O leg/O ,/O because/O if/O the/O sidewalk/O was/O n't/O mended/O properly/O this/O means/O that/O somebody/O was/O greedy/O for/O money/O ,/O or/O something/O or/O other/O ,/O and/O the/O whole/O tenor/O of/O the/O whole/O thing/O was/O to/O so/O control/O your/O thinking/O that/O you/O could/O at/O any/O time/O come/O to/O the/O conclusion/O that/O ,/O directly/O or/O indirectly/O ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION -LRB-/O overnment/O ,/O and/O capitalism/O were/O responsible/O for/O all/O your/O troubles/O and/O all/O your/O problems/O ./O 
In/O this/O regard/O ,/O the/O whole/O concept/O of/O psychology/O ,/O the/O whole/O concept/O was/O that/O of/O a/O delinquent/O child/O could/O be/O delinquent/O because/O he/O was/O n't/O brought/O up/O properly/O by/O his/O parents/O ./O 
That/O was/O wrong/O ,/O frowned/O upon/O ,/O that/O it/O had/O to/O be/O something/O wrong/O with/O the/O country/O for/O him/O to/O be/O a/O delinquent/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
They/O therefore/O resisted/O very/O much/O this/O whole/O psychological/O approach/O ./O 
And/O ,/O frankly/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O understand/O why/O they/O did/O n't/O interfere/O with/O my/O show/O ./O 
Mr./O DoyrE/PERSON ./O 
Who/O interfere/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O say/O I/O do/O n't/O understand/O why/O they/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYm/O ./O 
Who/O did/O n't/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALri/O ,/O ?/O 
;/O N./O The/O party/O ,/O the/O leadership/O ./O 
I/O was/O always/O expecting/O them/O to/O crack/O down/O ,/O but/O they/O for/O some/O reason/O never/O did/O ./O 
In/O any/O case/O ,/O I/O can/O only/O conclude/O that/O they/O would/O have/O felt/O they/O would/O have/O trouble/O because/O niy/O material/O was/O completely/O documented/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O all/O medical/O records/O ,/O alnd/O they/O would/O have/O had/O a/O heck/O of/O a/O time/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYL/O ./O 
./O 
How/O would/O they/O have/O cracked/O down/O on/O your/O show/O What/O could/O they/O have/O done/O with/O your/O show/O ?/O 
You/O were/O the/O boss/O of/O it/O ./O 
You/O were/O the/O author/O of/O it/O ./O 
How/O could/O the/O Communists/O have/O done/O anything/O to/O your/O show/O ?/O 
You/O were/O under/O a/O contract/O ./O 
Mr./O AIJTAn/O ./O 
By/O this/O ,/O I/O mean/O that/O they/O could/O have/O ordered/O me/O to/O change/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O you/O would/O n't/O have/O obeyed/O their/O orders/O ./O 
You/O were/O under/O contract/O ./O 
Mr./O AIAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O certainly/O would/O n't/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyu/PERSON ./O 
What/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O certainly/O would/O not/O have/O obeyed/O them/O ./O 
But/O what/O I/O was/O saving/O ,/O I/O often/O wondered/O why/O they/O did/O n't/O and/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O it/O is/O very/O possible/O that/O they/O realized/O that/O they/O ,/O legally/O ,/O they/O could/O n't/O control/O me/O ,/O and/O left/O well/O enough/O alone/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O in/O the/O party/O then/O I/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLz/O ./O 
How/O much/O later/O on/O could/O they/O have/O bossed/O you/O and/O controlled/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O not/O --/O certainly/O not/O during/O the-you/O see/O ,/O the/O show/O ,/O the/O form/O of/O the/O show/O was/O prepared/O and/O developed/O and/O submitted/O to/O CBS/ORGANIZATION before/O I/O joined/O the/O party/O ./O 
While/O I/O was/O in/O the/O party/O is/O when/O CBS/ORGANIZATION bought/O the/O show/O ,/O and/O we/O were/O bound/O to/O a/O particular/O format/O ,/O and/O nothing/O could/O be/O done/O ./O 
Mr./O Dons/PERSON ./O 
Then/O there/O came/O a/O time/O in/O your/O party/O experience/O when/O the/O party/O could/O have/O controlled/O you/O in/O the/O show/O ,/O did/O n't/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLwre/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
81747-84/O --/O pt/O 8-4/O 362/O S/O IN/O TEN/O O0/O =/O UNST/O ACTWMIV/O DN/O ANOGLU/O AEA/O Mr./O Dom/PERSON ./O 
Not/O on/O this/O show/O ,/O but/O on/O a/O show/O I/O Mr./O AuAwN/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O after/O this/O show/O was/O over/O they/O could/O have/O ./O 
But/O time/O I/O went/O to/O work/O in/O the/O film/O industry/O I/O was/O already/O out/O of/O 20/O thearty/O ./O 
Mr.Donax/O I/O see/O ./O 
And/O the/O only/O reason/O you/O would/O n't/O have/O taken/O orders/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O this/O show/O is/O because/O the/O format/O and/O all/O was/O agreed/O to/O with/O CBSI/ORGANIZATION Mr./O AmAxD/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O Doym/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O under/O contract/O ?/O 
Mr./O Amax/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O DomE/O ./O 
If/O you/O had/O n't/O been/O under/O contract/O ,/O you/O would/O have/O been/O glad/O to/O change/O the/O format/O if/O the/O party/O had/O told/O you/O so/O I/O Mr./O Azra.fi/O I/O supose/O so/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvINwEa/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O of/O any/O instances/O in/O which/O a/O script/O ,/O either/O in/O radio/O or/O in/O the/O movies/O ,/O was/O altered/O at/O the/O insistence/O of/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O acting/O as/O a/O representative/O of/O the/O Communist/O Part/O Mr./O Au.ja/O Only/O by/O hearsay/O ./O 
I/O personally/O never/O had/O any/O direct/O personal/O knowledge/O of/O such/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O incident/O to/O which/O you/O refer/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O is/O n't/O a/O question/O of/O the/O incident/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O question/O of/O constant/O discussion/O of/O the/O material/O on/O which/O writers/O were/O working/O ./O 
In/O this/O regard/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O that/O the/O Communist/O writer/O working/O for/O films/O was/O always/O under/O the/O scrutiny/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O expected/O to/O check/O with/O his/O superiors/O as/O to/O what/O he/O was/O doing/O ,/O make/O sure/O that/O he/O was/O n't/O making/O any/O mistakes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENwNR/O ./O 
Are/O you/O speaking/O of/O superiors/O in/O the/O industry/O or/O superiors/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Superiors/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O particularly/O the/O educational/O experts/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
While/O I/O ca/O n't/O at/O the/O moment/O recall/O any/O specific/O story/O ,/O I/O do/O know/O that/O the/O writer/O was/O under/O surveillance/O by/O the/O party/O as/O to/O his/O work/O ,/O nnd/O nothing/O that/O could/O be/O construed/O as/O an/O antipropaganda/O would/O be/O tolerated/O ,/O nothing/O that/O could/O be/O considered/O anti-Russian/O would/O be/O tolerated/O ./O 
To/O glorify/O ,/O or/O not/O even/O to/O glorify/O ,/O to/O attempt/O to/O show/O in/O a/O good/O light/O an/O American/LOCATION tycoon/O ,/O for/O instance/O --/O by/O ``/O tycoon/O ''/O I/O mean/O a/O big-business/O man/O ,/O big/O corporation-to/O show/O him/O ats/O being/O a/O gentleman/O or/O a/O kind/O mali/O ,/O a/O liberal/O man/O ,/O would/O have/O been/O considered/O taboo/O ./O 
Me.Dom/O ./O 
You/O mean/O that/O screenwriters/O who/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O such/O as/O you/O ,/O would/O take/O their/O script/O away/O from/O their/O place/O of/O emplo/O ment/O and/O submit/O it/O to/O Communist/O educational/O functionaries/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O How/O would/O they/O check/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O this/O ,/O if/O they/O had/O been/O given/O an/O assignment/O of/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O ,/O a/O horror/O picture/O or/O western/O ,/O in/O which/O there/O was/O no/O opportunity/O for/O --/O or/O where/O the/O studio/O did/O not/O require/O that/O the/O writer/O comment/O ,/O in/O a/O sense-by/O ``/O comment/O ''/O I/O mean/O when/O you/O show/O a/O man/O a/O scene/O ,/O acting/O in/O a/O particular/O way/O toward/O his/O employees/O ,/O his/O family/O ,/O other/O people-this/O is/O in/O a/O sense/O portraying/O the/O character/O of/O am1an/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O say/O ,/O if/O it/O was/O the/O kind/O of/O a/O script/O where/O these/O possibilities/O did/O n't/O exist/O ,/O then/O there/O was/O n't/O any/O discussion/O ./O 
But/O if/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O ,/O the/O script/O dealt/O with/O ,/O in/O an/O way/O ,/O with/O issues/O ,/O attitudes/O ,/O ideas/O that/O could/O be/O made/O to/O seem/O to/O be/O detrimental/O to/O the/O party/O ,/O the/O writer/O COMMUNIST/ORGANIZATION ACTMVTES/ORGANIZATION IN/O TE/LOCATION LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 3521/O would/O certainly/O try/O to/O change/O them/O ./O 
And/O if/O he/O had/O trouble/O he/O would/O get/O help/O or/O try/O toget/O help/O ./O 
Mr./O DoML/O ./O 
Change/O them/O ./O 
But/O what/O I/O mean/O ,/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON ,/O would/O these/O Communist/O writers/O go/O to/O the/O point/O of/O taking/O their/O scripts/O away/O from/O the/O employer/O '/O a/O premises/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O take/O them/O to/O dignitaries/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O submit/O themI/O Mr./O AmLLAND/O ./O 
Absolutely/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O rule/O against/O taking/O a/O script/O home/O ./O 
I/O take/O scripts/O home/O to/O work/O on/O many/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O DoiaE/PERSON ./O 
There/O may/O not/O be/O any/O rule/O to/O taking/O them/O home/O ,/O but/O when/O you/O Communist/O writers/O would/O take/O them/O away/O from/O your/O employer/O 's/O premises/O to/O take/O them/O home/O ,/O would/O you/O also/O take/O them/O and/O submit/O them/O to/O your/O Communist/O bosses/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O they/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O DomE/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O did/O you/O I/O Mr./O AMIA/ORGANIZATION D./O No/O ,/O because/O ,/O you/O see/O ,/O I/O was/O not/O a/O member/O at/O the/O time/O I/O went/O to/O work/O in/O the/O film/O industry/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLLn/O ./O 
Why/O are/O you/O sure/O they/O would/O ?/O 
Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O because/O I/O know/O of/O instances/O ,/O although/O I/O can/O not/O recall/O the/O specific/O material-you/O know/O ,/O I/O would/O often/O hear/O Communist/O writers/O discussing/O the/O fact/O that/O he/O has/O a/O problem/O at/O the/O studio/O ,/O they/O want/O him/O to/O say/O something/O which/O he/O feels/O would/O be/O detrimental/O to/O the/O party/O ,/O or/O certain/O ideas/O they/O have/O ;/O and/O having/O trouble/O with/O the/O producer/O trying/O to/O switch/O it/O ,/O and/O what/O the/O heck/O can/O he/O do/O ,/O and/O discussing/O it/O back/O and/O forth/O ,/O on/O how/O to/O handle/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKson/PERSON ./O 
Would/O this/O be/O discussed/O at/O a/O meeting/O ,/O or/O would/O this/O be/O in/O the/O nature/O of/O a/O private/O discussion/O which/O you/O happened/O to/O be/O a/O party/O to/O orMr/O ./O 
ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Both/O ./O 
It/O could/O be/O the/O subject/O for/O informal/O discussion/O at/O a/O meeting/O or/O could/O be/O gone/O further/O into/O in/O a/O private/O discussion/O with/O a/O so-called/O expert/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O ,/O if/O not/O specifically/O ,/O generally/O ,/O any/O such/O discussion/O of/O a/O script/O at/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O on/O the/O problems/O such/O as/O you/O have/O described/O I/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
But/O ./O 
as/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O can/O not/O recall/O the/O specific/O time/O and/O place/O ./O 
But/O I/O definitely/O recall/O such/O discussions/O ./O 
M./O JACScON/O ./O 
