INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O INTHE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 2/O HEARINGS/O Before/O The/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-THIRD/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MARCH/O 26/O ,/O 27/O ,/O AND/O 28/O ,/O 1953/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O 81747/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1958/O COMMITTIO/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION DONALD/O L.JACKSON/O ,/O California/LOCATION MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION KIT/LOCATION CLARDY/LOCATION ,/O Michigan/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION CORDON/O H./PERSON SCHEIRER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O J./O ,/O Tennesee/LOCATION ROBERTT/O L./PERSON Kunzic/PERSON ,/O Consel/PERSON FRANK/PERSON S./PERSON TAVENNER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O Cheif/O Investigator/O THOMAS/PERSON W./PERSON BEALS/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ./O 
Cheif/O Clerk/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NixoN/PERSON ./O 
Director/O of/O Research/O CONTENTS/O March/O 26/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O of/O --/O Page/O 440/O Bart/O ---------------------------------/O Lytton/PERSON -LRB-/O recarlled/O -RRB-/O Jody/PERSON Gillbert/PERSON -----------------------------------------/O 461/O CharlotteDarling/O Adams/PERSON ---------------------------------/O 471/O Simon/PERSON Lazarus/PERSON M./O ---------------------------------------/O 478/O March/O 27/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O ofLeRoy/O Travers/O Hermdon/O ,/O Jr/O --------------------------------/O Richard/PERSON Byrd/PERSON Lewis/PERSON --------------------------------------/O Abraham/PERSON -------------------------------------------/O Minkus/O March/O 28/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O ofEdith/O Macla/O --------/O ------------------------------------/O Appearance/O of/O Charles/PERSON A./PERSON Page/PERSON ----------------------------/O Appearance/O of/O Harry/PERSON C./PERSON Steinmetz/PERSON -----------------------------/O Testimony/O ofBernard/O Lusher/O -----------------------------------------/O Ben/PERSON Maddow/PERSON -------------------------------------------/O Index/O ----------------------------------------------------------/O III/O 499/O 526/O 541/O 558/O 587/O 589/O 591/O 599/O 605/O The/O legislation/O under/O which/O the/O Ho/O ,/O use/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O operattes/O it/O Public/O Law/O -LRB-/O 01/O ,/O 79th/O Congress/ORGANIZATION -LSB-/O 1940/O -RRB-/O ,/O chapter/O 763/O ,/O 2d/O session/O ,/O which/O provides/O :/O Do/O it/O enactedd/O by/O the/O H/O na/O ite/O oand/O Ilosiim/O of/O RopKsacntatves/O of/O the/O united/O staloe/O of/O America/LOCATION itn/O Joiyreaa/PERSON uassenbl/O 'd/O ,/O \*/O \*/O \*/O i/O `/O AiiT/O 2-iMtULP1/O OF/O TII0/O 11OU10/O OP/O 10/O Iti00/O I/O '/O N/O `/O i/O `/O AT/O IVI/O HS/O RJU.M/O X/O 17/O ./O 
Commitee/O oi/O Un-Anerleani/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O ninie/O members/O ./O 
ItiLP/O ,/O Xl/O POWF-IW/O AND/O MITIR5/O OF/O CO1111IMKH/O :/O H/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Cominitee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-Amerlcan/O activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O `/O Te/O Comnilttee/O -LRB-/O in/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O i/O wholo/O or/O by/O subcommit/O ./O 
tee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O nike/O trout/O time/O to/O time/O Investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O aid/O objects/O of/O nitl-Ainerlean/O propaganda/O activities/O In/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 11/O -RRB-/O the/O ditlusloin/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propa/O ./O 
ganda/O that/O Is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Cmstitu/O ./O 
tion/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 111/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O In/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/O In/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O house/O -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/O If/O the/O 11ouse/O Is/O not/O In/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O It/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O Investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpoenas/O may/O be/O Issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O aniy/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 83D/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 8/O ,/O January/O 8/O ,/O 1953/O \*/O \*/O \*/O '/O a/O \*/O RULs/O X/O STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O L/O There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Con/O ./O 
gress/O ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ¥/O \*/O 0/O 0/O 0p/O 0/O Rut/O ./O 
%/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O Investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the.United/O States/O of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O Is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O In/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendatIons/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O Investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O Is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O It/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Suhpenas/O may/O be/O Issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O he/O served/O by/O any/O person/O desig/O ./O 
nated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O '/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 2/O THURSDAY/O ,/O NARCH/ORGANIZATION 26/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION Housp/ORGANIZATION ,/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O CouMMirrEr/O oN/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIrVITE/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O aZif/O ./O 
PUBLIC/O hEtAING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O adournment/O ,/O at/O 10:14/O a./O in./O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O -/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representutives/PERSON Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O Kit/PERSON Clardy/PERSON Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON iValter/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON and/O James/PERSON B./PERSON FPrazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON Jr/PERSON counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O chief/O investigator/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr/O cAief/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON i./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ;/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O VELW/O ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ./O 
Miss/O Reporter/O ,/O let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O present/O are/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Clardy/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Frazier/PERSON ,/O and/O the/O chairman/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O a/O quorum/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Before/O calling/O the/O first/O witness/O ,/O may/O I/O call/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O public/O a/O message/O I/O have/O received/O from/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VELE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVNNZR/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mrs./O Silvia/PERSON Richards/PERSON ,/O reference/O was/O made/O near/O the/O end/O of/O her/O testimony/O to/O a/O position/O taken/O by/O a/O person/O b/O ~/O y/O the/O name/O of/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON with/O reference/O to/O writers/O who/O played/O an/O important/O part/O in/O the/O war/O effort/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O telegram/O has/O been/O received/O from/O a/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON ,/O who/O states/O he/O is/O not/O the/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON referred/O to/O in/O that/O message/O ./O 
I/O think/O possibly/O I/O should/O read/O the/O telegram/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O and/O read/O the/O telegram/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON -LRB-/O reading/O -RRB-/O :/O DtEA/O SI/O :/O Silvia/PERSON Richards/PERSON in/O her/O testimony/O yesterday/O stated/O that/O a/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O were/O members/O of/O the/O screen/O writers/O '/O group/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O wish/O to/O state/O that/O I/O am/O not/O the/O Lewis/PERSON Allen/PERSON referred/O to/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O motion.picture/O director/O ,/O not/O a/O writer/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O never/O belonged/O to/O any/O writers/O '/O group/O or/O guild/O ./O 
This/O confusion/O came/O up/O once/O before/O and/O almost/O cost/O me/O a/O Job/O but/O fortunately/O it/O was/O corrected/O in/O time/O ./O 
In/O order/O to/O avoid/O a/O repetition/O of/O this/O and/O in/O view/O of/O the/O wide/O publicity/O of/O your/O hearing/O I/O would/O be/O very/O grateful/O If/O you/O would/O make/O a/O public/O statement/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
L/O 43ws/O Auzz/O ./O 
439/O 440/O COMMUNIL/O '/O A/O A0/O ,1/O IVITIVR/O IN/O TIM/O 1,08/O AN/O -LRB-/O IhM/O AIINA/O ir/O ./O 
Wi111/O ''/O ./O 
,/O Willy/PERSON I/O uii1iko/O it/O stttellienit/O ,/O regirlllig/O inuy/O conlfilOillIII/O identity/O ,/O thlt/O ,/O ill/O VlKO/O anyoiiezH/O li111111/O IN/O liiight/O 1li/O -RRB-/O lort/O 1114/O leIng/O it/O lllnieiiihi/O o/O -RRB-/O f/O the/O COnmnnlstl/O l/O I/O iaty/O or/O atie/O o/O -RRB-/O Ifo/O '/O l/O llelil/O -RRB-/O le/O '/O of/O -LRB-/O ,/O lle/O -LRB-/O ,/O olllllill/O ./O 
11i1/O ,/O i/O Pary/O ,/O l/O whoso/O Iitiiiii/O IN/O illaillir/O to/O fhiat/O Of/O 5Ollle/O o/O Iie/O '/O ,/O '/O j/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1solll/O ill/O it/O ¡/O Simlilhar/O oceu/O |/O piliil/O ,/O thlo/O coilillnftltm/O would/O welolll/O aihit/O H1/O -LSB-/O 111/O ,/O qI011rill/O or/O Afilli/O ./O 
il/O ill/O hdllltvy/O Mr./O '/O ,/O lill/O #ltI/O ~/O l/O o/O 0110/O ./O 
we/O Illight/O -LRB-/O 40o11r/O 11/O -RRB-/O il/O 41Ollfllmholi/O P11-oed/O ,/O I/O ''/O NNH11/O ,/O Mr./O -RSB-/O illf/O |/O 1ytiOll/O ,/O Will/O You/O r111ll14l/O to0/O I-he/O HIIIII/O -LRB-/O l/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O DART/O LYTTON/LOCATION ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O STEVEN/PERSON WEISMAN-Reoalled/O 1/O ir/O ,/O '/O l/O ^/O AV/O -RRB-/O \*/O ./O 
NI'I/O ,/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
Tiyttoi/O ,/O 1re/O you/O Ii/O -LRB-/O eoipalid/O Iby/O 1h1h/O couilll/O wh/O e/O coilpaIliad/O you1/O hler/O yosterlay/O I/O Air/O ./O 
LVTPIXON/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sii1/O '/O r/O ,/O ~/O lli/O ~/O lI/O iilX/O O/O ~/O ll/O i/O eH1/O lYCI/O ~/O X/O 1114/O ,/O Ai.W/O 8101iHil18010Ofiy/O who/O is/O ill/O C'oulrt/O todaiy/O ./O 
Mr/O '/O ./O 
WiSIIAN/O ./O 
My/O '/O 11111110/O Is/O Steve1/O W/O s1111111/O ,/O ,103/O Wesi/O 8h/O 1i/O stiet-0/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O Moflltt/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O liei/O yestoloday/O ,/O IN/O elgaild/O in/O the/O alluorll/O out/O today/O ,/O 111111ihis/O Il/O %/O %/O -/O pile!mr/O ./O 
fr.Lytt/O on/O ,/O at/O Ole/O t/O iwot/O yoiir/O lestiiaoiy/O wasN/O coil/O ./O 
tfinued/O over/O until/O today/O ,6/O okwere/O telling/O ,/O I/O No/O coilliniittet/O abLout/O all/O 0XVpIiOIWOi/O that/O i/O `/O oii/O hadiin/O I.As/O A/O ngtilem/O ./O 
``/O oU/O were/O advising/O tile/O coniniittee/O that/O In1talking/O to/O a/O m/O -LRB-/O ere/O -LRB-/O n/O writer/O fr.TAVNNN/O 1/O ./O 
the/O stittll/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O tUt/O WIIs/O IaIIle/O ,/O to/O you/O to/O Illh/O get1er1/O eeelc/O ,/O ``/O WIly/O doll/O `/O t/O ,/O you/O colnie/O ii/O and/O hcoine/O ono/O Of/O Itst/O ''/O -LRB-/O -RSB-/O tlepisentativo/O -RSB-/O cit/O Clardy/PERSON onltfed/O -/O lie/O hearing/O rooli/O fit/O this/O point/O ,/O M./O '/O 1AVCNN/O i./O And/O I/O belitee/O you/O wor-e/O considering/O that/O for/O a/O period/O of/O tOne/O and/O the/O individual/O cauno/O haeic/O to/O you/O auid/O 1a/O '/O o/O a/O statement/O ;/O to/O the/O general/O efrect/O that/O lie/O liun/O -LRB-/O derstool/O that/O yOU/O had/O been/O exPolled/O froil/O the/O Collulililst/O -RSB-/O 1arty/O inNew/O York/O anl/O that/O relatedd/O it/O situation/O which/O you/O ought/O to/O get/O ,/O ceared/O ilp/O ./O 
You/O stated/O further/O that/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O conversation/O this/O person/O iuade/O reference/O to/O the/O fact/O that/O if/O you/O did/O n't/O get/O this/O cleared/O up/O your/O uaUe/O would/O be/O ``/O Mud/O ''/O in/O this/O comnnu11ity/O ./O 
I/O asked/O you/O who/O made/O that/O statement/O to/O you/O and/O you/O said/O Mr./O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O expression/O that/O you/O made/O about/O the/O necessity/O of/O clearing/O up/O of/O this/O matter/O else/O your/O name/O would/O be/O ``/O Mud/O ''/O in/O this/O community/O has/O been/O interpreted/O in/O some/O sources/O as/O having/O constituted/O a/O threat/O on/O the/O part/O of/O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON as/O it/O means/O or/O a/O weapon/O to/O compel/O you/O to/O come/O into/O the/O party/O ./O 
If/O that/O is/O true/O ,/O I/O want/O you/O to/O state/O so/O clearly/O ,/O and/O if/O it/O is/O n't/O true/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O n't/O the/O correct/O interpretation/O of/O your/O testimony/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O for/O you/O to/O clarify/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O L-rrov/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON is/O about/O as/O threatening/O as/O the/O St./ORGANIZATION Louis/ORGANIZATION Browns/ORGANIZATION ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON was/O not/O threateiiing/O me/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O take/O it/O as/O a/O threat/O ./O 
I/O took/O it/O quite/O differently/O at/O the/O time/O and/O I/O would/O again/O conclude/O today/O that/O his/O purpose/O was/O not/O ,/O to/O threaten/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
His/O purpose/O was/O to/O advise/O me/O ./O 
That/O was/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O he/O approached/O it/O and/O that/O is/O the/O manner/O in/O which/O he/O handled/O it/O straight/O firough/O ,/O because/O more/O than/O tlat/O occurred/O ./O 
George/PERSON 's/O attitude/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O and/O he/O and/O I/O are/O friends/O ,/O and/O although/O I/O have/O n't/O seen/O George/PERSON for/O many/O ,/O many/O years/O ,/O his/O attitude/O seemed/O to/O COMMUNIWV/O A/O -LRB-/O TIVVITII/O \*/O IN/O `/O IMI/O 1AI4/O ANOI.GHd/O ARICA/LOCATION 441/O be/O ``/O lhiis/O 191ot/O ,/O good/O -LRB-/O for/O yol/O ./O 
ThiO/O will/O hat/O you/O ,/O will/O ,/O hurt/O ,/O your/O career/O '/O ./O 
Yolll/PERSON naime/O i/O Mud/O ,/O Why/O dol/O `/O ty/O .0/O 1omething/O o/O about/O it/O ?/O ''/O 
But/O t/O Mr./O To'i/O velillel/O ,/O before/O I/O go/O any/O furtlher/O in/O regard/O to/O -RRB-/O this/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O gilt/O a/O little/O 11111ll/O '/O 1/O ,/O oif/O of/O lily/O ln/O -LRB-/O linI/O regitrd/O 1A/O -RRB-/O an/O ici/O -/O d4/O 'n/O thitat/O -LRB-/O oe/O urre/O -LRB-/O d/O olily/O elli/O -LRB-/O liIlg/O tie/O room/O tllis/O ior/O liltg/O s/O Mr./O WAI\/rv-lt/O ./O 
Before/O yfu/O go/O ill/O toh/O Ii/O '/O it/O nllty/O I.gill/O 1/O ,/O right/O in/O lily/O own/O Illilid/O :/O Wailti/PERSON ./O 
fl/O Wias/O lolling/O yolu/O Wils/PERSON tl111L/O ino/O fialerility/O brotlher/O were/O get/O tilng/O ile/O 1hot/O of/O it/O ,/O is/O n't/O that/O It/O ?/O 
M/O '/O ./O 
LVI/ORGANIZATION `/O rON/O ,/O ,/O Y41/O ./O 
Maiy/O I/O silllk/O 0n/O tohn/O ch/O -LRB-/O 11/O `/O l/O ,/O alttde/O ,/O ?/O 
Mr./O l/O -RRB-/O ov/O ,/O H./O What/O ,/O was/O yomr/O lllsWl/O `/O e/O '/O You/O tiodhed/O y3lilr/O 1141/O -LRB-/O ./O 
Mr./O Lrzor/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O sir/O ./O 
Wihell/O I/O el1tled/O tile/O room/O thi/O morning/O ,/O itrather/O nice-looking/O grty/O ./O 
hialired/O youig/O woniit11itI/O -LRB-/O I/O ,/O ``/O Sliltlnle/O oil/O you/O ./O ''/O 
8/O e/O Hill/PERSON led/O wIenI411/O 1411Id/O ly/O ,1/O it/O ./O 
-LRB-/O ,1110/O ,/O litoo/O -RRB-/O le/O ,/O -LRB-/O ,/O ``/O ShaIlio/O oil/O file/O for/O what/O ?/O ''/O 
and/O she/O said/O ,/O ``/O 1For/O be/O fig/O a/O H1061/O pigeotl/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Slll8lllo/O 4/O -RRB-/O 1l/O yOll/O cll/O 11ii/O fll/O $/O s/O s/O t/O iS/O ly/O I/O fiel/O ./O ''/O 
I/O feel/O very/O ollrry/O for/O suhll/O 1tll/O 11111/O .111/O oi/O `/O ry/O fi/O \*/O ll/O heI/O Ihely/O lickileS4/O he1/O thicllheadedness/O thuit/O illa/O ~/O iloplIe/O ./O 
t111Pmt/O ,/O osill/O foit101n9/O -LCB-/O like/O ./O 
orililt/O ,/O thi111k/O thlat/O i/O -RRB-/O rinpi19/O tl/O .4/O ey/O Olight/PERSON o/O know/O that/O tliey/O do/O not/O intimidate/O people/O any/O ongelr/O by/O tis/O device/O ./O 
It/O is/O tired/O an/O -LRB-/O l/O worn/O out/O ;/O the/O vast/O Bulk/O of/O tile/O American/LOCATION people/O express/O thenselves/O quite/O differently/O ./O 
There/O was/O it/O 10117/O -RRB-/O 11011/O -LRB-/O -/O fill/O I/O ~/O Ot/O ,/O last/O hlij/O ItI/O ,/O 01/O '/O ,/O yestei/O `/O da11/O afternoon1/O from/O Stiff/O D/O ~/O iego/O $/O f0rom/O it/O Mr/O 's/O ./O 
liriy/O H06/O %/O ,/O whioi/O I/O -LRB-/O lon/O t/O know/O a1/O whio/O -LRB-/O !/O 
erfailll/O wits/O 11o/O -LRB-/O 0/O '/O 9/O -RRB-/O ek1lf/O ./O 
IioI/O wait/O phlasan/O ~/O t./O womanp/O who/O told/O mie/O site/O hItaril/O my/O testimony/O yestari/O `/O dy/O ./O 
Th/O '/O 1is/O encouraged/O fie/O ./O 
There/O wero/O inany/O other/O 09I19/O received/O ./O 
I/O tOink/O it/O ,/O is/O well/O thit/O flw/O I/O ,/O people/O know/O that/O by/O the/O use/O of/O terms/O like/O ``/O stA/O -RRB-/O ol/O pigeon/O ,/O ''/O ``/O link/O ,/O ''/O aid/O ``/O informer/O ,/O ''/O and/O No/O forth/O ,/O they/O brand/O themselves/O quite/O correctly/O its/O those/O involved/O in/O It/O conspiracy/O ./O 
I/O wits/O never/O iti/O a/O conspiracy/O ,/O and/O therefore/O I/O can/O never/O be/O a/O stool/O l/O -RRB-/O lgoll/O ./O 
Mr./O WAIT/O :/O I./O Biut/O more/O than/O that/O ,/O do/O n't/O they/O admit/O by/O tile/O ise/O of/O HIIch/O teirln/O lirtcyI/O that/O thly/O fire/O parties/O to/O some/O sort/O of/O ILn/O unlawful/O con/O ./O 
Mr./O ,/O i/O -/O o'zx/O ?/O 
./O 
I/O would/O rather/O think/O so/O ./O 
I/O would/O reach/O rather/O tile/O Name/O conclusion/O and/O inference/O from/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O CL.AnD/O ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O hear/O tile/O word/O ``/O stool/O pigeon/O ''/O used/O in/O connection/O with/O anything/O other/O than/O criminal/O ./O 
.../O Mr./O Lr/PERSON -/O roN/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O that/O the/O normal/O use/O of/O that/O word/O I/O You/O call/O a/O man/O itstool/O pigeon/O because/O -RRB-/O e/O is/O telling/O the/O authorities/O of/O something/O that/O has/O been/O done/O of/O an/O unlawful/O nature/O ./O 
Mr./O Lyro/PERSON -RRB-/O N./PERSON Well/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O that/O the/O term/O has/O been/O used/O a/O bit/O more/O broadly/O than/O that/O ,/O Congressman/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O sometimes/O it/O is/O used/O in/O labor/O circles/O in/O regard/O to/O anyone/O who/O talks/O to/O even/O management/O incertain/O instances/O ./O 
Mr./O CJJARY/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O generally/O find/O a/O red/O taint/O in/O connection/O with/O tile/O use/O of/O that/O word/O by/O that/O person/O ;/O do/O you/O not/O I/O Mr./O Lyvrox/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O that/O the/O people/O referred/O specifically/O to/O a/O conspiracy/O ./O 
I/O can/O only/O say/O that/O to/O le/O it/O clearly/O is/O evidence/O of/O a/O feeling/O of/O conspiracy/O ./O 
Mr./O CLAnRmy/O ./O 
They/O certainly/O are/O not/O on/O our/O side/O ./O 
Mr./O Lrro/PERSON ;/O ./O 
Let/O us/O put/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
442/O COMMNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O TIM/O LOS/O ANGLES/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVfENNER/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O the/O various/O experiepces/O that/O you/O had/O In/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O after/O you/O arrived/O here/O ,/O did/O you/O finally/O unite/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION again/O ?/O 
Air/O ./O 
Lrr.N/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O let/O me/O continue/O In/O regard/O to/O the/O last/O question/O and/O this/O question/O ,/O because/O we/O have/O a/O basic/O continuity/O there/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O reiterate/O ,/O so/O there/O is/O no/O question/O about/O it/O ,/O that/O George/PERSON Beck/PERSON did/O n't/O threaten/O me/O ./O 
-LRB-/O leorge/O Beck/PERSON was/O counseling/O me/O to/O the/O best/O of/O his/O knowledge/O and/O belief/O that/O this/O is/O what/O would/O happen/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O ./O 
George/PERSON Beck/PERSON would/O corrloborite/O at/O any/O time/O that/O he/O said/O it/O to/O me/O and/O that/O he/O advised/O me/O to/O handle/O the/O matter/O by/O clearing/O these/O charges/O up/O ./O 
Ho/PERSON pointed/O out/O at/O the/O time/O that/O if/O charges/O like/O this/O were/O bandied/O about/O ,/O that/O not/O only/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Coinmunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O but/O that/O liberals/O and/O nanny/O people/O who/O had/O no/O particular/O politics/O would/O hear/O vatgute/O and/O disturbing/O things/O about/O me/O ,/O or/O perhaps/O specific/O things/O ,/O and/O that/O they/O would/O then/O consider/O me/O anathema/O ,/O to/O their/O to/O their/O way/O of/O living/O or/O their/O principles/O or/O anything/O else/O ./O 
And/O he/O felt/O that/O the/O waves/O of/O such/O a/O reaction/O could/O be/O disastrous/O to/O my/O career/O and/O to/O my/O sense/O of/O well-being/O ,/O because/O my/O first/O response/O was/O ``/O Oh/O ,/O chuck/O it/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O do/O anything/O about/O it/O ./O ''/O 
After/O several/O conversations/O on/O the/O matter/O ,/O I/O had/O to/O conclude/O it/O was/O important/O ./O 
I/O was/O angry/O about/O it/O ,/O and/O ns/O more/O came/O to/O me/O my/O anger/O mounted/O ./O 
It/O was/O based/O on/O no/O facts/O ./O 
It/O was/O based/O on/O neither/O evidence/O nor/O what/O proved/O later/O to/O be/O factual/O ,/O so/O I/O began/O to/O set/O to/O work/O with/O a/O will/O ./O 
I/O was/O put/O in/O contact/O with/O an/O Elizaheth/PERSON Glenn/PERSON ./O 
1/O was/O given/O to/O understand/O that/O she/O was/O in/O a/O membership/O capacity/O in/O the/O Coxmunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
Did/O site/O have/O another/O name/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O ?/O 
Mr./O Lrrow/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O I/O may/O have/O given/O the/O wrong/O name/O there/O ./O 
Is/O it/O LeechI/O Mr./O TAvvNNmR/O ./O 
Our/O information/O is/O she/O was/O known/O at/O different/O times/O by/O both/O of/O those/O names/O ,/O Glenn/PERSON and/O Leech/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O LyTToN/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O have/O heard/O both/O references/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O her/O ./O 
I/O was/O put/O in/O contact/O with/O her/O by/O Beck/PERSON ,/O and/O she/O reviewed/O the/O story/O with/O me/O ./O 
She/O told/O me/O that/O there/O were/O a/O number/O of/O charges/O leveled/O against/O me/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O done/O everything/O ,/O apparently/O ,/O but/O set/O fire/O to/O my/O mother/O ./O 
She/O stated/O that/O I/O had/O been/O expelled/O from/O the/O party/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O best/O of/O their/O knowledge/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O had/O been/O considered/O as/O unreliable/O ,/O a/O provocateur-a/O term/O frequently/O bandied/O about-and/O that/O I/O had/O stolen/O a/O typewriter/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION headquarters/O and/O had/O pawned/O same/O ,/O and/O that/O I/O had/O deserted/O the/O party/O ./O 
The/O party/O likes/O faithful/O lovers/O and/O many/O other/O things/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O even/O recall/O them/O all/O :/O Now/O ,/O if/O she/O said/O that/O I/O deserted/O the/O party/O ,/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O this/O is/O true/O ./O ''/O 
But/O as/O to/O the/O typewriter/O incident/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O truth/O in/O it/O whatsoever/O ./O 
As/O to/O having/O been/O expelled/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O knew/O there/O was/O no/O truth/O in/O it/O whatsoever/O ,/O and/O presented/O the/O charges/O ./O 
I/O asked/O her/O what/O I/O could/O do/O about/O it/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O did/O n't/O seem/O that/O I/O could/O do/O very/O much/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O asked/O her/O if/O there/O was/O such/O a/O thing/O as/O a/O hearing/O ./O 
She/O said/O ,/O well/O they/O take/O care/O of/O it/O in/O their/O own/O way/O ./O 
She/O said/O she/O would/O correspond/O with/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANORLEB/O AREA/O 448/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O you/O ought/O to/O know/O something/O next/O week/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O it/O will/O be/O longer/O than/O that/O ./O ''/O 
Many/O months/O went/O by/O and/O -/O I/O became/O more/O and/O more/O agitated/O ,/O because/O now/O a/O process/O began/O ./O 
People/O previously/O friendly/O to/O me/O were/O no/O longer/O friendly/O ./O 
I/O would/O arrange/O to/O have/O dinner/O with/O friends/O ,/O my/O wife/O and/O I/O ,/O and/O at/O the/O lost/O minute/O the/O dinner/O date/O would/O be/O canc4ed/O ./O 
I/O would/O walk/O into/O gild/O meethgM/O and/O backs/O would/O be/O turned/O if/O I/O went/O to/O enter/O the/O conversations/O avid/O I/O became/O very/O agitated/O at/O this/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O pleasant/O ,/O and/O I/O still/O did/O n't/O fully/O understand/O it/O ./O 
I/O understood/O the/O emanation/O of/O it/O ./O 
I/O meant/O to/O say/O that/O I/O wits/O not/O equipped/O to/O handle/O it/O at/O this/O time/O ./O 
It/O therefore/O became/O a/O struggle/O on/O my/O part/O ,/O I/O should/O say/O ,/O and/O a/O very/O important/O one/O ,/O to/O clear/O these/O particular/O charges/O ./O 
I/O was/O n't/O concerned/O at/O that/O time/O with/O the/O issue/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O was/O concerned/O with/O the/O fact/O that/O apparently/O a/O rumor/O factory/O and/O a/O very/O competent/O rumor/O factory/O wts/O at/O work/O ./O 
Ohe/O incident/O brought/O it/O into/O its/O sharpest/O focus/O ./O 
I/O had/O been/O a/O proliflic/O provider/O of/O material/O for/O USO/O camp/O shows/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O I/O was/O told/O by/O the/O USO/O that/O I/O wrote/O more/O camp/O show/O material/O than/O auy/O other/O writer/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O was/O commended/O by/O them/O for/O that/O ./O 
Some/O of/O my/O sketches/O had/O played/O to/O as/O many/O ,/O I/O wits/O told/O ,/O as/O 6/O million/O meni/O ./O 
It/O seemed/O like/O an/O awful/O lot/O to/O me/O ./O 
And/O I/O doubted/O it/O ,/O but/O nevertheless/O I/O knew/O they/O were/O played/O to/O many/O ,/O many/O Army/O camps/O and/O installations/O throughout-where/O tightinF/O forces/O were/O stationed/O ./O 
rilhe/O USO/O w/O ~/O as/O trying/O to/O ./O 
get/O comedy/O material/O unslanted/O ,/O and/O they/O arranlgedl/O at/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild-not/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O the/O 11ollywood/O Writers/O '/O 11obilization-to/O have/O an/O evening/O in/O which/O theT/O would/O showv/O the/O kind/O of/O material/O that/O they/O wanted/O ./O '/O 
I/O hey/O gave/O me/O what/O was/O to/O the/O Communist/O the/O kiss/O of/O death/O ./O 
It/O shows/O my/O material/O as/O unslanted/O material/O ./O 
That/O evening/O Carole/PERSON Landis/PERSON and/O Fay/PERSON McKenzie/PERSON and/O Ed/PERSON Lorre/PERSON who/O ran/O USO/ORGANIZATION camp/O shows/O ,/O entertainment/O division/O came/O down/O together/O with/O others/O --/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O whom-to/O the/O ollywood-Roosevelt/O Hotel/O ,/O and/O they/O played/O these/O sketches/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O one/O sketch/O was/O the/O forerunner/O of/O a/O type/O of/O sketch/O that/O has/O become/O tiresome/O enough/O since/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O psychiatric/O sketch/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O there/O had/O n't/O been/O psychiatrist/O sketches/O of/O this/O character/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O very/O funny/O sketch/O ,/O and/O it/O had/O played/O already/O with/O teams/O taking/O it/O out/O and/O stars/O requesting/O to/O take/O it/O out/O ,/O even/O though/O it/O had/O ben/O old/O material/O by/O this/O time/O ,/O they/O still/O wanted/O to/O take/O it/O out/O to/O military/O installations/O ./O 
The/O sketch/O was/O played/O ,/O and/O most/O of/O the/O writers/O present/O sat/O on/O their/O hands/O ./O 
They/O did/O n't/O laugh/O ,/O they/O did/O n't/O applaud/O ,/O they/O did/O n't/O like/O it/O ./O 
This/O was/O rather/O unusual/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O by/O that/O time/O several/O hundred/O thousand/O American/O 01/O 's/O had/O laughed/O their/O heads/O off/O at/O the/O sketch/O ./O 
And/O these/O were/O supposed/O to/O be/O judges/O of/O material/O ./O 
It/O was/O brought/O in/O because/O it/O was/O to/O be/O the/O top/O laugh/O producer/O that/O the/O USO/ORGANIZATION had/O in/O its/O repertoire/O ./O 
They/O sat/O on/O their/O hanas/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O deeply/O agitated/O by/O this/O ./O 
I/O began/O to/O feel/O by/O this/O time/O that/O I/O was/O involved/O in/O a/O crusade/O ./O 
I/O had/O n't/O done/O what/O was/O charged/O ./O 
The/O feelings/O at/O that/O time/O were/O not/O political/O ;/O they/O were/O personal/O ./O 
I/O wanted/O to/O clear/O a/O name/O and/O be/O able/O to/O work/O again/O and/O work/O in/O peace/O ./O 
444/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O TILE/O LOS/O ANGELES/O AREA/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O many/O months/O ensued/O ./O 
It/O dissolves/O ,/O as/O you/O sy/O in/O motion-picture/O terminology/O ./O 
But/O lots/O of/O time/O elapsed/O ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O this/O time/O I/O did/O everything/O that/O I/O know/O to/O do/O to/O clear/O the/O so-called/O charges/O ./O 
Subsequently/O I/O was/O engad/O to/O do/O a/O documentary/O fl/O m/O by/O Prince/PERSON ./O 
ton/O Film/O Center/O ,/O the/O Rockefeller/ORGANIZATION Foundation/ORGANIZATION subsidizing/O it/O ,/O in/O Gloucester/LOCATION ,/O Mass./LOCATION ,/O on/O war/O shipbuilding/O ./O 
I/O wont/O up/O there/O and/O did/O the/O film/O and/O came/O back/O through/O Now/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
In/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION I/O went/O to/O Communist/O Party/O headquarters/O on/O 13th/O Street/O ,/O and/O I/O told/O them/O my/O story/O ./O 
I/O told/O them/O that/O there/O was/O this/O story/O extant/O on/O the/O west/O coast/O ,/O that/O it/O was/O n't/O true/O ,/O and/O I/O wanted/O them/O to/O produce/O for/O me/O any/O records/O which/O indicated/O any/O truth/O in/O these/O particular/O charges/O ./O 
q/O I/O also/O said/O to/O them/O ,/O ``/O If/O these/O charges/O are/O true/O ,/O would/O you/O have/O a/O record/O I/O ''/O They/O said/O ,/O ``/O Oh/O ,/O certainly/O ,/O we/O would/O ./O 
If/O the/O charges/O are/O true/O ,/O believe/O me/O ,/O we/O will/O have/O them.I/O About/O a/O half/O hour/O passed/O and/O a/O girl/O came/O to/O me/O who/O introduced/O herself/O as/O an/O organization/O secretary/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
In/O sviy/O event/O ,/O I/O was/O taken/O to/O another/O floor/O ./O 
I/O waited/O some/O more/O ./O 
8he/O came/O back/O down/O and/O told/O me/O ,/O ``/O Not/O only/O are/O there/O no/O charges/O against/O you/O ,/O but/O somebody/O up/O stairs/O knew/O you/O who/O says/O you/O are/O a/O md/O hty/O fine/O fellow/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O No/O ;/O we/O have/O no/O record/O whatsoevere/O and/O ,/O therefore/O there/O would/O n't/O be/O any/O truth/O in/O these/O charges/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O they/O seem/O to/O believe/O it/O in/O the/O West/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O that/O is/O pretty/O far/O away/O ./O 
What/O do/O you/O want/O us/O to/O do/O about/O it/O I/O ''/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O For/O heaven/O 's/O sake/O ,/O lot/O them/O know/O that/O these/O charges/O are/O untrue/O and/O tell/O them/O to/O stop/O their/O rumor/O factory/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O We/O will/O be/O very/O glad/O to/O ./O ''/O 
I/O appreciated/O that/O ./O 
I/O came/O back/O to/O the/O coast/O ./O 
I/O got/O in/O touch/O with/O the/O same/O people/O ./O 
No/O word/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
More/O time/O went/O on/O months/O ./O 
Finally/O ,/O apparently/O there/O was/O word/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O ao/O n't/O know/O what/O oiircuitous/O routes/O it/O took/O ,/O whether/O it/O came/O out/O by/O carrier/O pigeons/O or/O how/O ,/O but/O ,/O in/O any/O event/O ,/O apparently/O the/O word/O came/O out/O at/O that/O time/O that/O I/O was/O cleared/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION and/O that/O the/O charges/O were/O groundless/O ./O 
This/O Elizabeth/PERSON Leech/PERSON Glenn/PERSON again/O contacted/O me/O and/O told/O me/O that/O I/O was/O cleared/O and/O they/O regretted/O very/O much/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O had/O been/O so/O badly/O treated/O as/O a/O result/O of/O It/O ,/O she/O was/O sorry/O ,/O and/O she/O sent/O a/O rather/O inept/O public-relations/O officer/O ,/O I/O might/O say/O ,/O to/O see/O me/O at/O my/O home/O ,/O who/O explained/O that/O in/O revolutionary/O situations/O the/O innocent/O must/O die/O with/O the/O guilty/O ,/O it/O is/O just/O too/O bad/O ./O 
``/O We/O are/O sorry/O ,/O fellow/O ,/O that/O this/O hap/O ./O 
pened/O to/O you/O ./O 
We/O are/O sorry/O that/O for/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O now/O ,/O ''/O or/O a/O year/O ,/O whatever/O the/O time/O was/O ,/O ``/O we/O understand/O ,/O it/O is/O awful/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ./O 
``/O Once/O up/O in/O Michigan/LOCATION the/O same/O thing/O happened/O to/O me/O ,/O I/O was/O called/O a/O renegade/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ,/O ``/O a/O Trotskyite/O ,/O and/O some/O kind/O of/O deviationist/O ./O ''/O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O lived/O through/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O what/O it/O is/O and/O I/O understand/O ,/O ''/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
``/O And/O it/O is/O too/O bad/O ,/O but/O you/O must/O n't/O have/O any/O ill/O feeling/O toward/O the/O party/O ./O 
You/O must/O understand/O it/O ./O 
You/O must/O be/O a/O Bolshevik/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAvrsmm/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O name/O of/O the/O emissary/O that/O came/O to/O see/O you/O I/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIPA/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 445/O Mr./O Ln/PERSON rox/O ./O 
Her/O name/O and/O her/O face/O blotted/O out/O from/O my/O memory/O ,/O I/O think/O instantly/O ./O 
I/O found/O it/O itparticularly/O painful/O interview/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O like/O it./O ;/O I/O was/O tincoinfortable/O and/O tlnhappy/O about/O it/O ./O 
I/O have/O novel/O ,/O seen/O her/O before/O or/O since/O ./O 
I/O can/O only/O state/O that/O sho/O stated/O site/O was/O from/O Michigan/LOCATION ./O 
More/O than/O that/O I/O do/O not/O know/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O she/O did/O n't/O give/O me/O a/O name/O ./O 
I/O might/O make/O that/O point/O clear/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
People/O are/O not/O necessarily/O intro/O ./O 
duced/O to/O each/O other/O formally/O in/O tile/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O first/O names/O are/O often/O used/O ./O 
You/O will/O learn/O a/O name/O ,/O but/O you/O are/O not/O necessarily/O brought/O up/O to/O itperson/O and/O someone/O does/O n't/O say/O ``/O Comrade/O So-andSo/O ,/O meet/O Cotnlrado/O So-and-So/O ./O ''/O 
It/O is/O n't/O done/O th1is/O way/O ,/O at/O least/O in/O this/O short/O experience/O that/O I/O had/O ./O 
So/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O who/O sihe/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O a4sk/O a/O question/O itthis/O point/O ?/O 
./O 
I/O Mr./O VE/O ,/O ./O 
,/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsON/PERSON ./O 
YoU/O were/O told/O dutrin/O the/O ciurise/O of/O this/O interview/O that/O in/O the/O process/O of/O itrevolution/O the/O innocent/O sometimes/O had/O to/O stiffer/O along/O with/O the/O guilty/O ./O 
Did/O that/O strike/O you/O as/O being/O inconsistent/O with/O the/O party/O line/O as/O it/O generally/O operates/O ?/O 
This/O hysterical/O cry/O of/O smear/O that/O you/O hear/O from/O the/O Commuists/O ,/O from/O tile/O fellow-traieling/O press/O ,/O this/O hysterical/O dentnciation/O of/O committees/O of/O this/O kind/O ,/O simply/O beeau/O tiii/O tile/O course/O of/O tile/O investigation/O sometimes/O ,/O as/O happened/O yesterday/O ,/O an/O innocent/O name/O is/O mentioned/O ,/O which/O the/O committee/O attempts/O on/O all/O occasions/O to/O correct/O immediately/O ,/O but/O ,/O still/O this/O cry/O goes/O on/O ,/O ''/O -LRB-/O m.uil/O by/O asso/O -LRB-/O eiltion/O ,/O Faseists/O ,/O witehhunting/O ,/O everyred/O baiting/O ,/O ''/O were/O ,/O according/O to/O yoir/O statement/O ,/O they/O accept/O its/O day/O practice/O tile/O fact/O that/O a/O lot/O of/O innocent/O people/O are/O going/O to/O get/O hurt/O during/O this/O revolutionary/O period/O ./O 
This/O seems/O to/O me/O to/O be/O itvery/O glaring/O inconsistency/O in/O what/O they/O say/O and/O what/O they/O practice/O ./O 
That/O is/O not/O a/O question/O ./O 
It/O is/O simply/O an/O observation/O ,/O because/O it/O made/O a/O marked/O impression/O on/O me/O ./O 
The/O comrades/O talk/O out/O of/O one/O side/O of/O their/O mouth/O about/O one/O thing/O ,/O and/O out/O of/O the/O other/O about/O something/O else/O ./O 
Mr./O Lyr/PERSON `/O roN/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O Congressman/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O for/O a/O long/O time/O I/O wanted/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O I/O dig/O you/O ,/O Jackson/PERSON ,/O ''/O Laughter/O ./O -RSB-/O 
Mr./O VFtmWE/O ./O 
May/O we/O be/O Inorder/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O Ly/PERSON `/O roN/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O if/O you.are/O trying/O to/O pinpoint/O one/O incon/O ./O 
sistency/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O it/O might/O take/O us/O longer/O than/O your/O terms/O in/O Congress/ORGANIZATION to/O pinpoint/O all/O the/O inconsistencies/O in/O thie/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O line/O ./O 
Mr.JACKsoN/O ./O 
Tie/O committee/O has/O been/O working/O for/O many/O years/O to/O pinpoint/O a/O few/O of/O them/O ./O 
However/O ,/O this/O is/O an/O important/O one/O ./O 
Mr./O LYrroN/O ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O is/O a/O very/O important/O one/O ./O 
You/O and/O I/O are/O of/O a/O different/O political/O stripe/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O Democrat/O and/O you/O are/O a/O Republican/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O hallmark/O of/O America/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O LYTroN/O ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O we/O can/O sit/O and/O discuss/O our/O differences/O ,/O and/O we/O have/O ;/O not/O you/O and/O 1/O ,/O but/O a/O couple/O of/O Republicans/O have/O with/O me/O ,/O and/O other/O Democrats/O ./O 
Mr./O CAtry/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O n't/O had/O any/O differences/O up/O to/O date/O ./O 
Mr./O Lr/O `/O rro/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O me/O might/O ./O 
Mr./O CLrWY/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O work/O on/O it/O too/O hard/O ./O 
Mr./O Lymrox/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
We/O might/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O fear/O -/O ./O 
446/O COMMUNITIES/O AC/O ,/O TIVITIFB/O IN/O `/O T'fll/O LO/LOCATION ANOVI/LOCATION ,/O \*/O 1/O ANNKA/ORGANIZATION you/O Will/O Ihve/O troUblO/O with/O Mr./O WAI/O :/O EI/O ./O 
Take/O Ily/O word/O for/O it/O ,/O M./PERSON Clardy/PERSON Iino/PERSON tim/PERSON ./O 
1If/O ./O 
laYroN/O ./O 
I/O hlavo/O no/O fear/O thit/O ,/O would/O hold/O nme/O from/O quarreling/O Willi/PERSON this/O oltililittoe/O it/O ally/O poilt/O I/O felt/O qlllrrel/O wore/O t/O `/O olilli./O ,/O As/O it/O lIll/O -LRB-/O 1/O of/O fl/O -LRB-/O '/O ,/O IlIl/O -RRB-/O ll/O -LRB-/O t/O fiee/O iiiS/O WhOl/O l/O -RRB-/O l4ll./O ,/O II1K/O ,/O is/O it/O violtion/O -RRB-/O of/O fi'e/O boult/O ,/O t/O hat/O it/O ,/O l/O -RRB-/O e01/O IMlllig/O brooded/O -LRB-/O e/O lJt/O -LRB-/O l.For/O lIvo/O 's/O saike/O ,/O what/O ,/O colldl/O be/O more/O free/O HjHieth/O ?/O 
I/O hvoi/O a/O mhirophone/O and/O eulie'as/O ald/O a/O t/O COI111/O -RRB-/O itt/O '/O -LRB-/O If/O tll0/O -LRB-/O o111i/O ~/O S./O oHf/O t110/O I/O 1ited/O StIPS/O televiIsOill/O -LRB-/O nlln/O 11/O ,/O ltid/O lhe/O whole/O Aillelielill/O -RRB-/O libli/O to/O tolk/O to/O ./O 
%/O VialtIiore/O -LRB-/O olld/O Io/O free/O speechI/O Air/O ./O 
801oxIIItI/O ./O 
I/O yo/O -LRB-/O 1/O Iwro/O Ioillig/O reall/O well/O ,/O too./O ,/O ./O 
i/O -RRB-/O `/O li/O -LRB-/O e4d/O illW1h111/O ,/O le/O WASHililig/O 1111d/O t/O `/O lt/O it/O gt/O ,/O ti/O 111/O -RRB-/O nd/O t/O `/O h/O ,/O ,1/O O1U1Wilit/O li/O WOt/O loilig/O A111/O -LRB-/O lie/O would/O i/O `/O gil/O about/O ,/O it/O ./O 
f/O illink/O tle/O sfee/O -LRB-/O lh/O is/O free/O e/O titigi/O ,/O itsfrtee/O a/O M/O r./O I-I/O `/O OrN/O ./O 
If/O I/O 111011/O WOStI/O -RRB-/O `/O t/O ,/O 81111111el/O ho'I/O ,/O lie/O would/O could/O bo/O I/O -RRB-/O osgibly/O envisaged/O ./O 
The/O moe/O ltl/O ;/O ttltie/O ,/O s0/O floir/O iH/O lily/O V0olllfilelit/O Is/O -LRB-/O llee/O '/O -LRB-/O `/O fle/O -LRB-/O --/O ./O 
I/O relative-ti/O ,/O ll/O oIIin/O -RRB-/O portanit/O ./O 
tlilg/O is/O 111/O ,/O file/O lit/O -RRB-/O lOt/O inllkiig/O they/O 'll/O inOCetll/O nmstilS/O lter/O withI/O the/O gniilly/O ./O 
I/O h/O ;/O arnled/O dio/O Itliat/O wasx/O i1tAlillid/O ./O 
ard/O concept/O ./O 
Iutidersl/O an/O -LRB-/O d/O wilt/O wrote/O I/O -RRB-/O aulllll/O -RRB-/O lets/O ill/O i11tssiit/O ./O 
I/O doll/O '/O t/O recall/O exilctly/O whilt/O ./O 
Sl/O e/O said/O ,/O bit/O I/O wts/O told/O so1e/O ./O 
thing/O .110/O Said/O i/O riegatl/O '/O to/O this/O Iiiiitter/O ./O 
t/O wits/O give/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Iiotes/O ,/O iltt/O ,/O I/O vorbtimn/O ,/O quotes/O from/O Lenin/PERSON id/O others/O ,/O do/O n't/O ./O 
lecessiirily/O recall/O t/O ltheill/O wit/O reftired/O to/O Ii/O Stat/O `/O llient/O lllde/O by/O oneoliei/O w/O iosie/O fiulkelllberg/O ,/O wil/O also/O Colisidered/O a/O Iellgllle/O ,/O it/O is/O necessary/O to/O hvlle/O it/O discil/O -RRB-/O liled/O that/O ./O 
ina/O revolutiolnary/O situation/O it/O ,/O lolshevik/O prty/O all/O -LRB-/O -RSB-/O ulder/O thi/O -LRB-/O `/O tlllilrn/O ilsimee/O yol/O ca/O n't/O be/O too/O s/O -LRB-/O pielnilish/O as/O to/O wilat/O ile/O attitude/O w/O '/O ,/O lIS/O ./O 
the/O iovictim/O ./O 
And/O it/O but/O I/O happened/O to/O I/O said/O all/O this/O was/O lille/O ,/O wis/O asking/O a/O lot/O to/O ask/O me/O to/O be/O tolerant-I/O do/O n't/O kloW-Of/O 12/O or/O 15/O nionths/O of/O pretty/O rolgh/O piUllislient/O ./O 
I/O sly/O it/O is/O difficult/O to/O project/O to/O you/O the/O kind/O of/O punisllllent/O ,/O tllllt/O is/O involved/O ./O 
r1/O '/O ./O 
VLmTER/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O -LRB-/O `/O at/O tlttdetl/O |/O t/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O I/O itperhaps/O better/O than/O allyone/O ,/O because/O ever/O since/O I/O had/O the/O privilege/O of/O selling/O to/O tile/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION tile/O advisability/O of/O enacting/O all/O immigration/O code/O that/O would/O protect/O the/O United/LOCATION Staies/LOCATION I/O have/O been/O subjected/O to/O tile/O same/O thing/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O to/O such/O an/O extent/O that/O I/O often/O wondered/O about/O tile/O legitimacy/O of/O ily/O birth/O ./O 
But/O it/O comes/O front/O tile/O same/O source/O ;/O that/O is/O to/O be/O expected/O ./O 
Mr./O L/O n'troN/O ;/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O a/O fellow/O Pennsylvanian/O ,/O I/O can/O answer/O you/O in/O this/O fashion/O :/O No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O you/O did/O not/O have/O tile/O same/O experience/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O tile/O majority/O of/O tile/O people/O you/O knew/O backed/O your/O position/O ./O 
The/O majority/O of/O the/O people/O you/O knew/O and/O had/O to/O work/O witi/O still/O respected/O and/O admired/O you/O ./O 
But/O tlis/O was/O n't/O the/O case/O in/O my/O instance/O ,/O because/O the/O story/O became/O broader/O and/O broader/O ./O 
And/O in/O the/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O ,/O since/O I/O had/O identified/O myself/O in/O voting/O consistently/O for/O a/O number/O of/O years/O with/O the/O leftists/O ,/O even/O though/O I/O was/O not/O intile/O l/O -RRB-/O arty/O ,/O I/O had/O voted/O with/O them/O on/O virtually/O every/O issue/O ,/O and/O tley/O were/O fighting/O at/O that/O time/O to/O build/O a/O guild/O and/O they/O were/O n't/O political/O in/O their/O attitude/O for/O the/O guild/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O felt/O they/O were/O fighting/O to/O build/O a/O strong/O Screen/O Writers/O '/O Guild/O and/O I/O voted/O with/O them/O on/O issue/O after/O issue/O ,/O as/O I/O recall/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O probably/O COMMUNIM/O '/O A/O -LRB-/O VlIVITII04/O IN/O TiE/O 1,014/O ANORLETS/O AIlA/O 447/O liilH/O of/O iminy/O muleel/O writers/O ./O 
They/O itlentililed/O widi/O Iohin/O itl/O W00/O '/O 0i/O '/O 1/O ,/O l/O -LRB-/O koking/O for.illy/O c/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O llhlilly/O ,/O ./O 
hll/O wVsay/O ./O 
-/O l/O -LRB-/O ftists/O ,/O tle/O lil/O -RRB-/O i/O '/O ;/O ll.ls/O ,/O frnt3/O die/O ,/O I/O ds/O on/O through/O to/O tiho/O Ad/O ftill/O tliei/O Iiill/O ,/O b/O flllly/O of/O t/O hetm/O ,/O wo/O will/O fify/O ,/O were/O 10w/O Jil/O `/O ru/O ls/O --/O ~/O iot/O il/O of/O aitl/O `/O lctiig/O ilfg/O heir/O lacks/O iII/O -RRB-/O oli/O Iile/O ./O 
It/O WU133r11/O Lhau/O itil/O ,/O It/O hw5/O 11111/O Iaz11/O 1ot/O Iny/PERSON work/O and/O lily/O clir0r/O ./O 
You/O are/O still/O Il/PERSON Coiigi/PERSON '/O i./O Still/O a/O screenwriter/O ./O 
Mr./O `/O AVKNN/O :/O f/O ,/O ./O 
Will/O y/O -RRB-/O uf/O tell/O us/O Ihe/O result/O ,/O of/O the/O correction/O of/O the/O mllld/O the/O irrivill/O Of/O the/O eilli./O ,4/O ./O 
sary/O froln/O Mrs./O -LRB-/O `/O onllllllist/O Party/O `/O haig/O -LRB-/O ./O 
Jlllill/PERSON ?/O 
`/O ir/O ./O 
I/O wits/O iskedl/O to/O --/O I/O was/O told/O I/O would/O be/O conAl/O '/O ./O 
LA'IrON/O ./O 
YPH/O ,/O l/O I/O d/O ,/O ihll111/O ,1/O would/O not/O ,/O ltN/O thi/O iJilllieliv/O ,/O ,/O illy/O ll/O -LRB-/O hile/O tleite/O -LRB-/O l/O f/O `/O llrlh/O ri/O 1n/O -LRB-/O er/O ,/O `/O Oiiig/O h/O :/O k/O into/O thlie/O Ilrt/O ~/O y./O '/O 1I1w/O ill/O -LRB-/O eell.i/O I/O ,/O 1/O drew/O was/O that/O ,/O I/O -RSB-/O il/O Iltler/O -LRB-/O oi/O -RRB-/O 11/O back/O ili/O 11vw/O ,/O to/O ,/O hca.e/O if11did1/O `/O t/O ,/O why/O ,/O tilel/O ,/O of/O couls.et/O it/O ,/O would/O h/O just/O ,/O sillldy/O q./O e./O -LRB-/O d./O ,/O thait/O I/O mu1/O ./O 
st/O have/O be/O -LRB-/O nl/O guilty/O ,/O in/O the/O first/O J/O -RRB-/O hl/O -LRB-/O el/O ./O 
-LRB-/O IolI/O '/O t/O renihllllil/O -RRB-/O el/O ,/O it/O wasli/O '/O t/O Ve/O ,/O ry/O I/O was/O Hulb/O ./O -RRB-/O 
5/O '/O -LRB-/O li/O ifllt/O vollytet/O -LRB-/O li113/O '/O I/O first/O ,/O ini/O -LRB-/O etilug/O would/O he/O at/O log-ad/O I/O wits/O fodIt/O go/O to/O ai/O mietig/O ,/O lie/O home/O of/O Sill/LOCATION -RRB-/O ,/O M/O ,/O oore/O ./O 
All/O '/O ./O 
TAYMNI'il/O ./O 
-LRB-/O ,/O Jil/O you/O fix/O Ile/O liolie/O of/O S11u11/O Afoor/O ''/O ?/O 
ihe/O iIpl/O -RRB-/O `/O Jox/O illile/O little/O of/O the/O rieetlilg/O lit/O Mr./O LvYvroN/O ./O 
1t/O ,/O is/O very/O tliflicill/O ,/O to/O do/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O it/O witsMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O Iititi/O just/O Ill/O -RRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O roxilllaltly/O ./O 
T/O iN./O ,/O Approl/O -RRB-/O \/O ilillly/O ,/O I/O lhilll/O -LRB-/O it/O wls/O --/O it/O ,/O is/O hillrd/O to/O fix/O ./O 
Mr./O It/O was/O ill/O this/O period/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
V'emV/O wll/O ./O 
-LRB-/O ,/O lotgh/O to/O be/O If/O %/O `/O Oir/O Ilr0/O -/O 1I1111leto0/O fix/O it/O 1f111/O Ply/O sat/O isfthd/O il/O your/O own/O lin/O -LRB-/O ,/O why/O ,/O jlst/O ,/O proeee/O ti/O nd/O tell/O us/O whitt/O happened/O ./O 
Mr./O W/O `/O Avr/O :/O i./O ,/O Approximately/O is/O all/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O LyivoN/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O why/O I/O Jim/PERSON try/O ilg/O to/O recall/O it/O carefully/O ./O 
It/O maty/O have/O ocCurred/O infte/O fall/O of/O 1944/O or/O it/O may/O lae/O occurred/O early/O in/O 1945/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O difficult/O to/O remember/O ./O 
IifMr/O ./O 
TAVE/PERSON NNERI/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O whilt/O occurred/O when/O you/O went/O to/O that/O meetTr/O ./O 
LY'JrroN/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O possibly/O tell/O you/O ,/O since/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O to/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O was/O called/O thIo/O night/O before/O the/O meeting/O was/O canceled/O ./O 
Said/O ,/O ``/O I/O see/O ./O 
When/O is/O the/O next/O meeting/O ?/O ''/O 
``/O You/O will/O be/O called/O and/O told/O ./O ''/O 
T'hat/O is/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O rAVENNEJ/O ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O ,/O s/O who/O gave/O you/O this/O information/O I/O Mr./O LwroN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Just/O someone/O called/O andsaid/O ,/O ``/O Is/O this/O Bart/PERSON Lytton/PERSON I/O ''/O ``/O Yes/O ./O ''/O 
`/O Bart/PERSON ,/O this/O is/O Mary/PERSON ,/O ''/O or/O Jane/PERSON ,/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O name-I/O mean/O it/O was/O just/O the/O first/O name/O that/O was/O given/O to/O me/O on/O the/O telephone/O ./O 
And/O ``/O I/O was/O told/O to/O contact/O you/O ./O 
The/O meeting/O is/O canceled/O ./O ''/O 
Now/O ,/O I/O knew/O a/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O n't/O been/O at/O the/O meeting/O ,/O so/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O what/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON 's/O home/O it/O was/O ./O 
I/O knew/O it/O was/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON on/O Rossmore/LOCATION ./O 
And/O I/O knew/O a/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O knew/O him/O as/O president/O of/O the/O Radio/ORGANIZATION Writers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O saw/O this/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON subsequently/O ,/O in/O the/O next/O couple/O of/O weeks/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Sam/PERSON ,/O what/O about/O that/O meeting/O at/O your/O house/O ./O 
Why/O was/O it/O canceled/O ''/O 448/O COhtht1N/O :/O H1/O At/O ``/O IVITI/O 'M/O IN/O Ti'iii/O ILOM/O ANfllelsl/O :/O H/O AIIO4A/O Ho1itIId/O ,/O ``/O Wh/O `/O iktibdou/O Y/O 1011/O t/O `/O VIlt/O `/O ilt/O iuol/O 4111/O V/O ,/O nlet/O `/O hi/O 'd/O I/O d/O ,/O 111/O -LRB-/O ./O 
ItItwilml/O ,/O vit/O di/O ti/O Itid/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O h/O -LRB-/O 11/O -RRB-/O ,/O Sure/O ,/O I/O -LRB-/O Wits/O ./O 
You/O ijt/O -LRB-/O 1e/O `/O I-gllt/O ifWits/O ,/O ''/O 1111u1/O 1k/O 04It/O iwiite/O and/O wasi/O In/O hop/O i/O f/O t/O `/O itIn/O titIe'o/O had/O bi/O `/O tti-toot/O 0/O I/O tH/O ~/O liti/O Iv/O -LRB-/O Ill/O ~/O i/O ~/O ~/O 11/O -LRB-/O itilt/O l/O ikIs/O wasj4I/O '/O wh111/O oreur4d/O Iroot/O Iittiit/O thi/O '/O ~/O l/O ~/O l/O ~/O t/O ~/O iI/O atI/O `/O tp/O sto/O gt/O h/O `/O ot/O It/O '/O I/O I/O ,/O fe/O lit/O Iit/O I/O IIl/O o/O ,/O he/O 1111/O %/O 111thut/O 1/O wi/O I/O ,/O I/O '/O too/O s/O l/O ili/O 110W1111111le1111u1t/O And/O ~/O l/O fIt/O teolW1111/O III-1/O vis/O ,/O I/O waso/O %/O %/O It/O %/O li/O '/O %/O lIw/O i-o14/O -RRB-/O ed/O 11/O 111/O tiit/O 111111/O isu/O ls/O t/O 111/O -111/O ,/O oil/O iso/O tkll/O Irt/O wtsxt/O Iflte/O nt/O '/O l/O tth/O se/O w/O `/O t11iog/O w/O h1111/O ./O 
IT/O uttlnddI/O tIlli/O bitlt/O liii/O '/O to/O ret/O tttt/O '/O t/O t/O iit/O 11tltti/O l/O u/O `/O ng/O ,1111/O Ili/O 4/O -RRB-/O 1w/O %/O ii/O '/O f/O -RRB-/O ho/O tg/O e/O 111111/O t/O o/O ifi/O it/O tie/O i/O ivit111p/O s/O t/O g/O `/O iiitt/O l/O hnnI/O '/O 1.4/O gfiltuo/O s11/O -LRB-/O l/O ng/O her/O ets/O h/O `/O th.now/O ,/O I/O hat/O wasm/O itouu/O '/O i/O ,/O f1/O till/O 111111/O ./O 
Andoowi/O IIany/O Clveu/O ./O 
I/O `/O t/O ''/O `/O vap/O 114loll/O htidI/O Iok/O WI/O it/O i/O T/O l-lI/O was/O -LRB-/O it/O III-Oill/O WhttI/O '/O ./O 
\*/O Its1I/O s/O c1te11/O 1111/O -LRB-/O tol/O Iia/O ,/O u./O ./O 
./O 
lt/O 111/O A/O dItik/O I/O nfxO/O limi/O eil/O ''/O tho11i/O '/O i/O th/O `/O ill/O I/O a/O odit/O ./O 
Owntf/O I-t/O 1/O `/O otilg/O he/O I/O ifittus/O ofltm/O sli/O ouiut/O f/O ,/O ndo/O ~/O n/O wha/O ./O 
tit/O ./O 
itit/O rai-t/O iit/O vi/O ''/O i/O oral/O ito/O nihi/O '/O il/O 1111Ion/O s/O ~/O '/O ~/O kown/O utit/O ./O 
t/O 1e/O `/O oiO/O Itt/O t/O ``/O Iv/O ./O 
im/O Was-i/O ''/O itt/O -LRB-/O -LRB-/O low/O ,/O I/O t/O iki/O ./O 
thlAY/O of/O 1044/O 1oi/O ~/O ~/O hf/O mv/O rourt/O rvof/O .1/O 1/O -RRB-/O 1t/O llt/O Co/O ittl/O l/O iui'i/O `/O eldI/O lilti/O e/O d/O iajit/O ogIlii4aou/O kiw/O %/O %/O I/O ./O 
`/O of/O l/O -LRB-/O li/O '/O 1/O -RRB-/O t/O illaly/O vA1tf/O ./O 
Votlt11/O I/O t/O hllt/O f/O it/O ,/O l/O Ilvstilgitl/O -RRB-/O 1111/O ts/O tI/O ltidel/O '/O h/O l/O -LRB-/O loe/O il/O 10141/O g/O .110/O l1/O `/O hiO/O ;/O ilvdt/O ndw/O 1/O llioo/O tht/O sevi/O '/O l/O I/O ht/O '/O y/O reaAl/O ~/O Owhev/O old/O g1/O -LRB-/O t/O i/O the/O ISvtin/O ete/O enite/O oit/O Now/O .15/O ofieresntaf/O lefilsn/O '/O .11/O oltli/O o/O lil/O t./O vo/O '/O hll1at/O silr/O 11CfeI/O -/O ;/O u/O ititrsi/O l/O l/O lo/O lill/O cal/O tim/O -RRB-/O iiit/O -LRB-/O vilo/O k/O for11111/O of/O m/O stO/O ~/O ~/O itll/O ~/O v/O i/O '/O ./O 
ll/O ,111/O W/O i/O '/O tlwa/O w11141/O pyxongo/O ttnhr/O ~/O Iobil/O `/O ov/O to/O wIllofim/O liet/O a/O o/O -LRB-/O II/O Vtl/O '/O 5thttw/O `/O i/O `/O uio/O i.iI/O -LRB-/O `/O ut/O ~/O lert/O Thl/O fliHlos/O I/O ~/O utsler/O ~/O and/O --/O wll/O le/O u.o/O ''/O tht/O thewileYisterda/O atidwii/O wol/O ,/O ;/O tO/O b1101t/O ./O 
111e1/O Iave/O whio/O '/O alittvet/O `/O owoittu/O `/O sse/O wholwrael/O Itu/O ol/O heair/O ,/O o/O aif/O ./O 
Ou/O kt/O ronf/O o/O urIs/O eiarkVeteh/O bufoble/O a/O thht/O flint/O it/O 11Ie/O will/O -RRB-/O fiat/O irt/O o/O ni/O nI/O twol/O 11ormvd111/O i/O and/O rg/O Mn/O o/O Y/O ueexto/O ./O 
o/O -LRB-/O rod/O ~/O it/O ,/O lttern/O anagued/O hini/O aoth/O 01o/O uffo/O th/O ltill/O thiatiol/O ,/O that/O as/O what/O ./O 
./O 
oment/O ,14/O hat/O th/O s/O o/O Ilist1i/O Pat/PERSON acting/O hat/O IeEoarl/O oder/O ./O 
reSfo/O t/O olel/O sOly/O ``/O or/O ./O 
I/O therk/O thi/O oomlit/O eme/O thgey/O ./O 
wMost/O of4/O them/O th/O of/O -LRB-/O ght/O qititete/O 1oose/O Iof/O drwsterhro/O ea/O il/O r.dw/O aynied/O ./O 
h/O t/O as/O qumsitn/O eoioa/O oe/O I/O waoldlk/O tao/O s/O afi/O -LRB-/O ,/O o111w/O roo/O atir/O -LRB-/O li/O I/O olarev/O iIC/O inth/O Aloi/PERSON ifthParty/O PI/O ./O 
and/O e/O knthe/O that/O ter/O m/O e/O iire/O 11owder/O ./O ''/O 
I/O bmeoi/O quteadninre/O out.emk/O itsnd/O intc/O inyevbe/O ,/O thy/O fired/O ing/O adr/O It/O uost.e/O it/O ,/O tat/O wayeBodr/O ``/O lteadnige/O h/O I/O -LRB-/O `/O ONIhItININTl/O ACTl/O `/O Vl/O `/O l'lV/O ;/O IN/O 11011P/O ,/O 1,09/O ANOMY14/O ~/O ;/O 449/O -RRB-/O Ann/PERSON ,/O \*/O A/O T/O or/O i/O 11-1/O -LRB-/O wfi/O ''/O li/O ii/O '/O 11ir/O of/O -/O litev/O ~/O i/O iE/O fI/O imo/O jIE/O '/O 1lodI/O wins/O ,/O they/O Iil/O `/O I-I/O IIiowdtill/O ,/O If/O Htl/O hi/O e/O iii/O n111g/O of/O 1t4/O In/O 10f14/O '/O 1r/O ./O 
1/O I/O Nii/O 00lmnh/O '/O 111/O -RRB-/O 01m1wit/O Il/O gl/O `/O E'lit/O i./O 4jpiJi/O -LRB-/O li/O ,/O Ii1W14/O '/O i/O 1itlIiii/O turd/O 11l11t/O ./O 
ill/O Ow/O -LRB-/O 0/O `/O o11niw/O 10141/O ./O 
I111h/O '/O i/O Iv/O t/O ou/O lt/O -LRB-/O l'jiE/O CliE/O '/O Hite/O 111111/O of/O tli/O 1111411i111E4t/O fIit/O 1111f/O l/O 1/O -/O iE/O '/O 1Hrl/O '/O r/O lii/O tp.-oi/O u/O von/O tiriI/O ey/O HiJHEtIli/O 11/O '/O ./O 
TA.VI/O :/O N/O N11/O ,/O lI/O ./O 
I/O -RRB-/O id/O I/O li1t/O IPII/O -RRB-/O res/O `/O nf/O fit/O ,/O ./O 
iwi/O foili/O igo44/O yourl/O n/O `/O n11111/O il11o/O r.it/O 1I/O Co/O `/O l'/O ./O 
Iff/O -RRB-/O lEti/O flt/O '/O 1/O 0/O Ej1E11-ty/O ?/O 
fu/O ei/O 14WE/O -RRB-/O I/O Al/O '/O ./O 
I/O '/O i/O N/O Iit/O ,11/O ii/O '/O 1,44/O -/O now/O ,/O Ion/O 13/O 101/O ihl/O l/O `/O l/O ~/O l/O I/O -LRB-/O 1le/O oi.llwI/O EHN/O Anstll/O tI/O '/O S/O 11/O et.therjy/O ifl/O `/O i/O -LRB-/O E'it/O ii/O I/O '/O w/O r/O li/O mt/O w/O 1ori/O l/O wn/O Jees/PERSON ./O 
1/O '/O I/O iii/O 1ferj/O -RRB-/O E/O '/O Iill/O '/O 41nt/O rli/O gioif/O W/O ~/O l/O ~/O li/O -LRB-/O '/O 1114/O It/O ~/O ifI/ORGANIZATION v/O '/O 111/O ~/O elt/O `/O Vli1/O ttll1MW/O i/O '/O i/O 111ito/O Iii/O '/O 011/O ig/O fl/O -LRB-/O Et/O wiild/O it/O All/O ./O 
JY'I/O `/O EN/O ./O 
I/O donll/O '/O t/O iths/O I/O grou/O ./O 
ttm/O f/O o./O litlli/O OI/O P/O iPiii/O ~/O mE/O 1/O ,/O l/O 1114/O -LRB-/O Iii/O '/O g/O lllo/O i/O no/O ilOW/O ./O 
10/O I/O -RRB-/O l./O liffeik/O int/O shiiw/O 1i1o/O l'/O l/O O/O i/O liof.it/O ,/O i/O t/O l/O 11/O f/O NreIC/O 1/O toll/O i.goil/O 811Wo/O ./O 
l/O ~/O yprolil/O Writers/O -LRB-/O hif/O thed/O scre/O 111gol/O 1Ahl/O '/O ./O 
TIAVE/O :/O NNI/O ;/O T./O '/O ii/O l/O ~/O l/O 11tt/O tlie/O o/O tlo/O ?/O 
Al/O '/O ./O 
TiAVINNI11/O ./O 
Nowil/O ~/O l/O -LRB-/O 11/O kio/O ilVi04/O tl/O e/O le/O ft/O ,110/O 11/O 11o/O All/O ./O 
LVI/O `/O rOt/O ./O 
No/O -LRB-/O 111/O kdo/O %/O ./O 
I/O o/O '/O ,/O not./O :/O o/O o./O Wra/O '/O .114/O `/O l'AINU/O id/O ,/O -LRB-/O 1111f/O fle/O but/O etig/O had/O h/O i/O it/O pti/O `/O ndeii/O Mr./O Li/PERSON `/O r/O ,4/O N'ot/O ./O 
Wes/PERSON ,/O wis/O th/O -LRB-/O Jo/PERSON ./O 
IOi/O Mu/O '/O ./O 
IOlNI/O ./O 
SIM/O Wk/O +/O h/O ose/O '/O Uiow/O wefre/O -LRB-/O 1.3/O '/O ?/O 
asno/O MiveJeYrl1/O `/O ON/O ./O 
im/O it/O f/O ~/O illoffw/O -LRB-/O ieri/O slilfle/O ,/O ta/O Iti/O ./O 
meelting/O kin/O Nt/O he/O of/O Dcan/O Joito/O wifle/O AlM/O '/O ./O 
TAVEN/O ER/O ./O 
NWs/O lie/O YOU/O FIC/O `/O Oill/O Wr1i/O 101erhe/O fhel/O I/O io/O mrieting/O wasl/O l/O h/O Srw/O inCeSre/O eeci/O oaylatwoI/O or0/O nei/O a/O -RRB-/O ~/O iiS/O ALVYIAVONN/O ./O 
?/O 
hd/O -LRB-/O 1/O ayO/O oll/O ith/O c4omitt/O bri/O -LRB-/O efldbu/O ht/O Mrl/O ./O 
`/O VAV8/O ,/O NNER/O ./O 
IllW186101e4OMOP/O ?/O 
Mr./O ljy/O `/O tioN/O ./O 
I/O litonded/O itwofo/O meeting/O ~/O oe/O s./O I/O wthin/O antwd/O aieefng/O ipnOlwom/O oftin/O eetins.Onwsclcoe.Ibivety/O wer/O ./O 
iAVn/O NFtoteie/O Wgar/O oft/O stiike/O wrthr/O ?/O 
cneeneo/O Sui/O Un/O ionswere/O scouting/O at/O thaesi/O Itim/O ./O 
simeiwrtr/O Mr./O WellNI/PERSON Whng/PERSON ``/O fraction/O meind/O of/O tim/O refern/O toa/O fration/O mtino/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
thatil/O ocaion/O toderttnd/O Mr.747-roN-pt/O ./O 
2/O -/O 41W/O -LRB-/O IOMItNINl/O A/O ~/O VtVIVIlca/O IN/O lTOIN/O 1/O :/O ,01/O ANIIKIt/O ,/O MAlV/O hl/O t/O '/O ./O 
lll.NNI/O 1/O :/O li/O ./O 
,/O ill/O yolu/O tell/O fill/O %/O e/O it/O t/O `/O t/O '/O t/O who/O totak/O -RRB-/O 11/O ill/O thul/O friet/O -LRB-/O ott/O fileetiig/O t1111t/O ./O 
ou/O at/O teiild/O V/O hit/O '/O ./O 
14-l'r41M/O ./O 
nc/O htiga/O I/O Ilw/O 11/O -RRB-/O t111/O 1118/O -LRB-/O i/O -/O ,/O `/O Ill/O vIIniu/O `/O r/O ,/O WhVloI/O I/O know/O flhint./O ,/O iut/O irg/O ililitil/O `/O of/O seen/O witlets/O ,/O ni/O lol/O i/O fi/O lre/O 1110plo/O :/O :/O :/O iiol/O sloi/O :/O 411,11/O ol/O -LRB-/O 11tu1d/O 1/O -LRB-/O llIVIIrty/O t./O 11011111/O uid/O Iher/O I/O ItNill/O -LRB-/O ow/O o1fll/O lhe/O 11eldtlkli/O g/O 11li1t/O ./O 
I/O Ver/O '/O y/O u/O `/O lea/O lkIy/O ./O 
ole/O -LRB-/O i/O front/O ,/O I/O hilt/O it/O ./O 
WoldltI/O -LRB-/O 1111r/O ./O 
~/O l/O -LRB-/O 411l1/O -LRB-/O f.r/O lit/O %/O to/O j/O -RRB-/O l/O 11dtwli/O l'/O Illall/O ,/O %/O 11s/O havi/O ng/O sjH/O ''/O i/O ll/O -/O I1liv/O l/O ~/O '/O i/O t/O fily/O givenl/O I/O hlnt/O oi/O '/O jne/O ./O '/O 
or1/O tIleelI/O tig/O ./O 
l/O 110/O tthita/O ,/O %/O OlW/O 1111/O e/O ~/O l/O l/O l/O t/O iI8If/O t/O t14/O hutkI/O ht/O -LRB-/O `/O eiilis4t/O 1/O ~/O Ih/O -LRB-/O 4/O -RRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O 11/O rtI/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O $/O list/O V/O '/O ./O 
Al./O onti/O tract/O Ion/PERSON nitii11g/PERSON ,/O Johnt/O Wt/O '/O x/O hey/O alprwouetl/O il/O ,/O aIlId/O I/O r/O `/O u/O `/O nhl/O it/O flit/O '/O following/O lieetIng/O wias/O Ily/O last/O ./O 
Int/O `/O et-ing/O ./O 
hi-r/O ljtt/O '/O ,/O l/O :/O :/O ;/O oka/O I/O believe/O Olsw/O lwfill/O itll/O -/O ln/O -/O 1/O o14wiit/O -RRB-/O ittl/O i/O 110410-106I/O Tlhe/O eotilitt/O ee/O will/O b/O '/O e/O ill/O rteeSs/O fill/O 10l/O 0111,1/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O tlt/O 10114/O ./O 
afteri/O 11/O ./O 
.1/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 8hort/O ,/O ricess/O wvas/O taken/O ./O -RRB-/O 
hir/O ./O 
AI'iF/O ./O '/O 
\*/O ./O ''/O 
t.oiit/O will/O ho/O ill/O orid/O '/O ./O 
Mli/O '/O ./O 
T1AVVINNViI/O ./O 
IMP/O ./O 
C/O liffIiirial/O ,/O it/O h111/O jiSt/O 111/O -LRB-/O 1/O '/O t/O ee/O 11114/O lt/O '/O t/O t/O 4/O 1111/O atfeltin/O intt/O t/O het/O Iletei/O Olt/O 1w3/O -LRB-/O lki/O Wit/O `/O itt/O `/O ss/O of/O It/O P01180/O `/O N1i/O by/O tutu/O iiiiiietfAnn/O Morganl/O Iltdglt/O give/O rise/O to/O soniti/O iisit/O erstandrIig/O Jit/PERSON to/O the/O Ann/O Morgant/O It/O `/O fi/O `/O reld/O to/O bty/O ItIle/O Witnhess/O ./O 
I/O `/O Tere/O is/O fill/O Annt/O Wrgan/O whot/O is/O it/O ttutthttii/O iii/O the/O Los/LOCATION Aiignlm/LOCATION es/O -LRB-/O hioolH/O ./O 
Are/O youi/O well/O etnouigh/O naciilt/O -LRB-/O with/O tho/O Anti/O Morgant/O whtom/O you/O 11111toted/O n/O lie/O -LRB-/O 101180/O f/O ourto.tiliolyto/O he/O itllt/O tCostate/O thiatt/O it/O is/O notht/O erseuonl/O that/O ./O 
t/O just/O ./O 
reforild/O tot/O M./O jYItON/O ./O 
I/O linit/O itot/O itt/O '11/O HVtetuiiit/O '/O i-it/O le/O 1i/O -RRB-/O 1t/O '/O .4011/O you/O jus5t/O utiettiont/O to/O tt/O ./O '/O 
4tif3/O '/O that/O it/O ./O 
is/O not/O ,/O bit/O ./O 
I/O know/O tis/O ~/O ,/O tltint/O Aiti/PERSON Hoth/PERSON -/O oigallwas/O not/O ./O 
ai/O schoolteachler/O ./O 
Mri/O ./O 
r1AVF/O ./O 
NNr/O ~/O t./O A11/O -LRB-/O titwei/O jils/O beeni/O it/O schtoolteacheri/O to/O your/O knowiedje/O KMr.LI/O ,/O %/O rroN/O ./O 
I/O doubt/O that/O site/O has/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
TIAVENNERI/O ./O 
D/O ~/O o/O you/O know/O whotlter/O the/O Persotn/PERSON referred/O to/O ,/O that/O is/O tile/O person/O referred/O to/O by/O you/O as/O Ant/O i/O ranl/O ,/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgant/PERSON ,/O is/O '/O also/O known/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Anti/PERSON Roth/PERSON Morgami/PERSON Richards/PERSON ?/O 
Mir/O ./O 
Ltvro/PERSON ./O 
`/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O knowv/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
TiAvrNNIRR/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
Chairman/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O should/O state/O for/O tile/O nvo/O ~/O rd/O tht/O we/O know/O ,/O front/O our/O investigation/O Work/O ,/O that/O ,/O those/O names/O nifer/O to/O thle/O siuni/O person/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O that/O thle/O person/O mentioned/O by/O thle/O within/O is/O thle/O sameo/O person/O as/O Ann/PERSON Roth/PERSON Mtorgan/PERSON Richar/PERSON `/O ds/O who/O was/O stibpenaed/O ats/O a/O witness/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O Scunr/PERSON ~/O na/O ./O 
And/O not/O ./O 
the/O schoolteacher/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNE.R/O ./O 
And/O is/O an/O entirely/O different/O person/O from/O the/O school/O teacher/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O clears/O that/O up/O ./O 
Mr./O Cr/PERSON ./O 
%/O Rny/O ./O 
If/O it/O dos/O '/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ,/O you/O would/O welcome/O her/O appearing/O here/O if/O she/O =/O wse/O to/O ,/O so/O we/O may/O be/O certainV/O Mr./O TAlENNKR/O ./O 
Ohl/PERSON ,/O yes/O ;/O if/O she/O would/O fle/O to/O appear/O here/O ./O 
site/O will/O be/O welcome/O ./O 
-LRB-/O '/O 0M/O -LRB-/O N/O IMP/O ACT/O `/O IVI'PI/O I-H/O IN/O TiIM/O LOA1/O .0/O ANOI1/O ./O 
I/O ;/O M/O Alt/O iA/O 01/O ~/O IVII/O IIo/O IIIlNl/O 118/O ,/O j1101844/O ,/O fIIIIliI/O Iuiiti/O I/O Ior/O II/O I/O INe/O wI/O I/O '/O o/O re/O Wiii/O li401if1li1/O Paurty/O ,/O I/O if/O vl/O ?/O 
cti/O withIifhi/O geolu/O fir/O %/O w.1i-l/O `/O Ithho/O `/O iilitiuis/O At/O 1/O ./O 
./O 
II/O vroN./O ,/O welii/O ,/O oweutli/O ~/O i/O it/O rowiuc/O luaiiiwti/O g/O orI/O it/O ./O 
iiih/O hoino/O of/O to/O l/O 111/O ``/O t11w/O oVfr/O OoouP/O ofililli/O 111fi/O nu/O ,/O r/O ng/O I/O iii/O ti/O '/O 11lh/O 'd/O ,/O 1/O 4.1111/O 81111l/O 1111/O #/O 1111111-14i/O In/O ll/O -LRB-/O ed/O -LRB-/O If/O -RRB-/O Jlohni/PERSON fowui/O 1,1/O liii/O wvoui/O ,/O f/O .0/O iit/O `/O Nl/O ,/O Ilita/O Jiy/O -LRB-/O Iornefy/O ,/O -RSB-/O -RRB-/O fill/O 1111/O -LRB-/O l1Iji/O Iit/O #/O 11111i-14/O ,/O 1111/O -LRB-/O l/O S11ut44/O heyI/O ''/O agofi/O 11111/O Nliirvi/O -LRB-/O lark/O ./O 
y/O ig/O iiitori'iitlli/O wiew/O ~/O l/O ~/O tt/O All/O %/O T1AVtN/O NIt/O ,/O -LRB-/O I/O l/O You1/O gil/O II114/O iroi/O loted/O reluit/O i/O ng/O to/O I/O ho/O lu11t/O ./O 
1whisouu/O va.iu/O moeltilf/O IMM/O All/O %/O 0/O Cla/ORGANIZATION ./O 
-LRB-/O hrk/O ill/O Noiw/LOCATION York/LOCATION when/O hio/O All/O '/O ./O 
I/O TiifN/O ./O 
0uiY/O 11111/O 1at/O WP0111I/O -LRB-/O -LRB-/O ot1/O .4/O i/O Withi/O It/O grii11/O ilhid/O 1111/O `/O I/O `/O heui1fl/O ./O 
r/O -LRB-/O ol/O h/O `/O tvt/O e/O ,/O All/O '/O ./O 
TIAV-N/O NiiH/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O wvill/O youi/O tell/O iis/O ,/O jili/O `/O nitE/O ,/O tilly/O fisf/O her/O -LRB-/O -/O it/O -/O ./O 
14vilig/O iolie/O ColininnnIIis/O ciuisiii/O iiis1/O hill/O y01u/O 1111/O -RRB-/O '/O hilve/O regilrd/O i/O tug/O yoIiirles/O Party/O atOf114/O fI/O uhf/O OX/O III/O -/O h/O `/O iI/O tioiii1/O ORli/O -LRB-/O ``/O homn1sfI/O ,/O Ni/O I/O '/O ./O 
I/O VI-111N/O ./O 
I/O WONH/O fiiii/O i/O 111/O -LRB-/O o/O ~/O 1/O aN1/O ffi/O ~/O iiiii/O II/O V./O I/O had1/O -LRB-/O uIi/O `/O giti'i/O al/O ,/O ft/O i/O 's/O rew/O iiwetiiigm/O i/O atiet/O fill/O Iagint/O ,/O OX/O pel/O led/O firontu/O I/O liq/O partIy/O ./O 
`/O I/O `/O li/O -LRB-/O 4litiugePi/O I/O 1h11t/O I/O WONI/O gIMPerilly/O tO/O -LSB-/O i/O ItHla/O ill/O 111/O piif/O ,/O n/O nId/O 11111t/O I/O WONH/O prl/O '/O -LRB-/O tif/O `/O IOi/O ,/O IhtI/O co'iiiishti/O '/O l/O 11sail/O eilla/O '/O y/O of/O labor/O folid/O ,/O I/O people/O ./O 
I/O will/O let/O fihe/O ``/O people/O ''/O ,/O 1111ke/O their/O ./O 
ownl/O julgientill/O liht/O ./O 
010/O -LRB-/O 11t1/O when/O Chat/O Mrl/O ./O 
T1AIIN/O NEII/O ./O 
-LRB-/O ``/O ill/O youI/O give/O 11/O -LRB-/O leItj/O -RRB-/O ptOXiIllIff3/O to/O ine/O thut/O ,/O t/O hat/O ,/O o/O -LRB-/O `/O fiurref/O in/O Mr./O Ii-voN/O ./O 
ThaIi/O ./O 
ofetirredoi/O it/O m4001112/O late/O 19I15rtIhomniddheopf/O h145/O ./O 
1/O dotl.know/O ,/O Mrl/O ./O 
TJ/O `/O VENNPvit/O ./O 
At/O ./O 
he/O hiegiinning/O of/O yourl/O test/O iffloiiy/O you/O t-old/O usHIhiitt/O you/O ii-i/O 11/O fit/O -RRB-/O lnger/O '/O illI/O 5fil/O f/O '/O ii/O ughui/O ~/O i/O -/O ,/O LITi/O ''/O fN/O ./O '/O 
1/O `/O iuit/O ,/O N/O t/O `/O ighit/O ./O 
All/O '/O ./O 
TiAI'N/O NEiL/O ./O 
IV/O `/O lteii/O -LRB-/O lid/O youl/O teriuIIluiafen/O your/O ,/O sereen/O -/O ./O 
writ/O iii/O eare4/O \*/O r/O ?/O 
Mrl/O ./O 
TAIlON/O ./O 
At/O ,/O the/O suniie/O tinme/O t/O hit/O ./O 
I/O IA/O `/O riliiiistefI/O with/O t./O ie/O Colnmiuilist/O P/O ~/O arty/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O torilinettit/O ./O 
that/O t-ine/O ,/O boit/O I/O liafi/O no/O fuirthe/O -LRB-/O r/O careerr/O ,/O MI/O '/O ./O 
TAVE.NNER/O ./O 
Why/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Ai/O '/O -/O ,/O ljy'ixm/O ./O 
I./O fotlind/O t/O hat/O fromin/O linl/O fil/O it/O variety/O fil/O d/O chlargeqs/O were/O madie/O fll/O over/O town/O ,/O incorreat/O ideiititicatioiis/O ,/O idelitifihcltiolI/O Mott/PERSON at/O 'll/O 111lia1ppihy/O tit/O ./O 
it/O moment/O ./O 
like/O this/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O it/O writer/O named/O flai/O 're/O Lyn/PERSON -LRB-/O ifon/O wasli/O writing/O it/O picture/O ``/O I/O Mfaried/O atCommunist/O ./O ''/O 
I/O am/O not/O Barre/PERSON Ljyndonl/PERSON and/O lie/O was/O writitig/O an/O antti-Communlilist/O -RRB-/O icture/O ./O 
It/O was/O charged/O that/O ./O 
Blart/PERSON Lytton/PERSON wrote/O it/O ./O 
My/O wife/O was/O called/O ald/O dsho/O was/O cursed/O utp/O and/O -LRB-/O down/O roundly/O by/O at/O former/O friend/O ./O 
She/O wats/O told/O -LRB-/O ,/O ``/O Dont/O '/O t/O you/O believe/O thaft/O hie/O is/O n't/O writing/O it/O ./O 
We/O know/O hie/O is/O wvritn/O it/O ,/O ''/O for/O example/O ,/O find/O so/O 01/O -RRB-/O ./O 
I/O funflat/O ./O 
from/O ainy/O interview/O that/O I/O s9eemedl/O to/O have/O thereafter/O I/O did/O n't/O got/O atjob/O ./O 
An/O interesting/O 0o18/O to/O me/O was/O one/O wvhere/O a/O producer/O ,/O whom/O I/O did/O not/O know/O had/O expressed/O keen/O interest/O in/O it/O story/O I/O had/O wriittenl/O ./O 
I/O was/O invite/O to/O the/O studio/O to/O see/O thsIrdcra/O lwn/O to/O tlte/O studio/O ,/O RRO/O ,/O again/O ,/O and/O the/O producer/O wvas/O Adrian/PERSON Scott/PERSON ./O 
When/O hie/O saw/O who/O thle/O writer/O was/O lie/O apparently/O did/O n't/O like/O it/O ,/O let/O uts/O put/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
Hie/PERSON delivered/O me/O a/O stern/O lectur/O on/O fascism/O and/O dismissed/O me/O curtly/O without/O discussion/O of/O thle/O story/O ./O 
I/O was/O to/O be/O hired/O by/O Abe/PERSON Burrows/PERSON to/O write/O specialty/O material/O for/O him/O ./O 
I/O met/O him/O ait/O his/O request/O at/O the/O Brown/O Derby/O on/O Vine/O Street/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O Gee/O ,/O I/O have/O decided/O I/O do/O n't/O need/O a/O specialty/O writer/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O need/O a/O writer/O ./O ''/O 
And/O lie/O turned/O around/O and/O walked/O ou/O '/O t/O on/O an/O invitation/O to/O lunch/O ./O 
41201/O COMNIlST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THP/O ,/O LOS/LOCATION ANOBLES/LOCATION AREIA/LOCATION This/O kind/O of/O incidents/O kept/O oevirring/O ./O 
Wherever/O I/O turned/O I/O was/O astounded/O that/O while/O the/O party/O was/O notJarge/O ,/O they/O had/O as/O inany/O areas/O of/O Influence/O as/O the/O had/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Made/O several/O attempts/O to/O have/O a/O hearing/O on/O he/O matter/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O get/O back/O in/O the/O Coinmtuust/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O wanted/O no/O part/O of/O It/O ./O 
I/O had/O learned/O everything/O I/O had/O to/O learn/O about/O Itand/O everything/O it/O represented/O ,/O but/O I/O wanted/O a/O hearing/O because/O I/O wanted/O to/O be/O confronted/O with/O any/O evidence/O that/O might/O exist/O ,/O and/O I/O wanted/O to/O mio/O what/O they/O had/O to/O say/O ./O 
I/O was/O never/O afforded/O a/O hearing/O ./O 
I/O was/O never/O afforded/O any/O opportunity/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O ,/O ``/O We/O do/O n't/O have/O to/O give/O you/O a/O hearing/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O have/O to/O listen/O to/O you/O ./O 
We/O know/O what/O you/O are/O ./O ''/O 
I/O asked/O who/O told/O then/O those/O things/O ,/O and/O they/O said/O ,/O ``/O That/O is/O our/O business/O ,/O ''/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
The/O feeling/O there/O was/O simply/O that/O I/O was/O guilty/O because/O I/O was/O seen/O with/O an/O Army/O officer/O who/O was/O known/O to/O be/O an/O Intelligence/O officer/O ./O 
The/O Army/O officer/O was/O my/O brother/O ./O 
He/O wits/O a/O captain/O in/O the/O field/O artillery/O ./O 
Mr./O thAoKsON/O ./O 
So/O that/O was/O guilt/O by/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O L/O mN/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O guilt/O by/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O that/O a/O very/O relrehensible/O thing/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION parlance/O I/O Mr./O LrroN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O ``/O gtuilt/O by/O association/O ''/O isgenerally/O rerelensible/O and/O I/O think/O the/O Communists/O have/O very/O poor/O grace/O in/O ever/O accusing/O anyone/O else/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O fAc.KsoiN/O ./O 
Except/O for/O the/O fact/O that/O a/O bank/O cashier/O who/O travels/O around/O with/O thugs/O and/O holdup/O men/O ./O 
He/O does/O n't/O hold/O his/O job/O very/O long/O ,/O does/O heV/O Mr./O LrrroN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O you/O mean/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O be/O guilt/O by/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O LrrroN/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O what/O you/O mean/O ;/O yes/O ,/O that/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
But/O the/O Communists/O do/O practice/O guilt/O by/O association/O ./O 
Mr./O LyrtoN/PERSON ./O 
Most/O assuredly/O they/O do/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O about/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O CL./O ,/O wy/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O they/O never/O assassinate/O anybody/O 's/O character/O ./O 
Mr./O Lrrro/PERSON ./O 
They/O did/O their/O darndest/O to/O assassinate/O mine/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O let/O us/O put/O it/O this/O way/O :/O I/O was/O no/O longer/O welcome/O in/O any/O of/O the/O circles/O I/O previously/O knew/O ./O 
People/O would/O not/O talk/O to/O me/O about/O it/O ./O 
The/O very/O nice/O people/O to/O whom/O -LSB-/O -/O am/O indebted/O for/O my/O appearance/O here/O today/O ,/O Pauline/PERSON and/O Leo/PERSON Townsend/PERSON ,/O I/O went/O to/O ,/O because/O I/O had/O seen/O them/O at/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O I/O asked/O them/O what/O it/O was/O about/O ,/O and/O at/O that/O time/O they/O were/O n't/O out/O of/O the/O decompression/O chamber/O and/O they.appeared/O nervous/O and/O ill/O at/O ease/O about/O the/O matter/O ,/O and/O said/O that/O I/O had/O -/O better/O talk/O to/O somebody/O else/O ./O 
They/O were/O the/O only/O people/O ,/O incidentally/O ,/O who/O would/O even/O speak/O to/O me/O about/O it/O Others/O just/O simply/O turned/O their/O backs/O ./O 
Mr./O Dou/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O that/O only/O Communists/O who/O would/O talk/O to/O youI/O Mr./O Lrrror/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O would/O n't/O sy-I/O will/O put/O it/O a/O little/O strong/O than/O ``/O only/O Communists/O ./O ''/O 
I/O would/O may/O that/O tfe/O Reds/O have/O a/O lot/O of/O fellow/O travelers/O ,/O as/O you/O know/O ,/O and/O you/O get/O to/O know/O pretty/O well/O who/O the/O fellow/O travelers/O are/O or/O you/O would/O my/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O mabe/O ti/O s/O j1uo/O is/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whlmt/O be/O is/O a/O Communist/O rar/O member/O but/O I/O know/O he/O is/O a/O Cummunkt/O or/O i/O fellow/O traveler/O ./O ''/O 
The/O allow/O travelers/O ,/O in/O turn/O ./O 
have/O influence/O at/O concentric/O circles/O ,/O influence/O upon/O liberals/O ,/O we/O will/O may/O ,/O and/O this/O gwes/O on/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O they/O t/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O TIE/O LOS/O ANOELES/O AItRA/O 453/O did/O n't/O care/O what/O they/O said/O and/O they/O said/O many/O things/O that/O had/O no/O hasis/O in/O fact/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
What/O you/O are/O trying/O to/O say/O is/O that/O they/O are/O the/O most/O intolerant/O people/O on/O earth/O ./O 
Mr./O LrroN/PERSON ./O 
Tolerance/O is/O not/O even/O considered/O to/O be/O a/O virtue/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O according/O to/O its/O teachings/O ./O 
Mr.CLAIIDY/O ./O 
You/O are/O agreeing/O with/O me/O ,/O then/O ,/O I/O take/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O LyrroN/PERSON ./O 
Most/O assuredly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVrNNF.R/O Well/O ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O your/O experience/O in/O the/O Com/O -/O munist/O Party/O ,/O you/O left/O the/O field/O of/O screen/O writing/O ;/O is/O that/O what/O I/O understandI/O Mr./O Lnrov/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O let/O us/O say/O that/O it/O was/O certainly/O a/O large/O contributing/O factor/O ./O 
I/O was/O unable/O to/O secure/O another/O job/O in/O town/O ./O 
I/O had/O the/O interesting/O experience/O ,/O incidentally/O ,/O of/O being/O told/O by/O a/O couple/O of/O producers/O tlt/O I/O was/O a/O known/O Communist/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O 1low/O did/O you/O learn/O that/O I/O ''/O And/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O your/O name/O was/O dropped/O by/O a/O couple/O of/O people/O I/O know/O to/O be/O Communists/O ./O ''/O 
This/O was/O in/O that/O period/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O if/O it/O was/O necessary/O to/O state/O that/O I/O was/O a/O Communist/O not/O to/O get/O a/O job/O ,/O they/O would/O do/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYl/O ,/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O this/O question/O Y/O Mr./O VEWE/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DoYi/PERSON ,/O I/O hope/O you/O will/O see/O the/O pertinence/O of/O my/O question/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
1p/O until/O the/O time/O of/O ./O 
your/O trouble/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION leadership/O ,/O as/O a/O sc/O een/O writer/O you/O had/O been/O financially/O successful/O ?/O 
Mr./O LJrroN/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O had/O ./O 
Mr./O ID/O -RRB-/O oYL/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvFNqNER/O ./O 
You/O mentioned/O the/O name/O of/O Mr./O Stanley/PERSON Praeger/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O that/O for/O me/O ?/O 
Mr./O LrrorN/PERSON ./O 
P-r-a-e-g-e-r0/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvzNNzr/O ./O 
What/O is/O his/O occupation-what/O was/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O L0row/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O road/O show/O Lou/PERSON Costello/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O what/O you/O call/O a/O poor/O man/O 's/O comic/O ./O 
lie/O used/O to/O appear/O at/O all/O social/O affairs/O ana/O do/O skets/O and/O skitches/O -/O ``/O skets/O and/O skitches/O ,/O ''/O that/O is/O interesting/O ./O 
And/O he/O was/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O for/O a/O time/O employed/O at/O Twentieth/O Century-Fox/O a/O a/O comedian/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvZNNrYJ/O ./O 
Since/O the/O time/O of/O your/O withdrawal/O from/O the/O Coinmunist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O your/O expulsion/O ,/O have/O you/O engaged/O in/O any/O Conuntuist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ,/O to/O your/O knowledge/O I/O Mr./O Lrrrmo/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
In/O the/O decompression/O period/O ,/O which/O we/O will/O speak/O of/O again/O ,/O I/O supported/O Henry/PERSON Wallace/PERSON in/O 1948/O in/O his/O candidacy/O for/O the/O Piesidency/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O before/O the/O campaign/O and/O during/O part/O of/O it/O ,/O fut/O before/O the/O campaign/O was/O over/O however/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O like/O the/O associations/O that/O it/O required/O and/O I/O ceased/O that/O support/O ./O 
I/O voted/O for/O him/O ,/O however/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvzWUL/O I/O believe/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O that/O is/O all/O I/O desire/O to/O ask/O ./O 
Mr./O Vaw/O &/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr.JACISOX/O ./O 
Your/O contention/O ,/O as/O I/O unlermtand/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Lytton/PERSON ,/O is/O that/O as/O a/O result/O of/O you/O bretk/O with/O tho/O party/O that/O you/O wveri/O m/O turn/O ,/O reviled/O and/O blackliied/O by/O these/O with/O whom/O you/O hd/O ptWriosy/O be/O aiwiociated/O !/O 
Mr./O Lmonw/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O stronger/O t9a/O a/O ctentm/O ,/O ./O 
sir/O ./O 
At/O any/O tiame/O aw/O ny/O ploe/O I/O would/O pmvidb/O vidswo/O thattkA/O ism/O ANIJIIM/O A/O tA14/O VONIKIIIN/O IATI/O At/O ``/O PIVIItNH/O IN/O 11IN/O 1/O #/O 101t/O ~/O 0f4/O with/O tIa/O '/O l/O t/O til/O ti1/O ,444/O u/O %/O 0t/O 111/O 1ititili/O o/O tl/O opill/O il/O 1iit/O weat/O ttiti/O '/O PhitI/O %/O rly/O '/O ~/O '/O ots/O ,/O 4/O ''/O oitlvil/O did/O ,/O MIr/O ./O 
4/O ./O 
'till/O w/O ,/O `/O Iu'au/O hip/O O/O ''/O \/O 1411/O `/O itai/O whuvi/O I/O tad/O Ia/O '/O to/O itiivat/O Ht/O ,14/O I/O l/O it/O itumt/O '11/O 1Iii/O toh4/O t11/O 1i/O ~/O a/O `/O lielit/O fIi/O 'M/O oI/O ittt/O `/O atottle/O ttoto/O a/O jiud/O it/O Iwaa/O iloti'ii/O '/O I/O -LRB-/O 3/O `/O ba1/O ,/O bout/O IIhlilw/O ''/O ./O 
fil/O it/O 1tyt41111/O I/O `/O fil/O g/O i/O ~/O t/O it/O itt/O '/O \/O V1ut1/O obtu1/O ,/O u11/O oIt/O 111111111i4i/O ahil/O 114/O 0/O Ito/O utt/O '/O ,/O t/O i44/O thatu/O 1oto/O boltdif/O oo/O it/O itI/O ukht/O 11114a/O o/O 1/O 1.11/O fiiigi/O lilot/O filtl/O 11141414w/O w/O lilt/O ,/O wIll/O os/O ~/O ,/O til1111111/O t/O t/O ~/O it/O lt/O Ii/O llity/O but/O 1111/O I/O ito/O hibl/O o/O mlionlwilo/O i1t/O I110otI/O i/O loa/O '/O Ow/O Mildau/PERSON wh/O I/O 111k/O ll/O ~/O th/O i/O '/O ill/O '/O Ititfi/O jI/O htiuIIt/O c/O u/O roi/O itoo/O l'/O t/O utitt/O Io/O o/O tuill/O It/O .11111/O 14111aify/O 6k/O idt/O foINio/O -LRB-/O tit/O it/O Atl/O 141/O It/O \/O %/O ,/O fil/O iti'a/O 410/O ''/O lg/O IIIIIIII/O t/O t/O dotht11/O ti/O ttbitt/O ./O 
14i/O l/O 0/O \/O n1101110114/O ./O 
I/O ltiIt/O i/O '/O IsH/O Mux/O it/O ~/O ,/O thhtitllopt/O ~/O o'aio/O Itwilt/O '/O hit/O ``/O a/O ~/O a/O I/O ix/O t/O ~/O O/O m/O vi/O 14111i/O O/O pii/O towlv/O '/O atOt/O u/O ,/O 4/O ~/O '/O '/O t/O !/O 
1/O ti/O til/O I1b11t14t/O ItAti141111/O ,/O ba/O wht/O hoot/O Mr./O '/O $/O t/O `/O ov/O Noit/O -LRB-/O '/O t/O Ititilly/O that/O lhosot/O '/O -LRB-/O `/O utt/O `/O ittit/O o/O IiorCN/O ,/O I/O Io11itt/O IN14it/O '/O ll/O $/O lttOil/O t/O i/O w1/O '/O t/O tiA61tht/O tist/O ,/O Mr./O ItYvw/O '/O I/O ag/O dmi/O '/O t/O h/O Is/O i/O fitt/O huolo/O otutated/O h/O tolId.AIg/O `/O u/O ?/O 
thai/O tteaut/O 'd/O ./O 
11dt1t141/O IVitvol/O -/O Citottu/O il411mht-6/O ,/O g/O radio/O 1od/O telvilIon/O \*/O 41/O 1111it/O th011/O jst/O leek/O oiiie/O that/O -LRB-/O my/O tistettitt/O %/O 141116eihsCot/O t/O s/O ilt/O -LRB-/O ite/O Is/O toin/O `/O fel-oit/O ltilfi'ut/O Lors/O Aot/O them/O thtttoo/O Presfrv/O Art/O \*/O 11V/O tituCitj/O 's/O -/O 01uet1i/O asthe/O -LRB-/O `/O it/O veieuts/O Amrom/O tIu/O 3/O -RRB-/O t/O heatieIllVmot/O A/O ./O 
A.wHotIs/O Owirt/O whie/O `/O thRovttst/O tliv/O ql/O Oi/O iouoll/O ~/O h1104w/O tho/O Io/O \/O mliUn/O '/O 41othwlc/O ./O 
ittArtttee/O l'tui/O ~/O t/O '/O f/O uabstefill/O hatthis/O ~/O kRighlttt/O il/O oloIld.tlitpr/O ``/O o/O \*/O mibld/O `/O rXts/O tHasown/O total/O tar/O fo/O wortd/O to/O dIstrmist/O pbeimpa/O f/O ile/O lt/O r/O Aumert/O ./O 
wl/O i/O l/O ofl/O iiu/O ~/O us/O ./O 
1Wh/O c/O %/O \/O mmttte/O Is/O tho/O liost/O umn-Americatn/O featurow/O of/O life/O lIn/O the/O United/LOCATION Stnteutfwr/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 1Xn/O thtN/O itry/O devils/O of/O which/O they/O amcuse/O tile/O Krntilin/O andI/O Its/O pateltites/O ./O 
A/O kw/O `/O gkal/O firft/O step/O fisr/O tis/O Io/O the/O abolition/O tit/O the/O un-American/O counmittee/O ./O 
./O 
pproprIaUons/O for/O Its/O Wwwr/O kt/O `/O o/O ~/O mgrmmaust/O be/O urged4/O to/O vote/O ngtt44m1L./O ,/O #/O ,/O j/O The/O awd/O uuwAmricou/O ativtty/O I/O know/O is/O that/O ot/O the/O Un-Amprican/O Activities/O 100/O The/O arouds/O of/O attack/O tie/O iun-Americmn/O ./O 
Ihe/O procedure/O io/O ustAxirrn/O ./O 
The/O result/O ts/O un-Amnerican/O ./O 
for/O a/O man/O maty/O he/O condemned/O even/O It/O br/O b/O \*/O tewre/O OCbmatrew/O '/O f/O '/O e/O NSIWI'N/O lt/O '/O Al/O IV/O Ilf/O i/O 11/O 111/O '/O ,/O 1.415/O '/O ANIII/O '/O ./O 
id4Si/O Alflr/O -/O '/O A/O 4rArA/O 1/O ses/O ./O 
./O 
ft/O cf/O `/O eec/O Ift/O s/O I4/O 111/O 110/O id/O -1/O ,/O Vi/O i/O eteeii/O tci/O '/O fl/O %/O vicglill/O e/O '/O ,/O veccc/O I/O J11111/O 0411/O its/O rille/O 11111/O lot/O fil/O -/O fe/O `/O l1ifilii/O 011w/O ~/O for/O %/O vtcccf/O loll/O ''/O II-Otto/O 1e1e/O '/O 11ee114ectf/O ie/O ./O 
`/O teccc/O i/O ~/O i/O ee111iele/O '/O e/O IIeI/O Icllt/O e/O rc1110/O .../O lic/O W011/O ,1114/O 1se/O `/O ctt/O 1-01/O .1/O lilet/O t/O ~/O '/O ee/O i/O vib/O -RSB-/O wI/O l'1111/O ,1/O Ill/O wpw/O 1/O l/O %/O 11141111t/O `/O N/O ,/O All/O -/O 11/O ,/O 'll/O ii1111/O ``/O to/O Illc/O I/O ~/O cce/O Ii-st/O o/O ~/O il/O ccl/O W/O If/O irIcll/O ,/O v/O `/O ece/O Il/O '/O ~/O 1111/O 11lIl/O I/O lie11/O ,/O c/O c111/O 11l/O le/O 1/O i/O ceIite/O `/O cvieieci/O ll/O III/O i./O ;/O e/O lt/O `/O iet/O P-41/O I/O `/O tci/O i/O fec/O 11114eelcicl/O c/O '/O 11111/O i/O till/O ./O 
e/O ,/O foo/O illcif/O '/O ;/O te/O r/O ,/O l/O ifil/O li/O 111/O 1/O 11l/O oil/O '/O ~/O I/O Ii/O -/O i/O ,/O II/O '/O ./O 
I/O '/O feIl/O I/O I/O ,/O -LRB-/O IlelIwI/O m./O Iffsh/O 4/O 44/O ,/O ./O 
y/O I/O i/O 11111/O lc/O cc/O ./O '/O 
./O 
ll/O ie/O '/O ilt/O c/O cc/O c/O 811/O ./O 
i/O l/O l/O i/O `/O ece/O $/O les3/O c./O is/O i/O lesie/O l/O -,81/O I/O 11tc1iti/O i/O NI/O u/O ,/O W/O -/O tomi/O '/O I./O I/O e/O ts/O Iiecd/O $/O Il/O ccc/O Ii/O '/O c/O I.e/O '/O i/O %/O ce/O Ill/O it/O ,/O Ifciece/O ,/O oI/O '/O '/O c/O itriliii/O ,/O .11/O ,/O i/O i/O 1/O 1/O flc/O ci/O '/O cilot/O holc/O ly/O Ii/O l.-e/O '/O A/O wuilit/O ./O 
i/O Sitofrispit/O ,/O il/O IIc/O lii/O -/O g/O if11111e/O ./O 
%/O v/O tvtoilufcll/O 11.1,11114/O v/O `/O Iy/O ie/O '/O ,/O Ic111/O 111f/O lIc/O I/O f/O c11/O i/O ccce/O iicl/O c14/O 11011P./O ,/O fee/O 11v/O 111/O c411f/O ,/O Mr/O ,/O WVcitf/O .1/O c/O '/O I/O chuecck/O c/O `/O li/O ./O 
Ise/O `/O ccu/O All/O :/O ,/O S4ecec/O uccic/O ./O 
Is/O Iclicill/O ,/O v/O #cM/O 11cu0/O Ic/O :/O ./O 
111eel/O li/O cg/O ,/O efvo/O 1/O ./O 
lice1/O 111ccci/O s-411ly/O ecce/O Icleil/O 111111,4/O lc/O `/O cccccc/O 'll/O lec1P/O 1f0c/O ceck/O I/O ,/O lie/O 114/O ,/O e/O i/O t/O 14,11/O '/O ./O 
Ow/O il/O cI/O cg.cfh/O iIll-e/O 1/O 1.19/O ./O 
c/O tio/O ''/O ./O 
yiicic5/O '/O cc/O c/O ,/O c/O c/O I/O cr/O `/O ed/O jimi/O f/O Awcil/O ,/O Ali-c/O ,/O -LRB-/O `/O ieee/O Icemos/O NIre/O ./O 
V1/O ,1/O c./O 1110/O ''/O Yelf/O ce.ec/O ,/O Nitc/O ,/O I/O '/O -LRB-/O c/O `/O Icc/O `/O ie/O `/O c/O '/O fuufsy/O 4/O wc/O `/O ccim/O cluis/O li/O ./O 
elilgc/O lceso-o/O c/O y/O fo/O ``/O ict/O 111u1c1c/O 114/O `/O Ci/O c/O ciil/O '/O c/O ieicc/O 14I/O Mc/O '/O ./O 
HvIc/O Illi/PERSON ./O 
ccfihe/O f111/O if/O vccelic11vittlu/O ./O 
e/O `/O cccc/O cy/O te1ovl/O fieS/O ccee/O '/O ~/O `/O er/O sc/O eeed/O `/O Nc/O '/O ./O 
i/O ccc/O '/O ./O '/O 
./O 
./O 
1e0jc/O Ii/O rice/O '/O re/O `/O rsifta/O ,/O c/O iec/O ccol/O ice/O cc/O '/O i/O i/O to/O 1/O uce/O 111/O \*/O 111g/O c9I/O if/O i/O r./O 11/O folce01io/O r/O er/O `/O fileec/O Cit/O tocc/O ./O 
`/O wc/O '/O r/O a/O ./O 
i/O er/O icele/O \*/O IcS/O c/O `/O IA-11/O iti/O c/O icecy/O '/O -LRB-/O 1/O ./O 
./O 
ceilcc/O '/O Ie'eWil/O ivcc/O ./O '/O 
./O 
Me'e/O `/O cf/O llet/O ,/O ti/O isec/O `/O W111/O I/O lti/O u/O `/O cc/O eeilCc/O '/O ./O 
focvul1e/O 4-01111/O Thi'e/O piie/O re/O '/O ./O 
./O 
ceeis/O flt/O it/O ml/O of/O lit/O f/O litoff/O -RRB-/O ,/O ./O 
s/O tow/O ,/O wittlelv/O ooIiur/O `/O lfe/O tofiel/O ~/O cri/O ~/O re/O SSe/O Ate/O ,/O ,/O ./O 
`/O riieec/O As-i/O `/O civIc/O 's/O Coteisllos/O `/O e/O '/O fl/O re-w-fotis/O #tctv/O 11104H/O ~/O le11A/O dice.l/O n/O crov.Ivccccc/O 0cei1/O .11111/O '/O -LRB-/O lily/O ,/O f/O ,1/O ccc/O wcudcil/O u/O ie/O gc/O `/O Sflvcg/O eery/O wimc/O '/O fthct/O fins/O fi/O ~/O retrl/O cAclc.oe/O fo/O fIce/O pilief/O ,/O W/O -RRB-/O flow/O elctn/O Illl4/O teco/O fI/O `/O limpic/O `/O eI/O Ic141/O '16/O t5lclt/O 54/O `/O fimlccicci11/O I/O to/O ''/O ie/O ,/O '/O Arnofli-ir/O '/O 1fli1t/O flu/O '/O I-011inIfti/O '/O o/O fclat/O #/O dlons/O -RRB-/O irccio-c/O on/O ``/O own/O `/O i/O `/O hc0/O V11111/O ''/O cifwe/O ./O 
\*/O ,/O Ins/O isor/O nrd/O e/O ic/O rene/O ,/O toyi/O '/O th/O gc/O '/O -LRB-/O 11ijlfiIle/O fccifccec/O tct/O eccunucculuelcine/O IN/O vanctiicicis/O anid/O Ie/O `/O rrifycinxs/O fthin/O ,/O oi/O `/O rrior/O andi/O encfltieclonf/O dip/O ,/O toet/O isitsk/O ./O 
fo/O urtiC/O ~/O tfiul/O fccfiluce/O ecgiclucct/O inytiohccm/O \*/O aephent/O ,/O I/O trusft/O ?/O 
MI/O '/O ./O 
CLvARDYr/O ./O 
You/O arc/O et/O ill/O reading/O fromdprrit/O Mr./O Sc/O -LRB-/O uritnc/O ./O 
I/O ci/O reaid/O irg/O froncI/O lie/O pmtnpic/O let/O ./O 
Mr./O -LRB-/O `/O vAUD0Y/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O watit/O the/O aiciene/O to/O get/O the/O irnprecsimr/O that/O ,/O Acm/O it/O '/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 1tcsu/O `/O ely/O Xc111i/O 111/O we/O `/O sll/O ism/O ./O 
lebot/O `/O c/O `/O icie/O jobcl/O ,/O cc1H/O that/O ifi/O your/O idea/O ./O 
Mr./O Acesrceca/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O ,/O think/O theyyhv/O vte/O Now/O ,/O fihe/O Int/O o110/O :/O rlr/O htinr.w/O a/O ~/O n./O Jaegttnta/O Tho/O fears/O ./O 
whipped/O up/O fey/O the/O ton/O \*/O Atlruee'inx/O ~/O toroe/O the/O Sbcetar/O '/O offxnrc/O of/O hymiee'in/O andi/O greed/O ./O 
-LRB-/O `/O oindltfon/O ,/O ./O 
thnt/O ripell/O hcflcary/O for/O millionsc/O are/O perpet/O ``/O MtMI/O only/O beeauuio/O they/O are/O profitable/O for/O a/O few/O ./O 
Mr./O 0/O ,/O AIDY/O ./O 
You/O may/O it/O minifiter/O put/O that/O outt/O Mr./O Scmurnr/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O it/O might/O he/O well/O ./O 
in/O view/O of/O all/O of/O the/O nameoulaling/O and/O the/O `/O extravagant/O use/O of/O the/O kind/O of/O language/O not/O Mr./O WAvrim/O ./O 
460/O fl/O `/O ollttltly/O tised/O hy/O vitiIoto/O 14/O -RRB-/O ll6/O Oip/O oplerat.iol/O Alt/O '/O ./O 
Mr./O ¡/O A/O -LRB-/O VlTIVITIMS4/O IN/O `/O I/O `/O IIH/O IO/O -LRB-/O OMMINII11/O i/O eltrgtVgyIIiuaI/O ,/O |/O -LRB-/O '/O 01/O -LRB-/O lllhillgtoti/O AN/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O IuhK/O Itolnt/O 1w/O might/O ,/O to1/O i6xt/O %/O `/O Ill/O -LRB-/O hl/O lil/O Ilin/O tolll/O iI/O oxiiflly/O whial/O ,/O i/O wring/O with/O -LRB-/O CiAunIV/O ./O 
I/O votN/O fin/O '/O I/O hlt.I/O 11011/O ,/O iot/O Al./O ./O 
WltoN/O ./O 
,/O JA/O -LRB-/O `/O lIMN/O ,/O hIly/O I/O IIHl/O 011O/O -LRB-/O t11/O `/O sMtI/O htV/O ThIlI/O wtn/O ,/O Mr/O ,/O Lytton/LOCATION ./O 
DOMX1111Ch1141t/O ./O 
eli/O 'll/O AIRRA/O is/O -LRB-/O ii/O `/O di'ikel/O to/O O.w/O Ig/O ~/O ./O 
It/O ,/O 11111/O Mith/PERSON yell/O III/O filly/O Wily/O tfl0lll/O Y01ll/O ,/O -LRB-/O %/O X/O -/O llII/O Iho/O -LRB-/O 1/O ,/O Ouitll/O |/O t./O I/O 1/O `/O nt.y/O Mr./O IjY'i/O -RRB-/O ON/O ./O 
Yi/PERSON 's/O ./O 
All/O '/O ./O 
l/O t/O ;/O KHoN/O ./O 
i1/O 0ut11t/O '/O Wol/O ,/O l/O l/O %/O IhsIlini/O ,/O h./O -LRB-/O ./O 
tlllllillixl/O ,/O I/O `/O llihy/O lil/O il/O ?/O 
iA/O ,/O I/O -/O ./O 
r/O `/O I/O ,/O -RRB-/O N/O ,/O I/O dhonB/O `/O t./O klow/O what/O ,/O ilt/O ,/O -LRB-/O olitlt/O toitisi/O ./O 
Il/O 'till/O y/O liiio/O i4/O j1inmll/O ./O 
today/O ./O 
Alei/O ,/O '/O ACSON/O ./O 
WI1I/O ./O 
it/O ws/O YIMIO/O -LRB-/O IayV/O I/O ./O 
I/O -/O ,/O ./O 
mi/O N./O I/O -LRB-/O -RRB-/O Ily/O ily/O that/O ./O 
18/O I/O llow/O Ilie/O -LRB-/O ollllllnlt/O ./O 
I/O `/O i1r/O ./O 
y/O lil1e/O It/O would/O iave/O lit/O ./O 
All/O ./O 
CLIAR/O |/O DY/O ./O 
11/O ,/O ig/O 1/O I/O Iii/O -/O fi/O 'll/O -LRB-/O 01II1ll11llli/O ~/O lt/O 111c/O -LRB-/O 1/O ;/O WI/O ,/O '/O R1/O |/O Nir/PERSON ./O 
IAYP/O `/O hN/O ./O 
I/O t/O hIllik/O it/O ./O 
is/O 01106/O Air/O ./O 
CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
I/O idii/O `/O t./O 11lll/O to/O Hily/O it/O ./O 
ig/O ll/O of/O IInllt/O ,/O lutt/O it/O ,/O isid/O ,/O I.hist/O 0110iisl/O `/O t./O it/O hr/O ,/O I/O `/O I/O -RRB-/O roN/O ./O 
I/O thiltk/O so/O ./O 
it-r/O ./O 
Sa/O tt/O :/O llu/O ./O 
./O 
`/O I/O `/O le/O gilliee/O ll.jing/O i141/O ./O 
tteo/O lklls/O Iso/O ./O 
hut/O 111011V/O tI10I1/O 11l110/O ellol/O -LRB-/O iI/O hll/O wh41/O %/O 1o/O like/O t/O |/O h/O oer/O \/O tonl/O 1ilist/O --/O oit/O ,/O so/O IIlll/O ill/O b/O t/O lilJl/O hllot/O Illeters/O of/O t/O II/O -LRB-/O parly/O wh/O -RRB-/O il/O '/O SN/O Oilt/O 11h/O thillg/O ./O 
I./O I1/O I1hllVO/O jilt/O ,/O read/O ./O 
Mr./O VtrIJ1I/O ./O 
M/O -LSB-/O r./O Valter/PERSON ./O 
fl/O '/O ./O 
WAtIN/O `/O r./O I/O WOn/O ./O 
to/O eoit/O '/O -LRB-/O -LRB-/O `/O t11lllltIt/O VOI/O -LRB-/O 11/O blwfor/O -RRB-/O '/O o/O this/O A-14o/O oif/O Cilitig/ORGANIZATION 1/O i/O oC/O lllllitllen/O Vllulill/ORGANIZATION ~/ORGANIZATION t/O 0/O 111141/O 1/O 11l11/O surel/O ,/O '/O |/O hilt/O lily/O eolheliil/O est/O ,/O ,/O ,/O t/O Ili/O -LRB-/O -LRB-/O jot/O -RRB-/O 11111/O ./O 
we/O '/O 1kre/O oblliged/O to/O do/O ./O 
It/O ,/O 11s/O 1/O do/O aiboltit/O ./O 
`/O I/O `/O Iis/O n'tI/O ,/O is/O aittt1/O '/O ./O 
Soill/PERSON '/O f/O '/O Its/O lr/O doing/O it/O ./O 
ng1aittst/O Ou/O -RRB-/O `/O I/O -RRB-/O t/O tr/O judgllol/O ./O 
lit/O t/O `/O etailtnl/O took/O a/O lot/O itinr/O itites/O til11/O fortiitld/O to/O whilt/O ./O 
voll/O hItvo/O done/O than/O it/O ./O 
did/O for/O thooplohi/O who/O -LRB-/O l'10/O iter/O '/O o/O I1/O -LRB-/O I/O htid/O Ibhild/O th/O ift/O very/O -LRB-/O onstilltioll/O whiehl/O if/O !/O 
t/O hly/O |/O lld/O tlteir/O wily/O th11y/O Woild/O -LRB-/O itesiroy/O ./O 
Atil/O I/O congratulate/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O L/O -RSB-/O rrON/O ./O 
ihnlik/O you/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O O.AitIw/O ./O 
Let/O me/O join/O in/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O Lrrir/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O Vltair/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doy'a/O -/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
Cliairman/PERSON ,/O I/O wish/O to/O say/O this/O to/O the/O witle/O .../O I/O join/O heartily/O in/O thanking/O 3Ol/O for/O coming/O ad/O exposing/O the/O colispiracy/O which/O you/O ilid/O and/O the/O mnlner/O in/O whieli/O you/O did/O iL/O And/O in/O cOnlnee/O ,/O tion/O with/O that/O eompliItent/O to/O you/O ,/O T/O wish/O ,/O `/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O to/O say/O while/O I/O do/O not/O have/O more/O than/O just/O personal/O aequaintance/O with/O the/O counsel/O now/O sitting/O beside/O the/O witness/O ,/O lie/O had/O with/O him/O yesterday/O a/O very/O able/O ,/O distinguished/O attorney/O ,/O who/O lives/O in/O my/O old/O congressional/O district/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O andlI/O want/O to/O comIipliment/O him/O ,/O and/O the/O partner/O here/O today/O ,/O counsel/O for/O this/O witness/O ,/O as/O men/O of/O the/O bar/O ,/O successful/O as/O they/O are/O ,/O taking/O time/O to/O come/O to/O this/O sort/O of/O a/O proceeding/O and/O add/O dignity/O and/O patriotic/O attitude/O by/O the/O bar/O toward/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
./O 
Before/O I/O close/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O have/O received/O so/O many/O requests/O ;/O both/O orally/O here/O and/O over/O the/O phone/O ,/O and/O by/O messenger/O ,/O where/O people/O are/O asking/O under/O what/O basic/O law/O this/O committee/O functions/O ./O 
I/O have/O had/O four/O quesions/O to/O that/O effect/O this/O morning/O ./O 
While/O I/O have/O often/O referred/O to/O this/O ,/O I/O believe/O it/O is/O pertinent/O ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O observations/O by/O -LRB-/O MtJNiM/O `/O ip/O ACrOTIP/O IN/O IR/O fli/O dit-il/O ~/O ilml/O -LRB-/O Ol/O coljulte/O Iltli/O LrMhAi/O AN/O -LRB-/O IPM/ORGANIZATION ,/O hi/O from/O Old/O ,/O il/O epiw/O A/O ~/O I/O '/O A/O 467/O ly/O tht0/O ,/O ./O 
Tite/O Ommni/O lIfois/O fill/O thi-i/O n/O rini/O Act/O lviliv/O Iesiti/O wl/O i/O `/O sr/O by/O tsiliiiidilINI/O n/O ''/O i/O 1/O -LRB-/O 11/O ttsiii/O Iinn/O `/O tnto/O lii/O Vs/O '/O 4Nt/O lgn/O IltoiiN/O #of/O flit/O ,/O '/O I-Xis/O `/O ii/O ,/O flit/O -/O c/O `/O Iiti/O rtleir/O ,/O 11i1/O ii/O i/O ~/O 11il/O l/O III/O 11111/O NIVI0II/O fistll/O '/O 114141/O 8ii1ri40itflcanit/O $/O 1111iflIci/O -LRB-/O 11.1011/O #/O fori/O tin/O '/O I/O li/O Viii/PERSON I/O s/O `/O tsnt/O NIs/O `/O R1111/O I/O lii/O IIN/O itii/O W11111/O `/O si/O fl/O i/O rn1is/O '/O 1igii/O s/O `/O u1414foiinllev/O ure/O -/O N/O ill/O i/O lin/O '/O iri/O i/O i/O 051M/O si/O i/O '/O mmt/O tir/O qitie/O alite/O 1/O r/O oormai/O n'ic/O '/O l/O i/O tin/O ,/O m./O weao/O t/O 11.1/O mit/O oraii/O ~/O r/O `/O Miii/O iny/O mitic/O ./O '/O 
./O 
e/O fill/O ,/O ,/O ,/O tm/O li/O 1fit/O ,/O i/O in/O tufo/O e/O i/O '/O t/O mt/O iii/O '/O imsmris/O ei/O '/O ,/O li/O by/O tecigi/O ,/O N/O te/O 14/O \*/O aifaill/O fll/O rIliaIiter/O O/O lo/O lo/O I/O riiffoti/O thlisrli/O Ilm/O a1/O emtli'id/O mush/O imaiiiti/O sIt/O i/O i/O N/O Itoor/O it/O lit/O ,/O I/O II/O -/O Iofilts/O '/O I/O d/O 1111/O 11111111/O p/O rit/O i/O hP/O 11/O '/O 144/O or11/O 14a/O Jfiie/O tw/O 84110401/O lte/O 8rmti/O It/O -LRB-/O r/O ,/O catigtenx/O ,/O wh/O ii/O '/O l/O i/O 5them/O i/O `/O ti/O ~/O il/O '/O i/O ./O 
i/O lt/O ~/O i/O yl/O 111/O ie/O ed/O iIeo/O Jimt/O Wael5ofis/O itt/O li.iihi/O v/O 091/O owi/O `/O xiib/O I/O lio/O i/O '/O e/O Auitn/O `/O eiii/O pec.he/O o/O $/O filli/O 111d/O of/O it10tui180/O k/O 1110/O tie11116/O 1/O l/O ie1111/O ./O 
%/O Jii/O i/O -LRB-/O I/O 1H1/O 1/O -/O -LRB-/O 140/O 140/O 'S/O ./O 
~/O r/O odi/O '/O I/O rendl/O i/O '/O i/O t/O -RRB-/O 1-4114/O j'/O ilm/O -LRB-/O olw/O pollc/O rli/O N./O l/O of/O g1ui/O `/O il/O 1/O -RRB-/O lf/O Law/O Na/O '/O -/O '/O 4/O `/O eetslgrtca/O lE/O '/O 4Iil/O oa/O is/O i4e/O `/O tiili/O i/O vei/O e/O `/O iic/O `/O ol/O I/O I/O lif/O t/O 're/O S1i114/O '/O i/O ls-n/O t/O eA/O O/O Vti/O I/O 111/O f114/O 011/O fid/O it/O o/O 1/O 111/O -/O rmlilg/O ''/O i/O fc/O 're/O Xiti/O lie/O N/O ci/O llIli/O -LRB-/O cilil/O nit811/O a/O `/O i/O `/O sai/O `/O lll/O n/O li/O aiii/O iesr/O iI/O riill/O mi/O of11111iif/O l'Ji/O rt/O i./O %/O 83/O ii/O l'lirtliV/O ./O 
lli/O ri/O scfii/O y/O iiIfil/O '/O N'tiii/O 4/O `/O lveliil/O Pl/O '/O it/O lei/O ./O 
ili/O ra/O `/O n-Ims13Amyoi/O frce'i/O tiiiit/O ii/O 111/O lii/O li/O li/O `/O ro/O fir/O t/O vialf/O `/O rn/O 44u/O 111N/O '/O l/O I/O 'm/O -LRB-/O fnw8l11/O cifu'iis/O '/O 111111/O '/O j/O lo/O mm/O '/O titulg/O '/O I/O te/O rrlalIoil/O cutus/O Oh/O i/O Oy/O iirm/O tie/O '/O rce/O '/O ilitil/O -LRB-/O I/O -RRB-/O orguuiliMI11111/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Al/O -RRB-/O s-o/O ,/O ltik/O ti/O lrg/O auimslciclee/O itivnto/O wlao/O roui/O ,/O asm/O toieillg/O ifeth/O ve/O ~/O limen/O ,/O and/O I/O loegmllellrliIm/O rf/O Ir/O whi/O eotit/O '/O l/O ~/O f/O -LRB-/O `/O Itvesit/O liirgi/O Imirheeoff/O ItIm/O loy/O tr-nhsy/O devamnu/O lefiixal/O here/O ooeiske/O `/O lier/O groXpot/O ~/O -LRB-/O slirec/O tiie1111111/O o/O feUitedfWNISaempConge/O ,/O whichlminrodio/O th/O 81im/O '/O tt/O ./O 
foneres/O nti/O m/O 11/O --/O 1s/O its/O 4/O -LRB-/O 5Ct/O myor/O I/O i/O t/O -RRB-/O pvif/O `/O liymai/O co1ithsifl/O tot/O lee/O fact/O th/O eatt/O r/O -LRB-/O lo/O Ii/O fxiit/O here/O ,/O thiti/O w/O gin1/O -LRB-/O hie/O itttime/O yearn/O w/O -RRB-/O `/O e.ehueo/O at/O tt/O -RRB-/O o/O rad/O o/O thosr/O Coiiiltec/O ,/O o/O the/O vs/O nwihw/O euse/O Alesmof/O thinkOO/O hiclg/O i/O ,/O cwaeherth/O w/O n/O dsthe/O lrget/O atm/O ellr/O askte/O lif/O orb/O t111hs/O C/O o/O eoitllttOC/O ,/O there/O wr/O ofel/O '/O 2/O Vle-inaint/O It/O ir/O t/O hen/O tiopnese/O o/O f/O t/O United/ORGANIZATION ee/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION ores/O ofih/O I/O thepe/O 8/O ativColges1dp/O world/O Menimbers/O onply/O eatie/O ot/O Of/O IMr.s/O 10811/O o/O cal/O tir/O alytton/O ,/O I/O o/O of/O they/O collges/O ill/O tilpe/O rngy/O veryta/O sin/O ere/O a/O h/O 11/O -LRB-/O e.o/O sppreciatltionl/O for/O theiietstms/O n/O the/O greatethasis/O hjiE/O $/O ltii/O focr/O byohverre/O this/O committee/O Mr./O Ln/O `/O ri/O ~/O y./O ./O 
Thakio/O ,/O r./O byer/O 2appo/O oe/O ;/O aimi/O h/O tere/O ./O 
lth/O aer/O Mr./O FkAzIEui/PERSON ./O 
That/O ii/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O Vrjjwe/PERSON ./O 
./O 
