INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O INTHE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 9/O HEARING/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O APRIL/O 19/O ,/O 1956/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activitiaes/O -LRB-/O INDEX/O IN/O PART/O 10/O OF/O THIS/O SERIES/O -RRB-/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 17/O -/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1956/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O MORGAN/PERSON 'M/O MOULDER/O ,/O Missouri/LOCATION HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON E./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION RICHARD/O ABAENSDirector/O CONTENTS/O PART/O 7/O April/O 16/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofWilliam/O Don/PERSON Waddilove/PERSON -------------------------------/O S/O Edith/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O George/PERSON Rapport/PERSON -RRB-/O ./O 
--/O ./O 
./O 
--/O ./O 
---------/O ./O 
./O 
Afternoon/O session/O :/O Rubin/PERSON Decker/PERSON _/O ./O 
----------------/O --------------------/O Joseph/PERSON Pass/PERSON ---------------------------------/O Samuel/PERSON Berland/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Sylvia/PERSON Lardner/PERSON Barnell/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON -RRB-/O .../O --/O -/O Carter/PERSON Darnell/PERSON ---------------------------/O Milton/PERSON Kestenbaum/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Sidney/PERSON Greene/PERSON -/O .../O .../O .../O --------------/O ./O 
Paul/PERSON Powell/PERSON ./O 
-------/O ./O 
./O 
_/O --/O _/O --/O PART/O 8/O April/O 17/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O Nikolai/PERSON Khokhlov/PERSON --------------------/O ------/O Page/O 3660/O 3676/O 3695/O 3711/O 3718/O 3726/O 3728/O 3733/O 3737/O 3749/O 3756/O PART/O 9/O April/O 19/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofAlbert/O Glasser/PERSON ------------------------/O 3821/O Katherine/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON -RRB-/O -----------------/O 3837/O Herbert/PERSON Offner/PERSON ----------------/O 3841/O Sam/PERSON Fordis/PERSON ./O 
----------/O _/O -------------/O 3850/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON -------------------------------------/O 3854/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O of/O :/O Cryil/PERSON Towbin/PERSON .../O ./O 
--------------------------/O 3862/O Helen/PERSON Teverniti/PERSON ____/O -------------/O 3869/O Lewis/PERSON Elias/PERSON -----------------------------------/O 3870/O Leonard/PERSON H./PERSON Dahlsten/PERSON -----------------------------------/O 3881/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ------------------/O _/O -/O __/O _/O 3885/O Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ./O 
-----------------------/O 3887/O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -----------------------------------------/O 3887/O Manuel/PERSON L./PERSON Compinsky/PERSON ------------------------------------/O 3892/O Eudice/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -LRB-/O Mrs./O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON -RRB-/O -----/O 3896/O Milton/PERSON Feher/PERSON -------------------------------------------/O 3897/O PART/O 10/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofThomas/O Walfrid/PERSON Nelson/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Arthur/ORGANIZATION Globe/ORGANIZATION ---------------------------------------------/O Don/PERSON Christlieb/PERSON ------------------------------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofRamez/O Idriss/PERSON ---------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON DiFiore/PERSON ------------------------------------------/O Edgar/PERSON Lustgarten/PERSON ----------------------------------------/O In/O 3901/O 3915/O 3918/O 3934/O 3937/O 3939/O IV/O CONTENTS/O April/O 20/O ,/O 1956-Continued/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O of-Continued/O Morris/PERSON Boltuch/PERSON --/O ./O 
./O 
--/O ________/O --/O ___/O --/O Philip/PERSON Goldberg/PERSON --------/O _/O --/O --/O Joseph/PERSON Eger/PERSON -------------------/O Kalman/PERSON Bloch/PERSON --------/O _/O -------/O _/O Jack/O -LRB-/O L/O -RRB-/O Pepper/O -------------/O ______________________/O Jean/PERSON C./PERSON Musick/PERSON ------------------------/O Manuel/PERSON Newman/PERSON ------------------------------/O Roy/PERSON Frankson/PERSON -------------------------/O __/O ------/O _/O Herbert/PERSON Lessner/PERSON -----------------------------/O George/PERSON Kast/PERSON ------------------------------------/O April/O 21/O ,/O 1956/O :/O Testimony/O of/O :/O John/PERSON Walter/PERSON Porter/PERSON -------------------------------/O Jessica/PERSON Rhine/PERSON Wildman/PERSON -----------------/O _/O -----------/O Afternoon/O session/O ,/O testimony/O ofLouis/O R./PERSON Sherman/PERSON --------------------------------/O William/PERSON Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON ------------------------------/O Louis/PERSON R./PERSON Sherman/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ---------------------/O Thomas/PERSON A./PERSON Chapman/PERSON -------------------------------/O _/O Sidney/LOCATION London/LOCATION ---------------------------------/O _/O Alfred/PERSON Hale/PERSON Caplan/PERSON ---------------------------/O John/PERSON T./PERSON McTernan/PERSON -----------/O _/O --------------------------/O ./O 
121/O ./O 
STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERSANDDUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O \*/O \*/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5/O ,/O 1955/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O STANDINGCOMMITTEES/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O 5/O 5/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 9/O THURSDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 19/O ,/O 1956/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O at/O 9:40/O a./O m./O ,/O pursuant/O to/O recess/O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION -LRB-/O presiding/O -RRB-/O ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O and/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON and/O Courtney/PERSON E./PERSON Owens/PERSON ,/O investigators/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O call/O the/O next/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O come/O forward/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
You/O may/O be/O seated/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ALBERT/PERSON GLASSER/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O it/O is/O the/O practice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O advise/O all/O witnesses/O that/O they/O have/O a/O right/O to/O have/O counsel/O accompany/O them/O to/O the/O witness/O chair/O ,/O and/O the/O right/O to/O consult/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O they/O may/O desire/O during/O the/O course/O of/O their/O testimony/O ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION ,/O Ill./LOCATION ,/O January/O 25/O ,/O 1916/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
8855/O St./O Ives/O ,/O I-v-e-s/O ,/O Drive/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION 46/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O lived/O in/O California/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
California/LOCATION since/O 1922/O ./O 
I/O was/O 6/O years/O old/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ./O 
3822/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Graduate/O of/O high/O school-Roosevelt/O High/O School/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 1934/O I/O won/O the/O Alchin/PERSON ,/O A-1-c-h-i-n/O ./O 
Charity/O Foundation/O Award/O ./O 
After/O leaving/O the/O university-it/O was/O during/O the/O depression/O years1/O began/O to/O work/O gradually/O on/O movie/O circuits/O ,/O and/O trying/O to/O establish/O a/O reputation/O as/O a/O composer/O and/O conductor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wanted/O to/O find/O out/O what/O your/O profession/O or/O occupation/O is/O ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O it/O is/O both/O that/O of/O a/O composer/O and/O an/O instrumentalist/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O composer/O and/O conductor/O ;/O motion/O pictures/O ,/O radio/O shows/O ,/O television/O shows/O ;/O all/O types/O of/O commercial/O work/O ;/O and/O ,/O when/O I/O have/O time/O ,/O my/O concert/O work/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O its/O investigation/O the/O committee/O learned/O that/O ,/O for/O a/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O you/O had/O an/O opportunity/O to/O learn/O something/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION within/O a/O group/O of/O musicians/O in/O this/O area/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O ever/O a/O member/O of/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O composed/O of/O musicians/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Unfortunately/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O ,/O composed/O exclusively/O of/O musicians/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O Communist/O members/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O musicians/O alone/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O exclusively/O of/O musicians/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O over/O what/O period/O of/O time/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O such/O an/O organization/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O this/O was/O in/O 1943/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O over/O a/O period/O of/O perhaps/O from/O 6/O to/O 7/O months/O at/O most/O ./O 
I/O was/O recruited/O somewhere/O about/O the/O middle/O of/O the/O year/O ,/O around/O the/O summertime/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O became/O a/O member/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O ./O 
Through/O various/O family/O friends/O ,/O we/O became/O acquainted/O with/O a/O gentleman/O named/O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O ,/O a/O Dr./O Louise/PERSON Light/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON was/O a/O functionary/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
He/O was/O one/O of/O the/O officers/O ./O 
Which/O particular/O job/O he/O had/O I/O am/O not/O aware/O of/O ./O 
Actually/O it/O was/O organizer/O or/O chairman/O or/O something/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O pay/O much/O attention/O to/O it/O ./O 
We/O were/O soon/O aware/O that/O he/O was/O a/O high/O official/O in/O the/O high/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O summer/O of/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
The/O summer/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
We/O actually/O had/O met/O him/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O in/O the/O spring/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
After/O going/O to/O his/O house/O many/O times/O and/O being/O invited/O to/O his/O house/O and/O being/O wined/O and/O dined/O by/O them/O ,/O we/O realized/O years/O later/O as/O to/O why/O we/O were/O wined/O and/O dined/O ./O 
It/O was/O sort/O of/O a/O membership/O drive/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
But/O ,/O after/O seeing/O him/O there/O often/O and/O spending/O a/O lot/O of/O time/O with/O them-because/O ,/O for/O one/O thing/O there/O ,/O Dr./O Silver/PERSON is/O an/O extremely/O intelligent/O man/O ,/O and/O in/O his/O conversation/O ,/O even/O though/O most/O of/O the/O time/O it/O would/O lead/O toward/O politics/O which/O I/O was/O n't/O too/O much/O concerned/O with/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3823/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O it/O was/O educational/O ,/O if/O anything/O ,/O to/O hear/O him/O describe/O things/O and/O discuss/O political/O affairs/O along/O liberal/O elements/O ./O 
My/O background/O naturally/O had/O been/O slightly/O liberal/O all/O my/O life/O ./O 
My/O parents/O had/O been/O ./O 
My/O father/O had/O been/O a/O bodyguard/O at/O one/O time/O for/O Eugene/PERSON V./PERSON Debs/PERSON back/O before/O the/O First/O World/O War/O ./O 
And/O ,/O as/O the/O years/O went/O by/O ,/O this/O form/O of/O semiliberalism/O was/O more/O or/O less/O instilled/O in/O the/O conversation/O at/O home/O ./O 
,/O So/O my/O environment/O became/O a/O liberal/O form/O of/O education/O ./O 
When/O I/O heard/O Mr./O Silver/PERSON discuss/O things/O in/O a/O more/O radical/O light/O and/O stronger/O tone/O ,/O for/O basic/O curiosity/O reasons/O alone-I/O am/O a/O very/O curious/O guy/O ;/O I/O like/O to/O learn/O ./O 
And/O from/O Mr./O Silver/PERSON we/O began/O to/O learn/O various/O things/O which/O at/O times/O might/O have/O puzzled/O me/O and/O confused/O me/O as/O to/O how/O things/O operated/O under/O communism/O ,/O under/O different/O forms/O of/O liberal/O elements/O ./O 
As/O the/O time/O moved/O along/O through/O the/O spring/O he/O began/O pressuring/O us-I/O should/O n't/O use/O that/O word-asking/O us/O ,/O we/O are/O intelligent/O young/O kids/O ;/O I/O am/O a/O good/O musician/O ;/O I/O am/O going/O far/O ;/O I/O should/O come/O into/O the/O party/O and/O help/O organize/O a/O certain/O type/O of/O thing/O which/O they/O were/O eventually/O going/O to/O steer/O toward/O the/O Musicians/O Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O told/O that/O that/O was/O to/O be/O one/O of/O the/O objectives/O of/O this/O Communist/O Party/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O actually/O recall/O if/O Mr./O Silver/PERSON discussed/O this/O particular/O element/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
But/O in/O overall/O discussions/O they/O were/O pointing/O out/O that/O one/O of/O the/O lacks/O in/O America/LOCATION was/O the/O fact/O that/O we/O do/O n't/O have/O a/O Minister/O of/O Culture/O ,/O a/O general/O governmental/O agency/O which/O could/O help/O and/O control/O and/O sponsor/O music/O and/O all/O the/O allied/O arts/O like/O the/O various/O European/O countries/O have-France/O ,/O England/LOCATION ,/O Finland/LOCATION ./O 
Many/O of/O the/O European/O countries/O have/O a/O definite/O Minister/O of/O Culture/O ,/O so-called/O ,/O which/O helps/O guide/O all/O cultural/O things/O ./O 
That/O we/O here/O in/O America/LOCATION do/O n't/O have/O such/O a/O thing/O ,/O and/O we/O should/O have/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O which/O is/O true/O ./O 
This/O much/O I/O still/O believe/O today/O ./O 
We/O should/O have/O something/O like/O that/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O there/O was/O an/O item/O in/O the/O paper/O recently/O ,/O if/O I/O can/O find/O it/O at/O the/O moment/O ,/O where/O such/O a/O proposition/O is/O being/O sponsored/O in/O Congress/ORGANIZATION today/O ./O 
It/O came/O out/O a/O week/O or/O two/O ago/O where/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION does/O need/O some/O form/O of/O help/O from/O the/O Government/O toward/O the/O arts/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O on/O principles/O like/O this/O ,/O which/O are/O basically/O sound/O and/O correct/O ,/O which/O is/O something/O we/O Americans/O should/O have/O ,/O it/O sounded/O very/O correct/O at/O the/O time/O especially/O ./O 
And/O the/O general/O approach/O at/O the/O time/O was/O ,/O we/O have/O to/O build/O some/O form/O of/O educational/O program/O to/O present/O these/O things/O to/O the/O American/O public/O ./O 
How/O are/O you/O going/O to/O present/O it/O to/O the/O American/O public/O ?/O 
You/O have/O your/O Musicians/O '/O Congress/ORGANIZATION and/O invite/O all/O the/O greatest/O musicians/O in/O America/LOCATION or/O the/O world/O to/O come/O here/O at/O a/O big/O symposium/O ,/O and/O show/O the/O facets/O of/O music/O ,/O the/O culture/O of/O music/O ,/O how/O it/O can/O help/O the/O American/O public/O in/O various/O ways/O and/O help/O the/O war/O effort/O ,/O or/O something/O else/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Everything/O was/O to/O help/O build/O the/O war/O effort/O ,/O naturally/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O distinguish/O between/O the/O aid/O and/O assistance/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O in/O such/O a/O program/O ,/O and/O direction/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O in/O such/O a/O program/O ?/O 
77436-56-pt/O ./O 
9/O --/O 2/O 3824/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O you/O were/O present/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O day/O before/O yesterday/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
We/O heard/O about/O a/O Government/O agency/O which/O certainly/O is/O not/O the/O sort/O of/O agency/O that/O any/O of/O us/O would/O want/O ./O 
It/O was/O the/O agency/O which/O directs/O the/O cultural/O art/O or/O the/O agencies/O which/O direct/O cultural/O art/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
They/O should/O n't/O direct/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O distinction/O should/O be/O made/O very/O clear/O that/O ,/O while/O some/O such/O program/O as/O the/O one/O you/O suggest/O might/O be/O very/O meritorious/O and/O undoubtedly/O would/O be/O ,/O we/O should/O be/O very/O careful/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O so/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
should/O help/O in/O other/O ways/O ./O 
They/O should/O not/O direct/O ;/O they/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O join/O the/O comment/O of/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON at/O that/O point/O ./O 
The/O testimony/O day/O before/O yesterday/O was/O not/O only/O that/O Russia/LOCATION had/O an/O agency/O but/O there/O was/O a/O state/O controlMr/O ./O 
GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
They/O sure/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O controlled/O the/O writing/O and/O publication/O of/O the/O music/O ./O 
And/O no/O music/O other/O than/O jazz/O could/O even/O be/O published/O with/O -/O out/O the/O consent/O of/O the/O Russian/LOCATION or/O the/O Soviet/O Government/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O whole/O purpose/O of/O the/O emphasis/O on/O music/O and/O art/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION was/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O interpreting/O the/O Soviet/O philosophy/O to/O the/O Russian/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O contrary/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O that/O destroys/O ,/O in/O my/O book/O ,/O individual/O initiative/O and/O independent/O respect/O for/O the/O individual/O ,/O and/O places/O it/O as/O a/O servant/O of/O the/O state/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O much/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Which/O is/O contrary/O to/O the/O American/O philosophy/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
When/O the/O Soviet/O Government/O began/O to/O slap/O the/O wrist/O of/O Shostakovich/PERSON and/O Prokofiev/PERSON and/O other/O great/O ,/O sincerely/O great/O composers/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O and/O chastised/O them/O for/O writing/O an/O unSoviet/O type/O of/O music/O ,/O music/O against/O the/O culture/O of/O the/O Soviet/O form/O of/O government/O ,/O this/O is/O going/O a/O little/O bit/O too/O far/O ./O 
And/O there/O have/O been/O dozens/O of/O instances/O and/O cases/O where/O Russians/O themselves/O have/O told/O the/O world/O they/O have/O chastised/O these/O various/O indi/O -/O viduals/O for/O writing/O music/O not/O acceptable/O to/O the/O people/O ./O 
What/O means/O ``/O acceptable/O to/O the/O people/O ''/O ?/O 
Whose/O opinion/O are/O they/O taking/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Whenever/O you/O get/O government/O into/O that/O field/O do/O n't/O you/O run/O the/O risk/O ,/O however/O ,/O of/O eventual/O control/O and/O domination/O Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O entirely/O possible/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O so/O sure/O that/O the/O Government/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O interesting/O itself/O ,/O even/O by/O way/O of/O grantsin-aid/O ,/O in/O the/O promulgation/O of/O the/O cultural/O society/O ./O 
We/O can/O do/O that/O with/O our/O free/O institutions/O ,/O and/O have/O done/O it/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O think/O government/O has/O any/O part/O in/O it/O ./O 
Those/O are/O my/O own/O feelings/O ,/O because/O it/O eventually/O leads/O to/O control/O and/O domination/O by/O government/O whether/O you/O like/O it/O or/O not/O as/O soon/O as/O you/O start/O putting/O money/O into/O those/O programs/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O it/O is/O possible/O ?/O 
For/O example/O ,/O the/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Labor/ORGANIZATION has/O helped/O without/O interfering/O with/O labor/O ./O 
In/O the/O same/O sense/O ,/O we/O could/O have/O a/O Department/O of/O Culture/O if/O it/O is/O correctly/O set/O up/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3825/O Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O too/O many/O departments/O and/O agencies/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
This/O may/O be/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O as/O indicated/O by/O several/O members/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O we/O heard/O extensive/O testimony/O here/O 2/O days/O ago/O ,/O and/O in/O quite/O some/O detail/O ,/O regarding/O the/O political/O uses/O that/O were/O made/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION of/O the/O various/O arts/O ,/O which/O included/O music/O ./O 
Now/O after/O you/O got/O into/O this/O organized/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION composed/O of/O musicians/O and/O the/O Musicians/O Congress-was/O that/O the/O name/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Musicians/O Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Committee/O was/O established/O ,/O did/O you/O learn/O of/O any/O -/O thing/O indicating/O an/O effort/O to/O use/O that/O organization/O in/O a/O political/O way/O or/O to/O influence/O its/O decisions/O in/O a/O political/O way/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O much/O so/O ./O 
If/O I/O may/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O elaborate/O on/O that/O and/O explain/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O for/O you/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
As/O the/O work/O began/O to/O organize/O for/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O to/O be/O held/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION in/ORGANIZATION Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles-UCLA-we/ORGANIZATION had/O a/O few/O meetings/O ,/O gatherings/O of/O members/O and/O nonmembers/O of/O the/O party/O ,/O to/O discuss/O as/O to/O how/O the/O congress/O should/O take/O place/O and/O the/O form/O it/O should/O follow/O ,/O who/O should/O be/O invited/O ,/O who/O should/O n't/O be/O invited/O ,/O what/O they/O should/O expect/O and/O what/O they/O should/O say/O ./O 
Now/O as/O the/O discussion/O would/O come/O along/O ,/O we/O would/O drop/O out/O certain/O names/O ./O 
They/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O How/O about/O so-and-so/O ,/O a/O great/O composer/O ./O ''/O 
And/O they/O could/O kick/O it/O around/O ./O 
And/O the/O first/O big/O fight/O that/O I/O had/O with/O the/O group/O was/O about/O the/O name/O of/O Rachmaninoff/PERSON ,/O Sergei/PERSON Rachmaninoff/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O just/O passed/O away/O in/O the/O summer/O of/O 1943/O or/O late/O fall/O ,/O who/O was/O one/O of/O the/O towering/O lights/O in/O music/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O great/O geniuses/O of/O our/O time/O ,/O unquestionably/O ./O 
I/O said/O we/O should/O have/O a/O man/O like/O him/O represented/O ,/O or/O at/O least/O some/O of/O his/O works/O should/O be/O played/O as/O representative/O of/O today/O 's/O great/O music/O because/O we/O do/O have/O great/O geniuses/O ./O 
We/O talked/O about/O Beethoven/PERSON ,/O Bach/PERSON ,/O Brahms/PERSON ./O 
But/O we/O have/O greats/O in/O our/O own/O time/O who/O in/O a/O period/O of/O history/O will/O take/O shape/O along/O with/O the/O greatest/O composers/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
The/O minute/O I/O mentioned/O the/O name/O Rachmaninoff/PERSON there/O was/O a/O big/O outburst/O and/O a/O shout/O :/O ``/O That/O dirty/O White/O Russian/O ?/O ''/O 
And/O this/O began/O a/O long/O series/O of/O discussions/O and/O doubletalk/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O So/O what/O ?/O 
White/O Russian/O ./O 
Obviously/O ,/O we/O all/O know/O this/O ./O 
But/O the/O man/O is/O still/O a/O great/O genius/O ,/O a/O great/O composer/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O big/O men/O of/O our/O time/O ./O 
What/O the/O heck/O has/O politics/O got/O to/O do/O with/O music/O ?/O 
Is/O this/O going/O to/O be/O a/O congress/O of/O politics/O or/O music/O ?/O 
Music/O comes/O first/O as/O far/O as/O I/O am/O concerned/O ./O ''/O 
And/O as/O time/O subsequently/O proved/O ,/O in/O most/O of/O these/O cases/O ,/O members/O of/O Communist/O beliefs/O ,/O intense/O beliefs-they/O carried/O the/O political/O beliefs/O to/O a/O greater/O extent/O than/O the/O musical/O beliefs/O ./O 
They/O loved/O politics/O more/O than/O music/O ./O 
And/O ,/O once/O this/O picture/O began/O to/O become/O clear/O to/O me/O ,/O then/O I/O knew/O there/O was/O something/O wrong/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O to/O get/O out/O and/O get/O out/O fast/O ./O 
There/O were/O other/O names/O of/O individuals/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O the/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION area-certain/O composers/O who/O were/O very/O small/O ,/O very/O petty/O ,/O veryI/O should/O n't/O say/O stupid/O because/O they/O might/O be/O intelligent/O people/O ,/O but/O the/O music/O they/O write/O is/O very/O inferior/O and/O very/O low/O grade/O ./O 
3826/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O The/O orchestrations/O on/O certain/O occasions/O ,/O I/O know/O personally/O ,/O as/O I/O have/O studied/O some/O of/O the/O scores/O ,/O a/O third-grade/O orchestra/O student/O would/O be/O ashamed/O to/O orchestrate/O what/O these/O big/O men/O were/O doing/O ./O 
It/O was/O ridiculous/O ./O 
These/O men/O were/O being/O pushed/O to/O the/O front/O ./O 
This/O one/O should/O lead/O this/O symposium/O ;/O this/O one/O should/O definitely/O be/O in/O charge/O of/O American/O folk/O music/O ;/O this/O man/O was/O ,/O in/O my/O opinion/O ,/O a/O very/O inferior/O composer/O ,/O a/O very/O small-time/O situation/O ./O 
And/O it/O is/O very/O unfortunate/O that/O his/O work/O should/O be/O pushed/O so/O to/O the/O fore/O ,/O that/O the/O general/O American/LOCATION public/O should/O hear/O his/O things/O rather/O than/O other/O greater/O men/O of/O more/O significance/O and/O importance/O ./O 
Slowly/O ,/O as/O the/O congress/ORGANIZATION committee/ORGANIZATION began/O to/O take/O shape/O and/O more/O and/O more/O of/O these/O names/O were/O dropped/O ,/O and/O more/O of/O the/O greater/O men/O who/O might/O be/O White/O Russians/O or/O unsympathetic/O to/O liberal/O causes/O were/O dropped/O out/O and/O eliminated/O ,/O the/O whole/O thing/O began/O to/O take/O a/O definite/O political/O shape/O ./O 
We/O were/O saying/O goodby/O ,/O good/O luck/O ,/O and/O thank/O you/O ,/O and/O I/O backed/O out/O in/O a/O hurry/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENXER/PERSON ./O 
You/O backed/O out/O of/O the/O congress/O ./O 
Did/O you/O also/O back/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
The/O party/O ,/O simultaneously/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O joint/O venture/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O hold/O a/O position/O of/O any/O kind/O in/O the/O Musicians/O Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O had/O been/O appointed/O secretary/O and/O treasurer/O of/O the/O original/O congress/O committee/O ./O 
And/O I/O was/O to/O help/O raise/O funds/O and/O collect/O the/O money/O and/O hang/O on/O to/O the/O money/O and/O protect/O it/O ./O 
Apparently/O they/O felt/O I/O was/O the/O only/O honest/O fellow/O in/O the/O bunch/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O why/O ./O 
I/O had/O to/O get/O stationery/O printed/O ,/O and/O we/O just/O had/O enough/O money/O for/O 1/O ream/O of/O paper/O which/O at/O that/O time/O cost/O around/O $/O 7/O ./O 
We/O had/O $/O 10/O in/O the/O treasury/O ./O 
So/O we/O had/O 1/O ream/O of/O stationery/O printed/O up/O ,/O which/O was/O this/O ,/O which/O fortunately/O we/O have/O maintained/O the/O balance/O of/O the/O ream/O ./O 
And/O on/O the/O ream/O of/O stationery/O my/O name/O is/O listed/O as/O secretary-treasurer/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O see/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O offer/O that/O letterhead/O in/O evidence/O ,/O and/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O marked/O ``/O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON Exhibit/O No./O 1/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O so/O ordered/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O testimony/O is/O going/O to/O develop/O ,/O but/O I/O would/O add/O to/O the/O insertion/O the/O stipulation/O that/O the/O mere/O appearance/O of/O a/O name/O on/O the/O letterhead/O does/O not/O connote/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O sympathy/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O GL.SSEm/O :/O ./O 
Definitely/O not/O ./O 
That/O is/O very/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
With/O that/O understanding/O ,/O the/O exhibit/O will/O be/O admitted/O into/O evidence/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O let/O us/O go/O back/O a/O little/O further/O ./O 
You/O have/O told/O us/O that/O ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O your/O associations/O and/O discussion/O of/O matters/O in/O which/O you/O were/O interested/O ,/O you/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O anything/O more/O in/O detail/O as/O to/O how/O you/O actually/O became/O a/O member/O ?/O 
That/O is/O ,/O who/O brought/O you/O in/O and/O whether/O you/O signed/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION cards/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3827/O GLASSES/O EXHIBIT/O No./O 1/O MUSICIANS/O CONGRESS/O 1655/O CHEROKEESTREET/O ,/O ROOM/O 301/O COMMITTEE/O HOLLYWOOD/O 28/O ,/O CALIFORNIA/LOCATION HEMPSTEAD3501/O ovlD/O MIU/O ,/O CL/O GILKulIK/O MUSICIANS/O CONGRESS/O COMMITTEE/O ./O 
LLHo/O pRESENTS/O OO/O HU/O 0000E00FS/O JN/O GREN/ORGANIZATION o/O Y/O S/O ,/O ''/O vu/O Classical/O and/O Swing/O -/O -/O Buffet/O Dinner/O WALTER/O FCKO/O ABEL/O ,/O Ma/PERSON ,/O r/O f/O Co/O ~/O imu/O cVIN/O cum/O The/O First/O of/O a/O Series/O oF/O Outstanding/O MusicalEvents/O n/O 1010/O Summit/O Drive/O Sat./O ,/O Dec./O ./O 
II/O ,/O 1943/O a/O $/O 200/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Or/O whether/O you/O paid/O dues/O and/O all/O matters/O of/O such/O character/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O time/O we/O were/O spending/O many/O evenings/O with/O free/O dinners-which/O we/O needed/O badly/O because/O we/O were/O broke-at/O the/O home/O of/O Mr./O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON ./O 
It/O came/O to/O the/O point/O where/O he/O finally/O said/O ,/O ``/O Look/O ./O 
You/O kids/O have/O got/O ./O 
to/O get/O in/O ./O 
This/O is/O silly/O ./O 
You/O are/O bright/O ,/O you/O are/O intelligent/O ./O 
You/O have/O got/O to/O join/O this/O thing/O and/O help/O establish/O this/O cause/O ,/O and/O help/O work/O for/O the/O war/O ./O ''/O 
Everything/O was/O the/O war-second/O front/O ,/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O help/O culture/O ;/O all/O the/O various/O double-talk/O phrases/O which/O were/O coming/O through/O ./O 
They/O had/O been/O so/O kind/O to/O us/O and/O so/O sweet/O we/O just/O felt/O so/O grateful/O ./O 
And/O when/O they/O kept/O saying/O ``/O You/O have/O got/O to/O sign/O ,/O ''/O they/O finally/O shoved/O a/O membership/O card/O in/O my/O wife/O 's/O hand/O and/O myself/O ,/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Now/O ,/O sign/O ,/O and/O no/O more/O backing/O out/O ./O 
Come/O on/O ./O 
Do/O it/O right/O now/O ./O ''/O 
3828/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O We/O took/O the/O cards/O and/O stood/O up/O against/O the/O wall/O ,/O and/O ,/O with/O a/O pen/O ,/O started/O to/O sign/O ./O 
I/O told/O my/O wife/O ,/O ``/O Wait/O a/O moment/O ./O 
One/O second/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O sign/O with/O your/O actual/O handwriting/O ./O 
I/O still/O do/O n't/O trust/O this/O thing/O ./O 
There/O 's/O something/O fishy/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O in/O my/O heart/O there/O 's/O something/O wrong/O ./O 
Put/O the/O pen/O in/O your/O left/O hand/O and/O write/O it/O backward/O so/O maybe/O ,/O in/O the/O event/O there/O may/O be/O trouble/O ,/O they/O could/O not/O trace/O it/O to/O me/O ,/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O in/O this/O ./O 
We/O are/O n't/O doing/O a/O wrong/O thing/O ,/O but/O we/O will/O go/O along/O with/O it/O for/O the/O ride/O ./O 
There/O is/O nothing/O to/O lose/O ./O 
We/O are/O n't/O doing/O anything/O wrong/O ./O 
We/O are/O n't/O doing/O any/O criminal/O acts/O ./O 
We/O do/O n't/O do/O any/O espionage/O ./O 
We/O would/O n't/O hold/O up/O a/O bank/O or/O kill/O anyone/O ./O 
We/O are/O doing/O no/O wrong/O as/O wrong/O goes/O ./O 
We/O are/O simply/O signing/O a/O piece/O of/O paper/O which/O means/O nothing/O ./O ''/O 
We/O signed/O the/O membership/O cards/O backward/O with/O our/O left/O hands/O ,/O and/O Mr./O Silver/PERSON and/O Louise-Dr/O ./O 
Light-raised/O holy/O heck/O with/O us/O ./O 
They/O screamed/O ./O 
But/O we/O stuck/O to/O our/O guns/O ./O 
We/O said/O ,/O ``/O No/O ,/O if/O you/O want/O it/O ,/O take/O it/O this/O way/O ./O 
That/O is/O good/O enough/O for/O you/O ./O ''/O 
And/O they/O finally/O accepted/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O soon/O afterward/O we/O were/O contacted/O to/O go/O to/O a/O meeting/O ,/O a/O membership/O drive/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O a/O membership/O drive/O ,/O but/O sort/O of/O a/O welcoming-to-the-Communist-Party/O type/O of/O thing/O ./O 
And/O after/O this/O meeting/O we/O had/O 3/O or/O 4/O ,/O 4/O or/O 5/O actual/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O 2/O of/O which/O were/O in/O our/O own/O home/O ./O 
The/O reason/O we/O had/O to/O have/O it/O in/O our/O own/O home/O was/O very/O simple/O ./O 
My/O little/O girl/O had/O just/O been/O born/O ,/O January/O 23/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O and/O was/O still/O a/O little/O infant/O ,/O 6/O ,/O 7/O ,/O 8/O months/O old/O ,/O and/O my/O wife/O was/O slightly/O nervous/O and/O high/O strung/O and/O refused/O pointblank/O to/O have/O babysitters/O ./O 
This/O was/O out/O of/O the/O question/O ./O 
Have/O a/O stranger/O watch/O our/O baby/O ?/O 
Nonsense/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O interrupt/O you/O a/O moment/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O my/O purpose/O to/O ask/O you/O anything/O regarding/O your/O wife/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O not/O our/O practice/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
However/O ,/O if/O the/O witness/O desires/O to/O mention/O his/O wife/O in/O order/O that/O it/O may/O be/O known/O what/O his/O wife/O 's/O position/O is/O ,/O it/O is/O all/O right/O for/O you/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O request/O the/O presence/O of/O my/O wife/O to/O come/O on/O the/O stand/O along/O with/O me/O and/O appear/O jointly/O ?/O 
Is/O this/O possible/O ,/O if/O you/O desire/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O can/O call/O her/O as/O soon/O as/O you/O complete/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
1/O interrupted/O you/O ./O 
You/O had/O come/O to/O the/O point/O where/O you/O signed/O your/O membership/O card/O and/O were/O asked/O to/O come/O to/O a/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSES/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
We/O went/O up/O to/O a/O home/O on/O Sunset/O Plaza/O Drive/O ./O 
Whose/O home/O I/O was/O n't/O aware/O of/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O and/O never/O have/O been/O ./O 
But/O when/O we/O came/O to/O this/O big/O ,/O very/O fine/O home/O ,/O there/O were/O about/O 40/O or/O 50/O people/O sitting/O around/O in/O the/O living/O room/O ./O 
And/O after/O a/O few/O minutes/O a/O gentleman/O came/O to/O the/O front/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Ladies/O and/O gentlemen/O ,/O welcome/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
And/O we/O said/O ,/O ``/O Welcome/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O thank/O you/O ./O ''/O 
Very/O friendly/O ,/O very/O jovial/O ,/O a/O lot/O of/O fun/O ,/O and/O all/O total/O strangers/O to/O me/O ./O 
We/O did/O n't/O know/O anyone/O there/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
A/O gentleman/O began/O to/O speak/O ,/O Mr./O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ,/O whose/O name/O has/O come/O up/O ,/O we/O know/O ,/O at/O various/O times/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O very/O bright/O man/O ,/O a/O very/O intelligent/O man/O ./O 
But/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O am/O concerned/O ,/O his/O political/O thinking/O was/O way/O off/O the/O beam/O ,/O completely/O confused/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3829/O He/O began/O to/O speak/O for/O an/O hour/O or/O two-I/O forget/O how/O long-just/O going/O along/O ,/O explaining/O the/O purposes/O and/O ideals/O and/O motives/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O America/LOCATION ,/O how/O they/O hoped/O to/O bring/O about/O certain/O changes/O in/O the/O Government/O through/O normal/O legal/O processes/O ,/O through/O the/O ballot/O ,/O through/O the/O vote/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O ,/O by/O the/O wishes/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION people/O and/O a/O majority/O ,/O following/O standard/O American/O basic/O procedure/O straight/O down/O the/O line/O ./O 
And/O he/O talked/O and/O talked/O and/O talked/O ./O 
And/O at/O times/O he/O would/O go/O off/O on/O tangents/O ,/O which/O at/O times/O sounded/O like/O double/O talk/O ./O 
And/O toward/O the/O end/O he/O kept/O building/O up/O toward/O the/O fact/O that/O we/O have/O to/O do/O this/O through/O normal/O legal/O processes/O ,/O due/O process/O of/O law/O ./O 
He/O pounded/O his/O fist/O and/O would/O get/O very/O dynamic/O because/O he/O is/O a/O very/O dynamic/O man/O ,/O and/O kept/O stressing/O the/O fact/O that/O through/O the/O American/O system/O way/O of/O law/O we/O shall/O accomplish/O these/O purposes/O ./O 
Now/O when/O he/O got/O through/O ,/O my/O wife/O ,/O who/O is/O a/O very/O ,/O very/O spunky/O little/O woman/O ,/O raised/O her/O hand/O to/O ask/O a/O question/O ./O 
And/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O ''/O and/O pointed/O to/O her/O ./O 
And/O she/O said/O ,/O ``/O Mr./O Lawson/PERSON ,/O what/O is/O the/O ultimate/O goal/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O ''/O 
And/O he/O immediately/O went/O into/O a/O long/O series/O of/O double/O talk/O ,/O divergence/O ,/O tangents/O ,/O all/O over/O the/O place/O ./O 
He/O did/O n't/O answer/O her/O question/O one/O iota/O ./O 
When/O he/O finally/O got/O through/O with/O the/O story/O ,/O ``/O But/O ,/O ''/O she/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O still/O ask/O the/O same/O question/O ./O 
What/O is/O the/O ultimate/O goal/O ?/O 
What/O happens/O if/O we/O ca/O n't/O accomplish/O this/O through/O legal/O process/O ,/O through/O the/O ballot/O box/O ?/O ''/O 
Again/O he/O went/O off/O on/O a/O long-winded/O story/O ,/O evading/O the/O issue/O ./O 
Three/O or/O four/O times/O she/O kept/O after/O him/O ./O 
And/O I/O almost/O started/O to/O poke/O her/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O Hey/O ,/O cut/O it/O out/O ./O ''/O 
I/O did/O n't/O realize/O what/O she/O was/O after/O ./O 
She/O kept/O needling/O him/O ./O 
Not/O needling/O ,/O but/O insisting/O he/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O at/O least/O answer/O the/O simple/O question/O :/O What/O is/O the/O ultimate/O goal/O ?/O 
And/O he/O finally/O got/O so/O angry/O ,/O and/O his/O face/O flushed/O up-I/O should/O n't/O use/O the/O word/O ``/O red/O ./O ''/O 
But/O his/O face/O came/O red/O ,/O and/O he/O just/O blurted/O out/O But/O strong/O ./O 
with/O vehemence/O ,/O ``/O Revolution/O ./O ''/O 
My/O wife/O said/O ,/O ``/O That/O does/O it/O ./O ''/O 
He/O forgot/O himself/O for/O a/O moment/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O forgot/O himself/O ./O 
I/O assume/O that/O because/O there/O was/O a/O general/O murmur/O of/O dissatisfaction/O in/O the/O group/O ./O 
They/O felt/O this/O was/O n't/O necessary/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Murmur/O of/O dissatisfaction/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Dissatisfactsion/O ./O 
But/O we/O knew/O right/O then/O and/O there/O ,/O oh/O ,/O oh/O ,/O something/O is/O wrong/O ./O 
This/O is/O definitely/O silly/O ,/O ridiculous/O ,/O because/O to/O follow/O this/O type/O of/O thinking/O requires/O an/O individual/O that/O has/O certain/O basic/O elements/O of/O conceit/O ,/O of/O vanity/O and/O ego/O where/O they/O think/O that/O what/O they/O feel/O is/O so/O correct/O that/O they/O and/O they/O alone/O have/O the/O true/O message/O for/O the/O world/O ./O 
These/O people/O are/O so/O vain/O in/O a/O small/O ,/O petty/O way/O that/O ,/O once/O they/O get/O the/O idea/O of/O communism/O or/O socialism/O implanted/O in/O their/O brain/O ,/O they/O feel/O this/O is/O the/O only/O way/O that/O can/O help/O humanity/O go/O forward/O ./O 
They/O become/O so/O stodgy/O and/O so/O stupid/O in/O their/O steadfastness/O and/O so/O blindthey/O can/O not/O see/O other/O ways/O and/O they/O refuse/O to/O accept/O other/O ways/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
3830/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
TO/O me/O this/O is/O so/O ridiculous/O ,/O so/O foolish/O ./O 
They/O just/O can/O not/O comprehend/O how/O big/O the/O world/O is/O ,/O how/O much/O more/O there/O is/O to/O life/O and/O living/O than/O just/O their/O one/O little/O idea/O ./O 
And/O once/O we/O began/O to/O feel/O these/O things/O ,/O this/O trend/O ,/O we/O gradually/O backed/O off/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O What/O have/O we/O done/O now/O ?/O ''/O 
When/O it/O finally/O came/O to/O the/O breaking/O point/O we/O said/O ,/O ``/O We/O 'll/O get/O out/O and/O get/O out/O fast/O ./O 
This/O is/O too/O much/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O who/O were/O the/O leaders/O of/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O That/O is/O ,/O the/O persons/O you/O found/O to/O be/O the/O leaders/O after/O you/O joined/O the/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSES/O ./O 
There/O was/O one/O gentleman/O whom/O I/O always/O had/O a/O sort/O of/O secret/O fascination/O for-put/O it/O that/O way/O ;/O his/O intelligence/O ,/O a/O very/O lucid/O man/O ,/O a/O very/O fine/O brain/O ./O 
His/O name/O was/O Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON ./O 
This/O man/O steered/O ,/O ran/O ,/O did/O everything/O ./O 
He/O was/O just/O general/O factotum/O as/O far/O as/O I/O could/O tell/O ./O 
He/O was/O always/O present/O at/O our/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O gathered/O he/O was/O present/O at/O all/O the/O other/O meetings/O ./O 
He/O must/O have/O had/O three/O bicycles/O to/O run/O all/O over/O the/O town/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDEn/PERSON ./O 
Are/O your/O references/O to/O these/O people/O in/O the/O year/O 1943/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
1943/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Only/O 1943/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O any/O persons/O who/O held/O or/O seemed/O to/O hold/O positions/O in/O that/O organization/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O person/O who/O would/O collect/O the/O dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
As/O to/O officials/O ,/O our/O particular/O group/O was/O very/O loosely/O strung/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O definite/O ,/O intense/O type/O of/O job/O ./O 
But/O various/O people/O would/O be/O appointed/O at/O various/O times/O to/O do/O a/O certain/O type/O of/O thing-literary/O director/O ,/O to/O read/O some/O current/O book/O and/O discuss/O it/O at/O meetings/O and/O try/O to/O make/O us/O all/O buy/O the/O book/O ,/O which/O is/O one/O of/O the/O gimmicks/O ,/O too/O ,/O to/O help/O raise/O money/O ./O 
The/O literary/O director/O at/O one/O time/O ,/O when/O we/O were/O at/O the/O party/O in/O 1943/O ,/O was/O a/O fellow/O named/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ./O 
This/O I/O recall/O vividly/O because/O he/O gave/O a/O long/O dissertation/O on/O one/O of/O the/O books/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O and/O discussion/O groups/O were/O held/O on/O that/O particular/O subject/O ./O 
I/O think/O he/O was/O also/O the/O treasurer/O of/O our/O group/O at/O one/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O R-o-t-h/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
R-o-t-h/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
A/O very/O fine/O violinist/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O theMr/O ./O 
MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Order/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O names/O of/O any/O other/O members/O of/O that/O group/O you/O can/O now/O recall/O ?/O 
Before/O doing/O that/O I/O want/O you/O to/O know/O of/O your/O own/O personal/O knowledge/O that/O they/O were/O members/O of/O this/O particular/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O if/O you/O know/O they/O were/O members/O through/O your/O personal/O knowledge/O ,/O then/O we/O want/O that/O information/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
These/O are/O the/O only/O names/O I/O can/O actually/O recall/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O a/O lot/O of/O soul/O searching/O ./O 
At/O times/O certain/O names-you/O think/O of/O a/O nerson/O 's/O face/O ./O 
Going/O back/O 13/O years/O ,/O it/O is/O n't/O easy/O to/O remember/O who/O is/O who/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3831/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O going/O to/O identify/O these/O people/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/O organization/O or/O as/O members/O of/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION group/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
These/O individuals/O here/O I/O can/O recall/O definitely/O as/O having/O come/O to/O my/O home/O at/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O Esther/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON ,/O Carla/PERSON Altman/PERSON ,/O A-l-t-m-a-n/O ,/O Herb/PERSON Offner/PERSON ,/O O-f-f-n-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEE/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Herb/O or/O Herbert/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O GLAssER/PERSON ./O 
And/O Herb/PERSON ,/O H-e-r-b/O ,/O Lessner/PERSON ,/O L-e-s-s-n-e-r/O ./O 
Cyril/PERSON Towbin/PERSON ,/O C-y-r-i-1/O T-o-w-b-i-n/O ./O 
Sol/PERSON Kaplan/PERSON ,/O S-o-1/O K-a-p-1-a-n/O ./O 
Martha/PERSON Goldberg/PERSON ,/O Anita/PERSON Short/PERSON ,/O Kathryn/PERSON Becker/PERSON and/O Carroll/PERSON Hollister/PERSON ,/O H-o-l-l-i-s-te-r/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O say/O Becker/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Becker/PERSON ,/O B-e-c-k-e-r/O ./O 
These/O are/O the/O only/O people/O whom/O I/O definitely/O know/O had/O been/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O interrupt/O you/O at/O this/O pointThose/O were/O the/O meetings/O you/O say/O the/O Communist/O group/O held/O in/O your/O home/O ./O 
Were/O those/O meetings/O limited/O ,/O within/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O to/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
The/O two/O meetings/O that/O we/O had/O at/O our/O home/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O were/O only/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Limited/O to/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
And/O I/O might/O add/O to/O this/O there/O was/O nothing/O surreptitious/O ,/O nothing/O secret/O ,/O nothing/O cloak-and-dagger/O type/O of/O thing/O at/O all/O ./O 
The/O windows/O were/O wide/O open/O ./O 
We/O had/O the/O bakery/O come/O to/O the/O front/O door/O and/O deliver/O all/O the/O bakery/O goods/O for/O refreshments/O later/O ./O 
It/O was/O all/O very/O clean/O ,/O very/O official/O ,/O very/O normal/O ,/O very/O decent/O ;/O nothing/O wrong/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
We/O paid/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O when/O I/O could/O afford/O it/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O did/O you/O pay/O them/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKsON/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
In/O what/O years/O were/O these/O meetings/O conducted/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
1943/O ,/O between/O August/O or/O September/O and/O about/O December/O ./O 
The/O reason/O I/O know/O that/O ,/O in/O December/O we/O began/O to/O get/O out/O and/O get/O out/O fast/O ,/O was/O the/O fact/O that/O on/O December/O 11/O you/O will/O find/O a/O little/O card/O attached/O to/O the/O Musicians/O Congress/O letterhead/O ./O 
We/O threw/O our/O first/O party/O to/O raise/O funds/O for/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O question/O was/O how/O could/O we/O raise/O funds/O and/O get/O money/O to/O get/O the/O show/O on/O the/O road/O for/O the/O congress/O ./O 
So/O the/O thought/O was/O expressed/O we/O should/O throw/O a/O big/O party/O ,/O serve/O refreshments/O and/O have/O a/O lot/O of/O good/O entertainment/O and/O charge/O admission/O ,/O and/O raise/O money/O by/O passing/O the/O hat/O ./O 
So/O all/O the/O girls/O got/O together/O and/O cooked/O all/O the/O food/O ,/O a/O bunch/O of/O turkeys/O ,/O potato/O salad-the/O usual/O things/O for/O a/O big/O spread/O ./O 
Entertainers/O were/O invited/O ,/O and/O a/O big/O party/O was/O thrown/O at/O a/O home/O which/O is/O listed/O on/O the/O card/O ,/O the/O address/O there/O ,/O on/O December/O 11/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
We/O had/O very/O many/O big/O celebrities/O of/O the/O motion/O picture/O world/O who/O had/O nothing/O to/O do/O with/O those/O elements/O at/O all/O ,/O because/O this/O was/O now/O 77436-56-pt/O ./O 
9-3/O 3832/O AREA/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O completely/O the/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O very/O cultural/O institution/O on/O the/O surface/O ,/O and/O many/O people/O were/O drawn/O in/O without/O knowing/O or/O suspecting/O what/O might/O have/O been/O steering/O behind/O the/O scenes/O ./O 
We/O had/O a/O very/O successful/O party/O and/O raised/O a/O few/O hundred/O dollars/O ./O 
I/O was/O at/O the/O door/O collecting/O tickets/O and/O collecting/O admissions/O ./O 
My/O wife/O was/O helping/O serve/O the/O food/O and/O cooked/O two/O of/O the/O turkeys/O ./O 
And/O some/O of/O the/O girls/O from/O our/O party/O group/O cooked/O the/O other/O turkeys/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O very/O successful/O social/O affair/O ./O 
Put/O it/O that/O way/O ./O 
But/O various/O things/O were/O happening/O at/O this/O time/O before/O and/O during/O the/O party/O itself/O ,/O this/O party/O to/O raise/O the/O funds/O ,/O which/O began/O to/O give/O us/O various/O insights/O into/O these/O people/O 's/O character/O ,/O where/O they/O were/O so/O petty/O in/O various/O ways/O ./O 
We/O felt/O these/O ca/O n't/O be/O Communists/O ./O 
These/O people/O talk/O of/O working/O for/O the/O world/O ,/O for/O humanity/O ,/O to/O help/O humanity/O advance/O and/O go/O forward/O ./O 
And/O all/O this/O yak/O ,/O yak/O ,/O yak/O about/O humanity/O :/O ``/O We/O love/O humanity/O ./O ''/O 
And/O they/O were/O doing/O so/O many/O little/O petty/O things/O which/O did/O n't/O help/O humanity/O ,/O but/O showed/O how/O selfish/O they/O were/O ,/O how/O petty/O they/O were/O in/O their/O thinking/O and/O their/O living/O ./O 
And/O these/O two/O things/O are/O so/O diverse/O ./O 
How/O can/O we/O be/O petty/O and/O small/O and/O think/O of/O yourself/O in/O a/O selfish/O way/O and/O still/O think/O of/O humanity/O and/O work/O for/O humanity/O ?/O 
To/O me/O this/O is/O impossible/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O withdrew/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O you/O withdrew/O as/O financial/O secretary/O of/O the/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O become/O affiliated/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O any/O later/O date/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSES/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O your/O severance/O of/O ties/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION then/O was/O complete/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Complete/O and/O total/O ./O 
We/O stayed/O away/O from/O the/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION like/O a/O plague/O ./O 
We/O just/O went/O to/O one/O affair/O ,/O which/O was/O based/O on/O motion/O picture/O music/O ./O 
We/O are/O sorry/O we/O went/O ./O 
We/O completely/O avoided/O the/O entire/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O wanted/O no/O part/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Since/O that/O time/O have/O you/O had/O any/O credits/O in/O your/O profession/O ,/O or/O works/O that/O had/O any/O special/O standing/O as/O being/O antiCommunist/O in/O character/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O have/O ,/O very/O fortunately/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O are/O they/O ?/O 
years/O I/O have/O composed/O ,/O orchesMr/O ./O 
GIASSE/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O in/O the/O last/O 81\/2/O trated/O ,/O and/O conducted/O music/O for/O over/O 85/O motion-picture/O films/O ,/O and/O a/O few/O of/O these/O things/O including/O various/O types/O of/O films/O would/O be/O Top/O of/O the/O World/O ,/O I/O Shot/O Jesse/PERSON James/PERSON ,/O Geisha/O Girl/O ,/O Tokyo/LOCATION File/O 212/O ,/O Captain/O John/PERSON Smith/PERSON and/O Pocahontas/PERSON ,/O Huk/O ,/O H-u-k/O ,/O Paris/LOCATION Models/O ,/O Invasion/O USA/LOCATION ,/O Unmie-a/O Japanese/O word/O that/O means/O faith/O ./O 
Most/O of/O these/O pictures/O ,/O Tokyo/LOCATION File/O 212/O ,/O Invasion/LOCATION USA/LOCATION ,/O and/O Huk/O ,/O which/O I/O just/O completed/O 2/O months/O ago/O ,/O are/O very/O strong/O ,/O very/O dynamic/O anti-Communist/O pictures/O ./O 
Invasion/O USA/LOCATION was/O a/O story/O of/O the/O supposed/O future/O enemy/O invading/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O and/O how/O they/O could/O do/O it/O and/O what/O would/O happen/O if/O they/O did/O it/O ./O 
They/O could/O n't/O mention/O any/O definite/O country/O ./O 
We/O were/O n't/O concerned/O with/O getting/O international/O politics/O involved/O ./O 
But/O the/O idea/O was/O clearly/O brought/O to/O us/O as/O to/O what/O could/O happen/O in/O such/O an/O event/O ./O 
Tokyo/LOCATION File/O was/O made/O completely/O in/O the/O Orient/O ,/O in/O Tokyo/LOCATION ,/O and/O showed/O how/O some/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O methods/O operate/O ,/O what/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3833/O they/O have/O done/O in/O various/O ways/O ,/O and/O shows/O their/O machinations/O ,/O how/O they/O can/O accomplish/O certain/O purposes/O and/O how/O it/O was/O stopped/O by/O the/O Japanese/O Government/O with/O the/O help/O of/O the/O American/O Government/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O General/O MacArthur/PERSON was/O still/O in/O Tokyo/LOCATION ./O 
And/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O all/O of/O us/O who/O worked/O in/O the/O production/O ,/O had/O to/O be/O cleared/O by/O the/O general/O ,/O I/O was/O told/O later/O ,/O subsequently/O ./O 
Huk/O was/O a/O story/O of/O the/O Communist/O uprising/O in/O the/O Philippine/LOCATION Islands/LOCATION 5/O years/O ago/O ,/O and/O the/O damage/O it/O made/O and/O how/O it/O was/O stopped/O eventually/O by/O Magsaysay/PERSON ,/O the/O President/O of/O the/O Philippine/LOCATION Islands/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O effort/O made/O at/O any/O later/O date/O to/O get/O you/O back/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O so/O for/O one/O reason/O ./O 
We/O made/O it/O very/O clear/O and/O very/O self-evident/O we/O wanted/O no/O part/O of/O them/O ./O 
And/O I/O feel/O sure/O in/O my/O heart/O that/O we/O were/O the/O dirtiest/O buch/O of/O bums/O they/O ever/O recruited/O ./O 
They/O would/O n't/O want/O any/O part/O of/O us/O either/O ./O 
So/O it/O is/O mutual/O ,/O if/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O spoken/O with/O the/O witness/O ,/O nor/O heard/O him/O say/O anything/O until/O this/O hour/O ./O 
But/O you/O may/O not/O know/O ,/O Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O that/O this/O committee/O is/O here/O under/O what/O is/O known/O as/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ,/O passed/O in/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O delegating/O the/O members/O of/O this/O committee/O to/O investigate/O the/O extent/O of/O subversive/O activities/O and/O propaganda/O in/O our/O country/O whether/O it/O originates/O within/O our/O country/O or/O some/O foreign/O country/O ,/O and/O then/O to/O report/O what/O we/O find/O ,/O with/O our/O recommendations/O ,/O back/O to/O Congress/ORGANIZATION from/O time/O to/O time/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O type/O of/O an/O investigation/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O purpose/O of/O subpenaing/O you/O ,/O was/O not/O only/O to/O get/O the/O facts/O which/O you/O have/O given/O us/O ,/O but/O to/O see/O if/O there/O is/O a/O possibility/O of/O veering/O those/O facts/O toward/O improving/O ,/O modifying/O ,/O or/O amending/O legislation/O dealing/O with/O subversive/O activities/O in/O our/O country/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DosLE/O ./O 
The/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION has/O held/O ,/O and/O in/O commonsense/O ,/O that/O you/O ca/O n't/O legislate/O unless/O you/O know/O the/O facts/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
True/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O most/O recent/O case/O so/O declaring/O was/O the/O case/O of/O Quinn/PERSON ,/O which/O has/O been/O quoted/O by/O those/O who/O oppose/O this/O committee/O ./O 
It/O is/O true/O ,/O is/O it/O not/O ,/O that/O I/O have/O never/O spoken/O with/O you/O in/O your/O life/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O '/O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
So/O I/O have/O no/O idea/O what/O your/O answer/O is/O going/O to/O be/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O are/O at/O all/O familiar/O with/O the/O field/O of/O legislation/O as/O it/O is/O at/O present/O in/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Vaguely/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O have/O you/O given/O it/O any/O thought/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Which/O you/O can/O give/O us/O the/O benefit/O of/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
What/O I/O think/O you/O are/O driving/O at/O ,/O sir/O ,/O is/O if/O I/O have/O any/O ideas/O or/O thoughts/O that/O might/O help/O you/O as/O a/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O what/O I/O am/O saying/O to/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O American/O public/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O any/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSES/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
3834/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O your/O ideas/O or/O thoughts/O because/O we/O are/O making/O a/O study/O of/O that/O very/O subject/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O you/O should/O almost/O take/O a/O page/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/O book/O and/O throw/O it/O right/O back/O at/O them/O ./O 
It/O is/O very/O effective/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Throw/O what/O back/O at/O them/O and/O how/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
From/O an/O educational/O committee/O ./O 
What/O I/O have/O learned/O in/O the/O last/O month/O since/O I/O was/O subpenaed/O ,/O I/O have/O had/O a/O tremendous/O education/O and/O very/O enlightening/O ./O 
I/O have/O assembled/O all/O these/O things/O that/O have/O happened/O to/O us/O in/O the/O last/O month/O ,/O and/O it/O makes/O sense/O in/O one/O way/O ./O 
Many/O people/O have/O called/O us/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Gee/O ,/O Albert/PERSON ,/O I/O 'm/O so/O sorry/O for/O you/O ./O 
I/O 'm/O so/O sorry/O you/O have/O been/O called/O up/O ./O 
Gee/O whiz/O ,/O is/O n't/O it/O terrible/O ?/O ''/O 
I/O come/O back/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O No/O ./O 
This/O is/O wonderful/O ./O 
What/O is/O wrong/O ?/O 
What/O have/O I/O done/O that/O is/O so/O wrong/O ?/O 
I/O did/O n't/O kill/O anyone/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O rob/O a/O bank/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O do/O anything/O against/O my/O country/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O nothing/O criminal/O ./O 
I/O simply/O joined/O a/O rotten/O little/O Communist/O Party/O one/O time/O ,/O and/O got/O out/O fast/O ./O 
Big/O deal/O ./O 
What/O have/O I/O done/O that/O is/O so/O terrible/O ?/O 
Nothing/O ./O 
At/O the/O time/O I/O went/O in/O ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O not/O a/O bad/O thing/O ./O ''/O 
Now/O the/O fact/O that/O this/O is/O being/O cleared/O up/O ,/O and/O my/O name/O and/O reputation/O are/O being/O cleared/O up/O once/O and/O for/O all/O ,/O where/O there/O can/O be/O no/O suspicion/O as/O to/O where/O I/O stand/O and/O how/O I/O feel/O ,/O this/O is/O a/O good/O thing/O ;/O not/O a/O bad/O thing/O ./O 
I/O am/O darn/O glad/O the/O committee/O has/O called/O me/O in/O ./O 
I/O have/O had/O a/O chance/O to/O tell/O the/O whole/O American/O world/O where/O I/O stand/O and/O what/O I/O feel/O ,/O take/O it/O or/O leave/O it/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O way/O I/O am/O built/O ./O 
Now/O what/O you/O should/O do/O as/O a/O committee/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O is/O to/O have/O an/O actual/O educational/O committee-follow/O a/O page/O from/O the/O Communist/O form/O of/O operations-where/O you/O go/O on/O a/O deliberate/O campaign/O to/O tell/O the/O American/LOCATION public/O and/O get/O to/O the/O American/O public/O through/O the/O press/O ,/O the/O magazines/O ,/O articles/O perhaps-I/O do/O n't/O know/O how-television/O programs/O ./O 
But/O point/O out/O all/O these/O thousands/O and/O thousands/O of/O Americans/O all/O over/O the/O country/O who/O feel/O like/O I/O do/O ,/O who/O at/O one/O time/O or/O another/O were/O so/O liberal/O and/O felt/O a/O certain/O way/O for/O certain/O reasons/O ,/O and/O they/O wanted/O to/O do/O something/O to/O help/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O it/O would/O be/O fine/O to/O have/O you/O on/O television/O here/O today/O Would/O people/O then/O understand/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLAssBB/O ./O 
I/O wish/O I/O could/O ./O 
But/O get/O to/O the/O American/O public/O because/O there/O are/O thousands/O like/O me/O who/O are/O so/O frightened/O of/O you/O as/O individuals/O ,/O based/O on/O one/O fact/O ,/O that/O ,/O coming/O from/O a/O liberal/O element/O ,/O liberal/O background/O ,/O the/O fears/O of/O you/O as/O a/O committee/O are/O very/O intense/O ./O 
They/O hate/O you/O with/O all/O their/O blood/O ,/O for/O one/O reason/O :/O They/O have/O been/O told/O to/O hate/O you/O by/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION again/O and/O other/O liberal/O elements/O ./O 
Going/O way/O back/O to/O the/O Martin/PERSON Dies/O committee/O ,/O who/O did/O a/O great/O job/O with/O Fritz/PERSON Kuhn/PERSON when/O they/O got/O that/O son-of-a-gun/O out/O of/O the/O country/O and/O got/O his/O neck/O ,/O and/O the/O Nazi/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Once/O he/O jumped/O on/O a/O different/O form/O of/O political/O thinking/O ,/O they/O came/O back/O at/O him/O and/O slit/O his/O throat/O ;/O the/O liberal/O elements/O ./O 
The/O country/O has/O been/O told/O ,/O and/O it/O has/O been/O thrown/O down/O their/O throats/O by/O the/O publicists/O from/O the/O Communist/O Party-not/O necessarily/O ./O 
paid/O publicists/O but/O men/O working/O throughout/O the/O party/O and/O able/O to/O get/O these/O through/O in/O various/O ways-it/O has/O been/O shoved/O down/O the/O American/O public/O to/O hate/O your/O committee/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3835/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O say/O ,/O that/O Martin/PERSON Dies/O has/O since/O recovered/O completely/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O what/O comes/O out/O of/O it/O still/O makes/O a/O lot/O of/O sense/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
He/O did/O a/O magnificent/O job/O ;/O no/O question/O of/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O historical/O ./O 
You/O ca/O n't/O lie/O with/O history/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON proceed/O with/O his/O line/O of/O questioning/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O through/O giving/O us/O your/O recommendations/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O you/O should/O have/O a/O deliberate/O campaign/O of/O education/O of/O the/O American/LOCATION public/O that/O ,/O ``/O If/O you/O have/O anything/O to/O say/O pertaining/O to/O any/O form/O of/O Communist/O membership/O at/O one/O time/O or/O another/O ,/O come/O forth/O ./O 
We/O are/O not/O going/O to/O hurt/O you/O ./O 
We/O are/O going/O to/O help/O you/O ''/O -/O in/O the/O way/O I/O have/O been/O helped/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Again/O I/O repeat/O ,/O there/O could/O be/O no/O more/O effective/O way/O than/O to/O let/O the/O public/O see/O through/O the/O medium/O of/O television/O just/O what/O you/O are/O saying/O and/O doing/O here/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O true/O to/O a/O small/O extent/O ./O 
One/O appearance/O would/O n't/O do/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O constant/O form/O of/O punching/O it/O ./O 
It/O takes/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O view/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O have/O never/O spoken/O with/O you/O in/O my/O life/O or/O knew/O anything/O about/O you/O except/O what/O you/O have/O stated/O today/O ,/O I/O am/O going/O to/O ask/O you/O this/O question/O :/O Are/O you/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O directly/O or/O indirectly/O ,/O being/O paid/O or/O compensated/O for/O coming/O here/O without/O a/O lawyer/O and/O testifymg/O this/O morning/O Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O not/O ./O 
This/O is/O silly/O ./O 
Mr./O DovLE/O ./O 
Have/O you/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O directly/O or/O indirectly/O ,/O been/O promised/O any/O reward/O or/O compensation/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Absolutely/O not/O ./O 
It/O is/O silly/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O no/O basis/O for/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
There/O may/O not/O be/O any/O basis/O for/O such/O a/O question/O ,/O but/O there/O are/O people/O in/O this/O room/O who/O have/O sort/O of/O a/O sneer/O on/O their/O face/O right/O Vr.now/O ./O 
GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O they/O will/O come/O forth/O and/O say/O that/O ./O 
I/O expect/O villification/O from/O that/O forum/O ./O 
There/O is/O no/O question/O of/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O anticipated/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
This/O witness/O is/O not/O what/O they/O call/O ,/O in/O the/O Daily/ORGANIZATION People/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION and/O other/O anti-American/O papers/O ,/O a/O paid/O informer/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
They/O ca/O n't/O think/O for/O themselves/O ./O 
They/O are/O being/O told/O what/O to/O think/O ./O 
As/O far/O as/O the/O petty/O part/O of/O the/O pettinessMr/O ./O 
MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O except/O to/O say/O ,/O in/O the/O matter/O of/O the/O vilification/O you/O will/O receive/O you/O will/O have/O a/O considerable/O amount/O of/O company/O ,/O including/O a/O great/O many/O Members/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION who/O have/O been/O elected/O by/O their/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O be/O very/O proud/O to/O get/O the/O vilification/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
As/O long/O as/O the/O name/O of/O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON and/O Dr./O Louise/PERSON Light/PERSON have/O been/O brought/O into/O the/O testimony/O ,/O it/O should/O be/O in/O the/O record/O that/O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O also/O subsequently/O saw/O the/O same/O things/O that/O you/O did/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O got/O out/O of/O it/O ./O 
Both/O of/O them/O appeared/O before/O this/O committee/O and/O gave/O extremely/O valuable/O information/O based/O on/O their/O official/O capacity/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O further/O ./O 
3836/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O any/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O more/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O desires/O to/O express/O to/O you/O our/O appreciation/O for/O your/O courage/O and/O your/O cooperation/O and/O the/O contribution/O you/O have/O made/O in/O informing/O the/O public/O and/O this/O committee/O of/O such/O knowledge/O as/O you/O have/O concerning/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ./O 
In/O that/O connection/O I/O wish/O to/O say/O ,/O as/O an/O example/O ,/O I/O am/O sure/O your/O appearance/O before/O this/O committee/O will/O not/O affect/O your/O employment/O ./O 
You/O have/O had/O the/O courage/O ,/O the/O patriotism/O to/O come/O forward/O and/O state/O honestly/O ,/O without/O any/O reservations/O ,/O your/O past/O connections/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION approximately/O 13/O years/O ago/O ,/O and/O give/O a/O very/O thorough/O explanation/O about/O severing/O any/O connections/O you/O might/O have/O had/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Such/O conduct/O on/O the/O part/O of/O any/O person/O who/O appears/O before/O this/O committee/O certainly/O has/O never/O and/O should/O never/O affect/O their/O employment/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
And/O I/O am/O sure/O the/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O committee/O will/O concur/O with/O me/O that/O the/O employment/O of/O any/O other/O witnesses/O who/O would/O be/O just/O as/O honest/O and/O straightforward/O as/O you/O have/O been/O would/O not/O be/O affected/O either/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O country/O comes/O first/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Unless/O they/O continue/O to/O believe/O in/O the/O Communist/O philosophy/O they/O would/O not/O takePardone/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O make/O one/O more/O statement/O ?/O 
The/O thought/O that/O ocurred/O to/O us/O is/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O country/O comes/O first/O no/O matter/O what/O ./O 
So/O much/O so/O that/O in/O time/O of/O war/O when/O I/O am/O drafted/O and/O I/O get/O a/O letter/O from/O the/O President/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION requesting/O my/O presence/O at/O the/O induction/O center/O ,/O I/O have/O got/O to/O go/O whether/O I/O like/O it/O or/O not/O ,/O or/O whether/O I/O believe/O it/O or/O not/O ,/O or/O how/O I/O feel/O ./O 
This/O is/O immaterial/O ./O 
But/O when/O my/O country/O requests/O my/O presence/O or/O requests/O anything/O from/O me/O ,/O I/O have/O got/O to/O go/O and/O I/O have/O got/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
Now/O your/O committee/O has/O requested/O my/O presence/O here/O ./O 
It/O is/O by/O the/O same/O beholden/O duty/O I/O come/O and/O talk/O to/O you/O and/O answer/O any/O questions/O you/O may/O have/O to/O throw/O at/O me/O as/O an/O agency/O of/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
This/O is/O our/O country/O ./O 
If/O you/O do/O n't/O like/O it/O you/O can/O always/O get/O out/O ,/O which/O is/O an/O old/O cliche/O thrown/O around/O many/O times/O ./O 
The/O fact/O remains/O when/O you/O are/O here/O and/O love/O it/O as/O much/O as/O I/O do/O and/O intend/O to/O stay/O here/O and/O die/O here/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O cooperate/O and/O work/O with/O my/O country/O ./O 
If/O you/O are/O the/O elected/O representatives/O of/O my/O country/O what/O more/O can/O I/O say/O than/O to/O come/O back/O and/O say/O I/O will/O answer/O any/O questions/O you/O want/O me/O to/O without/O any/O nonsense/O or/O boloney/O ./O 
Many/O people/O want/O to/O evade/O these/O things/O ./O 
Why/O ?/O 
What/O have/O they/O done/O that/O is/O so/O horrible/O ?/O 
What/O did/O they/O do/O that/O they/O have/O got/O to/O escape/O from/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION ./O 
Did/O they/O throw/O a/O bomb/O somewhere/O ?/O 
Did/O they/O pass/O information/O along/O ?/O 
God/O knows/O what/O ./O 
They/O must/O have/O done/O some/O horrible/O thing/O which/O only/O they/O know/O about/O for/O which/O they/O would/O have/O to/O escape/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3837/O If/O they/O come/O here/O and/O say/O ,/O ``/O I/O take/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ''/O you/O say/O ,/O ``/O What/O have/O you/O done/O that/O is/O so/O horrible/O ?/O 
Belonged/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O was/O completely/O official/O and/O normal/O and/O correct/O at/O the/O time/O ?/O 
What/O is/O so/O bad/O ?/O ''/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
As/O you/O have/O stated/O ,/O you/O wanted/O to/O be/O a/O liberal/O ,/O and/O still/O have/O answered/O the/O questions/O ./O 
And/O there/O could/O be/O no/O question/O as/O to/O your/O loyalty/O by/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O still/O aware/O of/O many/O things/O wrong/O in/O the/O country/O ./O 
And/O that/O will/O be/O corrected/O in/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O to/O reinterate/O my/O statement/O I/O made/O in/O appreciation/O for/O your/O clear/O and/O convincing/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O my/O colleagues/O join/O with/O me/O in/O complimenting/O this/O gentleman/O on/O his/O musical/O achievements/O and/O attainments/O ./O 
Certainly/O music/O is/O a/O universal/O language/O ./O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O it/O is/O ;/O my/O language/O ,/O anyway/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ,/O Mr./O Glasser/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O GLAssER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Glasser/PERSON ./O 
Is/O she/O here/O ?/O 
Mr./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
My/O wife/O ,/O Mrs./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O is/O right/O back/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Will/O you/O hold/O up/O your/O right/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON withdrew/O from/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
The/O photographers/O will/O please/O be/O seated/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O KATHERINE/PERSON GLASSER/PERSON -LRB-/O MRS./O ALBERT/PERSON GLASSER/PERSON -RRB-/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Katherine/PERSON Glasser/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O the/O wife/O of/O Mr./O Albert/PERSON Glasser/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O you/O were/O not/O subpenaed/O as/O a/O witness/O ;/O were/O you/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O came/O in/O voluntarily/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O your/O husband/O 's/O testimony/O the/O fact/O of/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O made/O known/O ./O 
We/O will/O give/O you/O an/O opportunity/O to/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O without/O reiterating/O his/O testimony/O ,/O just/O what/O period/O of/O time/O you/O were/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O anything/O you/O desire/O to/O state/O to/O the/O committee/O regarding/O your/O knowledge/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLAssER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O according/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O I/O know/O we/O got/O in/O in/O 1943/O because/O we/O base/O this/O upon/O roughly/O the/O date/O my/O child/O was/O born/O ./O 
That/O day/O was/O not/O rough/O ,/O but/O the/O child/O was/O born/O in/O January/O of/O 1943/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O shortly/O after/O that/O ,/O a/O few/O months/O ,/O that/O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON and/O Dr./O Louise/PERSON Light/PERSON asked/O us/O to/O join/O ,/O and/O we/O finally/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O how/O long/O did/O you/O stay/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
3838/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O a/O matter/O of/O just/O a/O few/O months/O as/O far/O as/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O because/O I/O recall/O the/O printed/O little/O program/O slip/O from/O December/O 11/O ,/O 1943/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O after/O that/O that/O we/O broke/O with/O the/O entire/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O break/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Because/O their/O premises/O and/O principles/O did/O not/O agree/O with/O ours/O ./O 
We/O happen/O to/O be/O free/O thinkers/O ,/O and/O we/O believe/O in/O free/O speech/O and/O free/O opinion/O ,/O and/O did/O not/O believe/O in/O being/O directed/O as/O to/O what/O I/O shall/O say/O or/O what/O I/O shall/O think/O or/O how/O I/O shall/O feel/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O to/O this/O day/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O ,/O while/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O felt/O that/O you/O were/O restricted/O in/O that/O way/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O in/O many/O ways/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULiER/O ./O 
At/O that/O point/O may/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O :/O During/O the/O period/O of/O time/O Soviet/O Russia/LOCATION was/O our/O ally/O in/O the/O World/O War/O ,/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION had/O not/O yet/O held/O or/O cited/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O being/O a/O world/O conspiracy/O to/O overthrow/O our/O form/O of/O government/O by/O force/O if/O necessary/O ./O 
Is/O that/O not/O correct/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O that/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
DO/O you/O recall/O the/O first/O meeting/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O that/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
The/O very/O ,/O very/O first/O meeting/O that/O I/O recall/O quite/O vividly/O ,/O for/O obvious/O reasons/O ,/O was/O that/O meeting-I/O believe/O it/O was/O a/O telephone/O call/O ,/O and/O we/O were/O told/O to/O go/O to/O this/O address/O at/O Sunset/O Plaza/O Drive/O ./O 
And/O it/O was/O one/O of/O these/O welcome-to-the-Communist-Party/O meeting/O things/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O in/O whose/O home/O that/O meeting/O was/O held/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
At/O first/O we/O thought/O it/O was/O in/O the/O home/O of/O th-Mr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O say/O whose/O home/O you/O thought/O it/O was/O unless/O you/O know/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O ./O 
We/O presumed/O it/O was/O the/O speaker/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Excuse/O me/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O hear/O you/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O we/O presumed/O that/O it/O was/O the/O man/O who/O spoke/O to/O us/O ./O 
We/O thought/O it/O was/O his/O home/O ;/O that/O was/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O ,/O ``/O spoke/O to/O you/O ''/O ?/O '/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O trying/O to/O tell/O us/O the/O various/O premises/O of/O what/O the/O Communist/O Party/O intended/O doing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O the/O speaker/O at/O that/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLAssER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O speaker/O at/O that/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLAssER/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O do/O not/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O his/O home/O or/O not/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSES/O ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O took/O place/O at/O that/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSE/PERSON ./O 
As/O best/O as/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O it/O was/O welcome/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O it/O was/O a/O group/O meeting/O of/O various/O groups/O ;/O integration/O in/O other/O words/O ./O 
And/O then/O they/O went/O on/O to/O explain/O the/O various/O premises/O of/O what/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meant/O ,/O which/O meant/O sharing/O things/O ,/O all/O the/O people/O sharing/O the/O businesses/O ,/O the/O various/O ,/O what/O we/O consider/O liberal/O premises/O ./O 
And/O then/O I/O became/O a/O little/O disgruntled/O with/O certain/O things/O because/O ,/O you/O know/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O create/O a/O certain/O situation/O you/O have/O to/O arrive/O `/O COLMMtNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3839/O there/O by/O some/O means/O ./O 
And/O I/O wanted/O to/O know/O what/O the/O means/O were/O ./O 
And/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O can/O recall/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O such/O thing/O as/O revolution/O ./O 
It/O was/O all/O evolution/O ./O 
But/O it/O still/O did/O n't/O make/O sense/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O I/O just/O kept/O asking/O questions/O because/O after/O the/O discussion/O was/O concluded/O they/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O any/O questions/O from/O the/O people/O sitting/O here/O ?/O ''/O 
And/O this/O just/O bothered/O me/O because/O I/O wanted/O to/O know/O what/O is/O the/O eventual/O deal/O that/O we/O are/O getting/O to/O ./O 
And/O finally/O he/O made/O the/O statement/O that-I/O mean/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O he/O was/O mad/O at/O me/O because/O I/O was/O a/O youngster/O then/O ,/O and/O he/O might/O have/O just/O blurted/O it/O out/O and/O not/O meant/O it-I/O ca/O n't/O presume/O to/O think/O for/O him/O but/O this/O is/O what/O he/O did/O say/O :/O He/O says/O ,/O ``/O By/O revolution/O ,/O we/O will/O be/O able/O to/O evolve/O all/O the/O things/O that/O we/O want/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O anything/O else/O said/O by/O Mr./O Lawson/PERSON on/O that/O occasion/O which/O you/O recall/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLAssR/O ./O 
Not/O that/O I/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O musical/O family/O or/O organization/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O am/O ./O 
SMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
In/O what/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O an/O orchestra/O manager/O ,/O which/O means/O that/O I/O hire/O the/O musicians/O for/O the/O orchestras/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O also/O a/O copyist/O and/O librarian/O ,/O which/O means/O writing/O down/O the/O notes/O for/O the/O musicians/O to/O be-able/O to/O play/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O particular/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION after/O this/O welcoming/O meeting/O referred/O to/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O musicians/O '/O group/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O from/O what/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O there/O were/O not/O more/O than/O 20/O to/O 25/O attending/O at/O any/O one/O meeting/O ./O 
But/O they/O were/O all/O musicians/O ./O 
`/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O your/O husband/O has/O testified/O that/O several/O of/O the/O meetings/O were/O held/O in/O your/O home/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O they/O were/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O there/O were/O two/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Willyou/PERSON give/O the/O committee/O the/O names/O of/O persons/O that/O you/O yourself/O can/O identify/O as/O having/O attended/O Communist/O Party/O :/O meetings/O of/O the/O group/O of/O which/O you/O were/O a/O member/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O can/O ./O 
Kalman/PERSON Bloch/PERSON ,/O B-1-o-c-h/O ,/O and/O his/O wife/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O her/O first/O name/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O Mrs./O Kalman/PERSON Bloch/PERSON as/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
Anita/PERSON Short/PERSON ,/O Sam/PERSON Albert/PERSON ,/O Doris/PERSON Albert/PERSON ,/O Blanche/O Sweet-Mr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Doris/PERSON Albert/PERSON the/O wife/O of/O -/O Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O Sam/PERSON Albert/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON returned/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O at/O this/O point/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O Blanche/O Sweet/O and/O her/O husband/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O his/O first/O name/O ./O 
And/O Henry/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O Esther/PERSON Roth/PERSON ,/O Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON ,/O Carla/PERSON Altman/PERSON ,/O Herbert/PERSON Offner/PERSON ,/O O-f-f-n-e-r/O ,/O Herbert/PERSON Lessner/PERSON ,/O L-e-s-s-n-e-r/O ,/O and/O his/O wife/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Don/PERSON ChristliebMr/PERSON ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ;/O What/O is/O that/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Christlieb/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O it/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
C-h-r-i-s-t-1-i-e-b/O ;/O Victor/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON ,/O Eudice/PERSON Shapiro/PERSON Gottlieb/PERSON ./O 
77436/O --/O 56-pt/O ./O 
9/O --/O 3840/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Eudice/O ,/O E-u-d-i-c-e/O ./O 
Helen/PERSON TannenbaumMr/PERSON ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Spell/O the/O name/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
T-a-n-n-e-n-b-a-u-m/O ./O 
Cyril/PERSON T-o-w-b-i-n/PERSON ,/O Towbin/PERSON ;/O Kathryn/PERSON Becker/PERSON ,/O B-e-c-k-e-r/O ,/O Carroll/PERSON Hollister/PERSON ;/O Sol/PERSON Kaplan/PERSON ,/O and/O Martha/PERSON Goldberg/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O leave/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O same/O time/O that/O your/O husband/O did/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
We/O do/O everything/O together/O ./O 
So/O we/O left/O it/O together/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O point/O may/O I/O ask/O this/O question/O :/O To/O your/O knowledge/O were/O these/O two/O meetings/O of/O the/O musicians/O '/O group/O that/O were/O held/O at/O your/O home/O limited/O in/O attendance/O to/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O was/O it/O a/O closed/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
From/O my/O knowledge-and/O this/O I/O am/O quite/O certain/O of-these/O were/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O ./O 
They/O were/O closed/O only/O to/O Communists/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O they/O were/O open/O only/O to/O Communists/O ./O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Excuse/O me/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O they/O were/O open/O only/O to/O Communists/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O there/O any/O additional/O fact/O you/O have/O not/O already/O testified/O to/O regarding/O your/O reasons/O for/O leaving/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O you/O might/O want/O to/O tell/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O actually/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O before/O ,/O what/O they/O wantedFor/O instance/O ,/O like/O ,/O take/O the/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
When/O they/O wanted/O to/O raise/O funds/O they/O wanted/O just/O to/O have/O a/O party/O and/O just/O have/O entertainers/O ./O 
I/O said/O this/O is/O ridiculous/O ./O 
How/O can/O you/O do/O this/O to/O people/O ./O 
You/O just/O call/O them/O in/O and/O ask/O them/O for/O funds/O ./O 
You/O have/O to/O give/O them/O something/O ./O 
So/O that/O is/O when/O I/O started/O with/O the/O dinner/O ,/O with/O the/O turkeys/O that/O were/O discussed/O ./O 
And/O by/O the/O time/O I/O got/O through/O we/O had/O the/O most/O beautiful/O turkey/O dinner/O for/O everybody/O ./O 
They/O had/O the/O most/O wonderful/O entertainment/O ,/O and/O the/O entire/O price/O was/O $/O 2/O ./O 
And/O we/O still/O made/O a/O profit/O for/O the/O Musicians/ORGANIZATION Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
So/O it/O can/O be/O done/O like/O ladies/O and/O gentlemen/O instead/O of/O just/O asking/O people/O to/O contribute/O for/O their/O thoughts/O ./O 
And/O these/O were/O things/O that/O did/O disturb/O me/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O live/O this/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O anything/O else/O you/O desire/O to/O say/O to/O the/O committee/O Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O tell/O the/O woman/O who/O sat/O next/O to/O me/O that/O I/O am/O very/O proud/O to/O be/O my/O husband/O 's/O wife/O ,/O no/O matter/O what/O she/O said/O ./O 
And/O I/O heard/O everything/O that/O she/O said/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O if/O I/O started/O a/O disturbance/O ,/O but/O nobody/O says/O anything/O about/O my/O husband/O without/O my/O permission/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O in/O this/O hearing/O room/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSES/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Any/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
We/O will/O have/O order/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 3841/O Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
In/O addition/O to/O what/O you/O have/O said/O ,/O I/O assume/O ,/O Mrs./O Glasser/PERSON ,/O you/O share/O your/O husband/O 's/O views/O concerning/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O its/O objectives/O ?/O 
Mrs./O GLASSER/PERSON ./O 
In/O every/O possible/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O as/O a/O witness/O ./O 
