INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O INTHE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 4/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O JULY/O 1/O AND/O 2/O ,/O 1955/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O ,/O 0/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1955/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Chairmno/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Illinois/PERSON MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W/PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON E./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION THOMAB/LOCATION W./LOCATION BEALE/LOCATION ,/O Sr./O ,/O Chief/O Clerk/O II/O CONTENTS/O PART/O 1/O June/O 27/O ./O 
1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofPaul/O Wright/PERSON Orr/PERSON ------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O Andries/PERSON Deinum/PERSON Page/O 1440/O 1474/O ------/O Anita/PERSON Bell/PERSON Schneider-June/O 28/O ,/O 1955/O -/O Testimony/O ofAngela/O Clarke/PERSON -------------------------------------/O ./O 
--/O ./O 
Cecil/PERSON Beard/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Diamond/O Kim/O 1498/O -/O 1523/O 1538/O 1543/O -----------/O Diamond/O Kim/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --------------/O Sue/PERSON Lawson/PERSON --/O -----------------/O George/PERSON Hugh/PERSON Murray/PERSON Maitland/PERSON Hardyman/PERSON --------/O 1565/O 1572/O 1575/O Afternoon/O session/O PaRT/O 2/O June/O 29/O ,/O 1955/O Testimony/O ofGeorge/O Hugh/PERSON Murray/PERSON Maitland/PERSON Hardyian/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -----------/O Raphael/PERSON Konigsberg/PERSON Afternoon/O session/O Syhl/PERSON ia/O Schonfield/O ---------------/O Jean/PERSON Wilkmson/PERSON --------------------/O Frank/PERSON C/PERSON Davis/PERSON --/O Irene/PERSON B/PERSON Boverman/PERSON ------------/O Carl/ORGANIZATION Sugar/ORGANIZATION -----------------/O 1599/O 1656/O 1668/O 1676/O 1679/O 1689/O 1697/O PART/O 3/O June/O 30/O ,/O 1955/O Testimony/O ofMatthew/O Samuel/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O Jr/O ./O 
-------------------/O William/PERSON Elconin/PERSON ----------------/O William/PERSON Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON .../O ------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O William/PERSON Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ------------/O Max/PERSON Benjamin/PERSON Natapoff/PERSON ---------------------------------/O Tashia/O Freed/O Max/PERSON Appleman/PERSON -----------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON W./PERSON Aidlin/PERSON -----------------------------------------/O PART/O 4/O July/O 1/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofStephen/O A./O Wereb/O --/O ./O 
---------------/O Afternoon/O session/O Stephen/PERSON A./PERSON Wereb/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -----------------------------/O James/PERSON Burford/PERSON -------------/O Anne/PERSON Pollock/PERSON ./O 
--------------------------------------------/O MeyerVaughn/O Margaret/O July/O 2/O ,/O 1955/O Testimony/O of/O -------------/O -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ---------/O Wereb/PERSON A./PERSON Stephen/PERSON ----------/O --------------/O John/PERSON Waters/PERSON Houston/PERSON ------/O Harry/PERSON Hay/PERSON ----------------------------------------------/O Martha/PERSON Hard/PERSON Wheeldin/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Louis/PERSON Stark/PERSON --------------/O Robert/PERSON L./PERSON Brock/PERSON ./O 
121/O \*/O \*/O STANDINGCOMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O PO/O \/O ERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O a/O n/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O ,/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5/O ,/O 1955/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O COMMITTEES/O STANDING/O 1/O There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O conlist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O Xl/O POWEKS/O AND/O DUTIES/O ot/O COMMIIITTF/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O l1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O in-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O The/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcomlinttee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 4/O FRIDAY/O ,/O JULY/O 1/O ,/O 1955/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTrrTIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O at/O 9/O :/O 40/O a./O m./O ,/O pursuant/O to/O recess/O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ;/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O please/O convene/O ./O 
Mr./O Wereb/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O please/O rise/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Mr./O WERE/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O STEPHEN/O A./O WERE/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Stephen/PERSON A./PERSON Wereb/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O noted/O that/O you/O are/O not/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
You/O are/O familiar/O with/O the/O rule/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O are/O you/O not/O ,/O that/O you/O are/O entitled/O to/O counsel/O if/O you/O so/O desire/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
W-e-r-e-b/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Wereb/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O at/O Alpha/O ,/O N./PERSON J./PERSON ,/O April/O 27/O ,/O 1898/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O presently/O reside/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O resided/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Thirty/O -/O five/O years/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O had/O grade-school/O education/O ,/O high-school/O education/O ,/O and/O I/O have/O had/O 1/O year/O of/O business/O and/O business/O administration/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Pennsylvania/ORGANIZATION ./O 
1780/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O present/O time/O I/O own/O and/O operate/O the/O Weber/ORGANIZATION Typewriter/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O had/O occasion/O in/O the/O past/O to/O be/O employed/O by/O any/O investigative/O branch/O of/O the/O Federal/O Government/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O that/O employment/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O how/O it/O happened/O that/O you/O were/O employed/O in/O that/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
My/O attention/O first/O to/O subversive/O talks/O ,/O literature/O ,/O activities/O ,/O was/O drawn/O by/O leaflets/O ,/O speeches/O ,/O and/O aggressiveness/O and/O the/O proRussian/O attitude/O of/O certain/O people/O along/O my/O stops/O ,/O and/O this/O alarmed/O me/O to/O such/O an/O extent/O that/O I/O took/O the/O necessary/O steps/O to/O inquire/O further/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O do/O you/O mean/O by/O saying/O ``/O along/O your/O stops/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
During/O my/O work/O at/O the/O Typewriter/O Service/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O your/O being/O employed/O by/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION ,/O had/O you/O been/O affiliated/O in/O any/O manner/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O not/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O testified/O prior/O to/O today/O on/O the/O subject/O of/O communism/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O courts/O or/O before/O what/O bodies/O did/O you/O testify/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O testified/O at/O the/O Smith/O Act/O trials/O of/O Schneider/PERSON -/O man/O v./O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION Government/O in/O 1953/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O and/O then/O I/O appeared/O before/O this/O committee/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION last/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O for/O a/O limited/O purpose/O at/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O not/O at/O that/O time/O testify/O generally/O about/O your/O knowledge/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION area/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O result/O of/O being/O employed/O by/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bu/ORGANIZATION -/O reau/O of/O Investigation/O ,/O did/O you/O seek/O admission/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O hand/O you/O a/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O what/O appears/O to/O be/O a/O Communist/O Party/O card/O ./O 
Will/O you/O identify/O it/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Document/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O my/O membership/O book/O in/O the/O Hawthorne/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O issued/O to/O you/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O issued/O to/O me/O by/O the/O membership/O director/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O one/O Vernon/PERSON L./PERSON Potter/PERSON ,/O at/O my/O home/O ,/O who/O identified/O himself/O as/O the/O membership/O chairman/O of/O that/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O the/O card/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O shows/O the/O name/O of/O the/O person/O who/O was/O the/O owner/O of/O the/O book/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
It/O does/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
S./PERSON A./PERSON Weber/PERSON ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1781/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
S./PERSON A./PERSON Weber/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O name/O is/O Wereb/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O your/O party/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O used/O during/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O but/O this/O name/O has/O been/O published/O in/O the/O Daily/O News-not/O the/O Daily/O News/O ,/O but/O the/O Legal/O Daily/O ,/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O doing/O business/O under/O the/O name/O of/O Weber/ORGANIZATION Typewriter/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION and/O it/O was/O at/O the/O behest/O and/O suggestion/O of/O some/O of/O my/O accounts/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O took/O legal/O steps/O to/O change/O it/O to/O that/O only/O doing/O business/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
But/O that/O is/O the/O name/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION by/O which/O you/O registered/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ;/O they/O never/O knew/O my/O real/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O work/O within/O the/O Communist/O Party/O for/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O from/O October/O of/O 1943/O until/O the/O 1st/O of/O January/O or/O thereabouts/O of/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O prompted/O you/O to/O undertake/O an/O assignment/O of/O that/O character/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O my/O people/O came/O from/O Europe-they/O came/O from/O a/O place/O of/O oppression-and/O I/O was/O born/O here/O and/O I/O just/O could/O not/O quite/O understand/O the/O stories/O that/O I/O heard/O from/O immigrants/O and/O other/O people/O who/O have/O taken/O refuge/O here/O ,/O what/O a/O wonderful/O place/O this/O is/O ,/O and/O how/O anyone/O could/O attempt/O to/O use/O force/O or/O violence/O to/O try/O to/O overthrow/O or/O even/O subversion/O to/O overthrow/O this/O type/O of/O government/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O motivated/O you/O in/O undertaking/O this/O difficult/O assignment/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O these/O years/O which/O you/O gave/O to/O work/O within/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O find/O it/O to/O be/O a/O difficult/O assignment/O and/O one/O which/O influenced/O your/O life/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O influence/O I/O have/O ever/O had/O with/O my/O association-that/O is/O ,/O through/O the/O association/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party-was/O a/O greater/O love/O that/O I/O have/O for/O the/O country/O ,/O because/O of/O their/O teaching/O ,/O of/O their/O unacceptable/O philosophy/O ,/O of/O their/O impossible/O attitude/O ,/O and/O the/O continuous/O mistrust/O of/O one/O another-the/O revolutionary/O tendencies/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O if/O I/O did/O have/O ,/O shall/O we/O say/O ,/O such/O a/O thought/O as/O a/O progressive/O thought/O ever/O in/O my/O bones/O ,/O which/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O had/O ,/O that/O certainly/O would/O have/O cured/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O sense/O do/O you/O use/O the/O term/O ``/O progressive/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O mean/O that/O as/O the/O Communist/O Party/O uses/O it/O ./O 
There/O are/O times/O that/O it/O is/O more/O applicable/O to/O use/O that/O you/O are/O a/O progressive/O rather/O than/O a/O Communist/O ,/O wherever/O the/O case/O may/O fit/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O if/O you/O are/O an/O active/O person/O in/O the/O union/O ,/O they/O do/O not/O exactly/O relish/O the/O idea/O of/O you/O standing/O out/O there/O as/O a/O Communist/O but/O they/O would/O rather/O have/O you/O there/O as/O a/O ``/O progressive/O ''/O person/O ;/O or/O if/O you/O are/O active/O in/O any/O politics/O of/O any/O kind/O ,/O they/O try/O and/O avert/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION approach/O from/O anything/O ,/O but/O what/O they/O try/O to/O do/O is/O use/O the/O words/O ``/O progressive/O ,/O ''/O ``/O democratic/O ,/O ''/O ``/O democracy/O ./O ''/O 
They/O drag/O that/O around/O just/O like/O a/O dirty/O rug/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O anything/O of/O significance/O that/O occurred/O within/O a/O few/O months/O prior/O to/O the/O time/O you/O actually/O became/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O carrying/O out/O your/O assignment/O which/O would/O be/O of/O value/O to/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
1782/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WEREP/PERSON ./O 
./O 
Just/O the/O sort/O of/O an/O explanation/O of/O how/O hard/O it/O is/O to/O get/O into/O this/O group/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O I/O tried/O wholeheartedly/O ,/O I/O attended/O every/O function/O advertised/O in/O the/O Peoples/O Daily/O World/O and/O everywhere/O where/O I/O might/O have/O met/O some/O of/O these/O ``/O progressive/O ''/O people/O ,/O I/O have/O attended/O every/O function/O and/O it/O took/O meMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
In/O using/O the/O term/O ``/O progressive/O ,/O ''/O are/O you/O using/O it/O in/O quotation/O marks/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
In/O quotation/O marks-still/O the/O same/O men/O ,/O still/O the/O same/O answer/O as/O in/O the/O previous/O answer/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O tried/O my/O very/O best/O ,/O visited/O book/O stores/O at/O that/O time/O known/O as/O the/O progressive/O book/O shop/O ,/O and/O there/O Marxist/O literature/O of/O all/O types/O was/O to/O be/O had/O ;/O guides/O as/O to/O how/O to/O be/O a/O good/O Communist/O ;/O Lenin/PERSON 's/O works/O ,/O Stalin/PERSON 's/O works/O ,/O and/O I/O managed/O to/O read/O up/O on/O those/O the/O best/O I/O could/O until/O I/O was/O finally/O approached/O to/O join/O the/O party/O at/O one/O of/O the/O functions/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O a/O 3-month/O chore/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O who/O it/O was/O that/O approached/O you/O to/O interest/O you/O in/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O month/O of/O January/O in/O 1944/O a/O Wilhelmina/PERSON Mase/PERSON ,/O whom/O I/O knew/O for/O a/O long/O time/O as/O a/O functionary/O and/O as/O one/O of/O the/O fulltime/O workers/O at/O the/O Peoples/O Daily/O World/O ,/O approached/O me/O and/O signed/O me/O up/O for/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O the/O proper/O spelling/O of/O the/O name/O M-a-i-s-e/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREK/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O as/O far/O as/O I/O can/O remember/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENN/PERSON ER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O proceed/O to/O describe/O what/O occurred/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
At/O this/O party/O there/O were/O approximately/O two/O to/O three/O hundred/O people/O present/O ./O 
It/O was/O held/O at/O 2200/O West/O Seventh/O Street/O and/O it/O was/O held/O by/O the/O West/LOCATION Lake/LOCATION group/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O known/O as/O the/O West/LOCATION Lake/LOCATION Club/LOCATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O had/O a/O lot/O of/O drinking/O ,/O they/O had/O an/O affair/O called/O their/O social/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O celebration/O of/O an/O officers/O '/O installation/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O Willamena/PERSON Maise/PERSON was/O also/O installed/O as/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O West/LOCATION Lake/LOCATION group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O it/O that/O actually/O gave/O you/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION card/O ,/O the/O photostatic/O copy/O of/O which/O I/O exhibited/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O WERER/PERSON ./O 
A/O person/O known/O to/O me/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Vernon/PERSON L./PERSON Potter/PERSON came/O to/O my/O home/O and/O I/O identified/O myself/O and/O he/O identified/O himself/O as/O the/O membership/O chairman/O of/O the/O Hawthorne/ORGANIZATION Conununist/ORGANIZATION group/O ,/O and/O he/O gave/O me/O my/O membership/O card/O and/O also/O my/O first/O assignment/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O assignment/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
My/O first/O assignment/O was/O ,/O sir/O ,/O to/O attend/O a/O function/O known/O also/O as/O an/O installation/O affair/O at/O the/O home/O of/O one/O John/PERSON and/O Georgiana/PERSON Garrish/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O address-I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O the/O number/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O on/O Paseo/PERSON de/PERSON Gracia/PERSON in/O Redondo/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O spelling/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREn/O ./O 
G-a-r-r-i-s-h/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O party/O 's/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O security/O measure/O taken/O to/O ascertain/O your/O future/O reliability/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O you/O entered/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O or/O was/O any/O such/O security/O measure/O taken/O at/O a/O later/O date/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Security/O measures/O of/O that/O type/O were/O taken/O at/O a/O later/O date/O ./O 
I/O was/O closely/O watched/O and/O sent/O to/O workers/O '/O school/O the/O first/O time/O before/O I/O was/O integrated/O into/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O again/O briefly/O what/O this/O first/O assignment/O was/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1783/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
This/O first/O assignment/O was/O for/O me/O to/O attend/O this/O inauguration/O affair/O on/O Paseo/PERSON de/PERSON Gracia/PERSON at/O the/O home/O of/O Garrish/PERSON ,/O and/O there/O the/O new/O elected/O or-well/O ,/O I/O would/O not/O say/O elected/O ,/O but/O dictated/O officers/O of/O the/O club/O were/O introduced/O ./O 
I/O imagine/O there/O were/O 40/O or/O 45/O people/O there/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O did/O not/O know/O too/O many/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O identify/O Vernon/PERSON Potter/PERSON ,/O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON ./O 
the/O Garrish/PERSON family/O ,/O and/O Juanita/PERSON Smith/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O recall/O at/O the/O present/O time/O any/O more/O names/O that/O I/O would/O remember/O because/O that/O was/O my/O first/O affair/O ./O 
At/O this/O party/O ,/O of/O course/O after/O the/O introductions/O finally/O ,/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON was/O introduced/O ,/O brought/O out/O from/O one/O of/O the/O side/O rooms/O ,/O and/O he/O came/O in/O and/O they/O introduced/O him/O as/O the/O chairman/O ,/O the/O new/O chairman/O of/O the/O Hawthorne-Inglewood/O Communist/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O Hawthorne/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O There/O was/O no/O official/O meeting/O known/O as-like/O the/O other/O meetings/O that/O consist/O of/O Marxist/O class/O or/O an/O educational/O period/O ./O 
There/O was/O no/O educational/O period/O but/O there/O were/O some/O guessing/O games/O played/O such/O as/O what/O Lenin/PERSON did/O and/O who/O Engels/PERSON was/O ,/O and/O then/O they/O gave/O prizes/O ,/O maybe/O ,/O of/O a/O sandwich/O or/O so/O or/O gave/O you/O a/O little/O extra/O pamphlet/O if/O you/O had/O the/O right/O answers/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O answers/O because/O I/O did/O not/O know/O anything/O about/O them/O ./O 
Then/O there/O was/O this/O man/O Houston/LOCATION ./O 
When/O he/O was/O introduced/O to/O the/O crowd/O of/O 50/O people/O or/O 40/O people/O ,/O he/O expressed/O his/O feeling/O of/O gratitude/O to/O the/O crowd/O and/O stated/O at/O that/O time/O that/O if/O we/O had/O been/O reading/O the/O papers/O ,/O Russia/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O was/O divided/O into/O 16/O separate/O countries/O and/O if/O we/O worked/O hard/O enough/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION ,/O we-that/O is/O ,/O the/O Communists-we/O could/O make/O this/O country/O the/O 17th/O state/O or/O country/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O his/O first/O name/O ,/O Houston/LOCATION 's/O first/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
John/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVESNNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O become/O well/O acquainted/O with/O Mr./O Houston/PERSON in/O your/O future/O connection/O with/O the/O Hawthorne/ORGANIZATION Group/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
We/O became/O personal/O acquaintaneces/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O met/O him/O on/O the/O average/O of/O ,/O oh/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O 3/O times/O a/O month/O or/O sometimes/O 5/O times/O a/O month/O ./O 
It/O would/O all/O depend/O on/O the/O assignments/O and/O the/O meetings/O that/O we/O held/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O here/O ,/O please/O ./O 
You/O mean/O that/O right/O here/O in/O Hawthorne/LOCATION and/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O Hawthorne/PERSON being/O ,/O as/O I/O remember/O it-maybe/O it/O is/O part/O of/O the/O city/O limits/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION now/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
But/O I/O know/O it/O is/O right/O next/O door/O to/O the/O city/O limits/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION on/O the/O south/O ./O 
You/O mean/O right/O there/O in/O our/O midst/O this/O man/O was/O preaching/O and/O advocating/O that/O your/O Communist/O cell/O work/O hard/O toward/O the/O objective/O of/O making/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION the/O 17th/O state/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O laughing/O matter/O ,/O I/O am/O sure/O ,/O for/O folks/O who/O may/O be/O in/O the/O room/O ;/O nothing/O funny/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O we/O going/O to/O get/O a/O star/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O know/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
No/O star/O was/O mentioned/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O would/O be/O at/O a/O meeting/O like/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O meeting/O I/O believe/O there/O were/O 40/O or/O 50/O people/O ,/O but/O outside/O of/O the/O names/O I/O have/O already/O called/O ,/O I/O could/O not/O identify/O more/O 1784/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O because/O I/O did/O not/O know/O any/O more/O ./O 
That/O was/O my/O first/O function/O and/O first/O assignment/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O at/O what/O level/O of/O authority/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION Houston/ORGANIZATION came/O from/O I/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O chairman/O ,/O and/O to/O become/O a/O chairman/O of/O any/O Communist/O group/O you/O must/O have/O the/O approval/O of/O the/O county/O officers/O and/O the/O county/O officers/O usually/O know/O and/O approve/O all/O candidates/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O at/O one/O time/O I/O was/O elected/O a/O membership/O director/O but/O the/O county/O kind/O of/O did/O not/O think/O that/O was/O the/O proper/O thing/O to/O do/O ,/O so/O they/O unelected/O me/O very/O quickly/O within/O 2/O months/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O I/O was/O not/O given/O any/O records/O at/O that/O time/O of/O any/O members/O or/O membership/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O given/O any/O authority/O like/O the/O other/O membership/O directors/O had/O ,/O and/O there/O was/O nothing/O done/O at/O club/O level/O that/O was/O not/O dictated/O by/O the/O county/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O know/O they/O unelected/O you/O ?/O 
Did/O they/O tell/O you/O so/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O believe/O I/O was/O told/O that/O Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON ,/O who/O has/O been/O the/O membership/O director/O up/O until/O that/O time/O ,/O would/O be/O the/O proper/O person/O for/O that/O job/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O directly/O told/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O not/O trusted/O ;/O but/O I/O could/O read/O between/O the/O lines/O that-well/O ,/O they/O were/O not/O sure/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O old/O a/O man/O would/O you/O estimate/O this/O fellow/O Houston/LOCATION to/O be/O that/O was/O speaking/O apparently/O with/O the/O authority/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION when/O he/O said/O the/O objective/O was/O to/O work/O to/O have/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION the/O 17th/O state/O of/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ?/O 
How/O old/O a/O man/O would/O he/O be/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O at/O that/O time/O approximately/O 36/O to/O 38/O years/O old/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O not/O a/O child/O ,/O then/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O not/O in/O his/O dotage/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O well-educated/O man/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O this/O meeting/O room/O at/O Inglewood/LOCATION ,/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION or/O cell/O where/O it/O met/O ,/O what/O decorations/O did/O they/O have/O so/O far/O as/O pictures/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O of/O people/O or-of/O course/O ,/O they/O had/O the/O flag/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION up/O ,/O did/O they/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O WYEREB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
They/O did/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
This/O was/O at/O a/O home/O of/O Mr./O and/O Mrs./O Garrish/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O see/O a/O flag/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION at/O any/O Communist/O cell/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O one/O time/O at/O the/O Embassy/O Auditorium/O they/O had/O one/O underneath/O the/O balcony/O in/O a/O little/O hidden/O corner/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O a/O flag/O that/O was/O small/O and/O there/O were/O so/O many/O large/O Commumist/O posters/O up/O that/O you/O certainly/O would/O have/O to/O be/O a/O trickster/O to/O see/O the/O American/O flag/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O kind/O of/O posters/O were/O up/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Money/O drives/O for/O membership/O and/O money/O drives/O for/O defense/O ,/O money/O drives/O for/O fighting/O different/O Congressmen/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O have/O any/O pictures/O of/O Stalin/PERSON or/O any/O of/O rest/O of/O the/O Communist/O leaders/O ?/O 
The/O reason/O I/O ask/O you/O that/O questionthe/O is/O that/O in/O many/O of/O our/O hearings/O we/O have/O evidence/O under/O oath/O by/O former/O bona/O fide/O Communists/O the/O fact/O that/O they/O never/O display/O an/O American/O flag/O in/O their/O club/O meetings/O or/O cells/O but/O they/O almost/O always/O have/O a/O picture/O in/O their/O established/O club/O rooms/O ,/O if/O they/O are/O such/O ,/O of/O Stalin/PERSON and/O Engels/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1785/O and/O these/O other/O Communists/O leaders/O but/O never/O any/O of/O distinguished/O Americans/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O never/O seen/O Stalin/PERSON 's/O picture/O ,/O with/O the/O exception/O at/O the/O Embassy/O Auditorium/O and/O at/O the/O Shrine/O Auditorium/O at/O one/O time/O ./O 
The/O rest/O of/O the/O times/O our/O group/O always/O met/O at/O different/O homes/O and/O under/O different/O circumstances/O ./O 
We/O tried/O never/O to/O meet/O twice/O in/O the/O same/O place/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O say/O you/O saw/O a/O picture/O at/O the/O Shrine/O Auditorium/O ,/O is/O that/O when/O the/O Communists/O had/O rented/O the/O auditorium/O and/O were/O conducting/O the/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O if/O you/O misunderstood/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O misunderstand/O ,/O I/O wanted/O the/O record/O clear/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
If/O they/O had/O Stalin/PERSON 's/O picture/O on/O those/O occasions/O ,/O they/O must/O have/O had/O the/O picture/O of/O some/O President/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION right/O alongside/O ,/O did/O they/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
They/O may/O have/O ,/O but/O at/O the/O present/O time/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O would/O be/O apt/O to/O recall/O it/O ,/O would/O you/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O think/O I/O looked/O for/O the/O President/O 's/O picture/O to/O be/O there/O ,/O but/O if/O I/O did/O ,/O I/O would/O have/O ignored/O the/O President/O 's/O picture/O regardless/O of/O the/O circumstances/O because/O I/O have/O always/O considered/O the/O President/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION to/O be/O a/O wonderful/O person/O ,/O no/O matter/O who/O he/O was/O ,/O and/O thought/O his/O picture/O might/O have/O been/O misused/O ./O 
At/O one/O time/O I/O think/O Mr./O Truman/PERSON 's/O picture/O was/O up/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O where/O ./O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O think/O we/O have/O had/O any/O testimony/O in/O any/O place/O in/O the/O country/O that/O any/O picture/O of/O any/O great/O American/O was/O displayed/O in/O any/O Communist/O cell/O meeting/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O reason/O for/O my/O question/O ,/O even/O though/O the/O pictures/O of/O Soviet/O great/O men/O were/O prominently/O displayed/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Mr./O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON give/O you/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION assignments/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
The/O very/O first/O assignment/O Mr./O Houston/PERSON gave/O me/O was/O to/O attend/O a/O workers/O school/O ./O 
This/O school/O I/O did/O attend/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O conducted/O in/O a/O building/O on/O Third/O Street/O between/O Spring/O and/O Broadway/O ./O 
At/O the/O present/O time/O I/O do/O not/O know/O the/O name/O of/O this/O building/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O on/O the/O second/O floor/O ./O 
There/O were/O no/O markings/O on/O the/O doors/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O see/O a/O number/O of/O people/O in/O the/O evening/O going/O into/O these/O places/O ./O 
So/O I/O followed/O one/O of/O the/O bunches-that/O is/O ,/O one/O of/O the/O groups-and/O I/O went/O into/O this/O class/O ./O 
There/O were/O 10/O weeks/O of/O this/O Marxist/O class/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O instructors/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O class/O I/O attended/O ,/O sir/O ,/O was/O taught/O by/O a/O man/O named/O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON and/O he/O taught/O the/O advanced/O Marxist/O sciences/O ,/O as/O they/O called/O it/O ,/O or/O Communist/O program/O ,/O and-well/O ,/O they/O asked/O me/O a/O question/O and/O I/O felt/O kind/O of/O stupid/O because/O I/O did/O not/O know/O what/O they/O were/O talking/O about/O ./O 
They/O asked/O me/O how/O long/O had/O I/O been/O a/O Communist/O ,/O and/O I/O told/O them/O I/O had/O just/O joined/O and/O been/O assigned/O to/O this/O school/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O Did/O you/O ever/O learn/O Marxism/O or/O communism/O ?/O ''/O 
and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O You/O go/O across/O the/O hall/O and/O there/O is/O another/O teacher/O ,/O Emily/PERSON Gordon/PERSON ,/O and/O she/O will/O teach/O all/O the/O beginners/O ./O ''/O 
Then/O I/O attended/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O nine/O sessions/O under/O the/O tutelage/O of/O Miss/O Gordon/PERSON ./O 
1786/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O have/O any/O further/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O -/O struction/O or/O schooling/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O had/O about/O 35/O different/O classes/O that/O I/O attended/O during/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O describe/O them/O in/O just/O a/O general/O way/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
The/O Peoples/O Educational/O Center/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O that/O at/O the/O instruction/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O to/O go/O there/O by/O Emily/PERSON Gordon/PERSON andMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Was/O that/O school/O being/O operated/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O only/O way/O I/O could/O explain/O that/O to/O you/O ,/O sir/O ,/O to/O be/O frank/O ,/O is/O that/O they/O did/O not/O want/O to/O be/O known/O as/O Communists/O ,/O but/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION gave/O them/O all/O their/O papers/O ,/O all/O their/O typewriters/O ,/O all/O the/O equipment/O ,/O all/O the/O money/O ,/O and/O the/O teachers/O ./O 
That/O I/O know/O to/O be/O true/O ,/O sir/O ,/O because/O I/O helped/O transfer/O some/O of/O the/O typewriters/O and/O some/O of/O the/O instructive/O literature/O which/O were/O of/O Communist/O nature/O into/O this/O school/O ./O 
I/O believe/O there/O were/O two/O teachers/O there/O ./O 
One/O was/O known/O as/O William/PERSON Wolf/PERSON ./O 
They/O introduced/O him/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Then/O there/O was/O one/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON who/O was/O the/O other/O instructor/O that/O I/O met/O and/O I/O knew/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O you/O attended/O 35/O classes/O ./O 
Do/O you/O mean/O by/O that/O a/O different/O teaching/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
You/O see/O ,/O the/O policy/O of/O the/O party/O isthat/O is/O ,/O it/O was/O at/O that/O time-that/O Marxism/O and/O Leninism/O and/O bolshevism/O would/O be/O the/O prime/O and/O the/O only/O objective/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O there/O would/O be/O refresher/O courses/O that/O would/O average/O 4/O to/O 5/O a/O year/O and/O they/O would/O be/O ,/O say/O ,/O classes/O of/O 4/O ,/O classes/O of/O 5-that/O is/O ,/O a/O series/O of/O 4/O or/O 5/O is/O what/O I/O meant-and/O they/O ,/O especially/O the/O leadership/O ,/O would/O be/O instructed/O to/O attend/O these/O meetings/O ./O 
These/O meetings/O ordinarily/O were/O held/O by/O full-time/O county/O functionaries/O ,/O such/O as/O the/O educational/O directors/O or/O working/O from/O the/O educational/O director/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ,/O sometimes/O the/O State/O :/O and/O then/O there/O were/O functionaries/O '/O schools/O ,/O preparatory/O schools/O ./O 
To/O become/O a/O functionary/O ,/O I/O have/O attended/O some/O of/O those/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
They/O are/O too/O numerous/O to/O mention/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O all/O between/O the/O year/O of/O 1944/O ,/O January/O ,/O and/O 1948/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O the/O first/O of/O January/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O substantial/O difference/O in/O the/O type/O of/O instruction/O that/O was/O received/O from/O January/O 1944/O up/O until/O 1948/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
The/O classes/O that/O were/O conducted/O directly/O by/O the/O party/O were/O of/O more/O revolutionary/O nature/O than/O conducted/O by/O the/O Peoples/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Center/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O Peoples/O Educational/O Center/O class/O was/O sort/O of/O an/O introductory/O class/O to/O some/O who/O might/O be/O a/O prey/O or/O easy/O prey/O to/O communism/O ./O 
Eva/PERSON Shafran-she/PERSON is/O deceased/O at/O this/O time-she/O was/O a/O Russian/LOCATION citizen/O and/O here/O direct/O from/O Russia/LOCATION to/O teach/O this/O ./O 
Eva/PERSON Shafran/PERSON held/O some/O open/O classes/O to/O labor/O leaders/O and/O union/O members/O ./O 
I/O think/O this/O was/O at/O the/O second/O floor/O of/O the/O Embassy/O Auditorium/O ,/O prior/O to/O my/O actu/O -/O ally/O becoming/O a/O member/O ,/O during/O the/O time/O I/O tried/O to/O gain/O membership/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O any/O of/O those/O classes/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1787/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O these/O classes/O generally/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Most/O of/O the/O classes/O for/O the/O club/O members/O were/O held/O in/O homes/O of/O people/O who/O had/O been/O Marxists/O for/O quite/O a/O while/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O number/O of/O classes/O held/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Lou/PERSON Stark/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O recall/O his/O address/O ./O 
Then/O there/O were/O a/O number/O of/O classes/O held/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON ,/O Mike/PERSON Gorman-a/PERSON number/O of/O classes/O held/O at/O William/PERSON Kellas/PERSON '/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O stop/O you/O there/O a/O moment/O ./O 
In/O mentioning/O the/O names/O of/O these/O persons/O in/O whose/O homes/O the/O meetings/O were/O held/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O know/O whether/O you/O knew/O those/O people/O to/O be/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ,/O because/O these/O were/O all/O closed/O Communist/O affairs/O and/O you/O could/O not/O enter/O unless/O you/O were/O identified/O or/O you/O had/O some/O identification/O from/O the/O county/O as/O a/O representative/O ,/O you/O were/O the/O instructor/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Up/O to/O this/O point/O you/O have/O mentioned/O the/O name/O of/O Mr./O Louis/PERSON Stark/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION because/O I/O issued/O him/O ,/O I/O believe/O in/O the/O year/O 1946/O I/O issued/O the/O membership/O cards/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O that/O it/O is/O a/O record/O of/O the/O Government/O that/O I/O did/O issue/O that/O card/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O second/O person/O that/O you/O named/O in/O whose/O home/O these/O meetings/O were/O held/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O who/O the/O second/O one/O was/O ?/O 
Mr./O T/O \/O EREB/O ./O 
Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON or/O William/PERSON Kellas/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Both/O of/O those/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON was/O the/O membership/O director/O of/O our/O group/O throughout/O most/O of/O the/O time/O ./O 
We/O had/O what/O they/O called/O club/O internal/O strife/O ./O 
That/O is/O where/O your/O distrust/O of/O 1/O member/O of/O another/O and/O the/O accusation/O of/O 1member/O and/O another/O was/O continuous/O ./O 
We/O had/O continual/O turnover/O ./O 
Instead/O of/O a/O man/O serving/O in/O an/O office/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 1/O year/O that/O he/O was/O supposedly/O elected/O to/O ,/O he/O would/O probably/O serve/O 3/O or/O 4/O months/O and/O something/O would/O come/O along/O and/O they/O would/O change/O officers/O ./O 
Then/O the/O home/O of/O this/O William/PERSON Kellas/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O known/O to/O me/O as/O a/O chairman/O ,/O I/O believe/O on/O two/O occasions/O of/O our/O Communist/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O the/O spelling/O K-e-l-l-a-s/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O one/O question/O here/O ?/O 
A/O few/O moments/O ago/O you/O said/O that/O some/O of/O these/O classes/O were/O more/O revolutionary/O in/O their/O nature/O and/O instruction/O than/O others/O ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O saying/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O way/O do/O you/O use/O the/O term/O ``/O revolutionary/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O call/O one/O class/O event/O to/O your/O attention/O ,/O sir/O ,/O with/O your/O permission/O ?/O 
We/O had/O a/O teacher/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Elizabeth/PERSON LeichMr/PERSON ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Elizabeth/PERSON L-e-i-c-h/PERSON G-l-e-n-n/PERSON ./O 
This/O woman/O was/O sent/O Comto/PERSON us/O by/O the/O county/O educational/O committee/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION munist/O Party/ORGANIZATION Educational/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ./O 
She/O was/O sent/O to/O teach/O us/O Marxism/O and/O Leninism/O ,/O of/O course/O ./O 
During/O this/O class/O she/O spoke/O of/O the/O 1788/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O progress/O of/O Marxism/O and/O Leninism/O and/O how/O well/O it/O is/O and/O tried/O to/O sell/O the/O idea/O of/O the/O capitalists/O not/O owning/O tools/O and/O labor/O ,/O having/O just/O labor/O ,/O but/O the/O people/O should/O own/O everything/O and/O how/O eventually/O it/O would/O wind/O into/O an/O impossible/O situation/O ./O 
So/O one/O of/O the/O members/O of/O the/O class/O asked/O what/O she/O meant/O by/O that/O ./O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O Of/O course/O I/O mean/O that/O there/O would/O be/O a/O revolution/O ,/O ''/O and/O she/O said/O this/O revolution/O would/O come/O about/O and/O there/O would/O be/O many/O people/O hurt/O ,/O people/O get/O killed-including/O workers/O ;/O there/O would/O be/O an/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O ,/O confiscation/O of/O private/O property/O ./O 
This/O woman/O ,/O sir/O ,/O was/O an/O official/O teacher/O of/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O hear/O her/O say/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O sat/O there/O and/O heard/O her/O say/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O that/O occur/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O occurred/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Lou/PERSON Stark/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
About/O what/O year/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O say/O the/O year/O of/O 1945/O ,/O latter/O part/O of/O 1945/O or/O first/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O a/O closed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
About/O how/O many/O people/O were/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O have/O notes/O ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O to/O hear/O them/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
I/O believe/O I/O haveMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O mean/O to/O take/O over/O your/O examination/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O since/O you/O asked/O that/O question/O he/O should/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O interested/O in/O that/O one/O particular/O thing/O ,/O that/O particular/O revolutionary/O matter/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
He/O should/O be/O allowed/O to/O refresh/O his/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O notes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O make/O those/O notes/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O made/O them/O regularly/O right/O after/O the/O meeting/O at/O the/O present/O time/O after/O I/O severed/O my/O connection/O with/O the/O partyand/O did/O manage/O to/O keep/O out/O a/O few/O little/O things/O for/O myself/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O have/O Isome/O information/O which/O was/O not/O easy/O to/O get/O ./O 
I/O could/O give/O you/O this/O class/O and/O the/O people/O that/O were/O there/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O here/O it/O is/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O a/O date/O on/O those/O notes/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ,/O just/O general/O ;/O no/O dates/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O it/O shows/O his/O teaching/O was-I/O beg/O your/O pardon/O ./O 
It/O was/O 1947/O ,/O not/O 1946/O ./O 
when/O There/O were/O present/O at/O that/O time/O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON ,/O Vernon/PERSON Potter/PERSON ,/O Jack/PERSON Karson/PERSON Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON ,/O Lou/PERSON Stark/PERSON and/O his/O wife/O Mrs./O Marion/PERSON Stark/PERSON ./O 
Mike/PERSON Gorman/PERSON and/O Ed/PERSON Fitzgerald/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O Lillian/PERSON Frong/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Lillian/PERSON Frong/PERSON ,/O F-r-o-n-g/O ,/O and/O Sam/PERSON Chriss/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O spelling/O of/O Chriss/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
C-h-r-i-s-s/O ./O 
That/O is/O phonetic/O ,/O as/O close/O as/O I/O ever/O came/O to/O the/O correct/O spelling/O ./O 
Marion/PERSON Stark/PERSON is/O the/O first/O name/O of/O Mrs./O Stark/PERSON ./O 
Pauline/PERSON Sullivan/PERSON ,/O Ida/PERSON Karson/PERSON ,/O Chester/PERSON Fein/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
F-e-i-n/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEnEn/O ./O 
Correct/O ,/O sir/O ;/O Adrienne/PERSON Fein/PERSON ./O 
And/O a/O man/O known/O to/O me/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Mel/PERSON Wilkerson/PERSON at/O that/O meeting/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O one/O more/O question/O ,/O Counsel/O ./O 
At/O that/O particular/O class/O which/O you/O have/O mentioned/O when/O this/O woman/O was/O describing/O the/O revolutionary/O action/O that/O had/O to/O come/O or/O would/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1789/O come/O in/O her/O judgment/O ,/O what/O part/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O was/O the/O Communist/O membership/O to/O play/O in/O the/O revolution/O ?/O 
What/O were/O they/O to/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O to/O be/O the/O prime/O and/O the/O ruling/O factor/O of/O this/O revolution/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
They/O would/O guide/O it/O and/O that/O was/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O they/O said/O the/O only/O way/O it/O could/O be/O done/O is/O having/O enough/O people/O in/O the/O labor/O unions/O who/O were/O Marxist/O trained/O and/O Marxist/O and/O eninist/O education/O and/O had/O the/O Stalin/O spirit/O ,/O and/O those/O people/O were/O the/O people/O who/O would/O help/O put/O about/O tins/O program/O ./O 
That/O is/O at/O one/O of/O the/O classes/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O number/O of/O classes/O of/O this/O nature/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O there/O were/O a/O number/O of/O classes/O of/O this/O nature/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O there/O were/O ./O 
I/O also/O recall/O another/O class/O that/O was/O held/O at/O the/O home/O of/O William/PERSON Kellas/PERSON ./O 
This/O man/O Kellas/PERSON was/O known/O to/O me/O as/O a/O party/O member/O and/O by/O his/O own/O admission/O as/O far/O back/O as/O 1923/O or/O 1924/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O was/O known/O by/O a/O different/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O Kellas/PERSON was/O a/O very/O ,/O very/O well/O read/O and/O well/O educated/O Marxist/O and/O all/O his/O time/O and/O all/O his/O effort/O went/O into/O the/O Marxist/O education/O and/O teaching/O ./O 
He/O taught/O a/O class/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O refer/O to/O my/O notes/O as/O to/O when/O this/O was/O again/O ,/O but/O I/O will/O give/O you/O a/O general/O idea/O of/O what/O they/O called/O a/O cadre/O class/O ./O 
This/O cadre/O class/O ,/O I/O will/O manage/O to/O explain/O ,/O is/O a/O class/O who/O is/O taught/O leadership/O ./O 
He/O most/O naturally/O was/O questioned/O as/O to/O what/O this-well/O ,/O we/O only/O have/O one/O leadership/O ,/O but/O at/O the/O present/O time/O what/O is/O it/O ?/O 
-/O and/O he/O said/O this/O cadre/O class/O is/O for/O a/O leadership/O of/O five/O depth/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Five/O depth/O ./O 
Five/O labor/O chairmen/O ,/O five/O literature/O directors/O ,/O five/O of/O everything/O ./O 
If/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION decided/O or/O the/O Government/O decided/O to/O have/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION arrest/O these/O people/O for/O subversive/O activities/O or/O trouble/O came/O along/O ,/O the/O second/O group/O automatically/O would/O step/O right/O up/O ./O 
If/O the/O police/O or/O some/O other/O law-enforcement/O agency/O came/O along/O and/O arrested/O these/O people/O ,/O the/O third/O would/O function/O and/O so/O on/O down/O the/O line/O until/O the/O five/O were/O exhausted/O ,/O and/O by/O that/O time/O there/O would/O be/O a/O fruitful/O result/O of/O this/O turmoil/O that/O he/O was/O speaking/O of/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
They/O recognized/O ,/O then/O ,/O the/O possible/O illegality/O of/O their/O actions/O and/O their/O organization/O in/O setting/O up/O such/O an/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
They/O never/O doubted/O for/O one/O moment/O that/O they/O were/O an/O illegal/O and/O a/O revolutionary/O group/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
If/O they/O thought/O for/O one/O moment/O that/O any/O member/O in/O that/O group/O did/O not/O have/O revolutionary/O ideas/O or/O was/O not/O progressing/O well/O enough/O in/O his/O Marxist/O teaching/O or/O his/O revolutionary/O tendencies/O ,/O he/O did/O not/O stay/O very/O long/O ./O 
The/O party/O would/O manage/O to/O bounce/O him/O or/O kick/O him/O out/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
As/O I/O understand/O it/O ,/O right/O here/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O in/O Hawthorne/LOCATION and/O other/O places/O ,/O these/O Communist/O meetings/O and/O classes/O which/O you/O attended/O ,/O this/O doctrine/O and/O philosophy/O which/O you/O have/O related/O was/O openly/O taught/O in/O secret/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in/O August/O of/O 1946/O ./O 
I/O have/O that/O ./O 
I/O also/O have/O other/O classes/O to/O that/O effect/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O or/O 2/O years/O after/O Earl/PERSON Browder/PERSON was/O kicked/O out/O of/O the/O control/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION because/O he/O believed/O that/O the/O two/O systems/O of/O economy/O could/O get/O 65500-55/O --/O pt/O ./O 
4/O --/O 2/O 1790/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O along/O side/O by/O side/O in/O the/O world/O ./O 
Did/O n't/O you/O ever/O hear/O anyone/O object/O to/O that/O sort/O of/O philosophy/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O they/O should/O get/O along/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O this/O revolutionary/O philosophy/O ./O 
Did/O n't/O any/O of/O the/O American/O citizens/O present/O there/O ever/O object/O to/O that/O sort/O of/O instruction/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O with/O all/O apologies/O to/O this/O committee/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O believe/O a/O Communist/O could/O be/O a/O citizen/O of/O this/O country/O because/O I/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O his/O allegiance/O would/O be/O strong/O enough/O to/O call/O himself/O a/O citizen/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O agree/O with/O you/O ,/O but/O then/O I/O am/O asking/O you/O now/O the/O question/O :/O Did/O you/O ever/O hear/O any/O American/LOCATION citizen/O object/O to/O this/O sort/O of/O teaching/O in/O any/O of/O these/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O even/O question/O them/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O just/O as/O to/O procedure/O sometimes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O the/O procedure/O whereby/O they/O were/O teaching/O that/O it/O would/O be/O necessary/O to/O arm/O sometimes/O ,/O use/O arms/O and/O force/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
In/O order/O to/O use/O arms/O and/O force/O to/O shoot/O people/O ,/O including/O workers/O ,/O to/O have/O bloodshed/O you/O must/O have/O arms/O ./O 
The/O source/O of/O arms/O I/O never/O was/O told/O where/O it/O would/O come/O from/O ,/O just/O how/O it/O would/O come/O about/O ./O 
I/O was/O never/O given/O that/O information/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O sure/O there/O were/O others/O who/O did/O have/O that/O information/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O me/O to/O go/O on/O further/O with/O these/O classes/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O TA/O ENNER/O ./O 
Let/O me/O ask/O you/O a/O question/O at/O that/O point/O ./O 
You/O spoke/O of/O Elizabeth/PERSON Glenn/PERSON being/O one/O of/O the/O instructors/O sent/O down/O from/O a/O higher/O level/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
You/O have/O told/O us/O of/O the/O nature/O of/O the/O instructions/O she/O gave/O you/O ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O us/O anything/O further/O about/O the/O instruction/O that/O she/O gave/O your/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Elizabeth/PERSON Leich/PERSON Glenn/PERSON taught/O a/O series/O of/O different/O classes/O ./O 
I/O mentioned/O to/O you/O the/O last/O ,/O the/O most/O outstanding/O of/O all/O ,/O and/O she/O of/O course/O taught/O Marxism/O ,/O Leninism/O ,/O the/O works/O of/O Stalin/PERSON ,/O wages/O and/O price/O ,/O and/O actions/O of/O labor/O in/O strife/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O type/O of/O education/O she/O taught/O ./O 
There/O were/O others/O that/O taught/O something/O different/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
Proceed/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
We/O had/O another/O series/O of/O classes/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Dan/PERSON McComb/PERSON ./O 
M-c-C-o-m-b/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O see/O the/O spelling/O ./O 
This/O man/O I/O knew/O to/O be/O a/O good/O Marxist/O ,/O a/O good/O Commie/O ./O 
He/O worked/O hard/O for/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O he/O also/O served/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O Hawthorne/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION group/O and/O at/O his/O home/O we/O had/O a/O series/O of/O classes/O that/O was/O taught/O by/O a/O person/O named/O Harry/PERSON Hay/PERSON ./O 
This/O man/O Hay/PERSON also/O identified/O himself/O to/O the/O group/O as/O being/O sent/O to/O our/O club/O as/O a/O teacher/O of/O MarxismLeinism/O by/O the/O county/O educational/O committee/O ./O 
He/O said/O that/O he/O was/O from/O the/O Eagle/LOCATION Rock/LOCATION district/O ,/O and/O he/O also/O was/O an/O active/O Communist/O for/O a/O long/O time/O ./O 
This/O man/O spoke/O of/O the/O American/O system/O of/O elections/O whereby/O the/O American/O elections/O are/O just/O not/O right/O ;/O they/O could/O n't/O beit/O is/O a/O Fascist-like/O election/O system/O and/O it/O could/O not/O serve/O the/O masses/O ./O 
Hie/PERSON taught/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION had/O a/O plan/O ./O 
For/O example/O ,/O he/O would/O say/O the/O maritime/O union/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O Now/O there/O is/O a/O good/O example/O for/O you/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O SCIIERER/PERSON ./O 
What/O type/O of/O elections/O did/O he/O propose/O ?/O 
Mr./O WiuEE/O ./O 
The/O general/O elections/O of/O representatives/O like/O yourself/O sir/O ,/O Government/O elections/O ./O 
Mr./O SciiEnER/O ./O 
Wliat/O type/O of/O elections/O did/O he/O propose/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1791/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O coming/O to/O that/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
He/O said/O that/O you/O take/O your/O maritime/O union/O ,/O for/O example/O ,/O as/O a/O group/O ./O 
Those/O people/O are/O not/O in/O port/O most/O of/O the/O time/O ./O 
They/O are/O absent/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O some/O of/O the/O absentee/O ballots/O never/O get/O in/O ./O 
What/O the/O party/O proposed/O at/O that/O time/O was/O to/O have/O one/O man/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION vote/O as/O a/O block/O for/O the/O maritime/O union/O ./O 
They/O questioned/O him/O somewhat/O as/O to/O the/O possibility/O of/O that/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O that/O many/O places/O in/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION or/O in/O countries/O where/O they/O have/O a/O Bolshevik/O government/O such/O practices/O are/O common/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O instead/O of/O having/O the/O workers/O always/O come/O in/O and/O vote/O ,/O they/O have/O one/O man/O cast/O the/O ballot/O for/O them/O as/O a/O blanket/O ballot/O ./O 
That/O was/O one/O of/O the/O series/O of/O classes/O ./O 
I/O have/O more/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O advocate/O any/O other/O system/O of/O voting/O ?/O 
Mr./O TEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O system/O whereby/O one/O man/O votes/O for/O a/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O advocate/O the/O proportional/O representation/O system/O of/O voting/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O a/O Fascist/O idea/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Proportional/O representation/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O if/O you/O took/O a/O man/O from/O a/O certain/O district/O because/O he/O represented/O that/O district/O ,/O that/O was/O not/O any/O good/O ;/O that/O was/O a/O reactionary/O idea/O ./O 
But/O as/O one/O man/O ,/O they/O would/O manage/O to/O pick/O and/O appoint/O and/O elect/O ./O 
Is/O that/O what/O you/O had/O reference/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O think/O you/O quite/O understand/O what/O I/O mean/O by/O proportional/O representation/O system/O of/O voting/O ,/O so/O I/O will/O just/O withdraw/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O one/O question/O along/O a/O different/O line/O ?/O 
I/O do/O not/O know/O what/O your/O answer/O may/O be/O because/O I/O have/O never/O discussed/O it/O with/O you/O ./O 
What/O did/O you/O see/O ,/O if/O anything/O ,/O in/O activity/O for/O or/O with/O children/O and/O young/O people/O ,/O the/O teen-age/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ?/O 
Did/O you/O come/O in/O touch/O with/O that/O phase/O of/O the/O activities/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
If/O so/O ,/O what/O did/O you/O learn/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
The/O only/O phase/O of/O that/O I/O know/O ,/O sir/O ,/O is/O that/O they/O had/O one/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Mayer/PERSON Frieden/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O his/O last/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
F-r-i-e-d-e-n/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
The/O Mayer/PERSON would/O be/O phonetic/O ,/O M-e-y-e-r/O or/O M-a-v-e-r/O ,/O I/O would/O not/O know/O ./O 
He/O had/O charge/O of/O the/O youth/O group/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O Young/ORGANIZATION Communist/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O became/O American/O Youth/O for/O Democracy/O ./O 
They/O tossed/O it/O around/O for/O some/O other/O name/O ./O 
I/O visited/O their/O office/O once/O or/O twice/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O not/O recall/O that/O II/O was/O too/O busy/O with/O other/O assignments/O to/O get/O into/O the/O youth/O group/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Our/O hearings/O all/O over/O the/O country/O show/O they/O very/O actively/O endeavored/O to/O get/O activity/O among/O American/O youth/O and/O interest/O ./O 
In/O fact/O they/O established/O camps/O known/O as/O a/O pioneer/O group/O to/O counteract/O the/O influence/O of/O the/O Boy/O Scouts/O and/O Girl/O Scouts/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O because/O they/O were/O asked-I/O remember/O that/O they/O impressed/O the/O classes/O ,/O especially/O on/O members/O ,/O to/O have/O their/O children-at/O that/O time/O their/O policy/O was/O a/O little/O different/O ./O 
They/O would/O shift/O their/O policy/O at/O will/O any/O way/O they/O liked/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O the/O policy/O was/O to/O get/O them/O into/O the/O YMCA/ORGANIZATION ,/O YWCA/O ,/O church/O groups-any/O groups/O whereby/O they/O could/O influence/O ./O 
In/O fact/O ,/O we/O ,/O the/O senior/O members/O of/O the/O organization/O ,/O also/O were/O requested/O to/O do/O so/O regardless/O of/O under/O what/O guise/O ./O 
It/O did/O not/O make/O any/O difference/O ./O 
We/O had/O a/O man/O by/O the/O name/O of/O George/PERSON Sandy/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O a/O full-time/O functionary/O for/O the/O party/O ,/O I/O guess/O during/O the/O WPA/O days/O and/O up/O ./O 
This/O 1792/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O man/O and/O I/O had/O personal/O meetings/O ./O 
,/O At/O the/O county/O offices/O we/O had/O meetings/O together/O ./O 
He/O met/O with/O our/O group/O a/O number/O of/O times/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O Now/O you/O Communists/O ,/O you/O have/O got/O one/O job/O to/O do-it/O does/O not/O make/O a/O bit/O of/O difference/O under/O what/O guise-you/O get/O into/O the/O general/O public/O ,/O get/O there/O ./O 
If/O you/O have/O to/O pick/O on/O a/O sewer/O bond/O issue/O ,/O pick/O on/O it/O ;/O go/O from/O house/O to/O house/O ./O 
Do/O n't/O tell/O them/O you/O are/O a/O Communist/O ,/O tell/O them/O you/O are/O a/O citizen/O and/O you/O are/O interested/O ,/O until/O you/O are/O well/O enough/O known/O whereby/O you/O can/O run/O for/O city/O council/O or/O whatever/O office/O that/O the/O public/O might/O think/O that/O you/O are/O fit/O for/O ./O ''/O 
And/O that/O was/O the/O program/O at/O one/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
I/O must/O not/O take/O more/O of/O the/O counsel/O 's/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O right/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ;/O it/O helps/O develop/O the/O picture/O ./O 
You/O were/O describing/O these/O various/O classes/O which/O you/O attended/O ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O said/O there/O were/O still/O others/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O there/O were/O ./O 
If/O you/O will/O excuse/O me/O a/O moment/O ,/O I/O do/O have/O one/O more/O I/O jotted/O down/O here/O that/O I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O the/O committee/O 's/O attention/O to/O ,/O to/O one/O other/O class/O here/O ./O 
Elizabeth/PERSON Leich/PERSON Glenn/PERSON had/O a/O series/O of/O classes/O with/O us/O and/O she/O spoke/O of/O manpower/O ./O 
She/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O it/O is/O hardly/O possible/O to/O recruit/O that/O many/O men/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O or/O into/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION group/O that/O would/O be/O a/O strong/O manpower/O group/O ./O ''/O 
Therefore/O ,/O she/O said/O ,/O that/O the/O party/O proposed/O to/O split/O this/O Nation/O into/O two/O nations/O ,/O creating/O a/O nation/O of/O the/O Negroes/O separate/O from/O the/O whites/O ./O 
This/O Negro/O nation/O who/O ,/O according/O to/O her/O words/O ,/O were/O an/O oppressed/O group/O ,/O would/O be/O very/O easy/O prey/O or/O very/O easy/O subjects/O to/O this/O manpower/O proposition/O that/O they/O had/O in/O mind/O ./O 
Now/O she/O spoke/O of/O this/O at/O two/O separate/O classes/O ,/O and/O all/O of/O a/O sudden/O it/O disappeared/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O why/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O read/O this/O in/O some/O other/O Communist/O literature/O previous/O to/O that/O time/O ./O 
Somehow/O or/O other/O all/O of/O a/O sudden/O a/O little/O fight/O over/O the/O thing/O and/O that/O was/O the/O last/O of/O it/O and/O we/O could/O not/O follow/O it/O up/O ./O 
In/O my/O position/O you/O could/O not/O ask/O too/O many/O questions/O ;/O you/O observed/O and/O partook/O in/O different/O things/O ./O 
This/O Negro/O nation/O was/O a/O very/O serious/O move/O at/O one/O time/O in/O other/O clubs/O because/O I/O knew/O other/O people/O in/O other/O clubs/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Negroes/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O properly/O so/O ,/O immediately/O rose/O up/O against/O any/O idea/O of/O segregation/O ./O 
That/O was/O just/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O they/O immediately/O abandoned/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREn/O ./O 
We/O had/O no/O Negroes/O in/O our/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O the/O testimony/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ./O 
was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O had/O testimony/O in/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O Milwaukee/LOCATION ,/O and/O a/O number/O of/O places/O on/O this/O subject/O ./O 
The/O estimate/O that/O Elizabeth/PERSON Glenn/PERSON gave/O that/O the/O Negro/O people/O would/O be/O an/O easy/O prey/O was/O found/O out/O not/O to/O be/O at/O all/O prophetic/O or/O correct/O ./O 
A/O great/O deal/O of/O evidence/O has/O been/O introduced/O showing/O that/O they/O met/O no/O substantial/O measure/O of/O success/O with/O the/O persons/O of/O the/O Negro/O race/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
The/O evidence/O is/O overwhelming/O that/O they/O resisted/O attempts/O to/O infiltrate/O groups/O almost/O better/O than/O any/O other/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
In/O many/O areas/O that/O has/O been/O the/O burden/O of/O the/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O add/O this/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O that/O the/O Negroes/O that/O I/O know/O and/O have/O known/O over/O the/O period/O of/O years/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION An/LOCATION -/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1793/O geles/O were/O all/O fine/O ,/O upstanding/O citizens/O ./O 
With/O the/O exception/O of/O very/O few/O ,/O say/O nine/O during/O my/O whole/O time/O of/O membership/O in/O the/O party-and/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O they/O stayed/O very/O long-I/O do/O not/O believe/O that/O I/O have/O known/O any/O Negro/O or/O person/O of/O the/O Negro/O race/O who/O was/O a/O willing/O prey/O or/O would/O accept/O such/O a/O policy/O at/O all/O ./O 
They/O were/O too/O busy/O trying/O to/O make/O their/O own/O way/O and/O trying/O to/O better/O themselves/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O appropriate/O ,/O perhaps/O ,/O for/O me/O to/O just/O refer/O to/O one/O paragraph/O at/O this/O point/O in/O view/O of/O the/O witness/O 's/O testimony/O about/O revolutionary/O methods/O ./O 
I/O read/O a/O couple/O of/O paragraphs/O of/O this/O decision/O the/O other/O day/O ./O 
This/O is/O the/O decision/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/LOCATION America/LOCATION v./O Title/O -LRB-/O 17,368/O -RRB-/O ,/O civil/O opinion/O by/O the/O Honorable/O Judge/O of/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION in/O this/O very/O building/O on/O June/O 4,1955/O ,/O Leon/PERSON R./PERSON Yankwich/PERSON ,/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION District/O Judge/O ,/O in/O which/O a/O defendant/O admitted/O he/O had/O been/O a/O Communist/O and/O was/O a/O Communist/O ,/O and/O he/O introduced/O the/O constitution/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O part/O of/O his/O defense/O ,/O by/O the/O way/O ,/O to/O the/O court/O ./O 
The/O court/O in/O this/O case/O said/O ,/O among/O other/O things/O :/O How/O anyone/O can/O find/O in/O themreferring/O to/O the/O literatuie/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION used/O by/O the/O American/O Communist/O Phrtyany/O advocacy/O of/O lawful/O means/O for/O effectuating/O the/O aims/O of/O communism/O or/O even/O lip/O service/O to/O democratic/O institutions/O is/O beyond/O our/O comprehension/O ,/O for/O there/O is/O none/O ./O 
As/O appears/O more/O fully/O from/O other/O writings/O by/O Lenin/PERSON which/O are/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O in/O one/O he/O states/O that/O the/O proletarian/O state/O can/O only/O be/O achieved/O ``/O through/O a/O violent/O revolution/O ./O ''/O 
This/O is/O repeated/O elsewhere/O ./O 
The/O Sixth/O World/O Congress/O of/O the/O Communist/O International/O 's/O held/O in/O 1928/O states/O emphatically/O that/O Leninism/O is/O the/O dominant/O approach/O on/O that/O -/O ``/O the/O overthrow/O of/O capitalism/O is/O impossible/O without/O force/O ,/O without/O armed/O uprising/O and/O proletarian/O wars/O against/O the/O bourgeosie/O ./O ''/O 
This/O interpretation/O is/O adopted/O by/O Stalin/PERSON ,/O who/O expresses/O it/O in/O this/O manner/O :/O ``/O The/O dictatorship/O of/O the/O proletariat/O is/O a/O revolutionary/O power/O based/O on/O the/O use/O of/O force/O against/O the/O bourgeosie/O ''/O I/O read/O that/O into/O the/O record/O and/O I/O repeat/O that/O which/O I/O have/O often/O repeated/O In/O this/O hearing/O and/O elsewhere/O :/O I/O do/O not/O see/O how/O any/O patriotic/O American/O since/O 1944/O or/O 1945/O could/O possibly/O have/O been/O an/O active/O participant/O in/O Communist/O cell/O meetings/O such/O as/O you/O attended/O ,/O sir/O ,/O without/O knowing/O that/O the/O primary/O objective/O or/O intention/O ,/O whenever/O it/O suited/O their/O convenience/O ,/O was/O to/O build/O up/O a/O philosophy/O that/O the/O American/O working/O people/O were/O justified/O in/O using/O force/O against/O constitutional/O government/O ./O 
I/O repeat/O it/O now/O ./O 
I/O just/O have/O never/O understood/O how/O a/O patriotic/O American/O could/O do/O that/O if/O he/O ever/O learned/O of/O that/O objective/O ./O 
The/O court/O in/O this/O case/O says/O ,/O and/O we/O know/O it/O ,/O that/O the/O Communist/O literature/O advocated/O that/O and/O still/O does/O ./O 
Mr./O TAENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wereb/PERSON ,/O what/O positions/O have/O you/O held/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
as/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O held/O various/O positions/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O was/O for/O a/O short/O time/O ,/O dipress/O I/O said/O ,/O membership/O director/O and/O Peoples/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION director/O ,/O the/O all/O to/O rector/O ,/O literature/O director/O ;/O I/O was/O a/O functionary/O delegate/O indusfunctionaries/O conventions/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O delegate/O to/O the/O Southwest/LOCATION have/O to/O look/O ./O 
It/O trial/O section/O and-gosh/O ,/O it/O has/O been/O so/O long/O I/O almost/O district/O also/O committee/O ;/O executive/O the/O was/O plenty/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O member/O of/O sir/O ./O 
manager/O for/O the/O Peoples/O World/O in/O the/O Southwest/LOCATION section/O ,/O Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O all/O this/O time/O you/O were/O an/O FBI/ORGANIZATION operator/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
paid/O inMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O I/O suppose/O you/O would/O be/O classified/O as/O a/O former/O or/O stoolpigeon/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ?/O 
1794/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O called/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O complment/O you/O for/O doing/O the/O job/O you/O did/O ,/O whether/O you/O were/O paid/O or/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Might/O I/O add/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O sir/O ,/O that/O I/O never/O was/O paid/O a/O salary/O by/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O had/O ,/O or/O rather/O I/O would/O put/O out/O and/O put/O all/O bills/O ahead/O of/O time/O ,/O made/O donations/O out/O of/O my/O own/O pocket/O to/O Communist/ORGANIZATION drives/O ,/O paper/O drives/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O drives/O ,/O defense/O drives/O ,/O out/O of/O my/O own/O pocket/O ./O 
I/O was/O reimbursed/O by/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION after/O I/O had/O given/O a/O statement/O to/O that/O effect/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Only/O your/O expenses/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O received/O 10/O cents/O worth/O of/O salary/O at/O any/O time/O from/O anyone/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O congratulate/O you/O more/O than/O ever/O if/O that/O is/O the/O case/O ./O 
I/O supposed/O you/O were/O paid/O a/O little/O something/O for/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WELEB/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O my/O freedom/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
and/O the/O honor/O of/O calling/O myself/O an/O American/LOCATION citizen/O is/O pay/O enough/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wereb/PERSON ,/O I/O asked/O you/O at/O -/O an/O earlier/O point/O in/O your/O testimony/O what/O security/O measures/O were/O taken/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O make/O sure/O of/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time-I/O am/O trying/O to/O find/O the/O exact/O time-two/O people/O came/O to/O my/O home/O ;/O one/O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O find/O the/O name/O of/O the/O other/O person/O ./O 
It/O was/O one/O evening/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O very/O anxious/O to/O give/O you/O the/O name/O of/O that/O person/O ./O 
Just/O one/O second/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O have/O it/O among/O a/O lot/O of/O these/O notes/O here/O ./O 
Elsie/PERSON Monjar/PERSON ./O 
At/O one/O time/O she/O also/O ran/O for/O city/O council/O ./O 
The/O Communist/O label/O did/O not/O do/O so/O good/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O city/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O sir/O ./O 
These/O two/O people/O came/O to/O my/O home/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Pete/PERSON ,/O what/O are/O you/O doing/O in/O the/O party/O ?/O ''/O 
That/O is/O not/O a/O very/O easy/O question/O to/O answer/O ,/O especially/O when/O you/O know/O that/O you/O are/O under/O a/O sham/O ,/O you/O are/O living/O a/O life/O other/O than/O what/O you/O really/O believe/O in/O ./O 
I/O made/O them/O explain/O just/O what/O they/O meant/O by/O it/O ./O 
I/O asked/O them/O a/O question/O on/O a/O question/O ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O John/PERSON ,/O do/O you/O have/O to/O be/O a/O bum/O to/O be/O a/O Communist/O ?/O ''/O 
That/O question/O kind/O of/O backed/O him/O down/O a/O little/O bit/O ./O 
They/O wanted/O to/O know/O all/O my/O progressive/O record/O ,/O shall/O we/O say/O ;/O again/O this/O bandied/O word/O of/O progressivism/O ./O 
I/O told/O them/O a/O story/O that/O happened/O to/O me/O when/O I/O was/O a/O young/O boy/O ./O 
It/O was/O of/O no/O consequence/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O a/O sales/O idea/O and/O it/O went/O over/O ./O 
I/O invited/O them/O to/O examine/O my/O home/O ,/O see/O if/O there/O were/O any/O police/O or/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION documents/O about/O ./O 
I/O just/O told/O them/O how/O ,/O gave/O them/O a/O real/O sad/O sob/O story/O ./O 
After/O them/O making/O me/O promise/O an/O allegiance/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O to/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION ,/O they/O left/O satisfied/O and/O I/O stayed/O on/O in/O my/O regular/O way/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O 21/O harrowing/O \//O 2/O hours/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O question/O raised/O about/O your/O wife/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O questions/O that/O did/O not/O seem/O to/O have/O a/O satisfactory/O answer/O in/O their/O mind/O was/O why/O my/O wife/O was/O not/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
My/O wife/O is/O a/O very/O good/O church/O member/O ,/O a/O very/O devout/O person/O ./O 
and/O it/O was/O a/O very/O hard/O thing/O to/O think/O one/O up/O ,/O so/O I/O said/O she/O had/O a/O very/O serious/O nerve/O disorder/O ,/O and/O therefore/O for/O the/O security/O of/O the/O party/O in/O my/O judgment/O she/O should/O not/O be/O a/O member/O ./O 
That/O was/O accepted/O ./O 
Now/O to/O give/O you/O a/O point/O of/O just/O how/O far/O they/O drove/O this/O security/O ,/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Bronson/PERSON Parrett/PERSON and/O Fern/PERSON Parrett/PERSON ,/O active/O Communists/O -/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1795/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Spell/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
P-a-r-r-o-t/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O would/O have/O to/O check/O ./O 
Would/O it/O be/O all/O right/O if/O I/O check/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O think/O you/O should/O make/O certain/O as/O to/O the/O spelling/O of/O the/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O try/O the/O best/O I/O can/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
He/O also/O was/O at/O one/O time/O chairman/O of/O our/O group/O ./O 
P-a-r-r-e-t-t/O ,/O B-r-o-n-s-o-n/O ./O 
His/O wife/O was/O Fern/PERSON Parrett/PERSON ./O 
Now/O at/O one/O time/O he/O got/O into/O difficulty/O with/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
We/O understand/O that/O there/O may/O be/O a/O little/O different/O spelling/O to/O that/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
There/O might/O be/O ,/O sir/O ,/O but/O that/O is/O as/O close/O as/O I/O can/O give/O at/O the/O present/O time/O ./O 
I/O still/O have/O n't/O found/O the/O name/O ./O 
Would/O you/O mind/O if/O I/O looked/O up/O the/O name/O and/O spelled/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O you/O can/O give/O it/O to/O us/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O tried/O to/O get/O these/O names/O correctly/O ./O 
I/O have/O an/O awful/O lot/O of/O names/O here/O ./O 
P-a-r-r-e-t-t/O ,/O Parrett/PERSON ./O 
His/O wife/O ,/O Fern/PERSON Parrett/PERSON ./O 
This/O man/O got/O into/O a/O difficulty/O of/O some/O type/O with/O the/O Communist/O leadership/O at/O the/O higher/O levels/O ./O 
He/O kept/O writing/O back/O to/O the/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION office/O continually/O and/O that/O was/O objected/O to/O by/O the/O local/O group/O here-that/O is/O ,/O the/O county/O group/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O he/O was/O tried/O by/O the/O Communist/O security/O group/O and/O banned/O from/O the/O party/O ./O 
His/O wife/O stayed/O on/O ./O 
They/O approached/O his/O wife/O within/O a/O few/O days/O of/O the/O time/O they/O approached/O meMr/O ./O 
SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O interrupt/O ?/O 
Did/O you/O ever/O attend/O one/O of/O the/O trials/O or/O hearings/O where/O members/O were/O barred/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O I/O have/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O but/O at/O this/O time/O I/O would/O like/O to/O leave/O that/O for/O a/O little/O later/O because/O it/O would/O confuse/O this/O thought/O of/O mine/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
They/O went/O to/O this/O woman/O and/O told/O her/O that/O unless/O she/O divorced/O her/O husband/O they/O would/O have/O to/O bounce/O her/O from/O the/O party/O or/O kick/O her/O out/O ./O 
The/O woman/O being/O a/O real/O Communist/O ,/O as/O she/O called/O herself/O ,/O did/O divorce/O her/O husband/O ./O 
That/O was/O not/O the/O only/O instance/O ./O 
There/O were/O many/O instances/O like/O it/O where/O they/O thought/O that/O the/O security/O of/O the/O party/O was/O affected/O by/O both/O man/O and/O wife/O not/O being/O members/O ;/O and/O if/O both/O did/O not/O wish/O to/O be/O members/O ,/O none/O of/O them/O could/O be/O members/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O if/O both/O did/O not/O want/O to/O become/O members/O of/O the/O conspiracy/O ,/O break/O up/O the/O home/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O home/O is/O the/O most/O important/O unit/O we/O have/O in/O our/O Nation/O of/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Break/O them/O up/O for/O the/O sake/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O is/O their/O philosophy/O ,/O if/O need/O be/O ,/O to/O further/O their/O conspiratorial/O aims/O ,/O dastardly/O objectives/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O at/O one/O time/O ,/O to/O answer/O your/O question/O ,/O Congressman/O ,/O that/O I/O attended/O a/O meeting-I/O did/O not/O get/O into/O all/O of/O the/O meeting/O because/O someone/O called/O me/O out/O as/O to/O the/O progress/O of/O the/O Peoples/O World/O drive/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O believe/O it/O was/O one/O Alice/PERSON Ward/PERSON ./O 
She/O called/O me/O out/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O they/O were/O trying/O one/O Lou-a/O man/O from/O Watts/LOCATION ./O 
I/O believe/O he/O also/O appeared/O in/O a/O number/O of/O Smith/PERSON cases/O ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O place/O his/O last/O name/O but/O it/O slips/O my/O mind/O a/O second/O ./O 
I/O did/O attend/O one/O of/O those/O farce/O trials/O ,/O a/O cut/O and/O dried/O affair/O ./O 
He/O 1796/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O was/O an/O enemy/O of/O the/O workers-they/O classified/O him/O so/O ./O 
Secret/O literature/O was/O made/O up/O to/O the/O effect/O and/O it/O was/O dispatched/O to/O each/O club/O that/O no/O one/O should/O speak/O ,/O contact/O him/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O shape/O ,/O manner/O ,/O or/O form/O on/O any/O business/O because/O he/O had/O contact/O with/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION or/O the/O police/O department/O or/O that/O he/O was/O an/O enemy/O of/O the/O working/O classes/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O individual/O 's/O name/O Lou/PERSON Rosser/PERSON Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O know/O the/O man/O by/O seeing/O him/O ./O 
I/O did/O not/O recall/O his/O name/O ,/O but/O that/O is/O an/O outstanding/O event/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Lou/PERSON Rosser/PERSON was/O blacklisted/O from/O obtaining/O any/O employment/O in/O certain/O areas/O ,/O was/O he/O not/O ,/O or/O am/O I/O wrong/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O believe/O I/O should/O comment/O on/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O his/O testimony/O very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Was/O not/O Mr./O Rosser/PERSON a/O Negro/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O prevented/O from/O getting/O employment/O ,/O he/O testified/O ,/O because/O of/O his/O breaking/O with/O the/O party/O ./O 
They/O attempted/O to/O discredit/O him/O with/O even/O non-Communist/O employers/O ./O 
I/O remember/O the/O testimony/O very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O failed/O to/O ask/O you/O a/O question/O I/O intended/O to/O ask/O you/O ./O 
When/O you/O were/O discussing/O these/O educational/O classes/O which/O you/O attended-I/O want/O to/O go/O back/O and/O pick/O it/O up-you/O told/O the/O committee/O about/O instruction/O that/O was/O received/O when/O Mr./O Harry/PERSON Hay/PERSON came/O to/O your/O club/O as/O a/O teacher/O sent/O from/O the/O educational/O commission/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O whether/O you/O told/O us/O where/O that/O meeting/O was/O held/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O meeting/O was/O held/O on/O Yukon/LOCATION Street/LOCATION at/O the/O home/O of/O Dan/PERSON and/O Eleanor/PERSON McComb/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O their/O home/O ./O 
The/O whole/O series/O of/O classes/O held/O by/O this/O Harry/PERSON Hay/PERSON was/O conducted/O at/O that/O address/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O I/O failed/O to/O ask/O you/O is/O :/O Who/O were/O present/O at/O that/O meeting/O ,/O if/O you/O can/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O again/O have/O to/O refer/O to/O my/O notes/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
By/O the/O way/O ,/O these/O are/O my/O own/O notes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O ask/O who/O were/O present/O ,/O I/O mean/O what/O persons/O as/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION were/O present/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O will/O be/O happy/O to/O give/O you/O that/O ./O 
There/O were/O John/PERSON Houston/PERSON ,/O Vernon/PERSON Potter/PERSON ,/O JackKarson/O ,/O Edith/PERSON Smith/PERSON ,/O Lou/PERSON Stark/PERSON ,/O Mike/PERSON Gorman/PERSON ,/O G-o-r-m-a-n/O ./O 
John/PERSON Baldo/PERSON ,/O B-a-l-d-o/O ;/O Ed/PERSON Fitzgerald/PERSON ;/O Lillian/PERSON Frong/PERSON ;/O Laura/PERSON Lee/PERSON Musick/PERSON ,/O M-u-s-i-c-k/O ;/O Edwin/PERSON Hagen/PERSON ,/O H-a-g-e-n/O ;/O Dan/PERSON McComb/PERSON ;/O Ellen/PERSON Taylor/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Mary/PERSON Rankin/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O present/O time/O I/O believe/O that/O is/O all/O I/O have/O as/O to/O that/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O the/O spellings/O which/O you/O have/O given/O phonetic/O spellings/O ?/O 
Mr./O WTERE/PERSON ./O 
Some/O may/O be/O ,/O sir/O ,/O but/O some/O are/O not/O ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O spellings/O I/O have/O which/O are/O correct/O would/O be/O the/O spellings/O that/O I/O have/O taken/O while/O I/O was/O membership-that/O is/O ,/O the/O Peoples/O World/O district/O manager/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O would/O have/O to/O have/O some/O type/O of/O a/O spelling/O which/O was/O near/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
9/O Did/O you/O give/O a/O phonetic/O spelling/O for/O the/O name/O Laura/PERSON Lee/PERSON Musick/PERSON COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1797/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O would/O be/O spelled/O M-u-s-i-c-k/O ,/O but/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O some/O of/O the/O spellings/O in/O my/O mind/O are/O phonetic/O ,/O sir/O ,/O and/O they/O are/O very/O ,/O very/O hard/O to/O place/O at/O the/O present/O time/O as/O to/O the/O exact/O spelling/O ./O 
I/O will/O try/O my/O very/O best/O and/O honest/O best/O to/O give/O you/O the/O nearest/O I/O possibly/O can/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O want/O to/O be/O as/O accurate/O about/O it/O as/O we/O can/O ./O 
The/O name/O Edwin/PERSON Hagen/PERSON ,/O as/O to/O the/O spelling/O of/O that/O name/O ,/O I/O am/O wondering/O whether/O it/O is/O a/O phonetic/O spelling/O you/O were/O giving/O or/O whether/O it/O was/O what/O you/O thought/O was/O the/O true/O spelling/O of/O the/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O a/O true/O spelling/O as/O far/O as/O I/O knew/O because/O Mr./O Hagen/PERSON came/O to/O my/O home/O a/O number/O of/O times/O and/O I/O have/O read/O a/O number/O of/O letters/O that/O were/O addressed/O to/O him/O by/O that/O name/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O just/O copied/O that/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O us/O see/O if/O we/O can/O give/O some/O further/O identifying/O facts/O about/O that/O individual/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Edwin/PERSON Hagen/PERSON was/O a/O refugee/O from/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O a/O Communist-banned/O refugee/O ./O 
He/O was/O banned/O into/O Holland/LOCATION ,/O and/O Holland/LOCATION I/O guess/O deported/O him/O as/O an/O undesirable/O ./O 
They/O deported/O him/O to/O Sweden/LOCATION ./O 
These/O are/O all/O according/O to/O his/O stories/O to/O me/O which/O were/O verified/O by/O his/O wife/O whom/O I/O met/O at/O one/O time/O and/O they/O laughed/O over/O it/O ./O 
Then/O Sweden/LOCATION deported/O him/O to/O Canada/LOCATION ./O 
He/O stayed/O a/O very/O short/O time/O in/O Canada/LOCATION and/O he/O was/O deported/O into/O Mexico/LOCATION and/O from/O Mexico/LOCATION he/O came/O to/O this/O country/O ,/O and/O under/O what/O circumstances/O I/O never/O did/O find/O out/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O where/O he/O lived/O Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O to/O his/O home/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O he/O no/O longer/O lives/O there/O ./O 
He/O lived/O in/O Inglewood/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O also/O a/O very/O ,/O very/O close/O friend/O ofMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O would/O not/O speak/O of/O other/O persons/O unless/O those/O other/O persons/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
They/O are/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O she/O was/O the/O head/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O the/O time/O of/O Hagen/PERSON 's/O last/O disappearance/O and/O that/O was-she/O was/O one/O of/O the/O Smith/O cases/O with/O Schneiderman/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O Dorothy/PERSON Healy/PERSON ./O 
I/O met/O him/O a/O number/O of/O times/O at/O her/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O you/O have/O told/O us/O that/O this/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O was/O the/O Hawthorne/PERSON group/O ./O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O who/O were/O the/O officers/O of/O that/O group/O from/O time/O to/O time/O as/O far/O as/O you/O can/O now/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
Would/O it/O be/O permissible/O to/O read/O that/O ?/O 
I/O had/O that/O prepared/O because/O it/O is/O hard/O from/O memory/O to/O remember/O all/O the/O names/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O that/O statement/O you/O have/O a/O statement/O which/O you/O made/O at/O the/O time/O of/O your/O reports/O to/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WEREB/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
These/O are/O all/O bona/O fide/O accepted/O names/O as/O Communists/O whom/O I/O have/O known/O and/O met/O at/O closed/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O and/O Communist/O functions/O and/O classes/O and/O functionary/O meetings/O ./O 
These/O people/O could/O not/O have/O attended/O any/O of/O these/O doings/O unless/O they/O were/O members/O in/O good/O standing/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
