INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 1/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-THIRD/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O MARCH/O 23/O ,/O 24/O ,/O AND/O 25/O ,/O 1953/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Un-Amercan/ORGANIZATION Activities/ORGANIZATION INCLUDING/ORGANIZATION INDEX/ORGANIZATION 0/O ``/O 1117/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1953/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUBE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O HAROLD/PERSON H/PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION ,/O Chairmsan/PERSON FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION MORGAN/LOCATION M./LOCATION MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION KIT/LOCATION CLARDY/LOCATION ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/O B/O ,/O FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION ROBERT/PERSON L./PERSON KUNZIG/PERSON ,/O Counsel/O FRANK/PERSON S/PERSON TAVENNER/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O Counsel/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON RUssELL/PERSON ,/O Chief/O Isvestsgator/O THOMAS/PERSON W./PERSON BEALE/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O Chtef/O Clerk/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O II/O ./O 
CONTENTS/O March/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Page/O Testimony/O ofDanny/O Dare/O _/O _/O .../O ./O 
./O 
__/O -----------/O _/O ./O 
------------------/O ./O 
268/O Harold/PERSON Adolph/PERSON Hecht/PERSON .../O _/O ------------/O ./O 
--/O .../O -----------/O ./O 
293/O Edward/PERSON Heubseh/PERSON ./O 
__/O ------/O __/O --/O .../O _/O --/O _/O ./O 
./O 
__/O ./O 
317/O Philip/PERSON Dey/PERSON Eastman/PERSON --/O .../O ./O 
-/O ./O 
./O 
_/O ./O 
./O 
__/O -/O ___/O .../O -319/O March/O 24/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O ofJulian/O Gordon/PERSON --/O ./O 
-------/O _/O .../O .../O .../O .../O .../O -/O .../O 327/O David/PERSON A./PERSON Lang/PERSON ----------------------------------------/O 336/O Max/PERSON Nathan/PERSON Benoff/PERSON ./O 
.../O ./O 
____________/O .../O .../O 355/O Francis/PERSON Edward/PERSON Faragoh/PERSON --/O .../O --------------------/O 361/O March/O 25/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O of371/O Edward/PERSON Huebsch/PERSON --------------------------/O 381/O Bart/PERSON Lytton/PERSON ---------------------------------------------/O Joseph/PERSON Springer/PERSON ---------------------------------/O 398/O --------/O 413/O Silvia/PERSON Richards/PERSON .../O ---------------------/O 433/O ./O 
--------------------------------/O ./O 
--------------------/O Index/O --/O ./O 
./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O ``/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O activities/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committtee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 83D/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 3/O ,/O 1053/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O anad/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 1/O MONDAY/O ,/O MARCH/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 10/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Bulding/O ,/O Hon./O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O appearance/O noted/O in/O transcript/O -RRB-/O ,/O Kit/PERSON Clardy/PERSON ,/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ,/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O and/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Louis/PERSON J./PERSON Russell/PERSON ,/O chief/O investigator/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O chief/O clerk/O ;/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ;/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O the/O committee/O please/O come/O to/O order/O ?/O 
Miss/O Reporter/O ,/O let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O there/O are/O present/O the/O following/O members/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O of/O the/O House/O of/O Representatives/O :/O Mr./O Clardy/PERSON ,/O of/O Michigan/LOCATION ;/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ;/O Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION ;/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ;/O Mr./O Frazier/PERSON ,/O of/O Tennessee/LOCATION ;/O and/O the/O chairman/O ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O which/O constitutes/O a/O quorum/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O for/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
I/O am/O advised/O that/O Representative/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O of/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O will/O arrive/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O day/O ./O 
And/O I/O am/O advised/O ,/O too/O ,/O that/O Mr./O -LSB-/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON -RSB-/PERSON Jackson/PERSON was/O detained/O on/O the/O way/O down/O here/O ./O 
Before/O the/O hearings/O resume/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O make/O a/O statement/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O the/O witnesses/O who/O have/O been/O subpenaed/O ,/O the/O television/O companies/O which/O are/O participating/O in/O the/O televising/O of/O this/O hearing/O ,/O and/O the/O public/O ./O 
After/O receiving/O a/O request/O to/O permit/O the/O televising/O of/O this/O hearing/O as/O a/O public/O service/O ,/O the/O following/O resolution/O was/O adopted/O by/O the/O committee/O on/O March/O 4/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Be/O it/O resolved/O ,/O That/O in/O the/O event/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O or/O the/O chairman/O of/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O duly/O appointed/O by/O the/O chairman/O ,/O shall/O admit/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O television/O facilities/O as/O a/O public/O information/O medium/O under/O the/O provisions/O of/O a/O resolution/O adopted/O by/O the/O committee/O on/O the/O 22d/O day/O of/O January/O 1953/O ,/O the/O hearing/O may/O be/O televised/O under/O the/O following/O conditions/O :/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O That/O television/O facilities/O in/O the/O hearing/O room/O be/O restricted/O to/O two/O cameras/O and/O the/O minimum/O lighting/O facilities/O practicable/O ,/O all/O television/O production/O to/O be/O available/O on/O a/O pooled/O basis/O to/O other/O established/O television/O companies/O desiring/O participation/O ;/O 268/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANGELES/O AREA/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O Telecasts/O of/O committee/O hearings/O shall/O be/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O a/O public/O service/O only/O and/O this/O fact/O shall/O be/O publicly/O announced/O on/O television/O at/O the/O beginning/O and/O close/O of/O each/O telecast/O ./O 
No/O commercial/O announcements/O will/O be/O made/O from/O the/O hearing/O room/O and/O no/O actual/O or/O intimated/O sponsorship/O of/O the/O hearings/O will/O be/O permitted/O in/O any/O instance/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O Upon/O the/O request/O of/O a/O witness/O that/O no/O telecast/O be/O made/O of/O him/O during/O the/O course/O of/O this/O testimony/O the/O chairman/O shall/O direct/O the/O television/O cameras/O to/O refrain/O from/O photographing/O him/O during/O the/O taking/O of/O his/O testimony/O ./O 
I/O also/O desire/O to/O call/O to/O the/O attention/O of/O the/O audience/O which/O is/O present/O that/O you/O are/O here/O as/O a/O courtesy/O of/O this/O committee/O and/O that/O the/O committee/O will/O not/O tolerate/O any/O demonstration/O either/O by/O way/O of/O approval/O or/O disapproval/O of/O anything/O which/O may/O occur/O during/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Smoking/O will/O not/O be/O allowed/O ./O 
There/O will/O be/O no/O standing/O in/O the/O aisles/O or/O along/O the/O walls/O ./O 
The/O area/O in/O the/O corridors/O immediately/O adjacent/O to/O the/O hearing/O room/O shall/O be/O considered/O a/O part/O of/O this/O hearing/O room/O while/O the/O committee/O is/O in/O session/O ./O 
Anyone/O who/O violates/O these/O instructions/O shall/O be/O removed/O from/O the/O hearing/O room/O by/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION marshal/O or/O his/O deputies/O who/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O his/O responsibility/O as/O a/O Federal/O officer/O ,/O is/O appointed/O sergeant/O at/O arms/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O preserving/O order/O during/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O ready/O to/O proceed/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVIENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O call/O as/O the/O first/O witness/O Mr./O Danny/PERSON Dare/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O stand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O before/O this/O committee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O DANNY/PERSON DARE/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O MARTIN/O GANG/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Danny/PERSON Dare/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
I/O do/O not/O see/O counsel/O present/O ./O 
Mr./O GANG/O ./O 
Martin/PERSON Gang/PERSON is/O my/O name/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Spell/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O Mr./O Dare/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
D-a-r-e/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O March/O 1905/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O briefly/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O educational/O background/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Public/O school/O ,/O eighth/O grade/O ;/O high/O school/O ,/O approximately/O 6/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O the/O record/O of/O your/O employment/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Sporadic/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Since/O 1935/O ,/O staging/O shows/O for/O picture/O theaters/O ,/O occasional/O studio/O jobs/O as/O a/O dance/O director/O ,/O unemployed/O for/O a/O period/O of/O approximately/O 2/O years/O from/O 1937/O to/O 1939/O ,/O and/O following/O that/O I/O was/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 269/O employed/O at/O a/O picture/O studio/O for/O approximately/O 6/O years/O ,/O and/O then/O unemployed/O from/O the/O middle/O of/O 1948/O to/O early/O 1950/O ,/O and/O from/O then/O on/O in/O television/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O during/O the/O course/O of/O the/O hearings/O conducted/O by/O this/O committee/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O September/O of/O 1951/O ,/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Martin/PERSON Berkeley/PERSON testified/O ,/O and/O I/O want/O to/O read/O you/O a/O portion/O of/O his/O testimony/O which/O related/O to/O you/O ./O 
This/O question/O was/O asked/O him/O :/O Is/O there/O an/O organization/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION known/O as/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O such/O an/O organization/O ;/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/O Did/O you/O come/O in/O contact/O with/O the/O work/O of/O that/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O worked/O ./O 
I/O attended/O a/O few/O meetings/O of/O the/O faction/O of/O that/O organization/O around/O 1938/O or/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr/O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O it/O was/O organized/O ?/O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON ./O 
The/O Hollywood/O Theater/O Alliance/O was/O organized/O directly/O by/O the/O Communist/O Party/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O presenting/O so-called/O progressive/O or/O left-wing/O anti-Fascist/O propaganda/O ./O 
I/O believe/O their/O first/O production/O ,/O which/O was/O the/O one/O I/O could/O n't/O think/O of/O before/O in/O relation/O to/O Mr./O Bassman/PERSON was/O Meet/O the/O People/O ,/O which/O was/O very/O successful/O ,/O both/O here/O and/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
I/O attended/O a/O meeting/O of/O the/O faction/O which/O helped/O organize/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O although/O I/O had/O no/O active/O part/O in/O the/O Theater/O Alliance/O at/O all/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O attended/O a/O meeting/O of/O this/O organization/O and/O subsequently/O when/O there/O was/O talk/O of/O doing/O my/O Lincoln/O play/O ,/O by/O that/O time/O there/O was/O no/O money/O left/O and/O the/O Lincoln/PERSON play/O was/O never/O done/O ./O 
The/O leading/O spirits/O in/O the/O faction/O wereQUESTION/O ./O 
And/O again/O ,/O by/O ``/O faction/O ''/O you/O are/O referring/O to/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON Dues-paying/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mostly/O ,/O actually/O ,/O the/O members/O of/O this/O faction/O were/O the/O men/O who/O helped/O organ/O ?/O 
the/O show/O and/O put/O it/O on-writer/O ,/O director/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O ./O 
Edward/PERSON Eliscu/PERSON ,/O a/O writer/O ,/O was/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O and/O very/O active/O in/O the/O show/O itself/O ./O 
Incidentally/O ,/O it/O was/O a/O very/O amusing/O show/O ./O 
Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Is/O he/O the/O same/O Robert/PERSON Rossen/PERSON who/O appeared/O before/O the/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION Un-American/ORGANIZATION Activities/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O far/O as/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Edward/PERSON Chodorov/PERSON Incidentally/PERSON ,/O he/O was/O the/O first/O producer/O I/O worked/O for/O in/O town/O ,/O and/O the/O man/O I/O went/O with/O was/O Guy/PERSON Endore/PERSON ./O 
To/O go/O back/O way/O early/O this/O morning/O ,/O he/O is/O a/O well-known/O playwright/O and/O producer/O ,/O and/O Henry/PERSON Blankfort/PERSON ,/O a/O writer/O ./O 
QUESTION/O Is/O he/O the/O same/O individual/O who/O appeared/O before/O this/O committee/O yesterday/O ?/O 
Mr/O BERKELEY/LOCATION He/O is/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
I/O saw/O his/O picture/O in/O the/O paper/O and/O there/O is/O no/O doubt/O in/O my/O mind/O ./O 
Danny/PERSON Dare/PERSON ,/O producer/O and/O director/O ,/O who/O has/O worked/O for/O several/O of/O the/O major/O studios/O in/O both/O capacities/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O is/O now/O working/O on/O television/O ./O 
And/O then/O the/O witness/O proceeds/O to/O name/O other/O persons/O who/O were/O connected/O with/O that/O enterprise/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Continuing/O to/O read/O :-RRB-/O QUESTION/O ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O she/O is/O the/O same/O Bess/PERSON Taffel/PERSON who/O occupied/O the/O chair/O yesterday/O that/O you/O are/O now/O occupying/O ANSWER/O Yes/O ./O 
she/O is/O the/O same/O girl/O George/PERSON Sklar/PERSON ,/O an/O excellent/O writer/O ;/O Irving/PERSON J./PERSON White/PERSON ;/O and/O Francis/PERSON Faragoh/PERSON ,/O the/O writer/O ./O 
QUESTION/O ./O 
Did/O you/O attend/O a/O meeting/O in/O the/O home/O of/O Offner/PERSON ?/O 
I/O understood/O you/O to/O say/O that/O you/O attended/O a/O meeting/O but/O you/O did/O not/O state/O where/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O BERKELEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O attended/O the/O first/O meeting/O of/O this/O group/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Mortimer/PERSON Offner/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O then/O a/O screen/O writer/O ,/O and/O today/O I/O believe/O is/O a/O television/O writer/O or/O producer/O or/O director/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O which/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O soon/O after/O that/O testimony/O was/O taken/O by/O the/O committee/O ,/O the/O committee/O received/O a/O telegram/O which/O I/O would/O like/O to/O hand/O you/O and/O ask/O you/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O can/O identify/O it/O as/O a/O telegram/O which/O you/O sent/O to/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
270/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O offer/O it/O in/O evidence/O and/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O marked/O as/O ``/O Dare/O Exhibit/O 1/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
It/O will/O be/O received/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O document/O referred/O to/O was/O received/O in/O evidence/O and/O marked/O ``/O Dare/O Exhibit/O No./O 1/O ./O ''/O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O telegram/O reads/O as/O follows/O :/O NEW/LOCATION YORK/LOCATION ,/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Chairman/O ,/O House/ORGANIZATION Un-American/O Activities/O Committee/O :/O Feel/O I/O have/O been/O unjustly/O accused/O ./O 
Can/O not/O understand/O vague/O charges/O in/O Berkeley/LOCATION testimony/O ./O 
Am/O willing/O to/O appear/O at/O once/O ./O 
Can/O you/O arrange/O conference/O tomorrow/O with/O committee/O counsel/O for/O this/O purpose/O ./O 
Please/O reply/O collect/O ./O 
Did/O you/O then/O receive/O a/O telegram/O from/O this/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O ask/O you/O to/O look/O at/O this/O copy/O of/O a/O telegram/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O that/O is/O a/O copy/O of/O the/O telegram/O you/O received/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O offer/O it/O in/O evidence/O and/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O marked/O ``/O Dare/O Exhibit/O 2/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
It/O will/O be/O received/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O document/O referred/O to/O was/O received/O in/O evidence/O and/O marked/O ``/O Dare/O Exhibit/O No./O 2/O ./O ''/O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O telegram/O reads/O as/O follows/O :/O DANNY/PERSON DARE/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION :/O Committee/ORGANIZATION expect/O to/O adjourn/O tomorrow/O ./O 
It/O bears/O date/O of/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1951/O ./O 
Will/O make/O arrangements/O for/O your/O appearance/O in/O Washington/LOCATION as/O soon/O as/O practicable/O after/O return/O of/O subcommittee/O ./O 
FRANCIS/LOCATION WALTE/LOCATION ,/O Acting/O Chairman/O ,/O Un-American/O Activities/O Committee/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O in/O response/O to/O that/O exchange/O of/O telegrams/O ,/O did/O you/O appear/O before/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O in/O Washington/LOCATION on/O September/O 27/O ,/O 1951/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O appeared/O there/O before/O some/O of/O the/O committee/O members/O had/O been/O able/O to/O return/O to/O Washington/LOCATION from/O the/O hearing/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O members/O of/O the/O staff/O who/O were/O working/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O records/O of/O the/O committee/O show/O that/O you/O did/O appear/O on/O September/O 27/O before/O a/O subcommittee/O composed/O of/O Representatives/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O James/PERSON B./PERSON Frazier/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O and/O Bernard/PERSON W./PERSON Kearney/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O that/O hearing/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O ,/O made/O this/O statement/O :/O I/O understand/O you/O desire/O to/O make/O a/O statement/O concerning/O testimony/O given/O within/O the/O last/O few/O days/O in/O California/LOCATION before/O the/O subcommittee/O that/O was/O taking/O testimony/O out/O there/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O question/O having/O been/O asked/O or/O statement/O made/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O reply/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Would/O you/O repeat/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
I/O 'm/O sorry/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 271/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Walter/PERSON ,/O according/O to/O the/O transcript/O of/O the/O testimony/O ,/O made/O this/O statement/O :/O I/O understand/O you/O desire/O to/O make/O a/O statement/O concerning/O testimony/O given/O within/O the/O last/O few/O days/O in/O California/LOCATION before/O the/O subcommittee/O that/O was/O taking/O testimony/O out/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O I/O will/O read/O from/O the/O transcript/O of/O your/O reply/O and/O ask/O you/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O is/O correct/O as/O far/O as/O you/O can/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O can/O only/O say/O what/O I/O read/O in/O the/O newspaper/O ,/O that/O he/O listed/O a/O large/O number/O of/O names/O ,/O of/O which/O mine/O was/O one/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O exact/O statement/O he/O made/O ,/O but/O the/O implication/O was/O he/O named/O me/O as/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
Mr./O WAITER/O ./O 
As/O I/O recall/O the/O testimony/O ,/O you/O are/O correct/O ./O 
He/O did/O list/O a/O great/O number/O of/O names/O of/O people/O who/O were/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION with/O him/O ,/O and/O he/O was/O very/O specific/O that/O these/O were/O all/O people/O that/O he/O knew/O and/O people/O who/O had/O attended/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION meetings/O with/O him/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O 10:20/O a./O m./O ,/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON entered/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON -LRB-/O continuing/O to/O read/O -RRB-/O :/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O not/O true/O ./O 
Did/O you/O make/O that/O reply/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O another/O place/O in/O the/O transcript/O of/O the/O testimony/O appears/O this/O :/O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O WALTER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
DARE/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
WALTER/O ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
DARE/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O those/O questions/O and/O replies/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
At/O another/O place/O in/O the/O transcript/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON asked/O this/O question/O :/O The/O question/O was/O did/O anybody/O ever/O ask/O you/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O that/O exchange/O of/O question/O and/O answer/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O that/O testimony/O the/O committee/O continued/O in/O its/O investigation/O regarding/O the/O statement/O and/O testimony/O made/O by/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Berkeley/PERSON regarding/O you/O ,/O and/O as/O a/O result/O of/O its/O investigation/O ,/O the/O testimony/O relating/O to/O this/O subject/O was/O referred/O to/O the/O Department/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Justice/ORGANIZATION for/O its/O consideration/O in/O determining/O whether/O or/O not/O prosecutive/O action/O was/O justified/O ./O 
Subsequently/O ,/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON received/O a/O letter/O from/O you/O in/O which/O appears/O this/O language/O :/O I/O did/O a/O very/O stupid/O thing/O in/O asking/O you/O to/O take/O me/O to/O Washington/LOCATION and/O then/O testifying/O falsely/O before/O the/O committee/O This/O was/O a/O copy/O of/O a/O letter/O addressed/O to/O another/O person/O which/O you/O sent/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ,/O according/O to/O your/O recollection/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
YOU/O also/O stated/O in/O the/O course/O of/O this/O letter/O :/O I/O will/O tell/O the/O committee/O everything/O I/O know/O and/O try/O to/O make/O amends/O ./O 
Was/O that/O contained/O in/O your/O letter/O ?/O 
272/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
TO/O Mr./O Walter/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O you/O whether/O or/O not/O any/O promise/O or/O representation/O of/O any/O kind/O was/O made/O by/O this/O committee/O or/O anybody/O in/O its/O behalf/O to/O you/O to/O induce/O you/O to/O come/O before/O this/O committee/O and/O make/O any/O statement/O whatever/O further/O than/O that/O which/O you/O had/O already/O made/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
None/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
IS/O your/O appearance/O here/O the/O result/O of/O your/O own/O initiative/O and/O your/O own/O decision/O in/O the/O matter/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O do/O you/O realize/O that/O the/O answer/O to/O any/O question/O that/O I/O might/O ask/O you/O might/O be/O used/O in/O a/O subsequent/O proceeding/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O in/O spite/O of/O these/O things/O ,/O you/O desire/O to/O appear/O before/O this/O committee/O and/O state/O to/O it/O all/O that/O is/O within/O your/O knowledge/O and/O truthfully/O answer/O all/O questions/O that/O are/O propounded/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O shown/O from/O the/O transcript/O of/O the/O record/O ,/O you/O denied/O before/O this/O committee/O that/O you/O had/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O what/O do/O you/O desire/O to/O say/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O with/O my/O family/O ,/O employed/O ,/O and/O the/O way/O the/O news/O was/O broken/O to/O me/O was/O quite/O a/O shock/O ./O 
I/O was/O called/O in/O by/O my/O employer/O and/O shown/O a/O newspaper/O article/O mentioning/O my/O name/O ,/O as/O the/O testimony/O showed/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O became/O panicky/O ,/O and/O realizing/O that/O if/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O Yes/O ,/O this/O is/O true/O ,/O ''/O I/O would/O immediately/O lose/O my/O job/O ,/O which/O I/O particularly/O did/O not/O want/O to/O do/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O not/O only/O from/O my/O financial/O standpoint/O but/O I/O was/O in/O the/O midst/O of/O doing/O an/O anti-Communist/O show/O called/O The/O Crusade/O for/O Freedom/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O nationwide/O telecast/O ,/O and/O I/O became/O emotionally/O panicky/O and/O I/O thought/O I/O could/O brazen/O it/O through/O ,/O because/O actually/O I/O had/O been/O so/O little/O advised/O that/O I/O just/O did/O the/O wrong/O thing/O ,/O did/O the/O stupid/O thine/O ,/O through/O fear/O and/O panic/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O the/O facts/O regarding/O your/O alleged/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O ?/O 
Were/O you/O at/O any/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O circumstances/O under/O which/O you/O became/O a/O member/O ,/O both/O as/O to/O time/O and/O place/O and/O method/O of/O recruitment/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
If/O you/O will/O bear/O with/O me/O ,/O I/O will/O try/O ./O 
Up/O until/O 1938/O I/O had/O been/O in/O show/O business/O all/O my/O life/O and/O never/O stayed/O in/O one/O place/O long/O enough/O to/O have/O a/O home/O ,/O and/O as/O a/O result/O had/O never/O voted/O or/O never/O been/O interested/O in/O politics/O ./O 
That/O year/O I/O went/O to/O a/O show/O and/O during/O intermission/O I/O overheard/O a/O conversation/O that/O disturbed/O me/O very/O much/O between/O two/O men/O who/O were/O talking/O about/O what/O a/O good/O job/O Hitler/PERSON was/O doing/O in/O Germany/LOCATION and/O that/O that/O was/O the/O right/O thing/O to/O do/O to/O the/O minorities/O over/O there/O ;/O of/O course/O ,/O he/O might/O be/O going/O a/O little/O too/O far/O in/O exterminating/O them/O ,/O but/O he/O should/O confiscate/O their/O possessions/O and/O put/O them/O in/O concentration/O camps/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 273/O I/O turned/O around/O and/O saw/O two/O very/O normal/O looking/O ,/O intelligent/O people/O who/O said/O it/O casually/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O frightened/O ./O 
I/O intended/O to/O be/O married/O shortly/O and/O raise/O a/O family/O ,/O and/O it/O preyed/O on/O my/O mind/O ./O 
I/O belonged/O to/O an/O athletic/O club/O where/O I/O spent/O my/O time/O playing/O handball/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
I/O discussed/O it/O with/O some/O of/O the/O members/O there/O ,/O and/O a/O couple/O of/O them/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O you/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O is/O going/O on/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O and/O you/O should/O try/O to/O learn/O ./O ''/O 
They/O started/O to/O tell/O me/O things/O about/O what/O was/O going/O on/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ,/O and/O how/O it/O might/O happen/O here/O unless/O people/O took/O an/O active/O part/O in/O fighting/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O asked/O to/O go/O tothey/O said/O it/O was/O a/O local/O election/O coming/O up/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O was/O interested/O ,/O would/O I/O go/O to/O see/O some/O of/O the/O candidates/O and/O hear/O what/O they/O said/O ,/O and/O see/O what/O they/O were/O doing/O to/O fight/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O was/O interested/O ,/O to/O vote/O for/O them/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O a/O couple/O of/O meetings/O ,/O and/O before/O I/O knew/O it/O I/O was/O a/O member/O ,/O of/O the/O Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O so/O I/O became/O interested/O ./O 
Then/O as/O a/O result/O of/O that/O ,/O I/O imagineincidentally/O ,/O I/O was/O not/O active/O in/O those/O organizations/O ./O 
My/O participation/O was/O signing/O a/O slip/O and/O paying/O dues/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O it/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O attend/O any/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O must/O have/O gotten/O on/O all/O the/O sucker/O lists/O ,/O because/O I/O started/O to/O get/O literature/O through/O the/O mail/O ,/O and/O one/O day/O a/O circular/O came/O asking/O me/O if/O I/O was/O interested/O in/O a/O live/O theater/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O I/O was/O ./O 
This/O was/O my/O profession/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O n't/O been/O employed/O for/O a/O couple/O of/O years/O ./O 
It/O said/O ,/O ``/O If/O you/O are/O interested/O ,/O come/O to/O a/O meeting/O at/O ''/O such/O and/O such/O a/O place/O ./O 
I/O went/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O where/O it/O was/O ./O 
There/O were/O at/O least/O 50/O or/O 60/O people/O there/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O quite/O sure/O that/O this/O was/O not/O the/O first/O meeting/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O it/O later/O turned/O out/O to/O be/O ,/O because/O there/O were/O committees/O functioning/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O that/O I/O was/O not/O there/O at/O the/O inception/O of/O this/O organization/O ./O 
This/O was/O supposed/O to/O be/O a/O nonprofit/O community/O venture/O to/O give/O employment/O and/O opportunity/O to/O young/O actors/O ,/O directors/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
It/O was/O decided/O by/O the/O people/O talking/O that/O the/O venture/O of/O this/O theater/O should/O be/O a/O musical/O revue/O ,/O because/O it/O would/O involve/O more/O people/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O what/O that/O meant/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O now/O ./O 
Volunteers/O were/O called/O for/O to/O assist/O in/O producing/O this/O show/O ,/O and/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O I/O raised/O my/O hand/O ;/O this/O was/O my/O line/O of/O work/O ,/O and/O I/O found/O myself/O on/O a/O committee/O with/O the/O job/O of/O producing/O this/O first/O show/O ./O 
I/O had/O never/O known/O any/O of/O these/O people/O before/O ,/O and/O the/O other/O people/O on/O the/O committee/O were/O Morley/PERSON ,/O Offner/PERSON ,/O Henry/PERSON Meyers/PERSON ,/O and/O Jay/PERSON Gorney/PERSON ;/O and/O we/O proceeded/O to/O start/O to/O work/O on/O gathering/O material/O for/O this/O show/O ./O 
At/O this/O meeting/O a/O gentleman/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Irving/PERSON White/PERSON came/O up/O and/O introduced/O himself/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O said/O he/O had/O been/O a/O stage/O manager/O on/O Broadway/O ,/O and/O said/O he/O knew/O me/O by/O reputation/O ,/O and/O said/O he/O thought/O I/O could/O make/O a/O good/O contribution/O to/O this/O show/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O we/O started/O to/O gather/O material/O ,/O and/O some/O time/O during/O the/O next/O 2/O or/O 3/O months/O Mr./O Edward/PERSON Eliscu/PERSON was/O added/O to/O this/O committee/O ./O 
There/O were/O arguments/O about/O what/O materials/O should/O go/O into/O the/O show/O and/O ,/O what/O materials/O should/O n't/O go/O into/O the/O show/O ,/O and/O one/O day/O Mr./O Irving/PERSON White/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O held/O some/O sort/O of/O position/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O it/O now/O was/O called/O ,/O came/O to/O me/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O You/O just/O do/O n't/O understand/O what/O the/O show/O should/O be/O about/O ./O 
You/O need/O a/O political/O education/O ./O 
If/O you/O are/O interested/O in/O fighting/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON ,/O you/O should/O join/O with/O the/O people/O who/O are/O doing/O this/O thing/O ,/O ''/O and/O the/O sum/O and/O 274/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O substance/O of/O it/O was/O that/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O And/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION are/O the/O people/O that/O are/O actually/O doing/O this/O ./O ''/O 
Well/O ,/O I/O asked/O him/O the/O two/O $/O 64/O questions/O ,/O ``/O What/O is/O this/O I/O hear/O about/O the/O Communist/O Party/O being/O dedicated/O to/O the/O overthrow/O of/O the/O Government/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION by/O force/O and/O violence/O ?/O ''/O 
He/O assured/O me/O that/O this/O was/O not/O true/O and/O he/O could/O show/O it/O to/O me/O in/O the/O constitution/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
I/O also/O asked/O him/O ,/O ``/O What/O about/O this/O talk/O I/O hear/O about/O taking/O orders/O from/O Moscow/LOCATION ?/O ''/O 
He/O said/O that/O was/O positively/O not/O true/O ,/O that/O the/O party/O is/O independent/O and/O acted/O on/O its/O own/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O thought/O it/O over/O and/O he/O kept/O talking/O to/O me/O and/O eventually/O I/O agreed/O to/O do/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O stated/O that/O Mr./O Irving/PERSON White/PERSON stated/O to/O you/O that/O you/O needed/O some/O political/O education/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O his/O statement/O to/O you/O in/O full/O and/O what/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O his/O making/O such/O a/O statement/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Incidentally/O ,/O this/O was/O around/O August/O 1938/O ,/O to/O set/O the/O date/O for/O you/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O had/O never/O been/O interested/O in/O politics/O and/O my/O motive/O for/O doing/O anything/O about/O joining/O any/O organization/O was/O to/O try/O to/O prevent/O what/O happened/O in/O Germany/LOCATION from/O happening/O here/O ,/O and/O while/O I/O might/O have/O been/O intense/O and/O eager/O to/O do/O something/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O maybe/O know/O the/O reasons/O why/O I/O was/O doing/O things/O ,/O and/O they/O said/O ,/O ``/O You/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O forces/O are/O that/O are/O actually/O behind/O the/O so-called/O Fascist/O movement/O in/O America/LOCATION ,/O and/O in/O order/O to/O understand/O that/O you/O must/O get/O an/O education/O ,/O and/O in/O order/O to/O see/O that/O the/O right/O material/O went/O in/O the/O show/O ,/O you/O should/O be/O able/O to/O analyze/O material/O and/O judge/O its/O value/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O then/O there/O was/O a/O definite/O connection/O between/O that/O conversation/O and/O the/O purpose/O of/O the/O show/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O believe/O so/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O was/O in/O that/O connection/O that/O you/O were/O advised/O to/O go/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O 's/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O special/O group/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O first/O gathering/O I/O went/O to/O with/O Mr./O White/PERSON was-there/O were/O about/O 30/O people/O present/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O at/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
Again/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O any/O of/O them/O ./O 
I/O do/O remember/O two/O people/O who/O addressed/O us/O ./O 
One/O was/O John/PERSON Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON and/O the/O other/O was/O a/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Cyril/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O know/O his/O last/O name/O and/O never/O have/O seen/O him/O since/O ./O 
Mr./O Lawson/PERSON spoke/O about/O what/O was/O happening/O here/O ,/O and/O the/O sum/O and/O substance/O of/O it/O was/O ,/O ``/O You/O ca/O n't/O be/O an/O ostrich/O and/O stick/O your/O head/O in/O the/O sand/O and/O say/O it/O ca/O n't/O happen/O here/O because/O it/O happened/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O ''/O 
This/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Cyril/PERSON spoke/O something/O about/O Marxism/O ,/O which/O did/O n't/O interest/O me/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O understand/O it/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O all/O I/O remember/O about/O that/O meeting/O ,/O except/O that/O I/O was/O told/O that/O in/O the/O future/O that/O it/O would/O be/O broken/O up/O into/O smaller/O groups/O of/O six/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 275/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O become/O a/O member/O of/O one/O of/O the/O smaller/O groups/O of/O six/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O that/O group/O meet/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O first/O meeting/O that/O I/O remember/O was/O at/O the/O home/O of/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O although/O he/O was/O not/O present/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O receive/O information/O as/O to/O where/O and/O when/O the/O meeting/O would/O be/O held/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Mr./O White/PERSON told/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O present/O at/O that/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
A/O woman/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Jessie/PERSON Burns/PERSON ,/O Tanya/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON ,/O a/O fellow/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Ray/PERSON Spencer/PERSON ,/O and/O a/O woman/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Pauline/PERSON Lauber/PERSON ,/O and/O also/O Mr./O Herbert/PERSON Biberman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O frequently/O did/O that/O group/O meet/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O whether/O it/O was/O supposed/O to/O be/O once/O a/O week/O or/O once/O every/O 2/O weeks/O ;/O I/O really/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Over/O how/O long/O a/O period/O of/O time/O did/O you/O meet/O with/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
To/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ,/O perhaps/O 5/O times/O maximum/O ,/O although/O I/O can/O only/O actually/O remember/O 2/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O sure/O I/O went/O to/O a/O couple/O more/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Could/O you/O further/O identify/O the/O persons/O you/O have/O named/O by/O their/O occupation/O or/O the/O work/O they/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O will/O think/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Irving/PERSON White/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O was/O trying/O to/O be/O a/O writer/O ,/O although/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O that/O ,/O where/O he/O was/O ,/O actually/O was/O ,/O ever/O employed/O ./O 
He/O had/O some/O sort/O of/O a/O small-paying/O job/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION for/O a/O while/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O I/O am/O pretty/O sure/O ./O 
Ray/PERSON Spencer/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O ,/O was/O also/O supposed/O to/O be/O a/O writer/O ,/O although/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O that/O he/O ever/O worked/O in/O a/O studio/O or/O anywhere/O that/O he/O ever/O worked/O ,/O or/O what/O he/O wrote/O ./O 
Jessie/PERSON Burns/PERSON ,/O I/O understood/O ,/O was/O a/O reader/O at/O a/O motion/O picture/O studio/O ./O 
Pauline/PERSON Lauber/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O was/O a/O secretary/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O positive/O ./O 
Tanya/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON was/O the/O wife/O of/O Frank/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON and/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O ballet/O theater/O or/O dancing/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O did/O it/O as/O a/O profession/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O as/O much/O information/O as/O you/O have/O to/O identify/O them/O by/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
So/O far/O as/O their/O vocation/O is/O concerned/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O how/O this/O particular/O group/O functioned/O ,/O as/O to/O what/O their/O purpose/O was/O ,/O what/O its/O chief/O interest/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
By/O this/O particular/O group/O you/O mean/O the/O Hollywood/O Theater/O Alliance/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O meant/O this/O particular/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
I/O was/O lost/O for/O a/O moment/O ./O 
Mental/O suggestion/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O remember/O that/O when/O I/O got/O there/O they/O were/O there/O already/O ./O 
A/O lot/O of/O lighter/O literature/O was/O out/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O we/O read/O one/O of/O them/O about/O fascism/O in/O America/LOCATION and/O what/O was/O happening/O in/O Germany/LOCATION on/O that/O particular/O subject/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O discussed/O ./O 
This/O occupied/O most/O of/O the/O meeting/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O I/O remember/O ./O 
276/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Oh/O ,/O I/O remember/O that/O we/O were/O told/O that/O there/O would/O be/O a/O rotating/O chairman/O each/O time/O so/O that/O each/O one/O would/O gain/O the/O experience/O of/O conducting/O a/O meeting/O ./O 
Then/O there/O was/O a/O discussion/O of/O another/O pamphlet/O on/O Marx/PERSON ,/O which/O I/O did/O n't/O understand/O ./O 
That/O is/O about/O all/O I/O remember/O about/O the/O meeting/O ./O 
I/O think-yes/O ;/O I/O think/O the/O dues/O were/O explained/O to/O us/O ,/O that/O if/O you/O were/O working/O you/O were/O supposed/O to/O pay/O 5/O percent/O of/O your/O salary/O ./O 
If/O you/O were/O n't/O working/O ,/O which/O I/O was/O n't/O ,/O it/O was/O either/O 10/O cents/O or/O 50/O cents/O a/O month/O ;/O I/O forget/O which/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O time/O that/O you/O attended/O those/O meetings/O ,/O did/O functionaries/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O higher/O levels/O appear/O before/O your/O meeting/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O swear/O to/O that/O ,/O but/O I/O got/O the/O impression/O that/O Mr./O Biberman/PERSON might/O have/O been/O ./O 
But/O the/O others/O did/O n't/O seem/O to/O be/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O interest/O did/O this/O particular/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O ,/O have/O in/O the/O alliance/O group/O that/O you/O first/O referred/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O had/O any/O distinct/O relationship/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O although/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION show/O was/O discussed/O in/O there/O ./O 
Perhaps/O after/O I/O left/O there/O was/O some/O purpose/O in/O this/O particular/O unit/O being/O formed/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O sure/O there/O must/O have/O been/O some/O motive/O in/O having/O these/O particular/O people/O in/O this/O group/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O I/O ever/O found/O out/O exactly/O why/O ./O 
Incidentally/O ,/O to/O give/O you/O another/O date/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O Mr./O White/PERSON solicited/O my/O membership/O in/O the/O party/O was/O around/O March/O of/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O us/O go/O back/O and/O consider/O further/O the/O work/O that/O was/O being/O done/O by/O the/O Theater/O Alliance/O in/O the/O production/O of/O the/O play/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O volunteered/O for/O a/O part/O in/O the/O production/O of/O that/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O to/O direct/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
To/O direct/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O name/O of/O the/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
It/O became-there/O was/O no/O name/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
It/O became/O known/O as/O Meet/O the/O People/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Meet/O the/O People/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O it/O a/O successful/O production/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O quite/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O it/O make/O money/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O the/O play/O run/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Over/O a/O year/O ./O 
I/O would/O say/O approximately/O a/O year/O and/O 3/O months/O ;/O somewhere/O around/O there/O ./O 
Mr/O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O the/O production/O went/O on/O to/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O a/O second/O company/O was/O formed/O while/O this/O company/O was/O playing/O here/O ,/O and/O the/O second/O company/O went/O on/O the/O road/O and/O then/O eventually/O opened/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O you/O have/O stated/O that/O Mr./O White/PERSON advised/O you/O during/O the/O progress/O of/O the/O work/O on/O this/O play/O ,/O that/O you/O needed/O political/O education/O and/O indicated/O that/O you/O did/O not/O understand/O the/O political/O implications/O from/O this/O play/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 277/O Have/O you/O made/O a/O study/O of/O that/O production/O to/O determine/O what/O the/O implications/O were/O from/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O have/O ,/O since/O my/O invitation/O by/O the/O committee/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O some/O research/O ,/O and/O what/O I/O thought/O was/O perfectly/O innocuous/O and/O amusing/O in/O those/O days/O ,/O as/O I/O read/O it/O now/O ,/O I/O can/O see/O the/O connection/O and/O what/O it/O actually/O was/O meant/O to/O accomplish/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O in/O a/O general/O way/O ,/O what/O would/O you/O say/O that/O it/O was/O meant/O to/O accomplish/O ,/O by/O the/O production/O of/O this/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O to/O propagandize/O and/O expound/O the/O theories/O that/O at/O that/O time/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O a/O question/O for/O my/O information/O ./O 
Do/O I/O recall/O the/O first/O name/O of/O Mr./O White/PERSON ,/O or/O who/O he/O isMr/O ./O 
DARE/O ./O 
Irving/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENin/O ./O 
Irving/PERSON White/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O spell/O Irving/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I-r-v-i-n-g/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O do/O you/O recall/O any/O particular/O features/O about/O this/O play/O that/O would/O demonstrate/O what/O you/O have/O just/O had/O to/O say/O ,/O namely/O ,/O that/O the/O play/O was/O intended/O to/O propagate/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O as/O it/O existed/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
YesMr/O ./O 
VELDE/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O at/O what/O time/O again/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O what/O was/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O at/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O might/O be/O best/O explained-I/O am/O not/O qualified/O to/O per/O se/O give/O a/O long/O explanation/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ./O 
1/O can/O only/O cite/O the/O relation/O of/O the/O material/O that/O went/O in/O the/O showMr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O the/O Communists/O at/O that/O time/O with/O Hitler/PERSON or/O against/O him/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
It/O depends/O on/O the/O day/O you/O are/O asking/O about/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O during/O the/O course/O of/O this/O the/O line/O changed/O ?/O 
Maybe/O not/O so/O much/O as/O being/O against/O Hitler-I/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
think/O they/O were/O always/O against/O him-but/O as/O regards/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O their/O sympathies/O changed/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O what/O is/O the/O first/O thing/O that/O occurred/O which/O would/O indicate/O political/O significance/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O this/O show/O had/O quite/O a/O long/O rehearsal/O period/O due/O to/O the/O lack/O of/O success/O in/O raising/O money/O and/O resistance/O to/O certain/O opinions/O contrary/O to/O the/O opinions/O in/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O what/O was/O not/O a/O Communist/O opinion/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O and/O there/O were/O certain/O groups/O that/O refused/O to/O rent/O space/O to/O the/O groups/O respecting/O their/O motives/O ./O 
There/O was/O trouble/O getting/O a/O police/O and/O fire/O permit/O for/O a/O certain/O building/O ,/O because/O pressure/O was/O put/O on/O the/O fire/O department/O not/O to/O issue/O the/O permit/O ./O 
As/O a/O result/O ,/O the/O show/O was/O in/O rehearsal/O and/O preparation/O for/O quite/O a/O long/O time/O ;/O I/O would/O say/O 6/O months/O ./O 
When/O the/O show/O first/O started/O to/O be/O prepared/O there/O was/O a/O song/O written/O called/O ,/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON ,/O Wo/O n't/O You/O Please/O Run/O Again/O ?/O 
,/O which/O was/O a/O plea/O to/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON for/O a/O third/O term/O ,/O and/O to/O forget/O all/O the/O opposition/O to/O a/O third/O term/O ./O 
By/O the/O time/O the/O show/O opened/O ,/O which/O by/O that/O time/O the/O Nazi-Soviet/O pact/O had/O occurred/O ,/O this/O never/O wound/O up/O in/O the/O show/O ,/O and/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O 31747-53-pt/O ./O 
1/O --/O 2/O 278/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O of/O fact/O ,/O there/O was/O some/O fairly/O anti-Roosevelt/O policies/O sketches/O in/O the/O show/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ''/O was/O not/O a/O play/O ,/O was/O it/O ?/O 
It/O was/O a/O series/O of/O specialty/O acts/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O musical/O revue/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
A/O musical/O revue/O rather/O than/O a/O play/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O consisting/O of/O songs/O ,/O skits/O with/O no/O story/O line/O ,/O but/O what/O was/O called/O a/O thread/O of/O a/O story/O ./O 
During/O this/O period/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O when/O this/O number/O did/O not/O get/O into/O the/O show/O ,/O this/O was/O around/O May/O or/O June/O of/O 1939/O ,/O and/O by/O that/O time/O ,/O by/O the/O time/O the/O show/O opened/O after/O Roosevelt/PERSON had/O supported/O Finland/LOCATION ,/O as/O a/O result/O of/O Russia/LOCATION 's/O attack/O on/O Finland/LOCATION ,/O the/O song/O was/O eliminated/O from/O the/O potential/O list/O of/O material/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O after/O Roosevelt/PERSON supported/O Finland/LOCATION did/O this/O song/O disappear/O from/O the/O script/O ,/O was/O it/O a/O matter/O of/O days/O or/O weeks/O or/O months/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
It/O was/O on/O a/O potential/O list/O of/O material/O for/O the/O show/O and/O then/O it/O just/O never/O got/O into/O the/O show/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O be/O specific/O about/O the/O exact/O date/O when/O somebody/O said/O ,/O ``/O This/O does/O not/O go/O into/O the/O show/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Your/O conclusion/O is/O it/O was/O on/O account/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION supporting/O Finland/LOCATION 's/O position/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Plus/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON giving/O aid/O to/O the/O Allies/O who/O were/O fighting/O Hitler/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Clardy/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
How/O was/O that/O handled/O ,/O Witness/O ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O was/O there/O some/O discussion/O amongst/O the/O entire/O group/O ,/O or/O did/O someone/O in/O particular/O merely/O hand/O down/O the/O order/O that/O ,/O ``/O This/O does/O not/O go/O in/O the/O play/O ''/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
This/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O because/O I/O had/O been/O in/O and/O out/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O while/O I/O continued/O to/O direct/O the/O show/O there/O was/O a/O committee/O that/O selected/O the/O material/O for/O the/O show/O ,/O of/O which/O I/O was/O one/O ./O 
Who/O ,/O what/O ,/O why/O decided/O this/O ,/O I/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
I/O do/O know/O it/O never/O got/O into/O the/O show/O ,/O but/O I/O actually/O could/O n't/O say/O how/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Based/O on/O the/O knowledge/O that/O you/O have/O acquired/O since/O that/O event/O ,/O would/O you/O say/O that/O the/O order/O ,/O however/O it/O came/O ,/O was/O from/O a/O group/O of/O Communists/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O am/O pretty/O sure/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O you/O mentioned/O the/O fact/O that/O the/O President/O gave/O aid/O to/O the/O Allies/O during/O a/O certain/O period/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O change/O made/O in/O the/O script/O that/O reflected/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O on/O that/O question/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O the/O question/O of/O aid/O by/O this/O country/O to/O the/O allies/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O have/O before/O me/O two/O of/O the/O scripts/O from/O the/O show/O ,/O one/O dated/O February/O 20/O ,/O 1940/O ,/O and/O the/O other/O dated/O January/O 20/O ,/O 1941/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 279/O In/O the/O version/O of/O 1940/O there/O was/O a/O sketch/O which/O was/O a/O prelude/O to/O a/O song/O and/O a/O dance/O ,/O which/O had/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Senate/ORGANIZATION as/O the/O setting/O ./O 
The/O only/O implication/O in/O that/O was/O that/O the/O scene/O was/O based/O on/O two/O fairly/O successful/O pictures/O at/O that/O time/O which/O were/O ``/O Mr./O Deeds/O Goes/O To/O Washington/LOCATION ''/O and/O ``/O Mr./O Smith/PERSON Goes/O To/O Town/O ,/O ''/O which/O was/O the/O only/O reason/O for/O the/O setting/O being/O in/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION ./O 
In/O the/O first/O script/O it/O had/O no/O political/O implication/O at/O all/O ,/O and/O was/O merely/O a/O setting/O for/O a/O song/O and/O a/O dance/O ./O 
By/O January/O of/O 1940/O the/O same/O sketch/O had/O been/O changed/O to/O attack/O ,/O ridicule/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON and/O ridicule/O his/O domestic/O policies/O ,/O satirized/O his/O giving/O destroyers/O to/O England/LOCATION and/O satirized/O the/O building/O of/O the/O factories/O for/O defense/O ,/O satirized/O his-or/O ,/O accusing/O him/O of/O stretching/O the/O Monroe/ORGANIZATION Doctrine/ORGANIZATION and/O ridiculed/O the/O idea/O any/O Senator/O would/O ask/O for/O a/O small/O amount/O for/O relief/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O this/O script/O was/O dated/O January/O 20/O ,/O 1941/O ,/O was/O it/O not/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O you/O said/O 1940/O ./O 
This/O is/O just/O to/O get/O the/O record/O straight/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
The/O second/O script/O was/O 1941/O ./O 
This/O was/O the/O same/O sketch/O ,/O only/O rewritten/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
At/O what/O point/O it/O was/O rewritten/O I/O ca/O n't/O say/O ,/O but/O by/O the/O time/O January/O 1/O ,/O 1941/O ,/O arrived/O ,/O this/O was/O the/O state/O it/O was/O in/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O would/O you/O give/O the/O committee/O a/O little/O clearer/O idea/O of/O just/O the/O way/O in/O which/O that/O satirization/O took/O place/O ,/O by/O reading/O pertinent/O parts/O of/O the/O script/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O Senate/ORGANIZATION is/O in/O session/O ./O 
Senior/O Senators/O ,/O secretaries/O and/O one/O junior/O Senator/O are/O all/O seated/O ./O 
Two/O gavel/O knocks/O ./O 
A/O comedian/O came/O out/O with/O a/O fishing/O rod/O and/O old/O fishing/O hat/O ,/O such/O as/O Roosevelt/PERSON used/O to/O wear/O ./O 
A/O hand/O comes/O out/O from/O the/O wings/O and/O takes/O the/O fishing/O rod/O away/O from/O him/O ./O 
He/O turned/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O Thank/O you/O ,/O Wendell/PERSON ./O ''/O 
This/O was/O during/O the/O Willkie-Roosevelt/O campaign/O ./O 
He/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O served/O you/O faithfully/O for/O 8/O years/O ./O ''/O 
The/O Senators/O applaud/O ./O 
``/O And/O I/O hope/O to/O serve/O you/O for/O 4/O more/O ./O ''/O 
Senators/O almost/O applaud/O ,/O but/O show/O resentment/O instead/O ./O 
``/O My/O message/O today/O is/O this/O :/O We/O have/O troubles/O in/O our/O country-now/O ./O 
We/O have/O unequal/O distribution/O of/O wealth-now/O ./O 
We/O have/O strife/O and/O havoc/O on/O all/O sides-now/O ./O 
And/O I/O plan/O to/O do/O something/O about/O itlater/O ./O ''/O 
Much/O applause/O ./O 
Two/O gavel/O knocks/O ./O 
Junior/PERSON and/O senior/O Senators/O :/O ``/O Mr./O President/O ./O ''/O 
A/O voice/O says/O ,/O ``/O The/O Chair/O recognizes/O the/O senior/O Senator/O ./O ''/O 
Senior/O Senator/O :/O ``/O I/O move/O we/O appropriate/O $/O 1/O billion/O for/O monkey/O glands/O for/O overage/O destroyers/O ./O ''/O 
All/O but/O junior/O Senator/O `/O applaud/O ./O 
Junior/PERSON and/O senior/O Senators/O :/O ``/O Mr./O President/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O Chair/O recognizes/O the/O senior/O Senator/O ./O ''/O 
Senior/O Senator/O :/O ``/O I/O move/O we/O appropriate/O $/O 5/O billion/O to/O build/O factories/O for/O underprivileged/O millionaires/O ./O ''/O 
All/O but/O junior/O Senator/O applaud/O ./O 
280/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Junior/PERSON and/O senior/O Senators/O :/O ``/O Mr./O President/O ./O ''/O 
``/O The/O Chair/O recognizes/O the/O senior/O Senator/O ./O ''/O 
Senior/O Senator/O :/O ``/O I/O move/O we/O appropriate/O $/O 12/O billion/O for/O rubber/O bands/O to/O stretch/O the/O Monroe/O Doctrine/O ./O ''/O 
All/O but/O junior/O Senator/O applaud/O ./O 
Junior/O Senator/O -LRB-/O angrily/O -RRB-/O :/O ``/O Mr./O President/O ./O ''/O 
Over/O the/O PAV/O -LRB-/O very/O tired/O -RRB-/O :/O ``/O Oh/O ,/O all/O right/O ./O 
The/O Chair/O recognizes/O the/O junior/O Senator/O ./O ''/O 
Junior/O Senator/O :/O ``/O Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O President/O ./O 
I/O move/O we/O appropriate/O $/O 1/O for/O relief/O ./O ''/O 
Everybody/O gasps/O in/O horror/O ./O 
Smnor/O Senator/O reaches/O for/O gun/O ./O 
Everybody/O jumps/O up/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O struggle/O for/O the/O gun/O ,/O which/O developed/O into/O a/O jitterbug/O dance/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O date/O of/O that/O script/O ,/O Mr./O Dare/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
January/O 20/O ,/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O would/O this/O be/O a/O convenient/O breaking-off/O point/O for/O a/O recess/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O recess/O until/O 5/O minutes/O after/O 11/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Short/O recess/O was/O taken/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Counsel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O you/O referred/O earlier/O in/O your/O testimony/O to/O the/O attack/O made/O by/O the/O Soviet/LOCATION Union/LOCATION on/O Finland/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O anything/O in/O this/O sketch/O or/O in/O any/O of/O the/O sketches/O or/O any/O part/O of/O this/O play/O which/O carried/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O with/O regard/O to/O Finland/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ./O 
If/O I/O may/O quote/O from/O the/O script/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O sketch/O in/O the/O show/O thatMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
The/O show/O you/O are/O referring/O to/O is/O ``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ''/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O sketch/O in/O the/O show/O which/O concerned/O two/O tramps/O out/O of/O work/O ,/O sitting/O on/O a/O bench/O discussing/O conditions/O ./O 
A/O policeman/O comes/O in/O ,/O and/O ,/O incidentally/O ,/O during/O this/O sketch/O there/O were/O jibes/O at/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON and/O the/O domestic/O policies/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
At/O the/O finish/O of/O the/O sketch/O a/O policeman/O comes/O in/O and/O tells/O the/O two/O men/O to/O get/O moving/O ./O 
As/O he/O says/O this/O ,/O a/O woman/O comes/O in/O with/O a/O receptacle/O asking/O for/O contributions/O ./O 
She/O says/O ,/O ``/O Officer/O ,/O would/O you/O care/O to/O make/O a/O contribution/O ?/O ''/O 
The/O cop/O says/O ,/O ``/O What/O is/O it/O for/O ?/O ''/O 
The/O woman/O says/O ,/O ``/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON 's/O fund/O for/O needy/O Finns/O ./O ''/O 
The/O cop/O very/O warmly/O says/O ,/O ``/O Why/O ,/O sure/O ,/O Lady/O ./O 
Poor/O things/O ./O ''/O 
And/O he/O drops/O a/O quarter/O in/O the/O can/O ./O 
``/O Thank/O you/O ,/O ''/O says/O the/O woman/O ,/O and/O she/O exits/O ./O 
The/O cop/O said/O to/O the/O men/O ,/O ``/O I/O thought/O I/O told/O you/O two/O bums/O to/O clear/O out/O ./O ''/O 
The/O two/O men/O start/O off/O and/O ,/O as/O they/O walk/O ,/O the/O first/O man/O says/O ,/O ``/O Hey/O ,/O are/O you/O a/O Finn/O ?/O ''/O 
The/O second/O man/O says/O ,/O ``/O No/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ?/O ''/O 
The/O first/O man/O says/O ,/O ``/O No/O ./O ''/O 
The/O second/O man/O says/O ,/O ``/O Too/O bad/O ./O ''/O 
The/O implication/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O being/O there/O was/O money/O for/O Finland/LOCATION but/O for/O nobody/O at/O home/O that/O needed/O any/O money/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 281/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O attack/O upon/O domestic/O policies/O which/O would/O carry/O out/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION line/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
As/O I/O studied/O it/O recently/O ,/O I/O think/O so/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O quite/O did/O n't/O realize/O the/O implication/O ./O 
This/O is/O a/O sketch/O called/O With/O Mr./O Hollywood/PERSON in/O Darkest/LOCATION Washington/LOCATION ,/O which/O opens/O with/O the/O depicting/O of/O a/O supposed/O Republican/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O was/O during/O the/O time/O the/O Republicans/O were/O going/O to/O pick/O a/O candidate/O to/O run/O against/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON ./O 
I/O guess/O it/O would/O be/O in/O 1940/O ./O 
They/O are/O trying/O to/O decide/O what/O kind/O of/O a/O candidate/O they/O should/O select/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O me/O to/O tell/O you/O about/O it/O orMr/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
I/O think/O if/O you/O just/O describe/O it/O generally/O it/O will/O be/O all/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
They/O say/O ,/O ``/O We/O have/O got/O to/O have/O a/O man/O who/O will/O appeal/O to/O the/O people/O ./O ''/O 
And/O he/O says/O ,/O ``/O There/O is/O ''/O -/O they/O have/O a/O candidate/O ,/O but/O he/O looks/O awful/O ./O 
He/O is/O a/O real/O scarecrow/O ./O 
They/O said/O ,/O ``/O We/O have/O got/O to/O do/O something/O to/O liven/O this/O man/O up/O ./O ''/O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O The/O only/O man/O I/O know/O to/O do/O it/O is/O Mr./O Hollywood/PERSON ,/O the/O big/O producer/O ./O ''/O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O What/O will/O he/O do/O with/O it/O ?/O ''/O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O Look/O what/O they/O did/O for/O the/O British/O Empire/O ,/O Lloyd/ORGANIZATION 's/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION London/ORGANIZATION ,/O Gunga/ORGANIZATION Din/ORGANIZATION ,/O Henry/PERSON the/O Eighth/O ./O ''/O 
They/O call/O Mr./O Hollywood/PERSON in/O to/O tell/O them/O how/O to/O make/O their/O candidate/O to/O appeal/O to/O the/O voters/O ./O '/O 
He/O brings/O his/O own/O makeup/O man/O with/O him/O and/O they/O ./O 
go/O to/O work/O on/O him/O ./O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O The/O first/O thing/O we/O have/O to/O `/O do/O is/O to/O delve/O into/O the/O complete/O characterization/O of/O the/O part/O ./O 
A/O man/O 's/O looks/O always/O reflect/O his/O thoughts/O ./O 
Where/O is/O the/O script/O ?/O ''/O 
One/O says/O ,/O ``/O Script/O ?/O 
What/O script/O ?/O ''/O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O As/O a/O president/O this/O man/O will/O stand/O for/O something/O ./O 
What/O 's/O his/O platform/O going/O to/O be/O ?/O 
What/O does/O he/O mean/O ?/O ''/O 
He/O says/O ,/O ``/O What/O are/O we/O going/O to/O promise/O the/O Republican/O voters/O ?/O ''/O 
``/O Oh/O ,/O that/O is/O different/O ./O 
The/O first/O thing/O we/O are/O going/O to/O promise/O -/O ''/O ``/O Wait/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Get/O ready/O ,/O please/O ./O ''/O 
``/O Now/O ,/O give/O it/O to/O me/O with/O feeling-emotion-dialog/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O day/O before/O election/O ./O 
He/O is/O presenting/O his/O platform/O to/O the/O people-the/O best/O people/O ./O 
His/O words/O will/O thunder/O ,/O `/O Lower/O taxes/O for/O the/O millionaires/O ,/O higher/O taxes/O for/O the/O workingman/O ./O '/O 
``/O Wonderful-make/O him/O generous-bighearted-more/O ,/O more/O ./O 
``/O His/O first/O cry/O will/O be/O ,/O `/O We/O must/O balance/O the/O budget/O ./O '/O 
Caution-give/O him/O caution/O ./O 
Cut/O down/O the/O relief/O ./O 
Thrift/O ./O 
More/O money/O for/O the/O Navy/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Strength/O ,/O let/O 's/O have/O strength/O ./O 
Cut/O down/O on/O public/O health/O ./O 
``/O More/O freedom/O for/O Wall/O Street/O ./O 
money/O for/O the/O farmer/O ./O 
Economy/O ./O 
Consideration-regard/O ./O 
Less/O More/O money/O for/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Amend/O the/O Wagner/PERSON bill/O ./O 
Amend/O the/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O ./O 
Scrap/O the/O WPA/O ./O 
Strengthen/O the/O FBI/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Give/O him/O everything/O ./O 
More/O money/O for/O the/O Air/ORGANIZATION Force/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Smash/O the/O Labor/O Trusts/O ./O 
More/O money/O for/O the/O rich/O ./O 
Throw/O out/O the/O New/O Deal/O ./O 
Bring/O back/O the/O Old/O Deal/O ./O ''/O 
And/O at/O that/O point/O he/O says/O ,/O ``/O Fine/O ,/O I/O think/O we/O have/O got/O him/O ./O '/O 
In/O the/O meantime/O the/O makeup/O man/O has/O been/O putting/O a/O mask/O on/O this/O character/O ,/O with/O his/O back/O to/O the/O audience/O ,/O and/O when/O they/O turn/O him/O around/O it/O is/O a/O mask/O of/O Mr./O Roosevelt/PERSON ./O 
The/O implication/O beingno/O matter/O what/O candidate/O the/O Republican/ORGANIZATION or/O Democratic/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION picked/O it/O would/O be/O the/O same/O thing/O ./O 
282/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O incidents/O that/O occurred/O during/O the/O production/O of/O this/O play/O ``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ''/O which/O indicated/O to/O you/O any/O political/O significance/O on/O the/O part/O of/O the/O individuals/O who/O were/O responsible/O for/O the/O production/O of/O the/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Not/O specifically/O ,/O that/O I/O can/O recall/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O realize/O it/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O perfectly/O obvious/O to/O me/O now/O that/O someone/O or/O some/O group/O were/O dictating/O ,/O how/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O what/O should/O go/O into/O this/O show/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O suggestions/O made/O by/O you/O at/O any/O time/O which/O were/O either/O approved/O or/O refused/O and/O which/O might/O indicate/O to/O the/O committee/O what/O the/O attitude/O was/O of/O those/O who/O were/O responsible/O for/O the/O production/O of/O this/O play/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O quite/O agree/O with/O everything/O that/O was/O said/O all/O the/O time/O ./O 
And/O I/O remember/O in/O one/O specific/O instance/O there/O was/O a/O number/O which/O concerned/O two/O couples/O dressed/O in/O tails/O and/O evening/O clothes/O ./O 
One/O was/O supposed/O to/O be/O a/O gigolo/O and/O the/O number/O in/O itself/O was/O quite/O innocuous/O ./O 
It/O wound/O up/O with/O the/O gigolo/O trying/O to/O find/O out/O which/O of/O the/O three/O had/O the/O most/O money/O ,/O his/O partner/O or/O the/O other/O woman/O ,/O and/O he/O eventually/O found/O out/O it/O was/O the/O other/O man/O ,/O so/O he/O asked/O him/O to/O dance/O with/O him/O ./O 
This/O was/O followed/O by/O an/O encore/O ,/O which/O was/O inserted/O at/O some/O point/O as/O these/O people/O left/O the/O stage/O ,/O of/O Hitler/PERSON and/O Stalin/PERSON coming/O in/O dancing/O together/O ./O 
This/O was/O sometime/O during/O the/O Soviet-Nazi/O pact/O ./O 
Mr./O Hitler/PERSON had/O his/O back/O to/O the/O audience/O and/O we/O could/O n't/O see/O his/O hand/O ,/O which/O was/O behind/O Mr./O Stalin/PERSON 's/O back/O ,/O until/O they/O reached/O the/O center/O of/O the/O stage/O ,/O at/O which/O point/O ,/O as/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON whirled/O Mr./O Stalin/PERSON around/O ,/O we/O saw/O a/O knife/O was/O pointed/O at/O Mr./O Stalin/PERSON 's/O back/O by/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON ./O 
My/O argument/O at/O the/O time/O was/O ,/O ``/O How/O can/O you/O do/O that/O ?/O 
You/O have/O to/O put/O a/O knife/O in/O both/O their/O hands/O if/O you/O want/O to/O be/O honest/O ./O ''/O 
This/O caused/O a/O big/O argument/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O that/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O Mr./O Stalin/PERSON was/O acting/O in/O good/O faith/O ,/O whereas/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON was/O a/O dangerous/O man/O and/O could/O n't/O be/O trusted/O ;/O he/O had/O a/O knife/O at/O Mr./O Stalin/PERSON 's/O back/O ./O 
This/O was/O n't/O in/O the/O show/O for/O a/O very/O long/O time/O ./O 
I/O forget/O at/O what/O point/O it/O went/O in/O and/O when/O it/O went/O out/O ./O 
I/O know/O it/O was/O in/O the/O show/O and/O I/O know/O this/O discussion/O and/O argument/O took/O place/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O do/O you/O remember/O ,/O Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O was/O it/O before/O or/O after/O the/O pact/O was/O broken/O ,/O before/O Germany/LOCATION marched/O on/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
What/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
1941/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOILDER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O with/O whom/O you/O had/O this/O conversation/O concerning/O the/O characters/O ,/O when/O you/O suggested/O to/O put/O a/O knife/O in/O each/O of/O their/O hands/O ,/O whom/O you/O were/O talking/O to/O ,/O discussing/O that/O problem/O with/O at/O the/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
People/O connected/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theatre/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
You/O ca/O n't/O remember/O who/O they/O were/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O that/O the/O people/O who/O worked/O on/O the/O committee/O joined/O in/O the/O discussion/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O also/O sure/O there/O were/O other/O people/O connected/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O could/O n't/O swear/O as/O to/O who/O exactly/O took/O what/O side/O or/O who/O agreed/O with/O me/O ./O 
I/O know/O it/O would/O have/O been/O discussed/O within/O the/O Hollywood/O Theatre/O Alliance/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O now/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 283/O Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O anyone/O else/O who/O was/O on/O the/O committee/O or/O in/O the/O group/O agree/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARL/PERSON I/O think/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
About/O how/O many/O out/O of/O the/O group/O agreed/O with/O you/O ,/O that/O you/O ought/O to/O have/O a/O knife/O in/O both/O their/O hands/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O not/O many/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O 2,3/O or/O 4/O out/O of/O the/O 12/O or/O 15/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Probably/O ./O 
Maybe/O less/O than/O that/O ,/O maybe/O 2/O or/O 3/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O the/O majority/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O were/O for/O the/O other/O version/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O definitely/O be/O before/O the/O peace/O pact/O was/O broken/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O imagine/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O it/O is/O obvious/O to/O me/O ,/O from/O your/O testimony/O ,/O that/O you/O claim/O to/O have/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION when/O you/O did/O because/O you/O felt/O at/O that/O time/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O opposed/O to/O anti-Semitism/O ,/O is/O that/O right/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O definitely/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O your/O reason/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O today/O that/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION is/O as/O anti-Semitic/O as/O the/O Nazi/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O under/O Hitler/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O do/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O understand/O anyone/O who/O at/O that/O time/O would/O have/O joined/O forces/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O actually/O joined/O the/O party/O to/O fight/O anti-Semitism/O ,/O why/O they/O could/O n't/O today/O ,/O with/O the/O same/O zeal/O and/O energy/O ,/O fight/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O because/O ,/O in/O essence/O ,/O it/O is/O much/O worse/O today/O ,/O because/O it/O tries/O to/O hide/O the/O fact/O it/O is/O anti-Semitic/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
You/O mean/O it/O is/O much/O worse/O than/O the/O Nazi/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O would/O think/O so/O ,/O because/O the/O Nazis/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O Fascists/O made/O no/O bones/O about/O where/O they/O stood/O ./O 
This/O is/O much/O more/O insidious/O ,/O by/O protesting/O ,/O ``/O No/O ;/O we/O do/O n't/O do/O that/O ,/O ''/O when/O all/O the/O reports/O and/O everything/O are/O quite/O the/O opposite/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O I/O thoroughly/O agree/O with/O your/O conclusions/O in/O that/O respect/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
In/O relation/O to/O that/O ,/O may/O I/O say/O this/O :/O In/O order/O to/O fight/O this/O ,/O if/O the/O organizations/O that/O are/O fighting/O communism/O could/O reach/O out/O and/O grab/O persons/O like/O myself/O ,/O I/O am/O sure/O there/O are/O millions/O of/O them/O with/O the/O same/O intensity/O ,/O and/O as/O the/O Communists/O grabbed/O me/O when/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O want/O to/O fight/O Hitler/PERSON ,/O ''/O that/O would/O be/O a/O great/O thing/O for/O the/O country/O ./O 
The/O minute/O I/O opened/O my/O mouth/O and/O said/O ,/O ``/O This/O is/O wrong/O ,/O you/O ought/O to/O do/O something/O about/O it/O ,/O ''/O they/O were/O ready/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O Here/O is/O how/O you/O do/O it/O ./O 
Let/O 's/O join/O this/O organization/O ./O ''/O 
If/O the/O same/O thing/O could/O be/O done/O for/O the/O other/O side/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O take/O an/O active/O part/O in/O it/O and/O I/O am/O sure/O there/O are/O thousands/O of/O others/O that/O would/O ./O 
There/O do/O n't/O seem/O to/O be/O the/O organizations/O on/O the/O level/O of/O myself/O to/O say/O ,/O ``/O Come/O on/O ,/O here/O is/O what/O you/O can/O do/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O this/O committee/O is/O doing/O something/O about/O it/O ?/O 
284/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O n't/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O talking/O about/O organizations/O like/O the/O Anti-Nazi/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O like/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Democratic/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION and/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ./O 
There/O are/O thousands/O who/O would/O join/O them/O ./O 
If/O one/O did/O n't/O suit/O the/O specific/O thing/O that/O they/O were/O fighting/O against/O ,/O there/O was/O another/O that/O suited/O their/O purpose/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O that/O what/O the/O American/O Legion/O and/O the/O veterans/O '/O organizations/O are/O doing/O ,/O sparking/O a/O pretty/O good/O move/O in/O that/O direction/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O fine/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O join/O the/O American/O Legion/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O talking/O about/O organizations/O thatMr/O ./O 
CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
You/O want/O an/O organization/O that/O is/O as/O broad/O in/O its/O membership/O as/O the/O electorate/O of/O the/O Nation/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
When/O I/O was/O asked/O if/O I/O wanted/O to/O produce/O the/O Anti-Communist/O Crusade/O for/O Freedom/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ,/O I/O jumped/O at/O the/O chance/O ./O 
That/O was/O something/O I/O could/O use/O my/O talents/O for/O ,/O just/O as/O the/O Communists/O used/O my/O talents/O for/O themselves/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O you/O think/O this/O committee/O will/O in/O some/O measure/O encourage/O the/O thing/O you/O are/O talking/O about/O and/O thus/O help/O to/O reach/O the/O ends/O you/O are/O suggesting/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
This/O is/O not/O a/O criticism/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
This/O is/O for/O organizations/O for/O people/O ,/O just/O as/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O supposed/O to/O be/O ,/O and/O they/O can/O say/O ,/O ``/O Let/O 's/O get/O together/O ,/O ''/O me/O and/O my/O neighbors/O ,/O ``/O and/O form/O an/O organization/O to/O do/O this/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
You/O want/O to/O fight/O fire/O with/O fire/O ,/O in/O other/O words/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
You/O have/O to/O do/O it/O with/O the/O same/O intensity/O they/O were/O supposedly/O fighting/O Hitlerism/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O knowledge/O of/O an/O organization/O called/O the/O Jewish/O League/O Against/O Communism/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O suggest/O that/O perhaps/O it/O might/O fill/O some/O of/O the/O qualifications/O you/O say/O you/O are/O looking/O for/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O mere/O fact/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O anybody/O belonging/O to/O it/O makes/O me/O think-and/O this/O is/O no/O criticism-they/O may/O be/O a/O little/O remiss/O in/O reaching/O the/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Perhaps/O the/O league/O is/O not/O on/O hand/O any/O time/O that/O the/O occasion/O arises/O to/O reach/O out/O and/O get/O a/O recruit/O ,/O as/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O at/O the/O time/O you/O heard/O the/O discussion/O and/O decided/O to/O do/O something/O about/O it/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O great/O weaknesses/O of/O freedom/O 's/O forces/O today/O is/O the/O lack/O of/O effective/O organization/O it/O has/O ./O 
The/O Communist/O Party/O ,/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ,/O is/O highly/O organized/O and/O highly/O vocal/O ./O 
If/O freedom/O is/O worth/O living/O for/O it/O seems/O to/O me/O it/O is/O worth/O looking/O for/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O look/O for/O it/O ,/O but/O I/O have/O n't/O been/O able/O to/O find/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O there/O are/O millions/O more/O like/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
There/O are/O a/O number/O of/O organizations/O doing/O extremely/O effective/O work/O against/O communism/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O with/O a/O little/O effort/O you/O could/O find/O some/O such/O organization/O to/O fit/O your/O own/O requirements/O and/O your/O own/O needs/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O do/O anything/O I/O can/O ,/O and/O anyone/O can/O have/O my/O phone/O number/O and/O call/O on/O me/O for/O my/O services/O ./O 
I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O do/O it/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 285/O Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O mention/O one/O organization/O ,/O one/O anti-Communist/O organization/O is/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O the/O Anti-Communist/O Crusade/O for/O Freedom/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
We/O had/O a/O professor/O in/O Washington/LOCATION who/O is/O also/O of/O the/O Jewish/O race/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O some/O of/O the/O members/O asked/O him/O ,/O I/O know/O I/O asked/O ,/O whether/O he/O did/O n't/O agree/O with/O what/O you/O said/O a/O moment/O ago/O ,/O that/O the/O Russian/O people/O and/O the/O Russian/LOCATION nation/O and/O its/O dictator/O are/O antiSemitic/O ./O 
He/O refused/O to/O agree/O ./O 
He/O said/O he/O had/O seen/O no/O evidence/O in/O that/O direction/O ./O 
Have/O you/O run/O across/O that/O sort/O of/O people/O out/O here/O ,/O in/O the/O Jewish/O race/O ,/O who/O take/O that/O attitude/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ,/O because/O I/O have/O n't/O associated/O with/O anybody/O like/O that/O for/O a/O long/O ,/O long/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O think/O of/O any/O excuse/O why/O anyone/O of/O the/O Jewish/O race/O should/O take/O an/O attitude/O like/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O certainly/O can/O not/O ,/O unless/O they/O refuse/O to/O believe/O the/O truth/O ,/O for/O other/O motives/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
A/O subsequent/O witness/O suggested/O about/O the/O only/O thing/O we/O could/O do/O with/O that/O man/O would/O be/O to/O send/O him/O over/O to/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
What/O do/O you/O think/O of/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O pass/O judgment/O on/O anything/O or/O anybody/O like/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O CLARDY/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O be/O a/O little/O harsh/O ,/O would/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O you/O stated/O this/O picture/O was/O a/O success/O financially-Mr/O ./O 
DARE/O ./O 
This/O play/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNFR/PERSON ./O 
I/O meant/O the/O play/O ./O 
This/O play/O ``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ./O ''/O 
What/O was/O done/O with/O the/O money/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O purpose/O for/O which/O the/O organization/O was/O formed/O was/O to/O do/O quite/O a/O variety/O of/O things/O ./O 
Produce/O dramatic/O shows/O and/O other/O things/O ,/O establish/O a/O school/O for/O actors/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
I/O had/O very/O little/O ,/O if/O anything/O ,/O to/O do/O with/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION once/O the/O show/O was/O finished/O ./O 
I/O know/O they/O produced/O a/O dramatic/O show/O ,/O which/O was/O a/O very/O big/O flop/O and/O lost/O money/O on/O it/O ./O 
It/O was/O a/O show/O called/O ``/O Zero/O Hour/O ''/O by/O Albert/PERSON Maltz/PERSON ./O 
Subsequently/O I/O heard/O that/O ./O 
By/O this/O time/O I/O think/O we/O were/O in/O the/O war/O and/O they/O were/O financing/O a/O little/O group/O of/O entertainers/O to/O go/O around/O and/O entertain/O in/O the/O defense/O factories/O ./O 
By/O this/O time/O I/O am/O sure/O they/O favored/O the/O defense/O factories/O and/O hospitals/O and/O Army/O camps/O ./O 
There/O were/O all/O sorts/O ;/O there/O was/O a/O finance/O committee/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O membership/O committee/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O ticket/O committee/O ./O 
Our/O only/O function/O was/O to/O produce/O this/O show/O ,/O so/O I/O could/O n't/O say/O what/O happened/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O official/O connection/O of/O Irving/PERSON White/PERSON with/O the/O Hollywood/O Theater/O Alliance/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O actually/O remember/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O for/O a/O time/O he/O was/O a/O paid/O employee/O of/O the/O Hollywood/ORGANIZATION Theater/ORGANIZATION Alliance/ORGANIZATION ,/O for/O a/O small/O amount/O of/O money/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O remember/O exactly/O in/O what/O capacity/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O has/O it/O been/O since/O you/O have/O seen/O Mr./O White/PERSON ,/O Mr./O Dare/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Mr./O White/PERSON ,/O in/O 1950/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Around/O a/O place/O called/O the/O Actors/O '/O Lab/O ./O 
286/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O he/O is/O still/O interested/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O do/O not/O ,/O because/O I/O have/O not/O discussed-as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O ever/O since/O then/O I/O have-incidentally/O ,/O I/O had/O not/O seen/O him/O from/O the/O time/O ``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ''/O closed/O in/O 1950/O ,/O and/O I/O saw/O him/O at/O that/O time/O ;/O and/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O I/O never/O discussed/O politics/O with/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O his/O occupation/O in/O 1950/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
He/O was/O engaged/O on/O a/O committee/O that/O was/O producing/O a/O show/O for/O the/O Actors/O '/O Lab/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O where/O he/O is/O at/O the/O present/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
NO/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O have/O n't/O seen/O him/O since/O then/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O it/O was/O a/O financial/O success/O ,/O this/O ``/O Meet/O the/O People/O ./O ''/O 
In/O what/O terms/O do/O you/O refer/O to/O it/O as/O a/O monetary/O success/O ?/O 
How/O many/O thousand/O dollars/O '/O profit/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O if/O you/O have/O ever/O heard/O or/O knew/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Gosh/O ,/O I/O could/O n't/O say/O ./O 
I/O know/O it/O made/O a/O couple/O of/O thousand/O dollars/O a/O week/O for/O a/O long/O period/O of/O time/O ./O 
It/O went/O on/O the/O road/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
For/O 6/O months/O or/O a/O year/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
For/O a/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
A/O couple/O of/O thousand/O a/O week/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O actually/O could/O n't/O be/O sure/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O name/O any/O great/O sum/O and/O then/O find/O out/O I/O was/O wrong/O ./O 
I/O know/O it/O made/O money/O ,/O and/O I/O know/O it/O made/O fairly/O important/O money/O ./O 
And/O ,/O in/O all/O fairness/O ,/O a/O lot/O of/O it/O was/O used/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O people/O working/O around/O ./O 
Whether/O they/O needed/O them/O or/O not/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O they/O were/O people/O who/O would/O be/O paid/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
But/O there/O was/O money/O made/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Through/O the/O course/O of/O your/O testimony/O you/O have/O given/O as/O reasons/O for/O your/O decisions/O and/O actions/O that/O it/O was/O because/O of/O your/O attitude/O on/O the/O issue/O of/O anti-Semitism/O ./O 
The/O question/O I/O am/O about/O to/O ask/O you/O has/O no/O reflection/O on/O you/O or/O to/O determine/O the/O issue-I/O ask/O you/O ,/O are/O you/O of/O Jewish/O heritage/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Frazier/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
You/O stated/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION some/O years/O ago/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O for/O approximately/O 2/O or/O 3/O months/O and/O have/O been/O out/O since/O then/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O the/O first/O faction/O that/O you/O belonged/O to/O consisted/O of/O 5/O or/O 6/O persons/O ,/O of/O which/O Mr./O White/PERSON seems/O to/O have/O been/O the/O moving/O spirit/O ./O 
Since/O your/O withdrawal/O have/O you/O had/O any/O contacts/O with/O the/O other/O members/O of/O that/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Any/O association/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 287/O Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O people/O were/O never/O friends/O of/O mine/O ,/O including/O the/O people/O who/O were/O in/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION Theater/LOCATION Alliance/LOCATION ,/O were/O never/O my/O social/O friends/O ./O 
Tanya/PERSON Tuttle/PERSON and/O -LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O Dare/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Gang/PERSON and/O others/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
And/O Mr./O White/PERSON had/O something/O to/O do/O with/O a/O show/O at/O the/O Actors/O '/O Lab/O ,/O which/O I/O directed/O in/O 1950/O ,/O early/O 1950/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O of/O your/O own/O knowledge/O whether/O these/O persons/O that/O you/O have/O mentioned/O are/O still/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
The/O persons/O I/O have/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O would/O n't/O have/O known/O ever/O since/O then/O ,/O because/O once/O I/O just/O stopped/O going-I/O went/O to/O 2/O meetings/O that/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O sure/O that/O I/O went/O to/O 1/O ,/O 2/O ,/O or/O 3/O more/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O just/O bored/O ./O 
I/O could/O n't/O sit/O around/O and/O listen/O to/O a/O lot/O of/O talk/O that/O I/O did/O n't/O understand/O ./O 
I/O was/O just/O interested/O in/O doing/O something/O to/O fight/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON ./O 
I/O just/O stopped/O going/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O asked/O by/O Mr./O White/PERSON about/O going/O to/O a/O meeting/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O 'm/O too/O nervous/O ./O 
I/O just/O ca/O n't/O sit/O around/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O you/O are/O talking/O about/O ./O ''/O 
Since/O that/O time/O no/O one/O has/O ever/O told/O me/O anything/O officially/O about/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION nor/O have/O I/O ever/O discussed/O any/O official/O business/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION with/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O was/O it/O when/O you/O withdrew/O your/O active/O part/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O from/O around/O March/O 1939/O to/O around/O May/O 1939/O ,/O which/O may/O explain/O the/O fact/O that/O I/O was/O unaware/O of/O things/O happening/O around/O the/O Hollywood/O Theater/O Alliance/O ./O 
I/O had/O already/O been/O out/O before/O the/O show/O went/O into/O its/O rehearsal/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O guess/O I/O was/O n't/O taken/O into/O confidence/O and/O given/O the/O reasons/O why/O certain/O materials/O should/O be/O in/O the/O show/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O FRAZIER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dare/PERSON ,/O since/O you/O severed/O your/O connection/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O have/O you/O attended/O any/O functions/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
By/O ``/O functions/O ''/O you/O meanMr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O attended/O any/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O DARE/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O never/O ./O 
