INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 5/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-THIRD/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O DECEMBER/O 2/O ,/O 1952/O ;/O FEBRUARY/O 17/O ,/O MARCH/O 12/O AND/O 27/O ,/O AND/O APRIL/O 7/O AND/O 13/O ,/O 1953/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O J1747/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFrICg/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1953/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION MORGAN/LOCATION M./LOCATION MOULDER/LOCATION ,/O Missouri/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON L/PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION KIT/LOCATION CLARDY/LOCATION ,/O Michigan/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR/O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION ROBERTL/O KUNrZI/O ,/O Counsel/O FRANK/PERSON S/PERSON TAVENNER/PERSON ,/O Jr/O ,/O Counsel/PERSON LOuIS/PERSON J/PERSON RUSSELL/PERSON ,/O Chief/O Investigator/O THOMASW/O ./O 
BEALE/LOCATION ,/O Sr/O ,/O Chsef/O Clerk/O RAPHAEL/PERSON I./PERSON NIXON/PERSON ,/O Director/O of/O Research/O II/O CONTENTS/O Page/O March/O 27/O ,/O 1953/O Testimony/O of/O Charles/PERSON H/PERSON Garrigues/PERSON -----------/O April/O 7/O ,/O 1953/O Testimony/O of/O Jerome/PERSON Robinson/PERSON _/O ./O 
_/O _/O --/O April/O 13/O ,/O 1953/O Testimony/O ofThomas/O Matthew/PERSON McGrath/PERSON .../O _/O Matilda/PERSON Lewis/PERSON ---------------/O .../O __/O ./O 
./O 
__/O ~/O ~/O .../O _/O ___/O December/O 22/O ,/O 1952/O ./O 
Executive/O statement/O of/O Anne/PERSON Kmney/PERSON --/O February/O 17/O ,/O 1953/O -/O Executive/O statement/O of/O Mildred/PERSON Benoff/PERSON ./O 
--/O March/O 12/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Executive/O statementsStanley/O Rubin/PERSON _/O -/O __/O -/O ______/O -/O ___/O --/O _/O _/O Sol/O Shor/O .../O .../O ./O 
./O 
_/O --------------/O ./O 
Leopold/PERSON Lawrence/PERSON Atlas/PERSON ----------------------/O _/O Pauline/PERSON Swanson/PERSON Townsend/PERSON -/O ___/O ./O 
__/O ./O 
./O 
__/O .../O __/O -/O __/O .../O ./O 
-/O .../O _/O Paul/PERSON Benedict/PERSON Radin/PERSON -----------------------/O ___/O Index/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERSANDDUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 83D/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 3/O ,/O 11,3/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O STANDINGCOMMITTEES/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O o/O \*/O \*/O a/O \*/O a/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O O/O '/O F/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
VI/O INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 5/O FRIDAY/O ,/O MARCH/O 27/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UK-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 3:10/O p./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 527-DU/O ,/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION House/ORGANIZATION Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O member/O present/O :/O Representative/O Harold/PERSON H./PERSON Velde/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O member/O present/O :/O Raphael/PERSON I./PERSON Nixon/PERSON ,/O director/O of/O research/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Acting/O upon/O the/O authority/O vested/O in/O me/O as/O chairman/O of/O the/O Conmmittee/O on/O Un-Amiercan/O Activities/O ,/O I/O have/O appointed/O myself/O as/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O one/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O executive/O session/O ./O 
Mr./O Nixon/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O please/O call/O the/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Charles/PERSON H./PERSON Garrigues/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Nixon/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O proceed/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O CHARLES/PERSON H./PERSON GARRIGUES/PERSON Mr./O NixoN/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Garrigues/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O appearing/O in/O response/O to/O a/O subpena/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
And/O will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
Charles/PERSON H./PERSON Garrigues/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Garrigues/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Before/O I/O answer/O ,/O may/O I/O ask/O this/O question/O :/O Is/O this/O proceeding/O now/O considered/O a/O part/O of/O the/O main/O hearing/O ?/O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O evidence/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O the/O record/O ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON is/O sitting/O as/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O one/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O receiving/O your/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O a/O public/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O wanted/O to/O be/O sure/O of/O that/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Kansas/LOCATION in/O 1902/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
At/O 1623/O Per/LOCATION Alta/LOCATION ,/O Albany/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
848/O COMMUiNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ,/O with/O the/O San/ORGANIZATION Francisco/ORGANIZATION Examiner/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O so/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O briefly/O what/O your/O previous/O occupational/O background/O is/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O a/O newspaperman/O for-comnenced/O about/O 1922/O ,/O working/O on/O many/O papers/O in/O southern/O California/LOCATION and/O Arizona/LOCATION ./O 
In/O 1926/O I/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION and/O worked/O on/O the/O old/O Express/O ,/O and/O I/O moved/O to/O the/O old/O Herald/ORGANIZATION in/O 19-I/O think/O it/O was/O 1929/O ./O 
I/O went/O fo/O the/O Daily/O News/O ,/O where/O I/O was/O employed/O ,/O with/O various/O leaves/O of/O absence/O ,/O until/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O 1935/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O those/O leaves/O of/O absence/O did/O you/O have/O other/O employment/O Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O did/O ./O 
I/O was/O engaged/O during/O most/O of/O that/O time/O in/O which/O I/O was/O working/O with/O the/O News/O as/O the/O political/O expert/O or/O political/O editor/O ,/O and/O from/O time/O to/O time/O I/O was/O assigned/O by/O Mr./O Boddy/PERSON to/O take/O leave/O and/O work/O for/O various/O civic/O and/O governmental/O organizations/O as/O an/O investigator/O of/O conditions/O ./O 
And/O at/O 2/O or/O 3/O times/O I/O was/O employed/O during/O those/O periods/O as/O investigator/O for/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Grand/O Jury/O ,/O or/O the/O District/O Attorney/O 's/O Office/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O which/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
In/O a/O special/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
In/O a/O special/O capacity/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O in/O order/O to/O complete/O the/O record/O ,/O will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O what/O your/O educational/O background/O was/O prior/O to/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O graduated/O from/O the/O Per/ORGANIZATION Alta/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O 1919/O and/O spent/O 1/O year/O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Southern/ORGANIZATION California/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O employed/O in/O a/O writing/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O what/O you/O would/O call/O a/O copyreader/O ,/O subeditor/O ./O 
That/O is/O one/O who/O reads/O copy/O and/O writes/O headlines/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O that/O ./O 
During/O most/O of/O this/O period/O you/O have/O been/O associated/O in/O the/O field/O of/O journalism/O ,/O has/O it/O been/O in/O a/O writing/O capacity/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O chiefly/O as/O a/O copyreader/O ,/O except/O when/O I/O was/O working/O on/O the/O Daily/O News/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O employment/O during/O the/O period/O of/O approximately/O 1935/O to/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O very/O scattered/O and/O vague/O ./O 
I/O really/O have/O to/O think/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Just/O generally/O ,/O I/O mean/O ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O particular/O period/O of/O employment/O with/O any/O paper/O or/O publication/O during/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O edited/O a/O little/O paper/O called/O the/O Utopian/O News/O for/O several/O months/O ./O 
I/O was/O engaged/O in/O political/O work/O as/O a/O free-lance/O public/O relations/O man/O at/O various/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O say/O ``/O political/O ,/O ''/O what/O do/O you/O mean/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARIrGUEs/O ./O 
I/O had/O a/O bureau/O ,/O a/O public/O relations/O bureau/O ,/O and/O we/O hired/O ourselves/O out/O to/O candidates/O ,/O prepared/O their/O copy/O andMr/O ./O 
NrxoN/O ./O 
For/O campaign/O purposes/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRGUEs/O ./O 
For/O campaign/O purposes/O ,/O yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O has/O there/O been/O any/O time/O during/O this/O period/O that/O you/O have/O related/O that/O you/O had/O occasion/O to/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O did/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 849/O Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O the/O circumstances/O of/O your/O joining/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O may/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O go/O back/O to/O the/O inception/O ,/O when/O I/O started/O the/O trend/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxow/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O hear/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
My/O first/O contact/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O inI/O think/O during/O the/O presidential/O campaign/O of/O 1934/O ,/O when/O I/O was/O employed/O on/O the/O Daily/O News/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O assigned/O there/O to/O go/O down/O and/O interview/O William/PERSON Z./PERSON Foster/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Just/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O clarification/O here/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O believe/O there/O was/O a/O presidential/O campaign/O in/O 1934/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
It/O could/O not/O have/O been/O ./O 
It/O must/O have/O been/O 1932/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
1932/O or/O 1936/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
1932/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O presidential/O campaign/O of/O President/O Roosevelt/O against/O President/O Hoover/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
That/O was/O 1932/O ,/O of/O course/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Continue/O ./O 
You/O saw/O William/PERSON Z./PERSON Foster/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O assigned/O to/O go/O and/O interview/O him/O ,/O which/O I/O did/O ./O 
I/O was/O rather/O impressed/O by/O the/O man/O 's/O attitude/O ,/O wrote/O what/O I/O would/O consider/O a/O very/O favorable/O honest/O interview/O ,/O was/O quite/O proud/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O it/O was/O probably/O the/O first/O honest/O interview/O written/O of/O a/O Communist/O and/O published/O in/O a/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION newspaper/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
For/O what/O newspaper/O was/O this/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
This/O was/O the/O Daily/O News/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O wasyou/O remember/O that/O was/O the/O depth/O of/O the/O depression/O ,/O and/O one/O of/O my/O jobs/O was/O meeting/O the/O people/O who/O came/O to/O the/O Examiner-to/O the/O Newsexcuse/O me-in/O search/O of/O some/O kind/O of/O help/O ./O 
Many/O people/O came/O there/O very/O desperate/O for/O food/O or/O paying/O their/O rent/O ,/O and/O during/O many/O days/O 20/O and/O 30/O sometimes/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O question/O them/O and/O sometimes/O ,/O very/O frequently/O call/O reports/O in/O to/O the/O WPA/O ,/O I/O would/O very/O frequently/O call/O friends/O of/O mine/O at/O the/O city/O and/O county/O offices/O and/O ask/O them/O to/O help/O this/O particular/O family/O or/O that/O particular/O family/O ./O 
After/O this/O interview/O with/O Foster/O I/O began/O to-or/O the/O boys/O came/O and/O called/O upon/O me/O ,/O several/O Commies/O whom/O I/O do/O n't/O now/O recall/O ,/O and/O they/O made/O no/O particular/O impression/O on/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
They/O were/O known/O to/O you/O as/O Communists/O or/O so/O identified/O themselves/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
They/O identified/O themselves/O as/O Communists/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
All/O Communists/O ,/O were/O they/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
As/O well/O as/O people/O of/O all/O other/O left-wing/O political/O beliefs/O ./O 
And/O during/O the/O campaign/O I/O had/O contact/O for/O the/O first/O time/O with/O what/O the/O people/O called/O first/O just/O ``/O the/O movement/O ,/O ''/O which/O consisted/O of/O the/O Communists/O ,/O Guild/O Socialists/O ,/O Walker/O Socialists/O ,/O Utopian/O Socialists/O ,/O remnants/O of/O the/O old/O IWW/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O merely/O ordinary/O socialists/O and/O left-wing/O Democrats/O ,/O and/O noted/O trade/O unionists/O ,/O began/O to/O come/O in/O later/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
They/O did/O n't/O make/O too/O much/O impression/O upon/O me/O ,/O except/O I/O became/O aware/O for/O the/O first/O time/O that/O there/O was/O a/O good/O body/O of/O political/O theory/O which/O I/O was/O not/O familiar/O with/O ./O 
During/O those/O times/O when/O I/O was/O engaged/O in/O political/O work/O for/O Mr./O Boddy/PERSON ,/O the/O publisher/O of/O the/O News/O ,/O as/O a/O reform/O investigator/O ,/O I/O had/O begun/O to/O theorize/O a/O great/O deal/O about/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O American/O Gov/O -/O 850/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O ernment/O ,/O municipal/O and/O higher/O governments/O ,/O and/O had/O at/O various/O times/O started/O preparation/O of/O a/O book/O relating/O to/O some/O of/O my/O experiences/O as/O an/O investigator/O ,/O and/O some/O of/O the/O things/O which/O I/O thought/O could/O be/O done/O and/O could/O not/O be/O done/O and/O should/O be/O done/O or/O should/O not/O be/O done/O in/O order/O to/O save/O the/O American/O system/O from/O downfall/O from/O internal/O corruption/O ./O 
As/O my/O experience/O in/O that/O direction/O became/O w/O ider/O I/O began/O to/O have/O more/O and/O more/O definite/O ideas/O ,/O and/O by/O 1935/O they/O had/O begun/O to/O crystallize/O in/O a/O book/O in/O which/O I/O set/O forth/O quite/O completely/O my/O conclusions/O as/O to/O the/O relationships/O between/O business/O and/O government/O ,/O the/O genesis/O of/O graft/O ,/O and/O that/O sort/O of/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Now/O ,/O fixing/O this/O again/O in/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O you/O just/O referred/O to/O 1935/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O commencement/O of/O this/O feeling/O ?/O 
1932/O ,/O 1929/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
The/O commencement/O of/O the/O feeling/O of/O relationship/O ?/O 
Mr./O Nixox/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O or/O that/O tendency/O or/O thought/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARIGUrES/O ./O 
My/O interest/O in/O the/O subject/O ?/O 
Mr./O NixoN/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Mv/O interest/O in/O the/O subject/O began/O when/O I/O was/O a/O kid/O ./O 
The/O first/O work/O I/O did/O I/O was/O a/O newspaper/O editor/O in/O Venice/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O when/O Venice/LOCATION had/O a/O realty/O boom/O in/O 1922/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O have/O any/O opportunity/O to/O do/O any/O more/O investigation/O probably/O until/O 1930/O ,/O when/O I/O assisted/O in/O the/O prosecution/O ,/O the/O detection/O and/O prosecution/O of/O certain/O people/O known/O as/O the/O dam/O graft/O ring/O ,/O which/O sent/O a/O couple/O of/O men/O to/O the/O penitentiary/O ,/O and/O out/O of/O that/O there/O came/O not/O only/O the/O political/O idea/O ,/O you/O might/O say/O moral/O idea/O of/O what/O should/O be/O done/O ,/O but/O I/O was/O interested/O to/O see/O if/O it/O was/O possible/O to/O convict/O a/O bribery/O case/O solely/O on/O circumstantial/O evidence/O ,/O and/O they/O did/O that/O in/O the/O first/O bribe/O case/O in/O American/O jurisprudence/O with/O no/O evidence/O other/O than/O circumstantial/O ,/O got/O a/O conviction/O and/O got/O it/O sustained/O by/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O NixoN/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
We/O will/O get/O down/O to/O the/O actual/O period/O of/O your/O joining/O ./O 
You/O have/O previously/O referred/O to/O your/O interview/O with/O William/PERSON Z./PERSON Foster/PERSON ./O 
Am/O I/O to/O understand/O that/O that/O was/O in/O connection/O with/O his/O presidential/O candidacy/O at/O that/O time/O Mr./O GAmRIGUES/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
And/O it/O was/O an/O assigned/O interview/O ?/O 
Mi/O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O an/O assigned/O interview/O ,/O just/O as/O any/O newspaperman/O would/O be/O assigned/O ./O 
The/O particular/O topic/O was/O how/O it/O feels/O to/O be/O a/O presidential/O candidate/O ./O 
He/O had/O been/O beaten/O up/O by/O a/O bunch/O of/O hoodlums/O in/O I/O believe/O one/O campaign/O speech/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O assigned/O the/O job/O of/O finding/O out/O how/O it/O feels/O to/O be/O a/O presidential/O candidate/O and/O to/O be/O beaten/O up/O in/O his/O campaign/O Mr./O Nixo/PERSON -/O As/O I/O understand/O from/O what/O you/O said/O before/O ,/O you/O were/O given/O what/O you/O considered/O a/O completely/O objective/O interview/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NixoN/O By/O Mr./O Foster/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O G/O \/O RRInUES/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O presented/O his/O point/O of/O view/O ,/O and/O I/O tried/O to/O get/O his/O personal/O point/O of/O view/O as/O accurately/O as/O I/O could/O ./O 
Mr./O Nixox/PERSON ./O 
In/O repeating/O it/O ,/O you/O mean/O Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
In/O repeating/O it/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
That/O ,/O as/O the/O record/O shows/O ,/O was/O in/O 1932/O ./O 
It/O was/O not/O at/O that/O time/O that/O you/O actually/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O that/O was/O my/O first/O contact/O with/O it/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ./O 
Then/O increasingly/O during/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O depression/O I/O began/O to/O come/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 851/O in/O contact/O with/O this/O segment/O of/O society/O who/O called/O themselves/O ``/O the/O movement/O ,/O ''/O and/O in/O 1935/O when/O I/O left/O the/O News-I/O think/O it/O was/O 1935/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O maybe/O I/O am/O wrong/O on/O the/O date/O ./O 
Late/O in/O 1935/O or/O early/O in/O 1936/O ,/O possibly/O ./O 
I/O had/O just/O finished/O my/O first/O book/O ,/O and/O it/O was/O accepted/O and/O I/O then/O began/O to/O debate/O the/O idea/O of/O doing/O another/O book/O on/O the/O relationship/O between/O labor/O and/O governent/O ,/O the/O potentialities/O in/O there/O ./O 
At/O that/O time/O I/O had/O been/O employed-it/O must/O have/O been/O in/O 1936/O ./O 
I/O was/O employed/O by/O a/O committee/O working/O for/O Harlan/PERSON Palmer/PERSON for/O district/O attorney/O ,/O and/O after/O that/O campaign/O ended/O I/O went/O to/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ./O 
I/O was/O then/O employed/O by/O the/O King-Ramsey-Connor/O defense/O committee/O ;/O investigated/O a/O murder/O trial/O in/O Alameda/LOCATION County/LOCATION a/O couple/O months/O ,/O where/O I/O met/O more/O and/O nore/O Communists/O I/O came/O back/O to/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION and/O went/O to/O work/O for/O the/O San/ORGANIZATION Diego/ORGANIZATION Sun/ORGANIZATION ./O 
That/O must/O have/O been/O early/O in/O 1937/O ./O 
And/O at/O that/O time/O I/O decided/O that/O I/O would/O make/O a/O thorough/O investigation/O of/O the/O potentialities/O of/O the/O labor/O movement/O in/O the/O same/O manner/O that/O I/O had/O previously/O done/O with/O the/O graft/O situation/O ,/O except/O to/O approach/O it/O on/O a/O different/O angle/O ./O 
I/O went/O down/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION offices/O and/O book/O shop/O ,/O headquarters/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ,/O and/O told/O them/O ,/O this/O man/O there/O ,/O that/O I/O wanted/O to/O join/O the/O party/O ./O 
He/O handed/O me/O a/O card/O and/O I/O signed/O it/O ./O 
And/O a/O couple/O of/O months/O later/O or/O possibly/O a/O month/O ,/O about/O that/O time/O ,/O I/O would/O say/O ,/O I/O had/O a/O call/O from/O him/O that/O I/O was/O to/O meet/O a/O certain/O man/O at/O a/O certain/O place/O ./O 
I/O remember/O who/O ,/O but/O where/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
Mr./O NixoN/PERSON ./O 
Fromn/O that/O you/O recruited/O yourself/O actually/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
There/O was/O no/O effort/O other/O than/O the/O initiation/O that/O you/O made/O in/O going/O to/O the/O headquarters/O and/O expressing/O your/O interest/O in/O becoming/O a/O member/O Mr./O GAjRRIUEs/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
lMr/O ./O 
NixoN/O ./O 
Who/O was/O it/O that/O you/O met/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Stanley/PERSON Hancock/PERSON ,/O the/O county/O organizer/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O county/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Was/O there/O the/O formality/O of/O issuing/O you/O a/O card/O ?/O 
Mi/O ./O 
G/O RRCIGciE/O ./O 
II/O -/O issued/O me/O a/O card/O or/O a/O book/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O now/O which/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O Nixox/PERSON ./O 
Were/O there/O any/O instructions/O given/O to/O you/O as/O to/O future/O meetings/O or/O activities/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O told/O that/O I/O was/O to-the/O party/O would/O keep/O in/O contact/O with/O me/O ,/O but/O that/O I/O was/O to/O keep/O undercover/O ,/O not/O to/O expose/O myself/O ,/O and/O they/O would/O have/O more/O information/O for/O me/O later/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Hancock/PERSON was/O the/O only/O one/O that/O you/O met/O at/O this/O particular/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
At/O that/O particular/O tune/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O Nixox/PERSON ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O were/O you/O given/O any/O instructions/O or/O indoctrination/O instructions/O into/O the/O party/O ,/O or/O Marxism/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O by/O this/O time/O I/O had/O begun/O to/O read/O theoretical/O Marxism/O ,/O which/O is/O what/O I/O say/O most/O interested/O me/O ,/O that/O aspect/O of/O it/O ./O 
There/O was/O a/O person/O who/O came/O to/O me/O or/O called/O me/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O would/O come/O to/O me/O from/O time/O to/O time/O and/O bring/O me/O pamphlets/O and/O books/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O the/O identity/O of/O any/O of/O those/O ?/O 
852/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
His/O name/O was/O Morrie/PERSON Smolan/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O not/O throughout/O the/O period/O of/O time/O assigned/O to/O any/O particular/O group/O or/O anything/O ,/O but/O more/O in/O a/O position/O of/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O for/O a/O little/O while/O ;/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O how/O long/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O know/O I/O was/O regarded/O with/O considerable/O suspicion/O at/O first/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Why/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Because/O I/O had/O recruited/O myself/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
At/O the/O time/O of/O your/O recruitment/O ,/O you/O made/O it/O known/O to/O them/O that/O you/O were/O in/O the/O newspaper/O field/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O told/O them/O ./O 
They/O knew/O my/O background/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O anyone/O else/O beside/O Stanley/PERSON Hancock/PERSON and/O Morrie/PERSON Smolan/PERSON that/O you/O recall/O now/O ?/O 
Mr./O GArRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O not/O very/O definitely/O ,/O other/O than/O a/O fellow/O named/O Dick/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O a-I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O his/O name/O ./O 
I/O think/O his/O last/O name/O was/O Richards/PERSON ./O 
They/O called/O him/O Dick/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O are/O not/O sure/O what/O his/O first/O name/O was/O ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O other/O identifying/O data/O that/O you/O could/O now/O recall/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O relation/O to/O him/O ./O 
I/O would/O know/O him/O if/O 1/O saw/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O a/O party/O functionary/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
A/O part-time/O party/O functionary/O or/O something/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O time/O while/O you/O were/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION that/O you/O were/O assigned/O to/O a/O particular/O group/O or/O unit/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O under/O the/O impression/O I/O got/O ,/O that/O those/O were/O a/O group/O ,/O and/O I/O can/O remember/O one/O meeting/O in/O particular/O at/O which/O Hancock/PERSON was/O not/O present/O and/O there/O was/O some/O criticism/O of/O Hancock/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O he/O was/O later/O disciplined/O or/O something/O at/O that/O time/O in/O connection/O with/O something/O at/O that/O meeting/O ./O 
But/O who/O was/O there/O except/O for/O Dick/PERSON and/O a/O woman-I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O who/O the/O woman/O was/O ,/O but/O her/O name/O is/O Bessie/PERSON ,/O but/O I/O could/O n't/O identify/O her/O ./O 
She/O is/O a/O housewife/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
And/O then/O I/O think/O you/O referred/O to/O having/O left/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ./O 
When/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O in-must/O have/O been/O probably/O October/O of/O 1937/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Where/O did/O you/O go/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O your/O party/O affiliation/O transferred/O from/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O it/O must/O have/O been/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O continued/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O came/O up/O here/O ;/O they/O asked/O me/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O the/O newspaper/O guild-of/O course/O ,/O by/O this/O time/O I/O was/O a/O part-time/O organizer/O employed/O either/O by/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Newspaper/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION or/O by/O the/O CIO/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ,/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O where/O my/O pay/O came/O from/O ,/O or/O maybe/O from/O both/O ./O 
And/O they/O were/O having/O trouble/O in/O the/O guild/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O and/O the/O guild/O officers/O here/O asked/O me/O to/O come/O up/O ./O 
Mr./O Nixox/PERSON In/O connection/O with/O your/O work/O nmorganizing/O the/O guild/O ,/O did/O you/O receive/O any/O instructions/O or/O directives/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O to/O what/O action/O your/O work/O should/O be/O directed/O to/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGCES/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O the/O sense/O of/O instructions/O or/O directions/O ;/O no/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 853/O Mr./O NIXoN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O would/O it/O be/O on/O a/O basis/O that/O because/O of/O your/O knowledge/O of/O the/O purposes/O and/O your/O activities/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O that/O your/O direction/O or/O the/O activities/O that/O you/O used/O in/O organizing/O the/O guild/O were/O influenced/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O the/O extent/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O well/O as/O an/O organizer/O for/O this/O particular/O organization/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O you/O can/O go/O further/O than/O that/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ,/O at/O least/O in/O theory/O ,/O because/O I/O believe/O in/O the/O importance/O of/O the/O labor/O movement/O as/O such/O ./O 
The/O guild/O ,/O according/O to/O the/O theory/O under/O which/O we/O were/O working/O ,/O was/O a/O very/O important/O aspect/O of/O that/O labor/O movement/O ,/O and/O anything/O I/O could/O do/O to/O strengthen/O the/O labor/O movement-Mr/O ./O 
NIXON/PERSON ./O 
By/O the/O guild/O are/O you/O referring/O to/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O referring/O to/O both/O ,/O although/O I/O mean/O the/O labor/O movement/O particularly/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Particularly/O in/O regard/O to/O aiding/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O that/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
When/O you/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O unit/O or/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O assigned/O to/O a/O unit/O ./O 
I/O remember/O going/O to/O the/O first/O meeting/O ,/O because/O it/O was/O not/O a/O meeting/O ,/O it/O was/O actually/O just/O not/O a/O real/O party/O meeting/O ./O 
But/O I/O think/O I/O stayed/O in/O that/O unit/O ,/O or/O possibly/O another/O unit/O was/O formed/O later/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O meet/O very/O much/O with/O the/O unit/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O the/O components/O of/O this/O unit/O from/O the/O newspaper/O field/O only/O ,/O or/O was/O it/O a/O miscellaneous/O unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O preponderantly/O so/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O somewhat/O mixed/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O any/O individuals/O who/O were/O in/O this/O unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O not/O too/O thoroughly/O ,/O not/O too/O distinctly/O ,/O for/O this/O reason/O ,/O that/O I/O do/O n't/O say/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O any/O of/O them/O ,/O butMr/O ./O 
NIXON/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O the/O interrogation/O here/O there/O are/O certain/O names/O that/O I/O will/O ask/O you/O if/O you/O can/O recall/O ./O 
During/O the/O organization/O of/O the/O guild/O was/O any/O outside/O help/O given/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Any/O help/O from/O outside/O the/O guild/O ?/O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O from/O outside/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O in/O the/O organizing/O of/O the/O unit/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O think/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O a/O person/O named/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ;/O I/O recall/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON ./O 
Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION guild/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O he/O in/O it/O at/O the/O time/O that/O you/O first/O knew/O him/O ?/O 
Were/O you/O in/O the/O unit/O when/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON joined/O the/O unit/O ,/O or/O was/O he/O already/O in/O the/O unit/O when/O you/O joined/O up/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
My/O impression/O is/O that/O Morgan/PERSON Hull/PERSON was/O a/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION member/O long/O before/O I/O was/O and/O before/O there/O was/O a/O guild/O ./O 
I/O knew/O him/O previously/O ./O 
He/O and/O I/O worked/O on/O the/O same/O paper/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O that/O period/O did/O you/O know/O an/O individual/O named/O Lou/PERSON Amster/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGuEs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O knew/O a/O Lou/PERSON Amster/PERSON ./O 
My/O impression/O is-Mr/O ./O 
NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O it/O a/O definite/O impression/O ?/O 
Mr./O GAmRIGUES/O ./O 
Not/O too/O definite/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O only/O an/O impression/O ?/O 
854/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O is/O a/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O an/O individual/O named/O Leo/PERSON Selkowski/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O knew/O Leo/PERSON Selkowski/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O I/O knew/O him/O to/O be/O in/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Urcel/PERSON Daniel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O knew/O her/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O record/O ,/O Miss/O Daniel/PERSON has/O appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O has/O admitted/O past/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O her/O during/O the/O time/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
My/O impression/O is/O that/O she/O was/O the/O secretary/O of/O our/O unit/O ,/O but/O the/O date/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O just/O now/O ./O 
It/O was/O sometime/O during/O the/O period/O ./O 
Just/O when/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O unit/O to/O any/O degree/O financing/O the/O guild/O ,/O your/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION unit/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGES/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think-it/O is/O hard/O to/O remember/O ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O place/O it/O as/O closely/O as/O I/O can/O ,/O but/O most/O of/O the/O unit/O members/O ,/O that/O is/O ,/O the/O party/O members/O were/O guild/O members/O unquestionably/O ,/O not/O all/O of/O them/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O but/O probably/O most/O of/O them/O ./O 
They/O were/O possibly/O during/O that/O time-this/O was/O the/O period/O ,/O if/O you/O recollect/O ,/O right/O after/O I/O got/O into/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O and/O they/O had/O at/O the/O time/O the/O policy/O of/O having/O open/O meetings/O ,/O where/O there/O were/O various/O types/O of/O open/O meetings/O ,/O but/O there/O was/O no/O longer/O ,/O as/O I/O understood/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O there/O were/O no/O longer/O occasional/O fraction/O meetings/O of/O the/O guild/O ,/O but/O the/O progressive/O interest/O we/O had/O in/O that/O term/O came/O from/O our/O crucial/O problems/O ,/O and/O we/O had/O 1/O or/O 2/O or/O 3/O or/O more/O nonparty/O members/O who/O were/O progressing/O the/O labor/O movement/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O you/O mean/O some/O of/O the/O individuals/O who/O were/O in/O attendance/O were/O not/O necessarily/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION members/O to/O have/O been/O in/O attendance/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O very/O difficult/O to/O distinguish/O between/O the/O two/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
_/O In/O those/O instances/O in/O which/O there/O is/O no/O question/O in/O your/O mind/O ,/O for/O the/O matter/O of/O the/O record/O ,/O we/O want/O it/O indicated/O by/O you/O ./O 
I/O mean/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O interrogation/O or/O the/O questioning/O is/O to/O have/O you/O identify/O the/O names/O of/O certain/O individuals/O whom/O you/O are/O certain/O of/O ,/O but/O if/O there/O is/O any/O question/O in/O your/O mind/O ,/O make/O it/O known/O so/O that/O the/O record/O will/O be/O complete/O on/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O say/O this/O before/O that/O ,/O that/O I/O remember/O distinctly/O 5/O or/O 6/O members/O of/O them/O that/O were/O in/O this/O labor/O guild/O mobilization/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O they/O were/O all/O Communists/O ./O 
I/O think/O 2/O or/O 3/O of/O them/O were/O ,/O and/O then/O there/O may/O be/O certain/O others/O that/O were/O in/O there/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O a/O person/O named/O Burke/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Burke/PERSON to/O be/O a/O Communist/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O know/O that/O he/O was/O in/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Dorothy/PERSON Healey/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O her/O before/O I/O was/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O and/O we/O had/O a/O good/O many/O discussions/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Charles/PERSON Judson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O knew/O Judson/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O he/O has/O testified/O that/O he/O was/O not/O in/O the/O party/O ,/O but/O I/O could/O say/O definitely/O he/O was/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 855/O Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O during/O the/O course/O of/O Mr./O Judson/PERSON 's/O testimony/O ,/O I/O believe/O he/O is/O one/O of/O the/O individuals/O who/O testified/O to/O his/O having/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Do/O you/O remember/O Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON was/O a/O party/O organizer/O ,/O if/O that/O is-I/O want/O to/O get/O that/O name/O right/O now/O ./O 
This/O is/O Paul/PERSON Cline/PERSON who/O was/O the/O party/O organizer/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O a/O Minua/PERSON Klein/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O knew/O Minna/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O she/O was/O a/O writer/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O her/O as/O a/O party/O member/O ,/O honestly/O ./O 
She/O was/O one/O of/O the/O people/O we/O saw/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
For/O identification/O ,/O she/O was/O the/O wife/O of/O Herbert/PERSON Klein/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O GAPMIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O knew/O Herbert/PERSON ,/O but/O whether/O they/O were/O party/O membersMr/O ./O 
NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O a/O William/PERSON E./PERSON Oliver/PERSON Mi/PERSON ./O 
GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O not/O at/O the/O time/O that/O I/O was/O there/O ./O 
I/O might/O say/O that/O there/O was/O some/O effort/O to/O recruit/O him/O at/O one/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O the/O testimony/O before/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O Miss/O Alice/PERSON Bennett/PERSON identified/O both/O Minna/PERSON Klein/PERSON and/O William/PERSON E./PERSON Over/PERSON as/O having/O been/O in/O this/O unit/O of/O the/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION Newspaper/ORGANIZATION Guild/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Philip/PERSON Johnson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Y.I/O mean/O not/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
I/O know/O him/O now/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O not/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O George/PERSON Shaffer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O did/O ./O 
George/PERSON Shaffer/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O S-h-a-f-f-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O GARRIGuES/PERSON ./O 
I/O saw/O him/O hand/O out/O a/O lot/O of/O folders/O ./O 
I/O know/O there/O are/O two/O people/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O know/O Ed/PERSON Robbins/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O think/O I/O know/O him/O ./O 
I/O did/O meet/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O him/O to/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O he/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O Sarah/PERSON Bognoff/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUEs/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O met/O Sarah/PERSON Bognoff/PERSON working/O in/O ,/O I/O think/O she/O was/O in/O the/O guild/O offices/O or/O some/O other/O union/O office/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O her/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O her/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Tom/PERSON O'Connor/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O him/O as/O a/O newspaperman/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Hai/PERSON e/O you/O during/O the/O course/O of/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION been/O assigned/O any/O Communist/ORGANIZATION name/O or/O any/O party/O name/O '/O Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O took/O a/O party/O name/O of/O E./PERSON Scott/PERSON ./O 
856/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O leave/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O NIxoN/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O formality/O in/O your/O leaving/O or/O did/O you/O merely/O drift/O away/O from/O the/O party/O and/O was/O there/O an/O actual/O break/O in/O your/O membership/O ?/O 
Mr./O GAxaIGEs/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O there/O was/O a/O break/O when/O I/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O no/O more/O contact/O with/O the/O party/O for/O a/O year/O or/O two/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O remember/O the/O approximate/O date/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
It/O must/O have/O been/O the/O early/O part/O of/O 1939/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O there/O any/O occasion/O or/O reason/O for/O you/O to/O feel/O all/O the/O time/O that/O you/O were/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O it/O was/O a/O revolutionary/O party/O or/O was/O a/O conspiracy/O in/O the/O sense/O of/O advocating/O the/O overthrow/O of/O this/O Government/O ,/O as/O it/O was/O stated/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O not/O in/O the/O sense/O in/O which/O the/O terms/O are/O now/O being/O used/O ./O 
That/O was/O not/O my/O experience/O with/O it/O at/O all/O ./O 
That/O was/O the/O particular/O point/O I/O studied/O most/O carefully/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O want/O to/O be/O in/O such/O a/O conspiracy/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
After/O you/O left/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION and/O left/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O were/O any/O efforts/O made/O to/O recruit/O you/O into/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O not/O contacted/O subsequently/O to/O be/O reactivated/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
Not/O at/O any/O time/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
And/O since/O the/O time/O you/O left/O you/O have/O had/O no/O further/O dealing/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON That/O is/O correct/O ,/O none/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O have/O not/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION since/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O GARRIGUES/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O NIXON/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O express/O my/O appreciation/O for/O the/O information/O which/O you/O have/O given/O us/O ./O 
Mr./O VELDE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Garrigues/PERSON ,/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O entire/O Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O I/O wish/O to/O express/O our/O thanks/O for/O your/O testimony/O today/O ./O 
You/O may/O be/O excused/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O witness/O was/O excused/O and/O the/O subcommittee/O adjourned/O subject/O to/O the/O call/O of/O the/O Chair/O ./O -RRB-/O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 5/O TUESDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 7/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O SLos/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O 1/O The/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 9/O -/O 15/O p./O m./O ,/O in/O the/O Cleveland/ORGANIZATION Room/ORGANIZATION ,/O Hotel/O Statler/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O acting/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O acting/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O and/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O counsel/O ;/O Thomas/PERSON W./PERSON Beale/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O chief/O clerk/O ;/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O please/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O call/O the/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Jerome/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O JEROME/PERSON ROBINSON/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
Jerome/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O RoBINsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O the/O practice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O make/O known/O to/O every/O witness/O they/O are/O entitled/O to/O have/O counsel/O with/O them/O if/O they/O desire/O ./O 
And/O furthermore/O ,/O you/O would/O have/O the/O right/O to/O consult/O counsel/O at/O any/O time/O during/O your/O interrogation/O ./O 
You/O understand/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Notwithstanding/O ,/O you/O are/O ready/O to/O proceed/O without/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Robinson/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ,/O February/O 25/O ,/O 1910/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupation/O Mr./O ROBINSoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O a/O photographer/O ./O 
SReleased/O by/O the/O committee/O ,/O April/O 13/O ,/O 1953/O ./O 
31747-53-pt/O ./O 
5-z/O 857/O 858/O COMMVIUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
Public/O school/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O now/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O RomINsN/O ./O 
I/O live/O in/O North/LOCATION Hollywood/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O lived/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
About/O 8/O ,/O 9/O years/O ,/O maybe/O 10/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Prior/O to/O that/O time/O ,/O where/O did/O you/O live/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
15/O East/O 53d/O St./O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O live/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
All/O my/O life/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O were/O you/O employed/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION for/O a/O period/O of/O 2/O years/O before/O coming/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O RoBINsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O a/O free-lance/O photographer/O ,/O mostly/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O engage/O m/O any/O other/O business/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION besides/O that/O of/O photography/O after/O your/O arrival/O here/O ?/O 
Mr./O ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr/O T.uVENNERC/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O that/O business/O ?/O 
Mr./O RoBINsoN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O employed/O in/O the/O shipyards/O when/O I/O first/O came/O out/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O information/O ,/O Mr./O Robinson/PERSON ,/O that/O in/O 1944/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O a/O branch/O of/O the/O Communist/O Palty/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O RoBINsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
On/O what/O grounds/O do/O you/O decline/O ?/O 
Mi/O ./O 
ROBINSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O fifth/O amendment/O ,/O I/O guess/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O see/O no/O occasion/O for/O my/O asking/O any/O additional/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Any/O questions/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr/O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O n't/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O RoBINsoN/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O need/O me/O again/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O from/O your/O subpena/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O the/O witness/O was/O excused/O and/O the/O subcommittee/O continued/O the/O executive/O session/O in/O relation/O to/O other/O matters/O ./O -RRB-/O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-Part/O 5/O MONDAY/O ,/O APRIL/O 13/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O Ux-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O 1/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 10:10/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O the/O chambers/O of/O Courtroom/O 9/O ,/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION and/O Courthouse/O Building/O ,/O Hon./O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O acting/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ,/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O member/O present/O :/O Representative/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O acting/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Staff/O member/O present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O call/O the/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Thomas/PERSON M./PERSON McGrath/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O THOMAS/O MATTHEW/PERSON McGRATH/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HIS/O COUNSEL/O ,/O WILLIAM/PERSON B./PERSON ESTERMAN/PERSON Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O the/O witness/O state/O his/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Thomas/PERSON McGrath/PERSON ,/O or/O with/O the/O middle/O name/O ,/O Thomas/PERSON Matthew/PERSON McGrath/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O county/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O an/O assistant/O professor/O at/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O us/O a/O brief/O r6sume/O of/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O first/O 8/O years/O ,/O I/O guess/O it/O is/O ,/O the/O public/O school/O of/O Highland/LOCATION Township/LOCATION ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O District/O 69/O ,/O if/O I/O am/O not/O mistaken/O ,/O the/O county/O of/O Cass/LOCATION ,/O in/O North/LOCATION Dakota/LOCATION ./O 
Following/O that/O ,/O 4/O years/O in/O high/O school/O ,/O Sheldon/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O the/O county/O of/O Ransom/O ./O 
Following/O that/O 4/O years/O I/O took/O a/O B./O A./O at/O the/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION North/ORGANIZATION Dakota/ORGANIZATION ./O 
`/O Released/O by/O the/O committee/O on/O same/O day/O ./O 
860/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O And/O following/O that/O ,/O a/O year/O and/O a/O quarter/O semester-I/O have/O forgotten/O how/O it/O was/O called-at/O Louisiana/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O when/O I/O took/O a/O master/O of/O arts/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O what/O year/O was/O that/O ?/O 
Mr/O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Master/O of/O arts/O ,/O 1939-40/O ./O 
Following/O that/O ,/O 1/O year/O at/O New/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ,/O University/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Oxford/ORGANIZATION ,/O Oxford/LOCATION ,/O England/LOCATION ./O 
That/O is/O about/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O attend/O Oxford/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr/O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
1947-48/O ./O 
The/O year/O 1947-48/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O receive/O any/O type/O of/O scholarship/O at/O Oxford/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O received/O a/O Rhodes/O scholarship/O ./O 
I/O received/O that/O scholarship/O in-I/O was/O a/O Rhodes/O scholar-elect/O for/O 1939/O ,/O if/O I/O am/O not/O mistaken/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O to/O Oxford/LOCATION until/O 1947/O ,/O because/O in/O the/O fall/O of/O 1939/O Rhodes/PERSON scholars/O were/O forbidden/O to/O go/O to/O England/LOCATION because/O of/O the/O war/O ./O 
Then/O there/O was/O the/O war/O ,/O and/O following/O the/O war/O I/O could/O n't/O manage/O to/O get/O there/O until/O 1947/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O was/O I/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O November/O 20/O ,/O 1916/O ,/O in/O North/LOCATION Dakota/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O your/O employment/O been/O since/O 1939/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Since/O 1939/O ,/O let/O 's/O see/O ./O 
It/O would/O have/O been/O since/O 1940/O ,/O since/O that/O is/O the/O year/O I/O took/O my/O degree/O ./O 
I/O taught/O one/O year/O then/O at/O Colby/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION in/O Waterville/LOCATION ,/O Maine/LOCATION ,/O and/O following/O that/O I/O jobbed/O around/O at/O this/O and/O that/O ,/O and/O went/O into/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O came/O out/O of/O the/O ArmyMr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O continue/O your/O employment/O from/O 1940/O until/O you/O went/O to/O the/O Army/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
From/O 1940/O until/O I/O went/O into/O the/O Army/O ,/O most/O of/O those/O jobs/O ,/O I/O guess/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
There/O are/O a/O couple/O I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Could/O I/O speak/O to/O you/O about/O this/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O Witness/O addresses/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O at/O this/O point/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O the/O authority/O vested/O in/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/ORGANIZATION UnAmerican/ORGANIZATION Activities/ORGANIZATION ,/O he/O has/O appointed/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON as/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O one/O to/O take/O testimony/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O question/O ?/O 
The/O employment/O record/O since/O 1940/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
His/O employment/O ,/O yes/O ,/O since/O 1940/O ,/O until/O he/O entered/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
Give/O them/O your/O best/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O a/O while/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O exactly/O how/O long/O ,/O for/O a/O law/O firm/O of/O Stern/PERSON and/O Pollett/PERSON ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O ,/O if/O I/O am/O not/O mistaken/O ,/O or/O ,/O Pollock/PERSON ,/O rather/O ,/O in/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION ./O 
Then/O I/O workedlMr.WHEELER/O ./O 
Approximately/O the/O dates/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Approximate/O dates/O ,/O this/O would/O have/O been-I/O think/O it/O would/O have/O been/O straddling/O the/O end/O of/O 1940/O and/O first/O part/O of/O 1941/O ./O 
And/O then/O later/O on/O I/O worked/O at/O Kearny/ORGANIZATION Shipyards/ORGANIZATION ,/O Kearny/LOCATION ,/O N./O J./O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O have/O beenMr/O ./O 
McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
From/O about/O March/O ,/O or/O something/O of/O that/O sort/O ,/O until/O 1/O went/O into/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O was/O about-I/O am/O not/O certain/O of/O this/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 861/O It/O was/O July/O or/O August/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
I/O remember/O I/O was/O going/O to/O get/O frozen/O into/O my/O job/O and/O I/O had/O the/O notion/O I/O wanted/O to/O be/O in/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ,/O so/O I/O quit/O the/O job/O and/O joined/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O VWIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O enter/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATI/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O something/O like/O August-it/O was/O the/O year/O of/O Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
1942/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
1942/O ./O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
Pearl/LOCATION Harbor/LOCATION was/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O December/O 7/O ,/O 1941/O ./O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O date/O ,/O August/O 1941/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
August/O 1941/O ,/O I/O think/O ./O 
Mr/O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O at/O this/O time/O ,/O are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
William/PERSON B./PERSON Esterman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O did/O you/O serve/O in/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
For/O 3/O years/O and/O some/O odd/O months/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O how/O many/O months/O ;/O or/O 4/O ./O 
Mr/O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O honorably/O discharged/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
At/O what/O rank/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Sergeant/O ,/O buck/O sergeant/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O discharged/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O discharged/O at/O Mitchel/LOCATION Field/LOCATION ,/O Long/LOCATION Island/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O your/O discharge/O ,/O what/O has/O your/O employment/O been/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
For/O the/O most/O part/O it/O was/O free-lance/O writing/O ./O 
I/O worked/O for/O ,/O oh/O ,/O I/O guess/O a/O couple/O of/O weeks/O or/O something/O like/O that/O ,/O for/O the/O New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION Employment/ORGANIZATION Service/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O nature/O of/O your/O writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
The/O nature/O of/O my/O writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Could/O I/O have/O the/O legislative/O purpose/O of/O this/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
In/O general/O ,/O the/O legislative/O purpose/O of/O the/O question/O is/O to/O determine/O in/O general/O what/O type/O of/O writing/O and/O what/O publications/O you/O have/O written/O for/O ,/O to/O determine/O whether/O or/O not/O it/O falls/O within/O the/O scope/O of/O this/O inquiry/O which/O is/O the/O extent/O and/O nature/O of/O Communist/O propaganda/O activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O a/O particular/O publication/O in/O mind/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O have/O no/O particular/O publication/O in/O mind/O ./O 
I/O assume/O your/O writings/O were/O in/O the/O realm/O of/O public/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O January/O 1947/O were/O youMr/O ./O 
Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O moment/O ./O 
ESTERMAN/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O withdrawing/O the/O question/O ?/O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O this/O on/O the/O same/O question/O ?/O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O was/O inquiring/O from/O you/O as/O to/O what/O the/O nature/O of/O your/O writing/O had/O been/O ./O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
862/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O McGnATH/PERSON ./O 
So/O far/O as/O I/O can/O see/O ,/O this/O question/O has/O no/O legislative/O purpose/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O rephrase/O the/O question/O ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O submit/O for/O publication/O any/O article/O or/O script/O to/O a/O publication/O known/O to/O you/O to/O be/O a/O Communist/O publication/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O McG/O -LRB-/O RATH/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O following/O reasons/O :/O After/O a/O dead/O serious/O consideration/O of/O the/O effects/O of/O this/O committee/O 's/O work/O and/O of/O my/O relation/O to/O it/O ,/O I/O find/O that/O for/O the/O following/O reasons/O I/O must/O refuse/O to/O cooperate/O with/O this/O body/O :/O In/O the/O first/O place/O ,/O as/O a/O teacher/O ,/O my/O first/O responsibility/O is/O to/O my/O students/O ./O 
To/O cooperate/O with/O this/O committee/O would/O be/O to/O set/O for/O them/O an/O example/O of/O accommodation/O to/O forces/O which/O can/O only/O have/O ,/O as/O their/O end/O effect/O ,/O the/O destruction/O of/O education/O itself/O ./O 
Such/O accommodation/O on/O my/O part/O would/O ruin/O my/O value/O as/O a/O teacher/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O proud/O to/O say/O that/O a/O great/O majority/O of/O my/O students-and/O I/O believe/O this/O is/O true/O of/O students/O generally-do/O not/O want/O me/O to/O accommodate/O myself/O to/O this/O committee/O ./O 
In/O a/O certain/O sense/O ,/O I/O have/O no/O choice/O in/O the/O matter-the/O students/O would/O not/O want/O me/O back/O in/O the/O classroom/O if/O I/O were/O to/O take/O any/O course/O of/O action/O other/O than/O the/O one/O I/O am/O pursuing/O ./O 
Secondly/O ,/O as/O a/O teacher/O ,/O I/O have/O a/O responsibility/O to/O the/O profession/O itself/O ./O 
We/O teachers/O have/O no/O professional/O oath/O of/O the/O sort/O that/O doctors/O take/O ,/O but/O there/O is/O a/O kind/O of/O unwritten/O oath/O which/O we/O follow/O :/O To/O teach/O as/O honestly/O ,/O fairly/O ,/O and/O fully/O as/O we/O can/O ./O 
The/O effect/O of/O this/O committee/O is/O destructive/O of/O such/O an/O ideal/O ,/O destructive/O of/O academic/O freedom/O ./O 
As/O Mr./O Justice/PERSON Douglas/PERSON has/O said/O :/O This/O system/O of/O spying/O and/O surveillance/O with/O its/O accompanying/O reports/O and/O trials/O can/O not/O go/O hand/O in/O hand/O with/O academic/O freedom/O ./O 
It/O produces/O standardized/O thought/O ,/O not/O the/O pursuit/O of/O truth/O ./O 
A/O teacher/O who/O will/O tack/O and/O turn/O with/O every/O shift/O of/O the/O political/O wind/O can/O not/O be/O a/O good/O teacher/O ./O 
I/O have/O never/O done/O this/O myself/O ,/O nor/O will/O I/O ever/O ./O 
In/O regard/O to/O my/O teaching/O I/O have/O tried/O to/O hold/O to/O two/O guidelines/O ,/O the/O first/O from/O Chaucer/O that/O ``/O gladly/O will/O I/O learn/O and/O gladly/O teach/O ''/O ;/O the/O second/O a/O paraphrase/O of/O the/O motto/O of/O the/O late/O General/O Stilwell/PERSON ``/O Illiterati/O non/O carborundum/O ./O ''/O 
Thirdly/O ,/O as/O a/O poet/O ,/O I/O must/O refuse/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O committee/O on/O what/O I/O can/O only/O call/O esthetic/O grounds/O ./O 
The/O view/O of/O life/O which/O we/O receive/O through/O the/O great/O works/O of/O art/O is/O a/O privileged/O one-it/O is/O a/O view/O of/O life/O according/O to/O probability/O or/O necehsity/O ,/O not/O subject/O to/O the/O chance/O and/O accident/O of/O our/O real/O world/O and/O therefore/O in/O a/O sense/O truer/O than/O the/O life/O we/O see/O lived/O all/O around/O us/O ./O 
I/O believe/O that/O one/O of/O the/O things/O required/O of/O us/O is/O to/O try/O to/O give/O life/O an/O esthetic/O ground/O ,/O to/O give/O it/O some/O of/O the/O pattern/O and/O beauty/O of/O art/O ./O 
I/O have/O tried/O as/O best/O I/O can/O to/O do/O this/O with/O my/O own/O life/O ,/O and/O while/O I/O do/O not/O claim/O any/O very/O great/O success/O ,/O it/O would/O be/O anticlimactic/O ,/O destructive/O of/O the/O pattern/O of/O my/O life/O ,/O if/O I/O were/O to/O cooperate/O with/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Then/O too/O ,/O poets/O have/O been/O notorious/O noncooperators/O where/O committees/O of/O this/O sort/O are/O concerned/O ./O 
As/O a/O traditionalist/O ,/O I/O would/O prefer/O to/O take/O my/O stand/O with/O Marvell/PERSON ,/O Blake/PERSON ,/O Shelley/PERSON ,/O and/O Garcia/PERSON Lorca/PERSON rather/O than/O with/O innovators/O like/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O not/O wish/O to/O bring/O dishonor/O upon/O my/O tribe/O ./O 
These/O ,/O then/O ,/O are/O reasons/O for/O refusing/O to/O cooperate/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O aware/O that/O none/O of/O them/O is/O acceptable/O to/O the/O committee/O ./O 
When/O I/O was/O notified/O to/O appear/O here/O ,/O my/O first/O instinct/O was/O simply/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/O ANGELES/O AREA/O 863/O committee/O questions/O out/O of/O personal/O principle/O and/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O rights/O of/O man/O and/O to/O let/O it/O go/O at/O that/O ./O 
On/O further/O consideration/O ,/O however/O ,/O I/O have/O come/O to/O feel/O that/O such/O a/O stand/O would/O be/O mere/O self-indulgence/O and/O that/O it/O would/O weaken/O the/O fight/O which/O other/O witnesses/O have/O made/O to/O protect/O the/O rights/O guaranteed/O under/O our/O Constitution/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O I/O further/O refuse/O to/O answer/O to/O the/O committee/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fourth/O amendment/O ./O 
I/O regard/O this/O committee/O as/O usurpers/O of/O illegal/O powers/O and/O my/O enforced/O appearance/O here/O as/O in/O the/O nature/O of/O unreasonable/O search/O and/O seizure/O ./O 
I/O further/O refuse/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O first/O amendment/O ,/O which/O in/O guaranteeing/O free/O speech/O also/O guarantees/O my/O right/O to/O be/O silent/O ./O 
Although/O the/O first/O amendment/O expressly/O forbids/O any/O abridgement/O of/O this/O and/O other/O freedoms/O ,/O the/O committee/O is/O illegally/O engaged/O in/O the/O establishment/O of/O a/O religion/O of/O fear/O ./O 
I/O can/O not/O cooperate/O with/O it/O in/O this/O unconstitutional/O activity/O ./O 
Lastly/O ,/O it/O is/O my/O duty/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O committee/O ,/O claiming/O my/O rights/O under/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O as/O a/O whole/O and/O in/O all/O its/O parts/O ,/O and/O understanding/O that/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O was/O inserted/O in/O the/O Constitution/O to/O bulwark/O the/O first/O amendment/O against/O the/O activities/O of/O committees/O such/O as/O this/O one/O ,/O so/O that/O no/O one/O may/O be/O forced/O to/O bear/O witness/O against/O himself/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O any/O further/O questions/O ?/O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O do/O ./O 
Where/O are/O the/O Kearny/ORGANIZATION Shipyards/ORGANIZATION located/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGiAT1H/PERSON ./O 
Kearny/LOCATION ,/O N./PERSON J./PERSON Mr./PERSON WHIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O Voll/PERSON a/O member/O of/O the/O shipyards/O branch/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION known/O as/O the/O Kearny/ORGANIZATION Club/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mr./O McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O McGRATII/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O incorporate/O all/O the/O reasons/O I/O have/O given/O in/O my/O declination/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O lived/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATH/PERSON ./O 
Since/O about/O April/O ./O 
I/O believe/O ,/O 1949/O ./O 
Mr./O WIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O have/O you/O been/O a/O teacher/O at/O Los/ORGANIZATION Angeles/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATII/PERSON ./O 
For/O 31\/2/O years/O ;/O at/O the/O end/O of/O this/O year/O it/O will/O be/O 31/O \//O years/O ./O 
Mr./O AYIIEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1951/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O John/ORGANIZATION Reed/ORGANIZATION division/O of/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O IMr/O ./O 
McGrath/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Esterman/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O McGRATII/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ,/O incorporating/O them/O without/O repeating/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O 1WHEELER/O ./O 
During/O the/O first/O quarter/O of/O the/O year/O 1952/O were/O you/O transferred/O from/O the/O John/PERSON Reed/PERSON division/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O the/O eastern/O division/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O county/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O MCGRATH/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O previously/O given/O ,/O and/O incorporate/O all/O my/O grounds/O as/O above/O ./O 
Mr./O WVIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Community/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION today/O ?/O 
Mr./O McGRATII/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O given/O and/O incorporate/O my/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
NO/O ./O 
864/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O JACKSUN/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O call/O the/O next/O witness/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Matilda/PERSON Lewis/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O MATILDA/O LEWIS/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O HER/O COUNSEL/O ,/O ROBERT/PERSON W./PERSON KENNY/PERSON Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O state/O your/O name/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
Matilda/PERSON Lewis/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O IWHEELER.Where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
In/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
In/O Laguna/LOCATION Beach/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
As/O principal/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Of/O what/O school/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEris/O ./O 
Park/O Avenue/O School/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O briefly/O relate/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O :/O I/O went/O through/O the/O schools/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O public/O schools/O ,/O and/O went/O to/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION and/O USC/ORGANIZATION ,/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O San/ORGANIZATION Diego/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O year/O did/O you/O graduate/O from/O the/O San/ORGANIZATION Diego/ORGANIZATION State/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O graduate/O from/O there/O ./O 
I/O worked/O ;/O taking/O work/O at/O the/O present/O time/O off/O and/O on/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O graduateMrs/O ./O 
LEWIS/O ./O 
I/O graduated/O from/O Columbia/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O what/O year/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O '/O 35/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O tell/O you/O exactly/O ,/O but-no/O ,/O '/O 36/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O '/O 36/O ,/O the/O summer/O of/O '/O 36/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O have/O you/O been/O employed/O since/O 1936/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O teacher/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O relate/O in/O which/O schools/O you/O taught/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O taughtMr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Giving/O the/O approximate/O dates/O ./O 
Mi/O s./O LEWis/O ./O 
I/O have/O done/O all/O my/O teaching/O in/O the/O Inglewood/LOCATION schools/O ,/O except/O for/O the/O last/O 4/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEILER/PERSON ./O 
Mrs./O Lewis/PERSON ,/O are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Leroy/PERSON Herndon/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O not/O answer/O any/O questions/O pertaining/O to/O my/O former/O husband/O or/O pertaining/O to/O the/O time/O I/O was/O married/O to/O him/O ./O 
I/O therefore/O refuse/O to/O answer/O any/O question/O for/O the/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
I/O have/O taken/O the/O Levering/O Act/O oath/O required/O of/O every/O teacher/O in/O this/O State/O ./O 
and/O if/O anyone/O has/O the/O courage/O to/O come/O forward/O in/O open/O couit/O to/O charge/O and/O prove/O I/O committed/O perjury/O ,/O I/O am/O ready/O to/O defend/O myself/O before/O a/O jury/O of/O my/O fellow/O citizens/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O American/O way/O ./O 
In/O the/O meantime/O I/O am/O entitled/O to/O the/O right/O of/O the/O presumption/O of/O innocence/O and/O not/O be/O compelled/O to/O give/O evidence/O against/O myself/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 865/O All/O your/O pertinent/O questions/O ,/O outside/O of/O the/O period/O of/O 1935-40/O ,/O will/O be/O answered/O by/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O what/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
1935-40/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O repeat/O the/O sentence/O in/O regard/O to/O the/O word/O ``/O perjury/O ,/O ''/O that/O contains/O the/O word/O ``/O perjury/O ''/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
The/O sentence/O starts/O ,/O ``/O I/O have/O taken/O the/O Levering/O Act/O oath/O required/O of/O every/O teacher/O in/O this/O State/O ,/O and/O if/O anyone/O has/O the/O courage/O to/O come/O forward/O in/O open/O court/O to/O charge/O and/O prove/O I/O committed/O perjury/O ,/O I/O am/O ready/O to/O defend/O myself/O before/O a/O jury/O of/O my/O fellow/O citizens/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O American/O way/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Herndon/PERSON testified/O under/O oath/O before/O this/O committee/O ,/O during/O the/O recent/O hearings/O ,/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O a/O member/O of/O a/O teachers/O '/O unit/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION ./O 
During/O the/O course/O of/O his/O testimony/O he/O stated/O that/O Matilda/PERSON Lewis/PERSON was/O also/O a/O member/O of/O this/O group/O ./O 
Is/O Mr./O Herndon/PERSON 's/O testimony/O correct/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mrs./O Lewis/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Kenny/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O for/O the/O reasons/O already/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Anne/PERSON Kinney/PERSON ,/O also/O known/O as/O Jane/PERSON Howe/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O on/O the/O same/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
She/O testified/O in/O an/O executive/O statement/O on/O December/O 22/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O that/O she/O was/O also/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION and/O also/O assigned/O to/O the/O teachers/O '/O unit/O ,/O the/O same/O group/O as/O Mr./O Herndon/PERSON ,/O and/O she/O has/O testified/O under/O oath/O you/O were/O also/O a/O member/O of/O that/O group/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O as/O stated/O before/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O local/O 430/O of/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Teachers/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
During/O what/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
About/O 1936/O or/O '/O 37/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O recall/O which/O ,/O and/O up/O toI/O paid/O dues/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O the/O exact/O date/O ,/O but/O as/O close/O as/O I/O can/O remember/O ,/O about/O 19-I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O it/O was/O '47/O or/O '/O 48/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O recall/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O because/O I/O was/O n't/O attending/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O offices/O did/O you/O hold/O in/O this/O union/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O vice/O president/O for/O 1/O year/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O recall/O what/O year/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O an/O article/O from/O the/O Santa/ORGANIZATION Ana/ORGANIZATION Register/ORGANIZATION dated/O July/O 14/O ,/O 1948/O ,/O with/O the/O heading/O ``/O County/O Parties/O Are/O Organized/O ./O ''/O 
In/O this/O article/O it/O states/O that/O you/O were/O elected/O secretary/O of/O the/O Independent/ORGANIZATION Progressive/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Orange/ORGANIZATION County/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Are/O you/O the/O same/O Matilda/PERSON Lewis/PERSON referred/O to/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O was/O interested/O in/O the/O Progressive/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1940/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O that/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O between/O those/O years/O for/O the/O same/O reasons/O given/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Between/O what/O years/O ,/O again/O ?/O 
Mrs./O LEWIs/PERSON ./O 
1935/O to/O 1940/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1941/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O At/O this/O point/O Mrs./O Lewis/PERSON conferred/O with/O Mr./O Kenny/PERSON ./O -RRB-/O 
866/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mrs/O LEWIS/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION from/O 1941/O to/O the/O present/O date/O ?/O 
Mrs./O Lmvis/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O Mrs./O Lewis/PERSON ,/O that/O you/O were/O an/O officer/O in/O the/O American/ORGANIZATION Federation/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Teachers/ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O have/O any/O personal/O knowledge/O of/O any/O efforts/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O influence/O in/O any/O way/O the/O actions/O or/O the/O policy/O of/O the/O organization/O ?/O 
Ml/O s/O LEWIs/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr/O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O '/O Mr./O WnHEELER/O ./O 
None/O at/O all/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Whereupon/O ,/O at/O 10/O :/O 40/O a./O m./O ,/O Monday/O ,/O April/O 13/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O the/O executive/O session/O adjourned/O ./O -RRB-/O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA-PART/O 5/O MONDAY/O ,/O DECEMBER/O 22/O ,/O 1952/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O STATEMENT/O '/O An/O executive/O statement/O given/O at/O 1/O :/O 30/O p./O m./O December/O 22/O ,/O 1952/O ,/O at/O room/O 1118/O ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION Roosevelt/LOCATION Hotel/LOCATION ,/O Hollywood/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
Present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O ANNE/PERSON KINNEY/PERSON 2/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Anne/PERSON Kinney/PERSON ./O 
1Mr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Chicago/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O am/O a/O graduate/O of/O Chicago/ORGANIZATION Normal/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ;/O now/O Chicago/ORGANIZATION Teachers/ORGANIZATION '/ORGANIZATION College/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O has/O been/O your/O employment/O background/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O taught/O for/O a/O year/O after/O I/O graduated/O from/O college/O ./O 
Later/O most/O of/O my/O employment/O was/O in/O clerical/O capacities/O ./O 
I/O worked/O as/O an/O inspector/O during/O the/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O employed/O during/O the/O war/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
From/O 1942/O to/O 1944/O I/O worked/O for/O Studebaker/ORGANIZATION Corp./ORGANIZATION in/O Chicago/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O been/O employed/O since/O that/O time/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
From/O the/O fall/O of/O 1944/O until/O December/O of/O 1946/O ,/O I/O worked/O for/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Office/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Professional/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Since/O then/O I/O have/O had/O temporary/O jobs/O of/O maybe/O 2/O to/O 4/O weeks/O '/O duration/O ,/O 3/O or/O 4/O of/O those/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O ever/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O join/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
August/O 1933/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O been/O known/O by/O any/O other/O name/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O Jane/PERSON Howe/PERSON ./O 
2SReleased/O by/O the/O committee/O Anne/PERSON Kinney/PERSON was/O sworn/O in/O as/O a/O witness/O by/O the/O court/O reporter/O ./O 
868/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O a/O Commulnist/O Party/O name/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr/O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
For/O what/O purpose/O did/O you/O use/O the/O name/O Jane/PERSON Howe/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Principally/O as/O a/O means/O of/O protecting/O the/O person/O with/O whom/O I/O was/O living/O at/O the/O time/O I/O joined/O ./O 
It/O was/O common/O practice/O for/O people/O to/O use/O a/O different/O name/O in/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O were/O the/O reasons/O for/O your/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Like/O many/O people/O ,/O I/O was/O appalled/O by/O what/O happened/O during/O the/O depression/O ,/O by/O the/O conditions/O under/O which/O people/O were/O forced/O to/O live/O ./O 
Being/O both/O idealistic/O and/O without/O any/O knowledge/O of/O political/O science/O or/O economics/O ,/O I/O was/O easily/O convinced/O that/O Marxism/O was/O the/O answer/O ./O 
When/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION seemed/O to/O be/O doing/O nothing/O that/O was/O effective/O ,/O I/O began/O to/O wonder/O if/O perhaps/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O where/O I/O would/O find/O more/O immediate/O activity/O ./O 
I/O did/O some/O reading/O in/O the/O public/O library/O which/O led/O me/O to/O believe/O that/O they/O and/O not/O the/O Socialists/O were/O following/O Marxist/O principles/O ./O 
Therefore/O ,/O in/O August/O 1933/O ,/O I/O applied/O for/O membership/O by/O going/O to/O the/O county/O office/O and/O asking/O to/O join/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O recruited/O by/O any/O specific/O person/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O becoming/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O to/O what/O branches/O were/O you/O assigned/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
First/O to/O a/O neighborhood/O branch/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O correct/O me/O if/O I/O am/O wrong/O about/O this/O ./O 
I/O understand/O that/O from/O October/O 1933/O to/O February/O 1934/O there/O was/O a/O special/O group/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O had/O forgotten/O about/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
February/O 1934/O to/O May/O 1934/O ,/O Hollywood/O street/O group/O ./O 
May/O 1934/O to/O September/O 1934/O ,/O a/O Burbank/LOCATION street/O group/O ./O 
From/O September/O 1934/O to/O the/O fall/O of/O 1935/O ,/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O fall/O of/O 1935/O to/O December/O 1938/O ,/O a/O teachers/O '/O unit/O ./O 
December/O 1938/O to/O August/O 1939/O ,/O 56th/O assembly/O district/O ,/O which/O is/O in/O the/O 13th/O Congressional/O District/O ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O August/O 1939/O to/O the/O fall/O of/O 1940/O ,/O section/O organizer/O ,/O 15th/O Congressional/O District/O ./O 
The/O fall/O of/O 1940/O to/O May/O 1942/O ,/O working/O on/O the/O county/O membership/O commission/O ,/O organizer/O of/O the/O 65th/O assembly/O district/O ,/O and/O for/O a/O short/O period/O of/O time/O county/O membership/O director/O ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O May/O 1942/O to/O the/O summer/O or/O fall/O of/O 1944/O ,/O a/O Studebaker/O plant/O unit/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
There/O is/O actually/O a/O gap/O of/O a/O few/O months/O there/O ,/O while/O I/O was/O in/O transit/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O explain/O that/O when/O we/O cover/O each/O group/O ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O going/O from/O here/O to/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Transferred/O ./O 
That/O can/O be/O clarified/O ./O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
That/O covers/O almost/O 6/O months/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O the/O fall/O of/O 1944/O to/O the/O fall/O of/O 1945/O ,/O the/O Hyde/O Park/O branch/O in/O Chicago/LOCATION ,/O a/O street/O unit/O ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O 869/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O reported/O to/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION what/O knowledge/O you/O have/O of/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O to/O what/O office/O did/O you/O give/O your/O infor/O -/O mation/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O March/O 1951/O ,/O in/O Phoenix/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Who/O were/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION assigned/O to/O the/O Socialist/O branch/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O remember/O Harold/PERSON and/O Mildred/PERSON Ashe/PERSON ,/O John/PERSON Spears/PERSON ,/O Marjorie/PERSON Hay/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O describe/O a/O little/O more/O fully/O each/O individual/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Harold/PERSON Ashe/PERSON was/O at/O that/O time/O State/ORGANIZATION secretary/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
John/PERSON Spears/PERSON was/O unemployed/O ./O 
Marjorie/PERSON Hay/PERSON was/O teaching/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION city/O schools/O ./O 
All/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O given/O any/O instructions/O by/O any/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION as/O to/O your/O activity/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O explain/O your/O answer/O more/O fully/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINnEY/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O now/O too/O well/O ,/O except/O we/O were/O supposed/O to/O build/O up/O this/O rank/O and/O file/O group/O ,/O which/O was/O sort/O of/O an/O opposition/O group/O to/O the/O State/O leadership/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O members/O of/O this/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION unit/O within/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION have/O anything/O to/O do/O to/O disrupt/O the/O normal/O proceedings/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O think/O the/O group/O tried/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O have/O any/O success/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
To/O a/O certain/O extent/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
There/O were/O perhaps/O 3/O locals/O of/O the/O Socialist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION that/O withdrew/O ./O 
Two/O of/O them/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O turned/O into/O unemployed/O organizations/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O the/O third/O one/O may/O have/O become/O a/O branch/O of/O the/O American/O League/O Against/O War/O and/O Fascism/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O was/O this/O accomplished/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
At/O this/O point/O I/O really/O could/O n't/O tell/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O identify/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION street/O branch/O to/O which/O you/O were/O assigned/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O only/O one/O I/O remember/O is/O Dr./O Tashjian/PERSON .1/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O individuals/O comprised/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION branch/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O there/O were/O about/O 10/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Then/O you/O recall/O no/O additional/O individuals/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Miss/O KIN-EY/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O testified/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O a/O street/O branch/O in/O Burbank/LOCATION from/O approximately/O September/O 1934/O to/O the/O fall/O of/O 1943/O ./O 
Can/O you/O identify/O the/O members/O of/O the/O Burbank/LOCATION group/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Bill/PERSON and/O Nina/PERSON Ingham/PERSON ,/O Albert/PERSON Lockett/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O all/O I/O can/O remember/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O WIEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O individuals/O comprised/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O there/O were/O just/O about/O 7/O or/O 8/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
From/O September/O 1934/O to/O the/O fall/O of/O 1935/O ,/O you/O stated/O you/O were/O a/O member/O at/O large/O ./O 
What/O is/O meant/O by/O the/O term/O ``/O member/O at/O large/O ?/O ''/O 
SDr/O Vaughan/PERSON A/PERSON K/PERSON Tashjian/PERSON 870/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION AREA/O Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O not/O attached/O to/O any/O branch/O of/O any/O sort/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
For/O what/O reason/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
Because/O I/O was/O given/O a/O special/O assignment/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
In/O your/O opinion/O ,/O would/O you/O say/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O at/O large/O and/O not/O assigned/O to/O any/O group/O because/O of/O security/O reasons/O of/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
I/O presume/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O any/O particular/O person/O ?/O 
Miss/O KINNEY/PERSON ./O 
