INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 3/O HEARING/O BEFORE/O THE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O FIRST/O SESSION/O JUNE/O 30/O ,/O 1955/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O INDEX/O IN/O PART/O 4/O OF/O THIS/O SERIES/O -RRB-/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 65500/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1955/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O Chairsan/PERSON MORGAN/PERSON M./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON Illinois/PERSON CLYDE/PERSON DOYLE/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION DONALD/PERSON I./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON B./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION GORDON/LOCATION H./LOCATION SCHERER/LOCATION ,/O Ohio/LOCATION THOMAA/LOCATION W./LOCATION BDALI/LOCATION ,/O Sr./O ,/O OMef/O COler/O n/O CONTENTS/O PART/O 1/O June/O 27/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofPaul/O Wright/PERSON Orr/PERSON -/O ./O 
_/O -/O __/O Afternoon/O session/O :/O Andries/PERSON Deinum/PERSON .../O ./O 
Page/O --/O 1440/O -------------------/O -/O --------/O _/O --/O Anita/PERSON Bell/PERSON Schneider/PERSON --/O .../O -------/O ./O 
-/O June/O 28/O ./O 
1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofAngela/O f/O larke/O ------/O Cecil/PERSON Beard/PERSON ./O 
-/O -/O _/O _/O ./O 
./O 
_/O --/O ./O 
-/O _/O -/O ___/O --/O --/O .../O .../O -/O -----/O -/O ./O 
----------/O ./O 
--/O 1474/O _/O -/O -----/O 1523/O _/O ./O 
_/O -/O Diamond/PERSON Kim/PERSON .../O ./O 
--------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O :/O Diamond/O Kim/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O -------------------------/O .../O Sue/PERSON Lawson/PERSON ./O 
---------/O _/O -_-/O ------/O George/PERSON Hugh/PERSON Murray/PERSON Maitland/PERSON Hardyman/PERSON --/O -/O 1538/O ___/O --/O 1498/O 1543/O 1565/O 1572/O 1575/O --/O _/O --/O PART/O 2/O June/O 29/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofGeorge/O Hugh/PERSON Murray/PERSON Maitland/PERSON Hardyman/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --/O Raphael/PERSON Konigsberg/PERSON .../O ----------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O :/O Sylvia/PERSON Schonfield/PERSON ./O 
--------------/O Jean/PERSON Wilkinson/PERSON -/O ./O 
./O 
-1676/O Frank/PERSON C./PERSON Davis/PERSON __/O -------------/O Irene/PERSON B./PERSON Bowerman/PERSON __/O Carl/PERSON Sugar/PERSON __/O ./O 
_/O ----------------/O 1599/O 1656/O 1668/O -/O 1679/O 1689/O 1697/O PART/O 3/O June/O 30/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofMatthew/O Samuel/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O Jr./O _/O -----/O --/O William/PERSON Elonin/PERSON ---------------/O William/PERSON Waid/PERSON Kimple/PERSON --/O Afternoon/O sessionWilliam/O Ward/PERSON Kimple/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O --/O Max/PERSON Benjamin/PERSON Natapoff/PERSON --------------------------/O 1707/O 1713/O 1731/O -/O Joseph/PERSON W./PERSON Aidlin/PERSON ./O 
------------------/O 1742/O 1761/O 1764/O 1768/O ./O 
-------------------------------/O Tashia/O Freed/O ./O 
Max/PERSON Appleman/PERSON ----------------/O --------------/O 1771/O PART/O 4/O July/O 1/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofStephen/O A./O Wereb/O -------------------/O Afternoon/O session/O :/O Stephen/PERSON A./PERSON Wereb/PERSON -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ---------------/O -------------/O James/PERSON Burford/PERSON ./O 
------------------------------/O ------------------/O .../O --/O --------------/O Anne/PERSON Pollock/PERSON --/O Margaret/PERSON Vaughn/PERSON Meyer/PERSON ------------------/O July/O 2/O ,/O 1955/O :/O Testimony/O ofStephen/O A./O Wereb/O -LRB-/O resumed/O -RRB-/O ./O 
---------------------/O John/PERSON Waters/PERSON Houston/PERSON ./O 
./O 
---------------------------------/O Harry/PERSON Hay/PERSON -----------------------------------------------------/O Martha/PERSON Hard/PERSON Wheeldin/PERSON -----------------------------------/O Louis/PERSON Stark/PERSON __/O -----------------------/O Robert/PERSON L./PERSON Brock/PERSON _/O Index/O ./O 
-LRB-/O See/O pt/O ./O 
4/O of/O this/O series/O ./O -RRB-/O 
121/O ./O 
STANDINGCOMMITTEES/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O AND/O DUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEE/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O of/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5/O ,/O 1955/O \*/O \*/O 5/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O STANDINGCOMMFITEES/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O following/O standing/O committees/O :/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERSANDDUTIESOFCOMMITTEES/O \*/O 5/O \*/O 5/O \*/O \*/O \*/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O ii/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 3/O THURSDAY/O ,/O JUNE/O 30/O ,/O 1955/O UNrrED/O STATs/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBco/O ITrrTEE/O OF/O THE/O COMMxITEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIvrrIE/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O California/LOCATION ./O 
PUBLIC/O HEARING/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O at/O 9:30/O a./O m./O ,/O pursuant/O to/O recess/O ,/O in/O room/O 518/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O ;/O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O and/O Gordon/PERSON H./PERSON Scherer/PERSON ./O 
Staff/O members/O present/O :/O Frank/PERSON S./PERSON Tavenner/PERSON ,/O counsel/O ,/O and/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O please/O be/O in/O session/O ./O 
May/O the/O record/O show/O ,/O please/O ,/O that/O the/O full/O membership/O of/O the/O subcommittee/O is/O here/O ,/O Congressman/O Scherer/PERSON on/O my/O left/O ,/O of/O Ohio/LOCATION ;/O Congressman/O Jackson/PERSON on/O my/O left/O ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ;/O Congressman/O Moulder/PERSON ,/O from/O Missouri/LOCATION ;/O and/O Congressman/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O from/O California/LOCATION ./O 
There/O are/O times/O when/O there/O is/O confusion/O of/O names/O and/O identity/O ,/O and/O here/O is/O a/O good/O illustration/O of/O one/O of/O the/O circumstances/O that/O comes/O to/O the/O committee/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O always/O glad/O to/O cooperate/O promptly/O and/O try/O to/O see/O that/O any/O person/O who/O should/O not/O be/O identified/O m/O any/O way/O with/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O or/O with/O the/O call/O of/O the/O committee/O as/O a/O witness/O ,/O is/O cleared/O as/O promptly/O as/O possible/O ./O 
Our/O distinguished/O counsel/O has/O mentioned/O from/O time/O to/O time/O in/O the/O last/O 2/O days/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON ,/O without/O including/O any/O middle/O initial/O in/O the/O name/O ./O 
I/O received/O this/O morning/O ,/O in/O fact/O ,/O every/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O received/O the/O same/O wire/O ,/O and/O we/O want/O to/O cooperate/O with/O this/O gentleman/O and/O read/O it/O into/O the/O record/O ,/O and/O so/O that/O the/O newspapers/O will/O hear/O it/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Representative/O CLYDEDOYLE/LOCATION ,/O Chairman/O ,/O House/ORGANIZATION Un-American/O Activities/O Subcommittee/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Great/O harm/O to/O me/O ,/O permanent/O and/O irreparable/O damage/O to/O the/O company/O ,/O Jan-uine/O Foods/O ,/O of/O which/O I/O am/O president/O ,/O is/O being/O done/O through/O the/O publicity/O given/O to/O a/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON now/O under/O investigation/O by/O your/O committee/O ./O 
This/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON was/O no/O relation/O to/O me/O ,/O not/O in/O any/O way/O connected/O with/O me/O ,/O my/O family/O ,/O or/O my/O company/O ./O 
Many/O of/O my/O customers/O and/O friends/O are/O confusing/O identity/O with/O me/O ./O 
In/O the/O name/O of/O justice/O may/O I/O respectfully/O request/O that/O you/O use/O every/O effort/O to/O inform/O each/O 1705/O 1706/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O member/O of/O your/O committee/O ,/O the/O press/O ,/O and/O the/O public/O ,/O that/O I/O ,/O Peter/PERSON S./PERSON Hyun/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O am/O not/O the/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON under/O investigation/O by/O your/O committee/O ./O 
If/O I/O can/O be/O of/O any/O service/O to/O you/O and/O your/O committee/O in/O the/O great/O work/O you/O are/O doing/O ,/O please/O feel/O free/O to/O call/O upon/O me/O at/O my/O office/O or/O my/O home/O ./O 
PETER/PERSON S./PERSON HYUN/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O -LRB-/O Signed/O -RRB-/O President/O ,/O Oriental/ORGANIZATION Foods/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Inc./ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O am/O glad/O to/O read/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O might/O say/O to/O the/O gentleman/O if/O he/O wants/O to/O further/O emphasize/O the/O fact/O that/O there/O is/O no/O identity/O in/O which/O he/O is/O involved/O ,/O we/O invite/O him/O to/O come/O up/O here/O and/O appear/O in/O person/O if/O he/O desires/O to/O ,/O and/O just/O so/O state/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O this/O reading/O should/O be/O sufficient/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O possibly/O I/O should/O state/O in/O addition/O that/O the/O staff/O knows/O very/O well/O that/O this/O is/O not/O the/O same/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON as/O to/O whom/O we/O heard/O testimony/O in/O the/O past/O few/O days/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYL/O ./O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O Peter/PERSON S./PERSON Hyun/PERSON ,/O Sr./O ,/O president/O of/O Oriental/ORGANIZATION Foods/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION ,/O Inc./ORGANIZATION ,/O is/O not/O the/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON we/O are/O interested/O in/O locating/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Counsel/O ,/O prior/O to/O the/O receipt/O of/O this/O telegram/O ,/O you/O did/O not/O know/O there/O was/O a/O Peter/PERSON S./PERSON Hyun/PERSON who/O was/O president/O of/O the/O Oriental/ORGANIZATION Foods/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION ,/O did/O you/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
We/O knew/O there/O was/O a/O Peter/PERSON S./PERSON Hyun/PERSON who/O was/O an/O entirely/O different/O person/O from/O the/O Peter/PERSON Hyun/PERSON who/O is/O involved/O in/O the/O testimony/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O say/O to/O the/O guests/O in/O the/O courtroom/O again/O this/O morning/O ,/O we/O appreciated/O your/O cooperation/O very/O much/O yesterday/O ./O 
The/O courtroom/O is/O ordinarily/O full/O of/O people/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O not/O altogether/O comfortable/O sometimes/O in/O the/O day/O when/O the/O circulation/O is/O not/O too/O good/O ,/O so/O we/O will/O appreciate/O your/O continued/O cooperation/O with/O us/O ,/O and/O please/O make/O no/O outburst/O or/O demonstration/O of/O any/O sort/O ,/O either/O of/O approbation/O or/O otherwise/O ,/O as/O to/O what/O any/O witness/O says/O or/O does/O ./O 
I/O mean/O that/O as/O an/O impartial/O instruction/O ./O 
We/O can/O not/O countenance/O any/O disapproval/O or/O any/O approval/O by/O hand/O clapping/O or/O by/O laughter/O or/O by/O any/O evidence/O for/O or/O against/O what/O any/O witness/O says/O ./O 
Before/O I/O proceed/O again/O in/O the/O matter/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O say/O to/O counsel/O if/O there/O are/O any/O different/O counsel/O in/O the/O room/O who/O have/O not/O yet/O appeared/O with/O a/O client/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O the/O advice/O of/O counsel/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O of/O a/O client/O ,/O is/O limited/O to/O the/O counsel/O advising/O his/O client/O ./O 
We/O regret/O that/O we/O do/O not/O have/O time/O or/O facilities/O to/O allow/O members/O of/O the/O bar/O to/O argue/O with/O us/O or/O to/O us/O ,/O but/O we/O simply/O do/O not/O ;/O and/O therefore/O we/O know/O we/O will/O have/O the/O cooperation/O of/O every/O lawyer/O who/O appears/O before/O us/O today/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ready/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O Matthew/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O come/O forward/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
Be/O seated/O ,/O please/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1707/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O MATTHEW/PERSON SAMUEL/PERSON VIDAVER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O BEN/PERSON MARGOLIS/PERSON Mr./O TAVENNR/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O sir/O ?/O 
Mr./O VDAVER/PERSON ./O 
My/O full/O name/O is/O Matthew/PERSON Samuel/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O Jr./O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O known/O by/O a/O nickname/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Ususally/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Matt/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O noted/O you/O are/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
Ben/PERSON Margolis/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Vidaver/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VIAVER/PERSON ./O 
San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O August/O 4,1913/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O your/O last/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O VAvER/O ./O 
V-i-d-a-v-e-r/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O you/O at/O any/O time/O resided/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O ViAVEE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O period/O of/O your/O residence/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Mr./O VmAVER/O ./O 
I/O first/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O 1919/O ./O 
I/O think/O we/O stayed/O here/O for/O a/O year/O or/O a/O year/O and/O a/O half/O ./O 
I/O returned/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O I/O was/O about/O 13/O years/O old/O ,/O 14/O ./O 
That/O would/O be/O after/O the/O depression/O started/O ,/O so/O it/O would/O be/O about/O 1929/O ,/O and/O remained/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION fairly/O consistently-I/O lived/O in/O other/O places/O for/O short/O periods/O of/O time/O ,/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION ,/O which/O is/O an/O independent/O community/O ,/O and/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ,/O San/LOCATION Francisco/LOCATION ,/O but/O mainly/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles-southern/LOCATION California/LOCATION area/O ,/O up/O until/O 1948/O ,/O I/O believe/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O some/O time/O was/O spent/O overseas/O during/O the/O war/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O give/O us/O the/O period/O when/O you/O were/O overseas/O ,/O or/O ,/O better/O still/O ,/O will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O when/O you/O entered/O the/O armed/O services/O and/O when/O you/O left/O ?/O 
Mr./O VDmAVER/O ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O merchant/O marine/O during/O the/O war/O ./O 
I/O believe/O it/O was/O possibly/O the/O last/O part/O of/O 1943/O through/O the/O first/O part/O of/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O this/O period/O between/O 1929/O and/O 1948/O when/O you/O lived/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O with/O the/O exceptions/O you/O mentioned/O ,/O I/O believe/O you/O said/O you/O lived/O at/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION for/O a/O period/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O very/O hard/O to/O say/O ./O 
I/O lived/O in/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION Canof/LOCATION the/O yon/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O not/O sure/O but/O I/O think/O that/O is/O specifically/O a/O part/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O although/O everyone/O considers/O it/O Santa/PERSON Monica/PERSON ,/O uses/O the/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION shopping/O district/O ,/O and/O so/O forth/O ./O 
I/O lived/O thereor/O 12/O my/O son/O was/O born/O there-on/O and/O off/O ,/O I/O guess/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 11/O years/O ;/O and/O then/O resided/O in/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION and/O Ocean/LOCATION Park/LOCATION ,/O I/O imagine/O altogether/O a/O period/O of/O maybe/O a/O year/O or/O two/O ./O 
lived/O Mr./O TAVENNE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O when/O you/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ?/O 
1942/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
That/O was/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O in/O the/O year/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
How/O long/O were/O you/O there/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Approximately/O a/O year/O ,/O maybe/O a/O little/O over/O a/O year/O ./O 
made/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Vidaver/PERSON ,/O the/O committee/O has/O not/O heretofore/O activities/O in/O Santa/LOCATION any/O extended/O investition/O of/O Communist/O Party/O Communist/O of/O can/O Monica/PERSON ./O 
It/O desires/O at/O this/O time/O to/O learn/O what/O it/O Party/O activities/O in/O that/O area/O ./O 
65/O 500-55/O --/O t./O 3-2/O 1708/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O At/O the/O time/O you/O lived/O in/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION ,/O the/O period/O of/O 11/O or/O 12/O years/O ,/O or/O any/O part/O of/O that/O time/O ,/O were/O you/O an/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O that/O area/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Before/O I/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O ask/O the/O Chair/O for/O some/O clarification/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O mean/O to/O make/O a/O statement/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O serious/O about/O this/O ./O 
It/O is/O my/O understanding/O that/O a/O citizen/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION has/O the/O right/O to/O use/O the/O provisions/O provided/O in/O the/O Constitution/O and/O the/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O in/O a/O situation/O such/O as/O this/O ,/O and/O that/O in/O doing/O so/O he/O in/O no/O way/O implicates/O himself/O in/O any/O question/O of/O guilt/O ,/O and/O that/O not/O only/O has/O he/O the/O right/O but/O that/O he/O has/O the/O duty/O ,/O when/O he/O considers/O that/O his/O constitutional/O privileges/O are/O being/O trespassed/O upon/O ,/O when/O he/O considers/O that/O his/O right/O to/O his/O own/O political/O opinions/O is/O being/O invaded/O ./O 
Is/O this/O not/O so/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O answer/O the/O gentleman/O by/O just/O saying/O this/O ,/O briefly/O :/O The/O committee/O feels/O that/O the/O witness/O is/O entitled/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O and/O should/O rely/O upon/O the/O legal/O advice/O of/O his/O counsel/O in/O answering/O any/O legal/O question/O ./O 
We/O are/O in/O no/O position/O to/O undertake/O ,/O even/O if/O we/O thought/O we/O might/O know/O the/O answer/O legally/O ,/O to/O give/O you/O any/O legal/O advice/O ./O 
But/O we/O will/O say/O this/O frankly/O :/O This/O committee/O greatly/O respects/O a/O witness/O who/O takes/O the/O chair/O where/O you/O are/O ,/O and/O conscientiously/O and/O in/O good/O faith/O and/O honestly/O claims/O the/O constitutional/O privilege/O ./O 
We/O do/O not/O criticize/O ,/O ever/O ,/O any/O witness/O who/O does/O that/O honestly/O and/O in/O good/O faith/O ./O 
Mr./O VIAvER/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
But/O we/O also/O shudder/O at/O the/O frequency/O with/O which/O witnesses/O take/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O and/O constitutional/O privileges/O in/O bad/O faith/O and/O without/O any/O intention/O of/O being/O honest/O with/O the/O Constitution/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O VAVER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O not/O the/O propriety/O of/O that/O step/O to/O be/O determined/O by/O the/O judiciary/O and/O not/O by/O the/O legislative/O branch/O of/O the/O Government/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Regular/O order/O ./O 
Mr./O DonE/O ./O 
We/O will/O proceed/O now/O ./O 
I/O have/O answered/O your/O point/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O you/O have/O gotten/O your/O point/O across/O ,/O have/O you/O not/O Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Thank/O you/O ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VDAVER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O question/O again/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Read/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O save/O some/O time/O ./O 
Was/O the/O witness/O an/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION at/O any/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O VIAVER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O asking/O the/O question/O Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O restating/O it/O in/O order/O to/O save/O some/O time/O in/O going/O back/O to/O the/O record/O ./O 
Is/O that/O the/O question/O !/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O VIAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O wish/O to/O assert/O my/O constitutional/O privilege/O ,/O and/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O based/O upon/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ./O 
Mr./O DonL/O ./O 
Very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O is/O now/O in/O the/O process/O of/O conducting/O an/O investigation/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ,/O where/O hearings/O are/O to/O be/O held/O next/O week/O ./O 
When/O you/O were/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION for/O the/O year/O 1942/O ,/O what/O was/O the/O occasion/O for/O your/O moving/O to/O that/O area/O Mr./O VmDAER/O ./O 
I/O consider/O this/O an/O improper/O question/O ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O it/O on/O the/O same/O basis/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1709/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O an/O organizer/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION in/O 1942/O Mr./O VmAvIE/O ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O all/O questions/O about/O my/O political/O activity/O ,/O my/O political/O thinking/O ./O 
This/O is/O my/O private/O opinion/O ,/O my/O actions/O ,/O and/O I/O base/O my/O declination/O to/O reply/O to/O this/O question/O on/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O to/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON testified/O before/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O this/O committee/O on/O January/O 23/O ,/O 1952/O ./O 
He/O attempted/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O information/O regarding/O the/O organizational/O setup/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION during/O the/O period/O that/O he/O was/O its/O organizational/O secretary/O ./O 
I/O asked/O him/O this/O question/O :/O Now/O let/O us/O proceed/O with/O your/O discussion/O of/O the/O 16th/O Congressional/O District/O ./O 
On/O page/O 53/O of/O exhibit/O 1/O I/O find/O reference/O to/O the/O 61st/O Assembly/O District/O of/O the/O 16th/O Congressional/O District/O ./O 
Is/O that/O one/O of/O the/O groups/O in/O the/O 16th/O District/O ?/O 
Mr./O SILER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
That/O is/O what/O is/O known/O as/O the/O West/O Adams/O group/O ,/O a/O large/O active/O branch/O ./O 
Question/O :/O Do/O you/O recall/O the/O nameof/O the/O organizer/O of/O that/O district/O ?/O 
Parenthetically/O ,/O '/O I/O should/O say/O we/O are/O discussing/O there/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O SLVEn/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O there/O were/O various/O ,/O unless/O you/O ask/O me/O for/O a/O specific/O one/O ./O 
Matt/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON was/O the/O organizer/O of/O the/O 16th/O Congressional/O District/O for/O a/O time/O ,/O and/O later/O went/O to/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION to/O become/O the/O section/O organizer/O out/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O Silver/PERSON also/O testified/O that/O you/O were/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O county/O committee/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O whether/O the/O statement/O of/O Mr./O Silver/PERSON was/O in/O error/O in/O any/O respect/O insofar/O as/O it/O related/O to/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O VmAVER/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O have/O already/O stated/O that/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O in/O this/O area/O based/O upon/O my/O constitutional/O rights/O ,/O and/O I/O understand/O the/O Chair/O is/O very/O anxious/O to/O expedite/O matters/O at/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON knows/O that/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O answer/O any/O such/O questions/O ./O 
What/O is/O his/O purpose/O in/O asking/O the/O question/O at/O this/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
To/O get/O it/O in/O the/O record/O ,/O show/O who/O you/O are/O and/O what/O you/O are/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O can/O exercise/O your/O constitutional/O privilege/O if/O that/O is/O what/O you/O feel/O you/O can/O honestly/O do/O ./O 
I/O might/O state/O that/O we/O understand/O your/O position/O ,/O so/O there/O is/O no/O need/O of/O your/O making/O any/O more/O preliminary/O remarks/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O this/O already/O in/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Are/O n't/O you/O reading/O from/O the/O record/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ,/O or/O stand/O on/O your/O privilege/O ./O 
Do/O you/O refuse/O to/O answer/O ./O 
If/O so/O ,/O on/O what/O grounds/O ?/O 
Mr./O VDAVER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O the/O statements/O of/O a/O paid-an/O informer/O ,/O anyway/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O if/O he/O was/O paid/O or/O not/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O wish/O to/O dignify/O this/O person/O ,/O who/O for/O some/O reason/O of/O his/O own/O wants/O to/O become/O an/O informer/O ,/O with/O an/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ,/O now/O ./O 
As/O an/O informer/O ,/O did/O he/O lie/O about/O you/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O read/O a/O book/O by/O Harvey/PERSON Matusow/PERSON which/O is/O pretty/O indicative/O of/O the/O situation/O informers/O find/O themselves/O in/O today/O ./O 
1710/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O an/O opportunityMr/O ./O 
VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
He/O asked/O me/O a/O question/O ./O 
I/O am/O elaborating/O on/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHsERE/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O please/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Let/O me/O finish/O ./O 
There/O is/O a/O question/O pending/O ./O 
I/O asked/O him/O a/O question/O ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O whether/O this/O man/O ,/O whom/O he/O attacks/O as/O an/O informer/O ,/O lied/O about/O him/O ./O 
He/O has/O an/O opportunity/O right/O here/O and/O now/O to/O say/O whether/O this/O man/O told/O the/O truth/O or/O whether/O he/O lied/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O see/O him/O take/O advantage/O of/O that/O opportunity/O ./O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O direct/O you/O to/O answer/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Witness/PERSON ,/O one/O way/O or/O another/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O at/O the/O beginning/O I/O asked/O you/O on/O a/O question/O of/O clarification/O about/O utilizing/O constitutional/O privilege/O ,/O and/O you/O stated/O that/O ,/O if/O I/O get/O you/O correctlyMr/O ./O 
DoYLE/O ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ./O 
You/O heard/O my/O answer/O ./O 
We/O understand/O your/O position/O ./O 
You/O are/O as/O anxious/O to/O save/O your/O time/O as/O we/O are/O toMr/O ./O 
VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O ./O 
But/O I/O want/O the/O situation/O to/O be/O cleared/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O as/O clear/O as/O crystal/O ,/O and/O you/O know/O it/O is/O ./O 
Now/O do/O n't/O be/O facetious/O about/O it/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O here/O to/O conceal/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Why/O do/O you/O not/O answer/O honestly/O Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Because/O I/O believe/O by/O utilizing/O these/O constitutional/O privileges/O ,/O I/O help/O to/O expose/O something/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O the/O witness/O please/O use/O them/O ,/O and/O let/O us/O get/O along/O ./O 
All/O that/O is/O necessary/O is/O to/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
The/O witness/O knows/O that/O ./O 
All/O the/O committee/O is/O asking/O you/O to/O do/O ,/O is/O to/O answer/O or/O decline/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
What/O question/O is/O this/O ?/O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O is/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON 's/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHEREi/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O asked/O him/O ./O 
He/O has/O been/O directed/O ./O 
If/O he/O does/O not/O want/O to/O answer/O ,/O let/O the/O record/O stand/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O the/O question/O again/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
The/O question/O was/O whether/O this/O man/O who/O you/O call/O an/O informer/O ,/O who/O you/O attack/O ,/O lied/O about/O you/O ./O 
You/O have/O the/O opportunity/O to/O now/O say/O whether/O he/O lied/O ./O 
Did/O he/O lie/O in/O anything/O he/O said/O about/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ,/O you/O know/O very/O well/O the/O situation/O that/O exists/O today/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O it/O very/O well/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
On/O this/O basis/O ,/O I/O am/O going/O to/O decline/O to/O honor/O this/O question/O with/O an/O answer/O based/O upon/O my/O constitutional/O rights/O of/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
So/O that/O the/O record/O will/O be/O clear/O in/O connection/O with/O Mr./O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON ,/O whose/O testimony/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON read/O ,/O Mr./O Max/PERSON Silver/PERSON was/O one/O of/O the/O top/O ,/O leading/O Communist/ORGANIZATION functionaries/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION for/O several/O years/O ,/O not/O paid/O by/O this/O committee/O a/O nickel/O ,/O but/O he/O got/O his/O belly/O full/O of/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O and/O came/O forward/O and/O is/O trying/O to/O make/O up/O for/O some/O of/O the/O damage/O he/O did/O when/O he/O was/O a/O Communist/O leader/O ./O 
I/O just/O want/O the/O record/O to/O show/O he/O is/O not/O a/O paid/O informer/O ,/O but/O he/O is/O an/O American/O citizen/O who/O got/O his/O belly/O full/O of/O the/O rottenness/O and/O garbage/O of/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ./O 
Mr./O VnIAVER/O ./O 
I/O said/O I/O did/O not/O know/O whether/O he/O was/O paid/O or/O not/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O the/O record/O to/O show/O he/O was/O not/O ./O 
class/O with/O Matusow/PERSON ./O 
1711/O He/O is/O not/O in/O a/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Vidaver/PERSON ,/O I/O take/O it/O from/O your/O testimony/O you/O are/O unwilling/O to/O give/O the/O committee/O any/O facts/O that/O may/O be/O within/O your/O knowledge/O regarding/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O in/O Santa/LOCATION Monica/LOCATION or/O in/O San/LOCATION Diego/LOCATION ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VmAVER/O ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
I/O am/O glad/O that/O fact/O has/O penetrated/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Maybe/O it/O will/O help/O to/O shorten/O this/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
I/O hand/O you/O two/O documents/O ,/O photostatic/O copies/O of/O affidavit/O of/O registration/O ,/O and/O will/O ask/O you/O to/O examine/O both/O of/O them/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Documents/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O examine/O the/O signature/O ,/O the/O name/O of/O Matthew/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON on/O both/O the/O documents/O ,/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O they/O are/O your/O signatures/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O withdraw/O my/O previous/O remark/O ./O 
Apparently/O it/O did/O n't/O penetrate/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O answer/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Is/O that/O the/O answer/O to/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Is/O n't/O it/O satisfactory/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O is/O satisfactory/O to/O you/O ,/O it/O is/O satisfactory/O to/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
If/O it/O is/O satisfactory/O to/O the/O committee/O ,/O that/O is/O the/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O ques/O -/O tion/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON said/O it/O was/O satisfactory/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Evidently/O it/O is/O not/O satisfactory/O to/O the/O rest/O ,/O and/O on/O second/O thought/O ,/O in/O light/O of/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION decision/O ,/O it/O is/O not/O satisfactory/O to/O me/O ,/O and/O I/O join/O in/O requesting/O the/O direction/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O do/O not/O accept/O that/O as/O a/O sufficient/O answer/O ,/O and/O I/O direct/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O the/O documents/O are/O ,/O if/O you/O know/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VIDAvER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O the/O documents/O speak/O for/O themselves/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O so/O direct/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Witness/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O ,/O based/O upon/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O desire/O to/O offer/O the/O documents/O in/O evidence/O ,/O and/O ask/O that/O they/O be/O marked/O ``/O Vidaver/O Exhibits/O Nos./O 1/O and/O 2/O ,/O ''/O respectively/O ,/O for/O identification/O only/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
So/O received/O and/O so/O marked/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O first/O document/O is/O a/O document/O signed/O by/O the/O name/O Matthew/PERSON S./PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O sworn/O to/O on/O September/O 24/O ,/O 1936/O ./O 
It/O is/O an/O affidavit/O of/O registration/O in/O which/O paragraph/O 9/O states/O :/O I/O intend/O to/O affiliate/O at/O the/O ensuing/O primary/O election/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
1712/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O The/O document/O ,/O Vidaver/PERSON Exhibit/O No./O 2/O ,/O bears/O a/O signed/O name/O of/O Matthew/PERSON S./PERSON Vidaver/PERSON ,/O and/O is/O sworn/O to/O on/O the/O 27th/O day/O of/O September/O 1938/O and/O states/O the/O same/O as/O the/O previous/O document/O in/O item/O 9/O ,/O namely/O :/O I/O intend/O to/O affiliate/O at/O the/O ensuing/O primary/O election/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O hand/O the/O witness/O a/O pamphlet/O compiled/O and/O published/O by/O the/O secretary/O of/O state/O of/O the/O State/O of/O California/LOCATION for/O the/O year/O 1942/O ,/O entitled/O ``/O Members/O of/O Democratic/O ,/O Republican/O ,/O Townsend/PERSON ,/O Prohibition/O ,/O and/O Communist/O State/O Central/O Committees/O ./O ''/O 
Will/O you/O examine/O pages/O 31/O and/O 32/O of/O that/O document/O ,/O please/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Document/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
After/O examining/O page/O 31/O ,/O will/O you/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O caption/O showsMr/O ./O 
MARGOLIs/O ./O 
We/O have/O not/O completed/O examining/O it/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O mind/O waiting/O until/O he/O finishes/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O him/O to/O have/O it/O in/O mind/O while/O he/O considers/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
We/O ca/O n't/O do/O 2/O things/O at/O 1/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O show/O the/O witness/O the/O document/O ?/O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O do/O one/O thing/O at/O a/O time/O ./O 
We/O will/O listen/O to/O the/O question/O or/O we/O will/O look/O at/O it/O ,/O not/O try/O to/O do/O both/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Margolis/PERSON ,/O you/O are/O not/O in/O a/O courtroom/O ./O 
Ca/O n't/O you/O courteously/O comply/O with/O counsel/O 's/O question/O to/O facilitate/O his/O asking/O the/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O MARGOLIs/PERSON ./O 
Does/O he/O want/O us/O to/O read/O and/O listen/O at/O the/O same/O time/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O not/O asking/O you/O the/O question/O ./O 
He/O is/O talking/O to/O your/O client/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O all/O counsel/O asked/O is/O that/O the/O document/O be/O handed/O to/O the/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O hold/O it/O while/O we/O look/O at/O it/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O the/O fuss/O is/O about/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O put/O the/O document/O where/O the/O witness/O could/O n't/O see/O it/O when/O I/O wanted/O him/O to/O look/O at/O it/O ./O 
Hold/O it/O where/O he/O can/O see/O it/O ,/O and/O it/O is/O perfectly/O satisfactory/O ./O 
Mr./O MARGOLIS/PERSON ./O 
Is/O this/O satisfactory/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O if/O your/O client/O is/O looking/O at/O it/O ./O 
With/O page/O 31/O of/O the/O document/O before/O you/O ,/O do/O you/O see/O at/O the/O top/O a/O caption/O stating/O ``/O Members/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ''/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O this/O document/O speaks/O for/O itself/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O ques/O -/O tion/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O do/O not/O accept/O your/O answer/O ,/O witness/O ,/O as/O sufficient/O ,/O and/O I/O direct/O you/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O based/O upon/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O any/O further/O time/O to/O examine/O the/O document/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Vidaver/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O now/O look/O at/O page/O 32/O ,/O the/O last/O page/O of/O the/O document/O ,/O and/O state/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O see/O in/O alphabetical/O order/O a/O list/O of/O names/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1713/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O already/O refused/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O similar/O to/O this/O or/O based/O upon/O this/O document/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O ques/O -/O tion/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O do/O not/O accept/O your/O answer/O as/O sufficient/O ,/O and/O I/O direct/O you/O to/O answer/O ./O 
You/O have/O looked/O at/O the/O page/O ./O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O based/O upon/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O observe/O under/O the/O ``/O V/O 's/O ''/O the/O name/O of/O Matthew/PERSON Vidaver/PERSON as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Central/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O year/O 1942/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O based/O upon/O reasons/O previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O desire/O to/O offer/O in/O evidence/O the/O frontispiece/O of/O the/O document/O and/O pages/O 31/O and/O 32/O ,/O and/O ask/O that/O it/O be/O marked/O ``/O Vidaver/O Exhibit/O No./O 3/O ''/O for/O identification/O only/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
It/O may/O be/O received/O and/O so/O marked/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O one/O more/O ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION now/O ?/O 
Mr./O VIDAVER/PERSON ./O 
Evidently/O it/O did/O n't/O penetrate/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O anwer/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O based/O upon/O reasons/O Mr./O VITDAVER/PERSON ./O 
previously/O stated/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O penetrated/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
No/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O SCIERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O excused/O ,/O Witness/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O William/PERSON Elconin/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Please/O raise/O your/O hand/O and/O be/O sworn/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Please/O be/O seated/O ./O 
BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O TESTIMONY/O OF/O WILLIAM/PERSON ELCONIN/PERSON ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O DAVID/O SCRIBNER/O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O Mr./O sir/O ?/O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ,/O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
My/O name/O is/O William/PERSON Elconin/PERSON ./O 
please/O ?/O 
TAVENNER/O ./O 
Will/O you/O spell/O your/O last/O name/O ,/O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
E-l-c-o-n-i-n/O ./O 
by/O counsel/O ./O 
TAVENNER/O It/O is/O noted/O you/O are/O accompanied/O Will/O counsel/O please/O identify/O himself/O for/O the/O record/O Mr.sCERIBE/O ./O 
New/LOCATION York/LOCATION City/LOCATION ./O 
David/PERSON Scribner/PERSON ,/O S-c-ri-n-e-r/O ,/O 11/O East/O 51st/O Strcet/O ,/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mr./O Elconin/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O born/O December/O 19/O \*/O land/O ,/O Ohio/LOCATION ./O 
14/O ,/O in/O the/O city/O of/O Cleve/LOCATION -/O 1714/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O briefly/O what/O your/O formal/O educational/O training/O has/O been/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O came/O to/O the/O city/O of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION at/O the/O age/O of/O 4/O ;/O went/O to/O elementary/O school/O and/O junior/O and/O high/O school/O in/O the/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION city/O school/O system/O ;/O proceeded/O then/O to/O California/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Technology/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O graduated/O in/O 1936/O or/O 1937/O with/O a/O bachelor/O of/O science/O degree/O in/O electrical/O engineering/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O the/O committee/O ,/O please/O ,/O what/O your/O record/O of/O employment/O has/O been/O since/O 1940/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O been/O an/O employee/O of/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Electrical/ORGANIZATION ,/ORGANIZATION Radio/ORGANIZATION and/ORGANIZATION Machine/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION America/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O field/O organizer/O up/O until/O ,/O I/O forget/O just/O when/O ,/O 4/O or/O 5/O years/O ago/O ,/O when/O I/O became/O international/O representative/O of/O that/O union/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O interrupt/O ?/O 
When/O did/O you/O first/O become/O a/O field/O organizer/O !/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1940/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O the/O exact/O month/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O was/O in/O March/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O field/O organizer/O until/O about/O 5/O years/O ago/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O continued/O continuously/O in/O employment/O ./O 
I/O simply/O was/O promoted/O ,/O so/O to/O speak/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O not/O understand/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O always/O been/O in/O employment/O with/O this/O union/O from/O that/O time/O until/O now/O except/O for/O the/O time/O I/O spent/O in/O the/O service/O ,/O but/O the/O title/O of/O my/O position/O changed/O from/O field/O organizer/O at/O one/O stage/O to/O international/O representative/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O tell/O us/O when/O it/O changed/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O the/O exact/O date/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O mentioned/O it/O was/O 4/O or/O 5/O years/O ago/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O exactly/O certain/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O would/O be/O in/O 1950/O or/O 1951/O ,/O then/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O told/O you/O I/O am/O not/O certain/O ./O 
I/O just/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
I/O can/O check/O my/O paychecks/O if/O you/O say/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O sufficiently/O accurate/O ./O 
I/O understand/O you/O to/O say/O you/O were/O field/O organizer/O continuously/O from/O about/O 1940/O up/O until/O you/O were/O promoted/O to/O the/O position/O of/O international/O representative/O ,/O with/O the/O exception/O of/O the/O time/O you/O were/O in/O the/O military/O service/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcoNIN/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O the/O period/O of/O time/O that/O you/O were/O in/O the/O military/O service/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O was/O in/O the/O military/O service/O approximately/O 3/O years/O and/O 3/O or/O 4/O months/O ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O the/O dates/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O know/O when/O you/O entered/O the/O service/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O entered/O the/O service/O the/O first/O time/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O in/O June/O of/O 1942/O ,/O and/O was/O an/O officer/O as/O a/O second/O lieutenant/O ;/O and/O then/O I/O was/O relieved/O from/O active/O duty/O in/O ,/O I/O believe/O ,/O December/O of/O the/O same/O year/O ;/O returned/O to/O the/O service/O in/O October/O of/O 1943/O and/O continued/O then/O until/O March/O of/O 1946/O when/O I/O was/O honorably/O discharged/O as/O a/O first/O lieutenant/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O say/O you/O were/O relieved/O from/O active/O duty/O in/O December/O 1942/O ./O 
Were/O n't/O you/O discharged/O as/O well/O as/O being/O relieved/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O received/O no/O such/O papers/O of/O discharge/O ./O 
I/O simply/O received/O orders/O to/O be/O relieved/O from/O active/O duty/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O not/O separated/O from/O the/O service/O on/O December/O 13,1942/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1715/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O told/O I/O was/O relieved/O from/O duty/O ,/O relieved/O from/O active/O duty/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O told/O I/O could/O sit/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O war/O out/O if/O I/O chose/O to/O ,/O but/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O that/O means/O separated/O from/O the/O service/O or/O not/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O receive/O any/O official/O document/O that/O I/O can/O recall/O ,/O indicating/O any/O kind/O of/O separation/O other/O than/O the/O order/O saying/O relieved/O from/O active/O duty/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O ./O 
Mr./O TAvENNER/O ./O 
What/O was/O the/O reason/O for/O the/O action/O taken/O by/O the/O Government/O in/O relieving/O you/O from/O active/O service/O or/O giving/O you/O a/O discharge/O ,/O whichever/O may/O have/O been/O the/O fact/O -LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O would/O like/O to/O tell/O you/O this/O in/O some/O detail/O ./O 
It/O wo/O n't/O take/O too/O long/O ./O 
I/O was/O relieved/O from/O duty/O ,/O as/O you/O say/O ,/O December/O 13-I/O am/O not/O questioning/O the/O day/O ;/O I/O said/O it/O was/O in/O December/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O sure/O of/O the/O timeand/O no/O explanation/O was/O given/O to/O me/O at/O that/O time/O ,/O none/O whatsoever/O ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O I/O recall/O inquiring/O of/O the/O adjutant/O on/O the/O given/O post/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O was/O at/O Fort/LOCATION Monmouth/LOCATION ,/O what/O the/O reason/O was/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O he/O did/O n't/O know/O ./O 
./O 
He/O said/O he/O thought/O it/O was/O a/O matter/O of/O mistaken/O identity/O or/O something/O ./O 
Thereafter/O ,/O when/O the/O orders/O were/O confirmed/O ,/O I/O checked/O with/O him/O again/O ,/O and/O he/O said/O he/O did/O not/O know/O and/O would/O seek/O to/O find/O out/O ./O 
He/O was/O unable/O ,/O apparently/O ,/O to/O do/O so/O ,/O but/O he/O never/O communicated/O with/O me/O again/O ./O 
I/O went/O to/O New/LOCATION York-Monmouth/LOCATION is/O very/O close/O to/O New/O York-and/O took/O this/O matter/O up/O with/O my/O union/O ,/O and/O we/O took/O it/O up/O in/O turn/O through/O our/O Washington/LOCATION legislative/O representative/O with/O the/O War/O Department/O ,/O and/O the/O War/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION communicated/O with/O our/O Washington/LOCATION office/O ,/O indicating/O that/O they/O were/O separating/O me/O from/O the/O service/O because/O I/O had/O supposedly/O been/O a./O w./O o./O 1.-absent/O without/O leave-on/O a/O given/O date/O ,/O and/O I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O the/O date/O ./O 
The/O facts/O ,/O however/O ,/O were/O ,/O I/O was/O n't/O a./O w./O o./O 1./O ,/O as/O they/O later/O admitted/O in/O another/O communication/O that/O I/O was/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O they/O claimed/O I/O was/O a./O w./O o./O 1./O ,/O I/O was/O actually/O in/O conference/O with/O the/O lieutenant/O colonel/O who/O was/O responsible/O for/O this/O corps/O area/O ,/O clearing/O up/O a/O false/O accusation/O made/O against/O me/O by/O a/O member/O of/O a/O company/O union/O ./O 
At/O least/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O I/O know/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O a/O company/O union/O or/O a/O management/O representative/O of/O a/O given/O company/O ./O 
The/O company/O 's/O name/O was/O Cannon/ORGANIZATION Electric/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION ./O 
We/O were/O engaged/O ,/O before/O I/O went/O into/O the/O service/O ,/O in/O organizing/O that/O plant/O ./O 
I/O was/O active/O in/O that/O campaign/O ,/O and/O went/O directly/O from/O there/O into/O the/O service/O ./O 
At/O the/O beginmng/O of/O my/O service/O ,/O I/O was/O over/O at/O Cal/O Tech/O for/O a/O refresher/O course/O in/O electronics/O of/O various/O types/O ,/O and/O word/O came/O to/O me/O through/O my/O friends/O in/O the/O union/O where/O they/O were/O continuing/O their/O organizational/O activity/O at/O that/O plant/O ,/O that/O 4/O or/O 5/O people/O were/O being/O discharged/O by/O the/O company/O for/O union/O activities/O ,/O and/O that/O the/O union/O wasMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
That/O goes/O out/O of/O the/O area/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O of/O your/O own/O individual/O case/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O told/O you/O what/O they/O told/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O no/O place/O for/O you/O to/O make/O a/O tirade/O against/O any/O union/O or/O against/O any/O company/O ./O 
We/O are/O asking/O for/O your/O military/O record/O ./O 
65500-55-pt/O ./O 
8/O --/O 3/O 1716/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
It/O so/O happens/O these/O false/O accusations/O -/O Mr./O DOYL/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O interested/O in/O your/O military/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O give/O it/O to/O you/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O I/O have/O a/O right/O to/O explain/O my/O reason/O for/O separation/O from/O the/O service/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O interested/O in/O your/O own/O military/O record/O ;/O not/O a/O question/O of/O controversy/O between/O you/O and/O the/O union/O or/O employer/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O explain/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O give/O you/O an/O opportunity/O to/O explain/O your/O own/O military/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
This/O has/O to/O do/O with/O that/O ,/O very/O much/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
There/O is/O a/O good/O deal/O of/O hearsay/O ,/O and/O you/O ought/O to/O know/O what/O your/O own/O military/O record/O is/O ./O 
Mr./O ELOONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O talking/O of/O my/O military/O record/O the/O best/O I/O can/O recall/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O go/O into/O the/O area/O of/O your/O union/O troubles/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcorNN/O ./O 
It/O so/O happens/O because/O I/O was/O an/O officer/O in/O the/O service/O I/O went/O to/O this/O given/O plant/O to/O prevent/O a/O strike/O ,/O because/O this/O was/O a/O plant/O producing/O defense/O parts/O ;/O and/O instead/O of/O the/O authorities/O being/O informed/O I/O was/O there/O to/O prevent/O a/O strike/O ,/O somebody/O maliciously/O told/O them/O I/O was/O there/O to/O incite/O a/O strike/O ,/O and/O as/O a/O result/O of/O the/O investigation/O being/O conducted/O around/O me/O and/O when/O I/O was/O conferring/O with/O the/O lieutenant/O colonel/O ,/O whose/O name/O I/O ca/O n't/O recall/O ,/O of/O this/O area/O ,/O they/O cleared/O it/O up/O and/O found/O out/O it/O was/O completely/O wrong/O ,/O that/O the/O charge/O was/O false/O ;/O and/O because/O of/O that/O reason/O I/O arrived/O in/O Fort/LOCATION Monmouth/LOCATION 1/O day/O later/O than/O the/O order/O originally/O called/O for/O my/O getting/O there/O ./O 
This/O information/O came/O out/O in/O the/O course/O of/O our/O investigation/O ,/O or/O rather/O ,/O our/O discussion/O of/O the/O matter/O with/O the/O War/ORGANIZATION Department/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O it/O has/O all/O been/O confirmed/O in/O writing/O ./O 
That/O was/O the/O reason/O we/O finally/O found/O out/O for/O my/O separation/O from/O active/O duty/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O confirmation/O in/O writing/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O have/O it/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Where/O is/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O it/O at/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O not/O bring/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O n't/O tell/O me/O what/O I/O was/O to/O be/O questioned/O about/O ./O 
I/O had/O no/O knowledge/O what/O you/O were/O going/O to/O talk/O to/O me/O about/O at/O all/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Representative/O Jackson/PERSON left/O the/O hearing/O room/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O make/O clear/O one/O last/O point/O on/O the/O military/O service/O ./O 
When/O I/O went/O back/O into/O the/O service/O ,/O it/O was/O with/O the/O understanding/O from/O the/O War/O Department/O ,/O I/O also/O have/O in/O writing/O ,/O signed/O by/O a/O brigadier/O general/O of/O the/O Under/O Secretary/O of/O War/O 's/O office/O ,/O there/O would/O be/O no/O further/O discrimination/O against/O me/O or/O prevention/O of/O my/O activities/O in/O the/O service/O as/O far/O as/O promotion/O was/O concerned/O ./O 
I/O rewon/O my/O commission/O ,/O and/O I/O came/O out/O as/O a/O first/O lieutenant/O ./O 
./O 
Those/O were/O the/O facts/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O situation/O ./O 
I/O gave/O you/O the/O dates/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O question/O of/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION activities/O on/O your/O part/O involved/O in/O your/O discharge/O from/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Army/ORGANIZATION on/O December/O 13/O ,/O 1942/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O ELcoNIN/O ./O 
That/O question/O was/O never/O mentioned/O to/O me/O by/O anybody/O at/O any/O time/O I/O was/O in/O the/O service/O ,/O and/O I/O tried/O on/O more/O occasions/O than/O one/O to/O find/O out/O what/O it/O was/O that/O was/O in/O any/O way/O interfering/O with/O my/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1717/O activities/O in/O the/O service/O as/O far/O as/O my/O being/O an/O officer/O was/O concerned/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O never/O able/O to/O get/O anyone/O to/O tell/O me/O anything/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION at/O that/O time/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O very/O naturally/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O know/O I/O am/O employed/O by/O the/O United/ORGANIZATION Electrical/ORGANIZATION Workers/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O have/O already/O made/O that/O clear/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O know/O that/O our/O union/O was/O just/O involved/O in/O the/O recently/O historic/O case/O of/O Emspak/LOCATION and/O Quinn/PERSON which/O the/O Supreme/ORGANIZATION Court/ORGANIZATION ruled/O on/O May/O 23/O ./O 
Sitting/O with/O me/O is/O the/O distinguished/O counsel/O of/O our/O union/O who/O won/O that/O case/O ,/O and/O this/O committee/O was/O involved/O in/O attacking/O our/O union/O in/O that/O case/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Answer/O the/O question/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O about/O to/O tell/O you/O why/O I/O am/O going/O to/O refuse/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOsLE/O ./O 
You/O are/O entitled/O to/O plead/O your/O constitutional/O privilege/O ./O 
You/O are/O fully/O advised/O by/O your/O legal/O counsel/O you/O know/O ,/O and/O we/O do/O not/O have/O the/O time/O for/O you/O to/O make/O a/O record/O here/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O your/O own/O publications/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O do/O have/O time/O to/O make/O records/O smearing/O people/O 's/O names/O ./O 
I/O should/O have/O a/O right/O to/O explain/O why/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O ./O 
If/O you/O want/O to/O ask/O the/O question/O ./O 
I/O will/O answer/O it/O in/O my/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O will/O not/O have/O time/O for/O you/O to/O entirely/O answer/O it/O in/O your/O own/O way/O ,/O you/O might/O as/O well/O understand/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O are/O willing/O to/O withdraw/O the/O question-Mr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O not/O willing/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Then/O I/O will/O answer/O it/O my/O own/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O will/O not/O have/O time/O to/O write/O a/O book/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Please/O continue/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O wish/O to/O ask/O questions/O and/O answer/O them/O ,/O both/O ,/O ask/O yourself/O the/O questions/O ./O 
If/O you/O want/O me/O to/O answer/O the/O questions/O ,/O give/O me/O a/O chance/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O going/O to/O have/O you/O observe/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O the/O same/O as/O every/O other/O witness/O is/O required/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O familiar/O with/O the/O fact/O there/O are/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O they/O are/O ./O 
If/O you/O ask/O me/O questions/O ,/O I/O understand/O I/O am/O entitled/O to/O answer/O them/O my/O own/O way/O ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O explain/O why/O I/O will/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O and/O similar/O such/O questions/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O make/O a/O request/O ,/O if/O I/O mayMr/O ./O 
SOHERER/O ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O the/O witness/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O without/O further/O speech/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O so/O direct/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O one/O question/O first/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O being/O asked/O a/O question/O by/O our/O counsel/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O trying/O to/O explain/O that/O this/O case/O which/O our/O union/O was/O just/O involved/O in/O specifically/O recites/O and/O directs/O itself/O to/O this/O type/O of/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O familiar/O with/O that/O case/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCoNIN/O ./O 
I/O wish/O you/O would/O practice/O some/O of/O the/O decisions/O involved/O in/O that/O case/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
You/O are/O not/O going/O to/O make/O a/O mockery/O out/O of/O this/O committee/O although/O you/O are/O trying/O to/O ./O 
We/O understand/O your/O methods/O and/O your/O reasons/O for/O using/O them/O ./O 
If/O there/O are/O any/O more/O out/O -/O 1718/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O bursts/O from/O anyone/O in/O the/O room/O ,/O we/O will/O clear/O the/O courtroom/O ,/O and/O if/O 5/O or/O 6/O of/O you/O people/O want/O to/O be/O responsible/O for/O everybody/O being/O put/O out/O of/O the/O courtroom/O ,/O then/O continue/O that/O sort/O of/O outburst/O ./O 
That/O is/O fair/O ./O 
That/O is/O my/O statement/O ./O 
If/O 5/O or/O 6/O of/O you/O want/O to/O be/O selfish/O enough/O to/O make/O everyone/O lose/O out/O on/O the/O information/O from/O sitting/O in/O the/O courtroom/O ,/O then/O you/O do/O that/O again/O ;/O and/O if/O we/O can/O identify/O the/O 5/O or/O 6/O ,/O the/O 5/O or/O 6/O will/O be/O put/O out/O and/O not/O the/O rest/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O request/O that/O my/O counsel/O have/O an/O opportunity/O to/O explain/O where/O this/O particular/O decision/O bears/O on/O this/O type/O of/O investigation/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O not/O a/O court/O ./O 
You/O know/O that/O and/O your/O counsel/O knows/O it/O ./O 
He/O has/O been/O before/O our/O committee/O before/O at/O Washington/LOCATION ./O 
He/O knows/O he/O is/O not/O allowed/O to/O address/O this/O committee/O ,/O and/O so/O do/O you/O ./O 
Our/O time/O is/O not/O sufficient/O to/O permit/O legal/O counsel/O to/O argue/O with/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
Since/O you/O are/O referring/O to/O me/O ,/O do/O you/O mind/O if/O I/O speak/O for/O myself/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
You/O well/O know/O our/O rules/O do/O not/O permit/O it/O ,/O and/O you/O know/O our/O rule/O is/O reasonable/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O actually/O sitting/O here/O does/O not/O make/O me/O counsel/O for/O the/O witness/O ,/O because/O I/O have/O no/O rights/O in/O that/O respect/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O a/O right/O to/O address/O the/O committee/O through/O your/O witness/O ,/O and/O you/O know/O it/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O the/O only/O way/O we/O can/O permit/O ./O 
We/O are/O questioning/O your/O client/O ,/O not/O you/O ;/O it/O is/O his/O answers/O and/O not/O yours/O which/O we/O are/O entitled/O to/O receive/O at/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O appreciate/O that/O ,/O having/O had/O that/O experience/O many/O times/O ,/O and/O by/O sitting/O here/O I/O am/O participating/O in/O a/O fraud/O in/O that/O sense/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O came/O clear/O from/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION to/O appear/O with/O this/O witness/O ,/O and/O we/O want/O you/O to/O have/O that/O privilege/O ,/O but/O you/O have/O been/O before/O us/O many/O times/O at/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O and/O you/O know/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O and/O so/O does/O your/O client/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O fraud/O in/O any/O sense/O ./O 
Your/O use/O of/O that/O word/O is/O highly/O inappropriate/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
Have/O they/O changed/O in/O respect/O to/O cross-examination/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOTLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute-you/O again/O deliberately/O violate/O our/O rules/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
This/O is/O a/O fair/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
You/O have/O a/O copy/O of/O them/O ./O 
I/O assume/O you/O read/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O the/O rules/O up/O to/O the/O time/O the/O witness/O appeared/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O asking/O a/O civil/O question/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O there/O has/O been/O any/O change/O in/O the/O rules/O to/O permit/O my/O cross-examination/O of/O any/O witnesses/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Counsel/O is/O in/O contempt/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Attorney/O Scribner/O ,/O you/O are/O again/O deliberately/O violating/O a/O reasonable/O rule/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Contempt/O of/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O ScRIBNER/O ./O 
That/O is/O a/O complete/O absurdity/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O be/O permitted/O to/O say/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O soon/O will/O be/O if/O you/O are/O not/O careful/O ./O 
If/O this/O were/O a/O court/O ,/O you/O would/O not/O dare/O persist/O in/O violating/O the/O court/O rules/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O happen/O to/O be/O familiar/O with/O the/O rules/O and/O the/O law/O on/O this/O subject/O matter/O ,/O and/O merely/O frightening/O counsel/O for/O a/O witness/O is/O not/O going/O to/O serve/O any/O particular/O purpose/O ,/O I/O promise/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O ask/O that/O you/O direct/O counsel/O to/O desist/O from/O further/O talking/O to/O this/O committee/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O S/O 1719/O Mr./O ELcoNIN/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O that/O is/O fair/O ,/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O my/O counsel/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O like/O to/O have/O him/O sit/O right/O here/O with/O me/O where/O I/O can/O talk/O with/O him/O ,/O not/O out/O in/O left/O field/O where/O I/O can/O wave/O hand/O signals/O at/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O now/O made/O a/O page/O of/O your/O book/O for/O publication/O ./O 
Let/O us/O proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O trying/O to/O make/O a/O book/O ./O 
That/O is/O the/O function/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O to/O try/O to/O get/O all/O publicity/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Since/O my/O counsel/O is/O prohibited/O from/O acting/O as/O counsel/O ,/O I/O will/O have/O to/O act/O as/O my/O own/O ./O 
Mr./O DomLE/O ./O 
He/O knows/O the/O rules/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O and/O so/O do/O you/O ./O 
Your/O statement/O that/O he/O has/O been/O prohibited/O from/O being/O your/O legal/O counsel/O is/O plainly/O false/O ./O 
He/O has/O ,/O however/O ,/O learned/O that/O he/O can/O not/O continue/O to/O deliberately/O violate/O our/O rules/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O may/O call/O that/O counsel/O in/O your/O opinion/O ,/O but/O it/O is/O not/O in/O mine/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O not/O going/O to/O permit/O you/O to/O read/O a/O legal/O decision/O in/O this/O case/O ./O 
We/O know/O those/O court/O opinions/O and/O repeat/O them/O ./O 
Your/O counsel/O sits/O by/O you/O at/O all/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O state/O my/O grounds/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O going/O to/O state/O them/O my/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O DoTLE/O ./O 
You/O are/O not/O going/O to/O take/O the/O time/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O read/O a/O legal/O decision/O with/O which/O we/O are/O already/O familiar/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcoNIN/O ./O 
Are/O you/O ashamed/O of/O the/O decision/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Proud/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O also/O proud/O of/O it/O ,/O very/O much/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O we/O have/O had/O enough/O of/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Maybe/O you/O do/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O state/O my/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
We/O have/O had/O enough/O of/O this/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcoNIN/O ./O 
I/O have/O several/O specific/O grounds/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O and/O that/O type/O of/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Those/O grounds/O are/O your/O constitutional/O grounds/O ,/O and/O you/O are/O entitled/O to/O plead/O those/O when/O you/O feel/O you/O can/O honestly/O do/O so/O ./O 
We/O respect/O honest/O use/O of/O constitutional/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
My/O understanding/O is/O I/O can/O use/O any/O grounds/O I/O think/O valid/O ./O 
You/O may/O judge/O them/O invalid/O later/O ,/O but/O I/O may/O use/O them/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O refer/O ,/O if/O I/O may/O ,/O since/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O can/O state/O this/O any/O better/O than/O Governor/O Warren/PERSON stated/O it/O in/O this/O decisionMr/O ./O 
DomE/O ./O 
We/O are/O perfectly/O familiar/O with/O that/O ./O 
We/O have/O the/O decision/O and/O text/O right/O before/O us/O on/O our/O desk/O ./O 
Here/O are/O the/O copies/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O heard/O Mr./O Moulder-Mr/O ./O 
DoYLE/O ./O 
You/O can/O refer/O to/O the/O decision/O ,/O but/O I/O will/O not/O permit/O you/O to/O take/O time/O to/O read/O that/O long/O decision/O ./O 
Mr./O ELoCNIN/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O intend/O to/O read/O that/O long/O decision/O ./O 
I/O heard/O Mr./O Moulder/PERSON make/O reference/O to/O this/O decision/O and/O the/O question/O of/O having/O to/O direct/O witnesses/O to/O answer/O with/O respect/O to/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
There/O are/O other/O portions/O of/O this/O decision/O valid/O to/O this/O matter/O and/O explain/O why/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O this/O kind/O of/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O would/O like/O to/O point/O them/O out/O one/O at/O a/O time/O ,/O and/O they/O are/O very/O brief/O ,/O and/O explain/O how/O they/O refer/O to/O my/O refusal/O to/O answer/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHEER/PERSON ./O 
Point/O of/O order/O ./O 
He/O has/O had/O ample/O time/O to/O comply/O with/O the/O chairman/O 's/O ruling/O ./O 
He/O can/O invoke/O his/O constitutional/O privilege/O 1720/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O if/O he/O wants/O to/O ./O 
He/O has/O not/O seen/O fit/O to/O do/O that/O ./O 
If/O he/O wants/O to/O make/O a/O speech/O and/O read/O a/O decision/O ,/O I/O ask/O that/O we/O proceed/O and/O ask/O the/O next/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O n't/O permitted/O me/O to/O state/O my/O reasons/O yet/O ./O 
I/O would/O like/O to/O do/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O are/O going/O to/O state/O your/O constitutional/O reasons/O ,/O do/O so/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O permit/O you/O to/O read/O that/O decision/O ./O 
You/O can/O refer/O to/O it/O if/O you/O want/O ,/O but/O we/O have/O the/O decision/O right/O here/O in/O printed/O form/O ./O 
We/O are/O familiar/O with/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcoNrw/O ./O 
I/O know/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O the/O people/O are/O necessarily/O familiar/O with/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O not/O here/O to/O make/O a/O speech/O for/O the/O benefit/O of/O this/O audience/O or/O for/O your/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O here/O to/O answer/O decently/O and/O cooperatively/O the/O questions/O in/O a/O dignified/O ,/O honest/O manner/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O ,/O but/O you/O are/O not/O permitting/O me/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O not/O permit/O you/O to/O write/O a/O book/O or/O make/O a/O record/O to/O suit/O your/O publication/O out/O of/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
Answer/O by/O giving/O your/O constitutional/O grounds/O if/O you/O honestly/O want/O to/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O say/O that/O my/O first/O reason/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O is/O that/O the/O powers/O of/O this/O committee/O to/O investigate/O are/O subject/O to/O recognized/O limitations/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
You/O are/O reading/O from/O the/O court/O decision/O ,/O and/O I/O said/O we/O are/O not/O going/O to/O permit/O you/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Now/O please/O desist/O ,/O because/O we/O will/O not/O permit/O you/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Do/O you/O understand/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O a/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O ELcoNne/O ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O be/O reading/O the/O decision/O ,/O however/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O answer-Mr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O reading/O the/O court/O decision/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O now/O ./O 
I/O glanced/O at/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O question/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
My/O question/O is/O this/O decision/O was/O made/O as/O a/O result/O of/O activities/O of/O this/O committee/O ,/O and/O it/O directs/O the/O type/O of/O thing/O that/O this/O committee/O can/O not/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O familiar/O with/O that/O ./O 
We/O have/O been/O informed/O by/O our/O legal/O counsel/O also/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
It/O seems/O to/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O best/O thing/O the/O committee/O could/O do/O is/O pack/O up/O and/O go/O home/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O these/O decisionsMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O now/O have/O this/O for/O your/O publication/O ./O 
Now/O a/O ahead/O and/O answer/O the/O question/O ,/O because/O you/O are/O not/O going/O to/O tae/O much/O more/O time/O of/O this/O committee/O on/O this/O occasion/O ,/O I/O can/O assure/O you/O of/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O appear/O to/O me/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O you/O seem/O to/O be/O frightened/O by/O this/O language/O here/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O something/O else/O for/O your/O publication/O ./O 
What/O else/O doyou/O want/O to/O get/O in/O Our/O courts/O are/O a/O bulwark/O of/O freedom/O an/O justice/O ./O 
e/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O want/O to/O know/O what/O I/O want/O in/O the/O publicationI/O I/O will/O be/O glad/O to/O tell/O you/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1721/O Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O directing/O you/O to/O answer/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON 's/O question/O ./O 
It/O is/O a/O simple/O valid/O question/O ./O 
I/O hear/O you/O now/O admit/O you/O want/O to/O make/O a/O showing/O for/O your/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O said/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O that/O I/O refuse/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O simple/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
Whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION while/O in/O the/O military/O uniform/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O is/O a/O very/O simple/O question/O ./O 
The/O Communist/O conspiracy/O is/O not/O friendly/O to/O the/O national/O security/O or/O defense/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O know/O what/O happens/O when/O people/O get/O accused/O ./O 
Tremendous/O damage/O done/O to/O reputations/O by/O all/O this/O sort/O of/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
You/O have/O gone/O far/O enough/O in/O being/O unreasonable/O about/O answering/O reasonable/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYE/O ./O 
And/O I/O mean/O that/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O what/O you/O mean/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Then/O cooperate/O as/O an/O American/O citizen/O with/O the/O committee/O by/O not/O making/O speeches/O for/O your/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O treat/O me/O as/O one/O ,/O I/O will/O cooperate/O as/O one/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O proper/O ./O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O give/O you/O the/O opportunity/O to/O exercise/O your/O constitutional/O privilege/O ,/O and/O we/O do/O not/O object/O to/O that/O at/O all/O where/O a/O witness/O thinks/O he/O is/O doing/O it/O honestly/O and/O fairly/O ,/O but/O again/O I/O am/O telling/O it/O to/O you/O frankly/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O permit/O you/O to/O monopolize/O the/O time/O of/O this/O committee/O in/O doing/O what/O you/O came/O here/O planning/O to/O do/O ,/O to/O abuse/O this/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O if/O I/O were/O to/O do/O what/O you/O wanted/O me/O to/O do/O ,/O you/O would/O let/O me/O stay/O here/O all/O night/O ./O 
Mr./O DYLE/O ./O 
No/O ,/O indeed/O ,/O we/O would/O not/O ./O 
You/O are/O wrong/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
You/O would/O if/O I/O became/O a/O friendly/O seal/O here/O ./O 
You/O would/O be/O glad/O to/O let/O me/O stay/O here/O and/O spiel/O out/O names/O ./O 
You/O would/O encourage/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O DOrLE/O ./O 
Now/O you/O have/O that/O for/O your/O publication/O ,/O also/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O true/O ;/O is/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
We/O would/O also/O expect/O a/O friendly/O witness/O to/O stick/O to/O the/O subject/O matter/O before/O us/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O way/O it/O has/O been/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O that/O is/O all/O I/O know/O about/O it/O ./O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O Do/O E./O Now/O will/O you/O answer/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON 's/O question/O ?/O 
I/O direct/O you/O to/O answer/O ./O 
We/O are/O not/O accepting/O your/O answer/O so/O far/O given/O as/O sufficient/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O n't/O finished/O it/O yet/O ./O 
Mr./O DOTLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O telling/O you/O we/O have/O not/O accepted/O your/O answer/O so/O far/O ,/O if/O you/O intend/O it/O as/O part/O of/O an/O answer/O ,/O any/O part/O of/O an/O answer/O ./O 
I/O am/O directing/O you/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
I/O understand/O the/O witness/O has/O refused/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
He/O desires/O to/O give/O his/O reasons/O for/O refusing/O ./O 
I/O agree/O with/O him/O that/O he/O is/O entitled/O to/O give/O his/O reasons/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O think/O you/O should/O read/O the/O argumentative/O portion/O of/O a/O court/O decision/O ./O 
I/O mean/O by/O that/O ,/O I/O do/O not/O think/O you/O are/O limto/O certain/O ited/O for/O your/O reasons/O for/O refusal/O to/O answer/O by/O limiting/O you/O 1722/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O provisions/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
If/O you/O have/O other/O reasons/O that/O you/O think/O are/O reasonable/O ,/O you/O are/O entitled/O to/O express/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O ELONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O so/O ,/O too/O ./O 
I/O am/O trying/O to/O do/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
My/O ruling/O is/O you/O are/O not/O entitled/O to/O read/O that/O decision/O ./O 
You/O are/O entitled/O to/O give/O your/O constitutional/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O refer/O to/O it/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O refreshing/O my/O memory/O as/O to/O my/O constitutional/O rightsMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O familiar/O with/O the/O decision/O ,/O and/O so/O are/O we/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
How/O do/O you/O know/O I/O am/O familiar/O with/O it/O ?/O 
I/O will/O decide/O what/O I/O am/O familiar/O with/O ,/O and/O you/O decide/O what/O the/O questions/O are/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O permit/O you/O to/O read/O that/O long/O decision/O ./O 
You/O manifestly/O show/O familiarity/O with/O the/O decisions/O ,/O and/O I/O am/O glad/O you/O are/O ./O 
You/O clearly/O have/O no/O need/O of/O refreshing/O your/O memory/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCoNIN/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O read/O it/O ./O 
Let/O me/O go/O ahead/O with/O my/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O n't/O read/O the/O decision/O ,/O please/O ,/O if/O you/O are/O not/O referring/O to/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O say/O I/O was/O n't/O referring/O to/O it/O ./O 
I/O said/O I/O was/O n't/O reading/O it/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O it/O is/O my/O opinion/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O no/O right/O to/O inquire/O into/O any/O of/O my/O private/O affairs/O or/O beliefs/O which/O are/O unrelated/O to/O any/O stated/O purpose/O ./O 
I/O think/O further/O this/O committee/O is/O misusing/O its/O power/O ;/O that/O it/O has/O no/O right/O whatsoever/O to/O engage/O in/O actions/O as/O if/O it/O were/O a/O court/O or/O a/O police/O force/O of/O any/O sort/O ./O 
And/O I/O think/O this/O committee/O has/O been/O doing/O that/O ,/O and/O I/O cite/O this/O as/O one/O reason/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O this/O kind/O of/O question/O ./O 
I/O think/O further/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O established/O by/O its/O record/O and/O by/O its/O personal/O treatment/O of/O me/O in/O the/O past/O ,/O not/O just/O today/O ,/O a/O record/O of/O bias/O and/O prejudice/O against/O me/O and/O the/O organization/O I/O represent/O so/O that/O it/O makes/O it/O impossible/O for/O me/O to/O get/O any/O kind/O of/O fair/O hearing/O here/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O clearly/O disagree/O with/O the/O witness/O in/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O explain/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O not/O a/O reason/O for/O refusing/O ./O 
opinion/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
That/O is/O your/O Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O do/O n't/O like/O it/O ,/O you/O can/O discount/O it/O ./O 
but/O this/O is/O a/O reason/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O feel/O I/O have/O an/O opportunity/O here/O to/O get/O a/O fair/O hearing/O whatsoever/O ,/O and/O I/O will/O tell/O you/O why/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O not/O interested/O in/O why/O ./O 
You/O have/O made/O your/O statement/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O all/O right/O ./O 
Please/O proceed/O promptly/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O further/O like/O to/O state/O that/O I/O took/O an/O oath/O to/O defend/O this/O country/O when/O I/O was/O a/O soldier/O ,/O against/O all/O enemies/O ,/O whether/O foreign/O or/O domestic/O ,/O and/O in/O my/O opinion/O this/O committee/O has/O acted/O as/O one/O of/O the/O most/O serious/O enemies/O of/O our/O constitutional/O rights/O ,/O and/O therefore/O is/O acting/O in/O a/O lawless/O manner/O ./O 
Mr./O MOULDER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O object/O to/O the/O statement/O ./O 
Mr./O DoyE/O ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ,/O witness/O ./O 
I/O will/O move/O to/O strike/O that/O out/O of/O the/O record/O ,/O that/O kind/O of/O baloney/O and/O misrepresentation/O ./O 
Our/O courts/O uphold/O the/O functioning/O of/O this/O committee/O under/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O can/O prove/O it/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1723/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O not/O going/O to/O burden/O the/O printed/O record/O with/O that/O sort/O of/O statement/O ./O 
You/O might/O as/O well/O understand/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O thought/O I/O was/O going/O to/O be/O permitted/O to/O state/O my/O grounds/O ./O 
I/O am/O taking/O very/O little/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
They/O are/O not/O grounds/O ;/O merely/O an/O attack/O on/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
The/O chairman/O has/O been/O busily/O attacking/O other/O people/O ./O 
I/O have/O a/O right/O to/O defend/O myself/O here/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O have/O that/O right/O ;/O do/O I/O not/O ?/O 
If/O you/O deny/O this/O to/O me/O ,/O what/O else/O do/O I/O have/O left/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O telling/O you/O I/O am/O not/O going/O to/O let/O that/O sort/O of/O junk/O go/O into/O the/O record/O for/O printing/O purposes/O by/O your/O publication/O or/O anybody/O else/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O a/O valid/O statement/O of/O fact/O before/O this/O committee/O ./O 
It/O is/O another/O false/O statement/O of/O yours/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O your/O publication/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
My/O further/O reasons/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O the/O question/O is/O that/O this/O committee/O can/O not/O inquire/O into/O the/O mind/O ,/O personal/O affairs/O ,/O my/O political/O beliefs/O or/O associations/O ,/O because/O of/O the/O provisions/O cf/O the/O first/O amendment/O of/O our/O Constitution/O ./O 
My/O last/O ground/O for.refusing/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O is/O that/O I/O refuse/O to/O be/O put/O in/O a/O position/O ,/O by/O questions/O such/O as/O this/O ,/O of/O appearing/O to/O be/O or/O being/O a/O witness/O against/O myself/O ./O 
This/O is/O one/O of/O the/O provisions/O of/O the/O Bill/O of/O Rights/O to/O which/O I/O refer/O ,/O and/O I/O cite/O that/O as/O one/O of/O the/O reasons/O for/O refusing/O to/O answer/O this/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O emphasize/O in/O citing/O that-Mr/O ./O 
SCHEER/PERSON ./O 
He/O has/O answered/O ./O 
He/O has/O refused/O to/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O still/O answering/O ,/O Mr./O Scherer/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O interrupting/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ,/O Witness/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O he/O has/O answered/O the/O question/O ./O 
He/O has/O invoked/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
He/O has/O invoked/O it/O properly/O ./O 
He/O has/O responded/O to/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Moulder/PERSON said/O I/O should/O have/O an/O opportunity/O to/O explain/O briefly/O my/O reasons/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O had/O an/O opportunity/O to/O explain/O ./O 
I/O know/O what/O you/O are/O doing/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
Maybe/O you/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O 's/O go/O ahead/O with/O the/O next/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O emphasize/O the/O statement/O that/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O is/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O defending/O the/O innocent/O people/O of/O this/O country/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O pleading/O the/O first/O and/O fifth/O amendments/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O mentioned/O those/O among/O many/O other/O grounds/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Go/O ahead/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
He/O has/O frankly/O answered/O the/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O SCHERER/PERSON ./O 
He/O has/O refused/O to/O say/O whether/O he/O was/O a/O Communist/O while/O in/O the/O Army/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
IS/O the/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O there/O permitted/O to/O make/O all/O these/O offhand/O comments/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O asking/O a/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
He/O is/O a/O member/O of/O the/O committee/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
What/O does/O that/O mean/O 65500-55/O --/O pt/O ./O 
3/O --/O 4/O 1724/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Elconin/PERSON ,/O you/O stated/O you/O were/O a/O field/O organizer/O in/O the/O UE/O from/O 1940/O up/O until/O 4/O or/O 5/O years/O ago/O ./O 
During/O that/O period/O of/O time/O was/O the/O law/O construed/O in/O such/O a/O manner/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O the/O UE/O was/O concerned/O ,/O as/O to/O require/O field/O organizers/O to/O sign/O the/O Taft-Hartley/O non-Communist/O affidavit/O ?/O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O a/O legal/O question/O ./O 
Do/O you/O prefer/O I/O answer/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O asking/O for/O construction/O of/O the/O law/O ,/O and/O you/O are/O a/O lawyer/O and/O he/O is/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O DoLE/PERSON ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O appeal/O to/O you/O ./O 
He/O is/O asking/O for/O construction/O of/O the/O law/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
If/O you/O want/O to/O talk/O to/O the/O committee/O counsel/O when/O not/O before/O the/O committee/O ,/O you/O may/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNEB/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O was/O a/O field/O organizer/O ,/O and/O he/O knows/O whether/O he/O was/O required/O to/O file/O ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O not-Mr/O ./O 
ELCONIN/O ./O 
You/O asked/O if/O the/O law/O required/O it/O ./O 
It/O is/O not/O the/O same/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O put/O it/O this/O way/O ,/O if/O there/O is/O any/O doubt/O about/O what/O it/O is/O ./O 
Were/O you/O required/O to/O sign/O a/O non-Communist/O affidavit/O during/O the/O period/O you/O were/O a/O field/O organizer/O for/O the/O UE/O ?/O 
-LRB-/O The/O witness/O conferred/O with/O his/O counsel/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
As/O a/O matter/O of/O record/O ,/O I/O did/O not/O file/O such/O a/O nonCommunist/O affidavit/O and/O was/O n't/O required/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
I/O was/O advised/O I/O was/O not/O required/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
During/O the/O period/O you/O were/O a/O field/O organizer/O ,/O you/O were/O not/O employed/O in/O the/O shop/O or/O in/O the/O industry/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ,/O is/O n't/O it/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O think/O that/O was/O more/O or/O less/O self-evident/O ./O 
A/O field/O organizer/O is/O an/O organizer/O ./O 
A/O worker/O in/O the/O shop/O he/O represents/O works/O in/O a/O shop/O ./O 
Is/O there/O much/O question/O about/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O aware/O of/O the/O fact/O ,/O are/O you/O not/O ,/O that/O this/O committee/O has/O inquired/O into/O the/O reasons/O for/O the/O act/O being/O construed/O in/O such/O a/O manner/O as/O to/O relieve/O officials/O of/O the/O union/O from/O qualifying/O under/O the/O Taft-Hartley/O Act/O in/O the/O sense/O of/O signing/O a/O non-Communist/O affidavit/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O aware/O of/O any/O such/O thing/O ./O 
When/O did/O you/O start/O this/O inquiry/O ?/O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O not/O aware/O the/O committee/O started/O it/O in/O 1949/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O never/O heard/O of/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O never/O heard/O of/O that/O ?/O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O explain/O it/O to/O you/O ./O 
because/O the/O committee/O found/O that/O the/O Atomic/ORGANIZATION Energy/ORGANIZATION Commission/ORGANIZATION was/O construing/O the/O law/O in/O such/O a/O way/O as/O to/O require/O officials/O of/O the/O union/O who/O were/O not/O employed/O in/O the/O shops/O to/O sign/O non-Communist/O affidavits/O ,/O on/O the/O theory/O that/O it/O was/O considered/O just/O as/O important/O to/O watch/O the/O security/O of/O a/O plant/O where/O officials/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O that/O is/O ,/O officials/O of/O the/O union/O were/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O it/O was/O to/O see/O to/O it/O that/O those/O working/O actually/O in/O the/O shop/O were/O not/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O disagree/O with/O you/O as/O to/O the/O facts/O ./O 
I/O am/O fully/O familiar/O with/O this/O situation/O ./O 
I/O was/O involved/O in/O a/O court/O caseMr/O ./O 
DOTLE/O ./O 
Just/O a/O minute/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 1725/O Mr./O SCRIBNER/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O completely/O misstating/O the/O fact/O ./O 
I/O am/O familiar/O with/O it/O ,/O and/O if/O you/O want/O information/O I/O will/O be/O delighted/O to/O give/O it/O to/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O has/O evidence/O on/O that/O subject/O ,/O and/O that.is/O a/O matter/O which/O this/O committee/O has/O investigated/O and/O made/O reorts/O to/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION about/O ./O 
I/O am/O inquiring/O of/O you/O about/O the/O same/O ting/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCOxM/O ./O 
I/O never/O heard/O of/O this/O committee/O 's/O investigation/O ./O 
I/O read/O a/O lot/O of/O lurid/O stories/O on/O this/O committee/O ,/O but/O that/O was/O n't/O one/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
You/O said/O you/O were/O not/O required/O ,/O as/O field/O organizer/O of/O your/O union/O ,/O to/O sign/O a/O non-Communist/O affidavit/O ./O 
Mr./O ELCONIN/PERSON ./O 
The/O law/O did/O not/O require/O that/O ./O 
It/O never/O has/O ,/O does/O n't/O now/O ./O 
Mr./O TAVENNER/PERSON ./O 
