INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-PART/O 11/O HEARINGS/O BEFORE/O TE/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O EIGHTY-FOURTH/O CONGRESS/O SECOND/O SESSION/O DECEMBER/O 16/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O JUNE/O 6/O ,/O AND/O JULY/O 5/O ,/O 1956/O Printed/O for/O the/O use/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O -LRB-/O INCLUDING/O INDEX/O -RRB-/O 0/O -LRB-/O Released/O by/O committee/O and/O ordered/O to/O be/O printed/O -RRB-/O UNITED/O STATES/O GOVERNMENT/O PRINTING/O OFFICE/O 77436/O WASHINGTON/LOCATION :/O 1956/O COMMITTEE/O ON/O UN-AMERICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O FRANCIS/PERSON E./PERSON WALTER/PERSON ,/O Pennsylvania/LOCATION ,/O hairmas/O ,/O HAROLD/PERSON H./PERSON VELDE/PERSON ,/O Illinois/PERSON MORGAN/PERSON H./PERSON MOULDER/PERSON ,/O Missouri/LOCATION BERNARD/PERSON W./PERSON KEARNEY/PERSON ,/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION CLYDE/LOCATION DOYLE/LOCATION ,/O Cahfornla/PERSON DONALD/PERSON L./PERSON JACKSON/PERSON ,/O California/LOCATION JAMES/PERSON B./PERSON FRAZIER/PERSON ,/O JR./O ,/O Tennessee/LOCATION GORDON/PERSON H./PERSON SCHERER/PERSON ,/O Ohio/LOCATION EDWIN/PERSON E./PERSON WILLIS/PERSON ,/O Louisiana/LOCATION RICHARD/PERSON ARENS/PERSON ,/O Director/O CONTENTS/O EXECUTIVE/O HEARINGS/O December/O 16/O ,/O 1953/O :/O Testimony/O ofJerry/O Fielding/O --/O June/O 6,1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofJudith/O Poska/O -------------------------------/O -----/O Virginia/PERSON Viertel/PERSON .../O .../O ./O 
./O 
Joseph/PERSON Ayeroff/PERSON ---------------------------------------------/O July/O 5,1956/O :/O Testimony/O ofJohn/O Hubley/PERSON ---------------------------------------------/O Index/O ------------------------------------------------/O 2/O Ordered/O released/O by/O the/O counulttee/O ./O 
Page/O 5769/O 5775/O 5789/O 5805/O 5809/O PUBLIC/O LAw/O 601/O ,/O 79TH/O CONGRESS/O The/O legislation/O under/O which/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION Committee/ORGANIZATION on/O Un-American/O Activities/O operates/O is/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ,/O 79th/O Congress/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O 1946/O -RRB-/O ,/O chapter/O 753/O ,/O 2d/O session/O ,/O which/O provides/O :/O Be/O t/O e/O -RRB-/O acted/O by/O the/O Senate/ORGANIZATION and/O House/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Representatives/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O Asieriva/LOCATION in/O Congressassembled/O ,/O \*/O \*/O \*/O PART/O 2-RULES/O OF/O THE/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O RULE/O X/O SEC/O ./O 
121/O STANDING/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
RULE/O XI/O POWERS/O ANDDUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O A/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O i/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O li/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O iii/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpeuas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
RULES/O ADOPTED/O BY/O THE/O 84TH/O CONGRESS/O House/O Resolution/O 5/O ,/O January/O 5,1955/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O \*/O RULE/O X/O 1/O ./O 
There/O shall/O be/O elected/O by/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION ,/O at/O the/O commencement/O of/O each/O Congress/ORGANIZATION :/O -LRB-/O q/O -RRB-/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O to/O consist/O of/O nine/O members/O ./O 
\*/O S/O \*/O \*/O 5/O 5/O \*/O RULE/O XI/O POWERSANDDUTIES/O OF/O COMMITTEES/O 17/O ./O 
Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O a/O -RRB-/O Un-American/O Activities/O ./O 
-LRB-/O b/O -RRB-/O The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O as/O a/O whole/O or/O by/O subcommittee/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O make/O from/O time/O to/O time/O ,/O investigations/O of/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O the/O extent/O ,/O character/O ,/O and/O objects/O of/O un-American/O propaganda/O activities/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O the/O diffusion/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION of/O subversive/O and/O un-American/O propaganda/O that/O is/O instigated/O from/O foreign/O countries/O or/O of/O a/O domestic/O origin/O and/O attacks/O the/O principle/O of/O the/O form/O of/O government/O as/O guaranteed/O by/O our/O Constitution/O ,/O and/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O all/O other/O questions/O in/O relation/O thereto/O that/O would/O aid/O Congress/ORGANIZATION in/O any/O necessary/O remedial/O legislation/O ./O 
The/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O shall/O report/O to/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O or/O to/O the/O Clerk/O of/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION if/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O not/O in/O session/O -RRB-/O the/O results/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O together/O with/O such/O recommendations/O as/O it/O deems/O advisable/O ./O 
For/O the/O purpose/O of/O any/O such/O investigation/O ,/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O ,/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O thereof/O ,/O is/O authorized/O to/O sit/O and/O act/O at/O such/O times/O and/O places/O within/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O House/ORGANIZATION is/O sitting/O ,/O has/O recessed/O ,/O or/O has/O adjourned/O ,/O to/O hold/O such/O hearings/O ,/O to/O require/O the/O attendance/O of/O such/O witnesses/O and/O the/O production/O of/O such/O books/O ,/O papers/O ,/O and/O documents/O ,/O and/O to/O take/O such/O testimony/O ,/O as/O it/O deems/O necessary/O ./O 
Subpenas/O may/O be/O issued/O under/O the/O signature/O of/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O or/O any/O subcommittee/O ,/O or/O by/O any/O member/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O ,/O and/O may/O be/O served/O by/O any/O person/O designated/O by/O any/O such/O chairman/O or/O member/O ./O 
Vi/PERSON INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 11/O WEDNESDAY/O ,/O DECEMBER/O 16/O ,/O 1953/O UNITED/ORGANIZATION STATES/ORGANIZATION HonsE/O OF/O RFPRESENTATTVFs/O ,/O SUBCOMITrEE/O OF/O THE/O CoaTTEn/O s/O ,/O ON/O UN-AmERICAN/O AcTvr/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O 1/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 10/O a./O in./O ,/O in/O room/O G-41/O ,/O Federal/O Building/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON and/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O both/O of/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Staff/O member/O present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
The/O committee/O will/O be/O in/O order/O ./O 
Will/O you/O raise/O your/O right/O hand/O Mr./O Fielding/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O to/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Be/O seated/O ,/O please/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O for/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O hearing/O this/O morning/O ,/O and/O under/O the/O authority/O of/O Public/O Law/O 601/O ,/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O committee/O ,/O Mr./O Velde/PERSON ,/O of/O Illinois/LOCATION ,/O has/O appointed/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O two/O consisting/O of/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON and/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ,/O as/O chairman/O ./O 
Also/O ,/O in/O pursuance/O of/O the/O provisions/O of/O Public/O Law/O 601/O the/O committee/O has/O caused/O to/O be/O subpenaed/O the/O witness/O who/O is/O here/O this/O morning/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O determining/O what/O ,/O if/O any/O ,/O information/O the/O witness/O may/O have/O in/O his/O possession/O which/O may/O be/O of/O help/O to/O the/O committee/O in/O proposing/O to/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION such/O remedial/O legislation/O as/O may/O be/O considered/O desirable/O ./O 
Proceed/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O JERRY/PERSON FIELDING/O ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O HELD/O &/O BROOKS/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O the/O witness/O state/O his/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
My/O name/O is/O Jerry/PERSON Fielding/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WuEELER/O ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WISFLER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O counsel/O please/O identify/O themselves/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
I/O Ordered/O released/O by/O the/O committee/O September/O 4/O ,/O 1956/O ./O 
5770/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O HrELD/O ./O 
If/O the/O committee/O please/O ,/O this/O witness/O is/O represented/O by/O Held/ORGANIZATION &/ORGANIZATION Brooks/ORGANIZATION ,/O of/O Beverly/LOCATION Hills/LOCATION ,/O Arthur/PERSON A./PERSON Brooks/PERSON ,/O Jr./PERSON ,/O and/O Benjamin/PERSON Held/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O appearing/O here/O this/O morning/O in/O response/O to/O a/O subpena/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O do/O you/O presently/O reside/O ,/O Mr./O Fielding/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O reside/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O VIIEELai/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O us/O a/O brief/O r6sum6/O of/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O was/O educated/O in/O the/O public/O schools/O and/O high/O schools/O of/O Pittsburgh/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ./O 
I/O did/O not/O attend/O the/O university/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O and/O where/O were/O you/O born/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O 1922/O in/O Pittsburgh/LOCATION ,/O Pa./LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O mind/O giving/O us/O the/O month/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
June/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
And/O the/O day/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
17th/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O give/O us/O a/O resmnu/O of/O your/O employment/O background/O since/O leaving/O school/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O employed/O as/O an/O arranger/O ,/O composer/O ,/O and/O conductor/O in/O the/O dance-band/O field/O and/O in/O the/O field/O of/O radio/O and/O television/O ./O 
ir/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O composer/O ,/O arranger/O ,/O and/O conductor/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O presently/O employed/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
_/O id/O by/O whom/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O am/O presently/O employed/O by/O the/O National/ORGANIZATION Broadcasting/ORGANIZATION Co./ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fielding/O ,/O are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O a/O person/O by/O the/O name/O of/O Judy/PERSON I/PERSON aymond/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O base/O my/O declination/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O of/O the/O Constitution/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O Judith/PERSON Raymond/PERSON testified/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O executive/O session/O on/O September/O 11/O ,/O 1953/O ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O her/O testimony/O she/O testified/O to/O the/O effect/O that/O she/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O late/O spring/O of/O 1945/O and/O severed/O her/O relationship/O with/O the/O party/O in/O the/O early/O part/O of/O 1949/O ./O 
I/O refer/O to/O page/O 26/O of/O her/O testimony/O ./O 
In/O the/O course/O of/O her/O testimony/O she/O related/O to/O the/O committee/O the/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION to/O which/O she/O was/O assigned/O ,/O and/O in/O identifying/O the/O individuals/O who/O were/O members/O of/O this/O group/O :/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON Do/O you/O recall/O the/O names/O of/O the/O other/O members/O of/O this/O group/O ?/O 
Miss/O RAYMOND/O I/O have/O some/O of/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O WEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O relate/O the/O ones/O you/O do/O recall/O ,/O and/O also/O identify/O them/O as/O to/O their/O occupation/O or/O any/O other/O pertinent/O information/O that/O you/O may/O have/O concerning/O them/O ?/O 
M/O ss/O RAYiOND/O Muni/O Diamond/O ;/O Bill/PERSON Wolff/PERSON ,/O a/O radio/O writer/O ;/O Jack/PERSON and/O Mary/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ,/O radio/O writers/O ;/O Gene/PERSON Stone/PERSON ,/O a/O radio/O writer/O and/O partner/O of/O Jack/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ;/O Angela/PERSON Clarke/PERSON ,/O actress/O ;/O Reuben/PERSON Ship/PERSON ,/O radio/O writer/O ;/O Jerry/PERSON and/O Ann/PERSON FieldingJerry/PERSON is/O a/O musician/O and/O composer/O for/O radio/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF/LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5771/O W1-ould/O you/O like/O to/O comment/O on/O this/O testinmion/O ,/O Mr./O Fielding/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIacLDIDN/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O would/O like/O to/O state/O `/O that/O I/O am/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION or/O am1y/O other/O affiliated/O or/O unaffiliated/O political/O organization/O ./O 
With/O regard/O to/O Miss-to/O the/O witness/O '/O testimony/O ,/O I/O respectfully/O decline/O any/O further/O comment/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O WITRELriz/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION in/O 1952/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O respectfully/O decine/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O WsEELR/O ./O 
Do/O I/O understand/O you/O state/O you/O are/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION today/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDIN1/O ./O 
I/O stated/O that/O I/O am/O not/O a/O inaiber/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O AVIIEELEr.Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION on/O December/O 15./O ,1953/O ?/O 
That/O was/O yesterday/O ./O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O a/O radio/O group/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O described/O by/O Judith/PERSON Raymond/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O acquainted/O with/O Muni/O Diamond/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O on/O the/O same/O gromads/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fielding/O ,/O do/O you/O know/O William/PERSON Alland/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O question/O ,/O sir/O ,/O on/O the/O same/O grounds/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDINO/PERSON ./O 
The/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O Mr./O William/PERSON Alland/PERSON appeared/O before/O the/O committee/O in/O executive/O session/O on/O November/O 23/O ,/O 1953/O ,/O and/O admitted/O prior/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION membership/O in/O the/O Hollywood/LOCATION area/O ,/O testifying/O that/O he/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O radio/O branch/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
And/O referring/O to/O page/O 54/O ,/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON testified/O in/O response/O to/O Mr./O Tavenner/PERSON 's/O questions/O :/O Mr/O TAvFNNE/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O would/O be/O well/O at/O this/O point/O to/O tell/O the/O committee/O who/O were/O members/O of/O this/O radio/O group/O ,/O and/O in/O doing/O so/O describe/O their/O position/O and/O activity/O in/O the/O party/O as/O well/O as/O you/O can/O ;/O and/O also/O which/O of/O them/O made/O the/O effort/O to/O have/O the/O meeting/O set/O at/O a/O time/O convenient/O to/O you/O and/O made/O an/O effort/O to/O bring/O you/O back/O into/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Well/O ,/O the/O radio/O branch/O consisted/O of/O Pauline/PERSON Hopkins/PERSON ,/O Sam/PERSON Moore/PERSON ,/O Mr./O ALLAND/PERSON ./O 
Davidson/PERSON ,/O Virgima/PERSON Mullen/PERSON ,/O Stanley/PERSON Waxman/PERSON ,/O Jerry/PERSON Fielding/PERSON ,/O Reuben/PERSON Ship/PERSON ,/O Mlike/PERSON Gene/PERSON Stone/PERSON ,/O Jack/PERSON and/O Mary/PERSON Robinson/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O like/O to/O comment/O on/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDINO/PERSON ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O comment/O on/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Alland/PERSON on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O will/O state/O again/O that/O I/O am/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O see/O no/O reason/O to/O pursue/O this/O further/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O to/O what/O year/O were/O you/O referring/O when/O Mr./O Fielding/O was/O a/O member/O in/O that/O group/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON Mr./O Alland/PERSON testified/O that/O he/O left/O the/O party/O in/O January/O or/O February/O 1949/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O the/O last/O group/O to/O `/O which/O he/O was/O assigned/O ./O 
So/O it/O would/O be/O in/O the/O year/O 1948/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O will/O state/O this/O ,/O Mr./O Fielding/O ,/O in/O asking/O you/O these/O questions/O :/O I/O noticed/O you/O pledged/O your/O constitutional/O privilege/O in/O not/O 77436-5/O --/O Pt/O ./O 
11/O -/O 2/O 5772/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O naming/O anyone/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O knew/O then/O ,/O and/O I/O can/O understand/O that/O ./O 
But/O ,/O naturally/O ,/O when/O you/O state/O you/O are/O not/O now/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O in/O view/O of/O the/O sworn/O testimony/O that/O we/O have/O that/O you/O were/O several/O years/O ago/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O I/O will/O state/O frankly/O I/O do/O n't/O intend/O to/O ask/O you/O as/O to/O who/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION with/O you/O in/O 1948/O and/O 1949/O or/O 1947/O ,/O or/O when/O you/O were/O ,/O if/O you/O were/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O to/O be/O fair/O with/O you/O ,/O the/O form/O of/O your/O answer/O makes/O me/O infer/O that/O there/O was/O a/O time/O when/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O this/O committee/O is/O in/O search/O ,/O also/O ,/O of/O any/O recommendation/O that/O it/O might/O receive/O from/O any/O American/LOCATION citizen/O as/O to/O their/O thinking/O in/O terms/O of/O legislation/O dealing/O with/O the/O subversives/O ./O 
You/O understand/O my/O statement/O ?/O 
We/O are/O looking/O for/O recommendations/O from/O patriotic/O citizens/O ,/O thinking/O citizens/O ,/O to/O help/O us/O understand/O their/O views/O regarding/O the/O field/O of/O legislation/O dealing/O with/O subversives/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O ever/O came/O in/O touch/O with/O any/O subversive/O activities/O any/O place/O ,/O either/O in/O the/O group/O identified/O or/O any/O other/O grout/O ,/O have/O you/O any/O suggestion/O to/O make/O to/O us/O ,/O Mr./O Fielding/O ,/O in/O that/O field/O ?/O 
In/O other/O words/O ,/O this/O is/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O Congress/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Have/O you/O any/O suggestion/O to/O make/O to/O us/O ?/O 
I/O have/O never/O met/O you/O in/O my/O life/O ,/O I/O am/O sure/O ,/O and/O never/O talked/O with/O you/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O what/O your/O answer/O may/O be/O ./O 
But/O I/O am/O just/O asking/O you/O in/O good/O faith/O ,/O have/O you/O any/O suggestion/O for/O us/O ,/O young/O man/O ?/O 
You/O have/O an/O important/O employment/O ;/O have/O you/O any/O suggestion/O to/O make/O to/O us/O as/O a/O congressional/O committee/O ?/O 
Mr./O FiELoiNG/O ./O 
May/O I/O say/O ,/O Congressman/O ,/O that/O I/O have/O always/O been/O and/O do/O consider/O myself/O a/O good/O citizen/O of/O this/O country/O and/O a/O law-abiding/O citizen/O ./O 
My/O profession/O is/O the/O music/O business/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O recommendations/O to/O offer/O this/O committee/O as/O to/O legislation/O on/O the/O matters/O which/O you/O mentioned/O ./O 
The/O Congressman/O stated/O that/O there/O was/O an/O inference/O in/O his/O question/O ,/O and/O I/O believe/O there/O is/O ./O 
And/O for/O that/O reason/O I/O have/O to/O decline/O further/O comment/O on/O this/O question/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O Doyn/PERSON ./O 
I/O know/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON would/O join/O me/O in/O making/O one/O further/O comment/O to/O you/O as/O a/O young/O man/O ./O 
We/O hope/O the/O time/O will/O come/O before/O too/O long/O when/O ,/O without/O your/O feeling/O any/O of/O your/O conscientious/O objections/O ,/O you/O will/O come/O to/O the/O point/O where/O you/O ,/O as/O a/O young/O American/O ,/O will/O voluntarily/O say/O to/O some/O constituted/O authority/O ,/O whether/O it/O is/O this/O committee/O or/O not/O ,/O ``/O I/O want/O to/O help/O you/O understand/O the/O problem/O of/O subversive/O activity/O in/O my/O country/O to/O the/O extent/O that/O I/O am/O able/O ./O ''/O 
One/O further/O comment/O ,/O Mr./O Fielding/O :/O I/O feel/O rather/O strongly/O that/O some/O of/O you/O young/O men/O and/O women/O who/O --/O again/O I/O will/O infer/O because/O of/O the/O form/O of/O your/O answer/O ,/O I/O will/O infer/O you/O were/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O whether/O yesterday/O you/O withdrew/O or/O 2/O years/O ago/O you/O withdrew-but/O there/O was/O a/O time/O ,/O I/O infer/O ,/O when/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O if/O that/O is/O true/O ,/O and/O we/O have/O sworn/O testimony/O by/O plenty/O of/O witnesses/O that/O it/O is/O true/O ,/O I/O want/O to/O urge/O you/O to/O get/O to/O t/O e/O point/O where/O ,/O as/O a/O patriotic/O -/O American/LOCATION citizen/O ,/O you/O can/O conscientiously/O say/O to/O the/O constituted/O law/O ,/O ``/O I/O may/O not/O be/O in/O a/O position/O to/O give/O you/O names/O of/O other/O men/O and/O women/O who/O were/O in/O the/O Communist/O Party/O with/O me/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O now/O in/O a/O position/O to/O tell/O you/O what/O I/O know/O about/O that/O whole/O problem/O ./O ''/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5773/O Again/O ,/O I/O am/O not/O obviating/O the/O possibility/O that/O you/O will/O get/O to/O the/O point/O where/O you/O will/O feel/O that/O the/O safety/O of/O your/O Nation/O ,/O against/O the/O Communist/O conspiracy/O ,/O will/O call/O upon/O you/O to/O help/O your/O Government/O even/O by/O relating/O names/O of/O former/O associates/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION if/O and/O when/O you/O were/O in/O it/O ;/O and/O I/O hope/O that/O time/O will/O come/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O suggesting/O that/O you/O violate/O your/O conscientious/O scruples/O ./O 
But/O I/O have/O come/O to/O the/O point/O in/O my/O experience/O where/O I/O think/O there/O can/O not/O be/O too/O many/O conscientious/O scruples/O when/O we/O face/O up/O to/O the/O fact/O of/O our/O own/O internal/O security/O as/O against/O the/O well-known/O subversive/O Communist/O conspiracy/O to/O use/O force/O and/O violence/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O inferring/O that/O you/O advocated/O that/O ,/O young/O fellow/O ./O 
It/O is/O fair/O for/O me/O to/O say/O that/O you-I/O am/O not/O inferring/O that/O you/O are/O advocating/O that/O philosophy/O ,/O but/O I/O am/O saying/O to/O you/O that/O some/O top/O men/O and/O women/O in/O America/LOCATION ,/O at/O the/O time/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O you/O were/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O did/O advocate/O ,/O and/O still/O advocate/O ,/O force/O and/O violence/O in/O connection/O with/O their/O contemplated/O revolution/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O taking/O advantage/O of/O you/O to/O preach/O to/O you/O ;/O believe/O me/O ./O 
But/O I/O do/O hope-and/O I/O am/O not/O criticizing/O your/O counsel/O in/O whatever/O way/O he/O advised/O you/O to/O answer/O ,/O either-but/O I/O am/O saying/O that/O I/O hope/O you/O will/O get/O to/O the/O point/O where/O you/O can/O put/O the/O first/O thing/O first/O ,/O which/O I/O believe/O is/O the/O internal/O security/O of/O your/O own/O Nation/O ./O 
That/O is/O all/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Fielding/O ,/O were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION when/O you/O entered/O the/O hearing/O room/O this/O morning/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
However/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O will/O state/O again-I/O will/O state/O that/O I/O am/O not/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O be/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION when/O you/O leave/O this/O conference/O room/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O intention/O of/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Mr./O Congressman/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Why/O have/O you/O no/O intention/O of/O joining/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
As/O I/O stated/O before/O to/O Congressman/O Doyle/PERSON ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O a/O very/O busy/O musician/O and/O I/O intend/O to/O continue/O to/O be/O one/O ;/O and/O I/O do/O not/O contemplate/O any/O organized/O political/O activity/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O in/O the/O past/O contemplate/O such/O organized/O political/O activity/O ?/O 
Mr./O FIELDING/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O sir/O ,/O I/O decline/O to/O answer/O that/O on/O the/O grounds/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Any/O reason/O why/O the/O witness/O should/O not/O be/O excused/O ?/O 
Mr./O WnxHEs/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
The/O witness/O is/O excused/O and/O released/O from/O the/O subpena/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 11/O WEDNESDAY/O ,/O JUNE/O 6/O ,/O 1956/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENTATIVES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OF/O THE/O CoxmnriE/O ON/O UN-ANiEICAN/O ACTIVITIES/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O ./O 
A/O -/O ubcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 10/O :/O 05/O a./O m/O ,/O in/O room/O 484/O of/O the/O Statler/O Hotel/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O IHon/O ./O 
Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O members/O present/O :/O Representatives/O Doyle/PERSON and/O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
taff/O member/O present/O :/O Alliam/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O DOLE/PERSON ./O 
The/O subcommittee/O will/O come/O to/O order/O ./O 
Let/O the/O record/O show/O that/O ,/O for/O the/O purpose/O of/O this/O hearing/O and/O under/O authority/O of/O Public/ORGANIZATION Law/ORGANIZATION 601/ORGANIZATION ,/O Francis/PERSON E./PERSON Walter/PERSON ,/O chairman/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O ,/O has/O designated/O Mr./O Morgan/PERSON M./PERSON Moulder/PERSON ,/O of/O Missouri/LOCATION ;/O Mr./O Donald/PERSON L./PERSON Jackson/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ;/O and/O Mr./O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON ,/O of/O California/LOCATION ,/O presiding/O ,/O as/O a/O subcommittee/O of/O three/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON and/O myself/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O are/O present/O ./O 
The/O hearing/O will/O proceed/O ./O 
Mlr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O first/O witness/O is/O Miss/O Judith/PERSON Poska/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Do/O =/O ./O 
./O 
Will/O you/O please/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O to/O this/O subconnittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mi/O s/O POShA/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O JUDITH/PERSON POSKA/PERSON Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
vill/O you/O state/O your/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Judith/PERSON Poska/PERSON ./O 
fr/O ./O 
WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O vou/O born/O ,/O Miss/O Poska/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
I/O was/O born/O in/O Montana-Utica/LOCATION ./O 
M/O -LSB-/O r./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O ask/O a/O question/O at/O this/O point/O ?/O 
I/O notice/O the/O witness/O is/O not/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O ./O 
It/O is/O the/O pr/O `/O ctice/O of/O the/O committee/O to/O allow/O witnesses/O to/O be/O accompanied/O by/O counsel/O if/O the/O witness/O so/O desires/O ,/O and/O I/O should/O like/O to/O have/O it/O appear/O in/O the/O record/O that/O you/O have/O been/O informed/O of/O this/O fact/O and/O also/O to/O inquire/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O desire/O counsel/O ./O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O because/O I/O can/O only/O tell/O the/O truth/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Very/O well/O ;/O but/O I/O felt/O it/O should/O appear/O in/O the/O record/O that/O you/O have/O the/O privilege/O of/O counsel/O if/O you/O so/O desire/O ./O 
2/O Ordered/O released/O by/O the/O committee/O August/O 7/O ,/O 1956/O ./O 
5775/O 5776/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Thank/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O well/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O perfectly/O willing/O to/O go/O ahead/O and/O testify/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O certainly/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O appearing/O as/O a/O voluntary/O witness/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoSKA/O ./O 
I/O am/O ;/O that/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WuHEELE/O ./O 
What/O is/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosiA/O ./O 
I/O graduated/O from/O public/O school/O in/O Seattle/LOCATION ./O 
And/O I/O went/O into/O the/O Curtis/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION of/O Music/O when/O I/O was/O 12/O ,/O and/O I/O had/O private/O tutors/O there/O ./O 
I/O studied/O French/O and/O English/O and/O things/O that/O go/O along/O with/O when/O you/O are/O young/O and/O you/O are/O taken/O out/O of/O public/O school/O ;/O when/O you/O concentrate/O on/O a/O profession/O or/O a/O career/O ,/O why/O ,/O they/O have/O you/O study/O ,/O make/O up/O your/O studies/O ./O 
You/O study/O English/O and/O that/O sort/O of/O thing/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
The/O Curtis/O InstituteMis/O PosKA/O ./O 
Is/O a/O musical/O institute/O ,/O a/O school/O of/O music/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O a/O musician/O by/O occupation/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O am/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O pursuing/O that/O occupation/O at/O the/O present/O time/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosxA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WaEaLR/O ./O 
Miss/O Poska/PERSON ,/O during/O our/O hearings/O here/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION beginning/O on/O the/O 16th/O of/O April/O a/O former/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O Don/PERSON Christlieb/PERSON ,/O stated/O in/O the/O course/O of/O his/O testimony/O that/O he/O knew/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Now/O ,/O subsequent/O to/O his/O identification/O of/O you/O ,/O I/O believe/O you/O became/O aware/O of/O his/O identification/O and/O notified/O the/O committee/O by/O telegram/O that/O you/O had/O not/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ;/O and/O I/O contacted/O you/O on/O the/O basis/O of/O that/O telegram/O ./O 
Miss/O PosA/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
And/O you/O desire/O to/O come/O before/O the/O committee/O and/O straighten/O out/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoswA/O ./O 
That/O is/O correct/O ./O 
Mr./O WHELLER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O proceed/O with/O what/O you/O wish/O to/O say/O ./O 
Miss/O POSA/O ./O 
What/O you/O say/O is/O absolutely/O true/O ./O 
It/O was/O during/O the/O war/O and/O I/O think/O Russia/LOCATION had/O been/O in/O the/O war/O ,/O oh/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O long/O ;/O but/O ,/O anyway/O ,/O all/O of/O us/O ,/O all/O of/O my/O friends/O and/O myself/O included/O ,/O were/O very/O anti-Nazi/O and/O anti-Fascist/O ;/O and/O playing/O around/O ,/O why/O ,/O I/O heard/O a/O lot/O of/O talk/O about/O the/O Marxist/O theory/O and/O how/O valiant/O the/O Russians/O were/O ,/O and/O so/O on/O and/O so/O forth/O ;/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O know/O from/O nothing/O about/O Marx/PERSON or/O the/O Russian/O Revolution-I/O knew/O that/O it/O had/O occurred-so/O I/O thought/O it/O would/O be/O interesting/O ,/O out/O of/O curiosity/O ,/O to/O find/O out/O what/O Marx/PERSON had/O to/O offer/O ,/O what/O his/O theory/O was/O ;/O because/O everyone/O was/O talking/O about/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O seemed/O rather/O stupid/O to/O me/O ./O 
Anyway/O ,/O subsequently/O Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON contacted/O me/O and/O invited/O me/O to/O go/O to/O meetings/O ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O at/O that/O time/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION was/O a/O recognized/O party/O ,/O it/O was/O on/O the/O ballot/O ,/O et/O cetera/O ;/O nothing/O was/O thought/O about/O it/O ./O 
However/O ,/O I/O went/O to/O a/O few-I/O ca/O n't/O remember/O how/O many/O I/O went/O to/O because/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O regularly/O ,/O for/O which/O they/O were/O pretty/O upset/O at/O me/O ,/O plus/O the/O fact/O that/O when/O I/O did/O go/O to/O a/O meeting/O I/O never/O knew/O my/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5777/O lesson/O ./O 
I/O had/O other/O things/O to/O do/O ,/O I/O was/O n't/O married/O ,/O and/O if/O I/O wanted/O to/O go/O out/O on/O a/O date/O ,/O I/O went/O regardless/O of/O the/O meeting/O ;/O and/O they/O wanted/O to/O know/O why/O I/O was/O n't/O there/O and/O where-I/O figured/O it/O was/O n't/O any/O of/O their/O business/O ./O 
I/O was/O free/O ,/O white/O ,/O and/O 21/O ;/O and/O I/O was/O going/O to-I/O did/O n't/O think/O that/O I/O should/O be/O regimented/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O like/O regimentation/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O place/O this/O in/O the/O context/O of/O a/O time/O ?/O 
What/O was/O the/O time/O period/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
You/O know/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
It/O must/O have/O been/O 1942/O or/O 1943/O ./O 
Mr./O AVSYKELER/PERSON ./O 
If/O I/O may/O intercede/O for/O a/O moment/O ,/O the/O records/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION of/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION County/LOCATION show/O that/O she/O was/O a/O member/O of/O the/O beginners/O '/O class/O in/O the/O year/O 1944/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Was/O it/O then/O 194/O -/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHLELER/PERSON ./O 
If/O that/O would/O help/O clarify/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O wanted/O to/O place/O this/O in/O its/O proper/O time/O period/O ./O 
Miss/O Posst/O ./O 
It/O was/O long/O ago/O and/O I/O had/O forgotten/O it/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O n't/O enough/O interested/O to/O --/O you/O know/O ,/O so/O it/O was/O 1944/O ./O 
So/O I/O was-I/O was/O there/O ,/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O to/O meetings/O regularly/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O reprimanded/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O like/O it/O ;/O and/O being/O religious-I/O am/O not/O fanatical/O ,/O but/O I/O go/O to/O church/O ,/O and/O I/O like/O to/O go/O ;/O if/O I/O want/O to/O go/O ,/O I/O go/O ;/O if/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O go/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O go/O ./O 
But/O ,/O by/O the/O same/O token/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O someone/O to/O tell/O me/O not/O to/O go/O ,/O any/O more/O than/O I/O want/O someone/O to/O tell/O me/O I/O am/O to/O go/O ./O 
I/O am/O free/O ,/O and/O when/O my/O basic/O liberties/O are/O jeopardized/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O like/O it/O at/O all/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O were/O criticized/O for/O going/O to/O church/O by/O this/O group/O of/O people/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosK/O _/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O was/O n't/O recommended/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O it/O was/O n't/O the/O thing/O to/O do/O ,/O you/O know/O ./O 
They/O frowned/O upon/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O I/O interviewed/O you/O last/O month/O there/O was/O some/O doubt/O in/O your/O mind/O whether/O you/O actually/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
To/O my/O knowledge/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O must/O have/O ,/O but/O if/O they/O have/O me/O down/O maybe/O I/O signed/O something/O ./O 
If/O I/O did/O ,/O I/O certainly/O was/O n't/O aware/O of/O it/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
That/O is/O how/O stupid/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Miss/O Posi-c/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
That/O is/O one/O thing/O ,/O I/O was/O supposed/O to/O give-I/O do/O n't/O know/O how/O much/O ,/O a/O certain/O percentage/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O know/O exactly/O the/O percentage/O of/O everything/O I/O made/O ;/O and/O I/O inquired/O as/O to/O why/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O it/O went/O into/O the/O party/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Who/O instructed/O you/O that/O you/O were/O supposed/O to/O give/O a/O certain/O portion/O of/O your/O earnings/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O if/O I/O remember/O ,/O Altman/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O always/O at/O the/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
How/O did/O you/O meet/O Mr./O Altman/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O PossA/O ./O 
He/O was/O a/O musician/O ,/O and/O we/O worked/O together/O a/O long/O ,/O long/O ,/O time/O ago/O when/O I/O first/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ./O 
I/O had/O known/O him/O for/O many/O years/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
When/O would/O that/O have/O been/O ?/O 
here/O Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O first/O came/O to/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION in/O 1932/O ./O 
I/O had/O been/O have/O to/O give/O him/O A/O for/O about/O a/O year/O when/O I/O met/O him/O ,/O I/O believe/O ;/O but/O I/O worked/O on/O me/O effort/O ./O 
They/O really/O worked/O on/O me/O ,/O but/O the/O more/O they/O the/O less/O I/O liked/O it/O ./O 
attended/O ?/O 
you/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O meetings/O would/O you/O say/O 5778/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Miss/O POSXA/O ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
Wheeler/PERSON ,/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
I/O might/O have/O gone/O to/O a/O dozen/O ,/O I/O might/O have/O gone/O to/O 10/O ./O 
I/O really-there/O were/O n't/O too/O many/O ./O 
Mr./O Wrnsarxa/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O say/O you/O were/O connected/O with/O this/O group/O for/O a/O period/O of/O 6/O months/O or/O less/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O 'd/O say/O 6/O months/O ,/O maybe/O ./O 
Maximum/O ,/O 6/O months/O Mr./O WIEELER/PERSON ./O 
Over/O that/O period/O of/O time/O ,/O did/O you/O attend/O approximately/O 12/O meetings/O ?/O 
Mi/O s/O POSXA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O '/O l/O say/O ./O 
I/O never/O did/O keep/O track/O ,/O but/O it/O !/O 
ould/O have/O been/O very/O easily/O ./O 
Mr./O WHELER/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O concerning/O the/O activities/O of/O this/O witness/O ./O 
Mr./O DOi-LE/O ./O 
Do/O you/O ,/O Mr./O ./O 
fackson/O ?/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O should/O like/O to/O discuss/O the/O meetings/O a/O little/O further/O ./O 
Where/O were/O the/O meetings/O held/O which/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
They/O were/O always/O at/O a/O different/O place/O in/O a/O privatesomeone/O 's/O private/O home/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Whose/O home/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
That/O I/O do/O n't/O even/O remember/O ,/O because/O they/O were/O always/O in/O someone/O 's/O -/O some/O different/O person/O 's/O place/O ./O 
They/O were/O n't/O musicians/O ,/O because/O that/O I/O would/O remember/O ./O 
We/O were/O never/O at/O Christlieb/PERSON 's/O house/O ./O 
I/O think/O once/O we/O went/O to/O Altman/PERSON 's/O place-we/O met/O at/O Altman/PERSON 's/O place/O ;/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O even/O remember/O where/O he/O was/O living/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
I/O do/O eIember/O very/O distinctly/O that/O I/O was/O supposed/O to/O go/O to/O one/O place/O and/O I/O got/O lost/O ./O 
It/O was/O quite/O far/O away/O from/O where/O I/O was/O living/O ,/O and/O I/O finally/O gave/O up/O and/O went/O home/O ./O 
I/O was/O disgusted/O with/O the/O whole/O business/O ./O 
Mr./O JTcKsoNr/O ./O 
During/O your/O attendance/O at/O these/O 8/O or/O 10/O meetings/O ,/O who/O elae/O attended/O these/O meetings/O ,/O in/O addition/O to/O yourself/O ?/O 
MISS/O POSKA/PERSON ./O 
./O 
S/O a/O nile/O ,/O Altman/PERSON was/O always/O there/O ,/O Christheb/PERSON some/O of/O tIme/O time/O ,/O and/O then/O they/O were/O made/O up/O of/O ,/O not/O musicians/O ,/O but/O ,/O oh/O ,/O there/O would/O be/O radio/O actors/O and/O people/O from/O the/O arts/O and/O sciences/O in/O the/O different/O fields/O ;/O maybe/O one/O would/O be/O a/O photographer/O ./O 
I/O know/O that/O once-oh/O ,/O do/O yon/O remember/O I/O told/O you/O who/O was/O there/O ,/O a/O writer/O in/O these/O erv/O well-john/O Howard/PERSON Lawson/PERSON was/O there/O at/O one/O meeting/O ./O 
Mr./O ./O 
,/O ixAisoN/O ./O 
And/O who/O else/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosEa/O ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O there/O were/O always/O very/O different/O ,/O as/O a/O rule/O a/O different/O group/O ,/O and/O I/O could/O n't/O name/O you/O them/O because/O I/O do/O n't/O remember/O ,/O and/O they/O were/O n't/O musicians/O ./O 
Ah/O ./O 
JxcmwsoN/O ./O 
You/O attended/O 8/O or/O 10/O or/O 12/O meetings/O over/O a/O period/O of/O some/O months/O ,/O during/O which/O time/O ,/O and/O to/O the/O best/O of/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O nit/O can/O remember/O only/O MNr.Lawson/O and/O Mr./O Altman/PERSON and/O Mr/O Christlieb/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O and/O I/O think/O once/O or/O twice/O Mrs./O Christlieb/PERSON was/O there/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcxsoN/O ./O 
How/O were/O you/O notified/O as/O to/O where/O you/O were/O to/O go/O to/O the/O -LRB-/O e/O meetings/O ?/O 
How/O did/O you/O receive/O word/O on/O that/O ?/O 
MIss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Either/O Altman-usually/O Altman/PERSON called/O me/O ,/O or/O I/O think/O once/O or/O twice/O Christlieb/PERSON called/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
They/O would/O tell/O you/O that/O the/O meeting/O was/O to/O be/O held/O in/O such/O and/O such/O a/O person/O 's/O house/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Much/O and/O such/O address/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5779/O Mr./O JACKSoN/PERSON ./O 
Such/O and/O such/O address/O ,/O and/O without/O further/O identification/O of/O whose/O address/O it/O was/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoseA/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O under/O the/O compulsion/O of/O your/O oath/O ,/O are/O you/O prepared/O to/O say/O that/O you/O can/O not/O now/O remember/O any/O other/O persons/O than/O the/O 3/O you/O have/O named/O ,/O or/O the/O 4/O ,/O including/O Mrs./O Christlieb/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Not/O by/O name/O ,/O no/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O ./O 
If/O I/O could/O ,/O I/O certainly/O would/O tell/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
If/O not/O by/O name/O ,/O can/O you/O identify/O any/O of/O these/O persons/O in/O any/O other/O way/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O except/O that/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O know/O that/O there/O would/O be/O an/O actor/O or/O sometimes/O I/O lmow/O that/O I/O would/O hear/O mention/O of/O photography/O and/O studio/O work/O ,/O and/O they/O were/O from/O the-I/O take/O it/O for/O granted/O they/O were/O from/O the/O arts/O and/O sciences/O ;/O but/O musicians/O ,/O I/O never-the/O only/O ones/O that/O I/O saw/O I/O mentioned/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsox/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O any/O of/O the/O actors/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
They/O were/O n't/O well/O known/O ,/O no/O ./O 
They/O were/O n't/O big/O names/O ,/O because/O those/O I/O would/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O terminate/O your/O association/O with/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O ca/O n't/O tell/O you/O exactly/O ./O 
It/O was/O n't/O very/O long/O ;/O I/O mean/O ,/O that/O I/O stopped/O completely/O going/O to/O meetings/O ./O 
When/O I/O stopped/O going/O to/O meetings/O they/O stopped/O speaking/O to/O me/O ,/O too/O ./O 
MT./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O any/O effort/O made/O to/O get/O you/O to/O return/O to/O the/O party/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
No/O ,/O they/O did/O n't/O ./O 
They/O just/O ignored/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKwou/PERSON ./O 
By/O ``/O they/O ,/O ''/O I/O suppose/O you/O mean/O the/O four/O persons/O you/O mentioned/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Christliebs/PERSON and/O the/O Altmans/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O is/O this/O substantially/O borne/O out/O by/O the/O Christlieb/PERSON testimony/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O present/O occupation/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
I/O am/O a/O musician/O ./O 
I/O play/O my/O violin/O and/O I/O am/O also/O in/O the/O real-estate/O business/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O now/O engaged/O professionally/O in/O the/O music/O field/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O do/O free-lance/O work/O ./O 
I/O am/O not/O under/O contract/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O more/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
As/O the/O record/O stands/O ,/O Miss/PERSON Poska/PERSON ,/O I/O believe/O you/O do/O not/O deny/O that/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O nor/O do/O you/O admit/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
To/O my/O knowledge/O I/O was/O n't/O ,/O but/O I/O must/O have/O been/O if/O they/O say/O that/O I/O was/O in/O the/O student/O class/O or/O the/O beginners/O '/O class/O or/O whatever/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
It/O would/O stand/O to/O reason/O if/O they/O asked/O you/O for/O a/O percentage/O of/O your/O salaryMiss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O they/O must/O have/O considered/O you/O as/O a/O member/O of/O their/O group/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoSKA/O ./O 
They/O must/O have/O ./O 
of/O your/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O this/O :/O Did/O you/O pay/O some/O percentage/O salary/O 77436-56/O --/O Pt/O 11-3/O 5780/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O never/O a/O penny/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O distribute/O any/O literature/O in/O the/O group/O ?/O 
Miss/O POlKA/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Or/O buy/O any/O literature/O ?/O 
Miss/O Posia/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Whatever/O literature/O Iliad/O ,/O they/O gave/O me/O to/O read/O ;/O which/O I/O neverMr/O ./O 
DoYL/O ./O 
When/O you/O went/O to/O the/O meetings/O ,/O with/O whom/O did/O you/O go/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSE/O k./O I/O went/O by/O myself/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Mr./O Lawson/PERSON speak/O at/O that/O one/O meeting-if/O you/O remember/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O sort/O of/O conducted/O the/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O -RRB-/O ,/O YLE/ORGANIZATION ./O 
What/O did/O you/O do/O to/O leave/O the/O group/O ?/O 
AhI/O ,/O PosK/O _/O ./O 
What/O did/O I/O do/O ?/O 
Mr./O DoyrE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
MUss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O just/O quit/O going/O ./O 
I/O just/O stopped/O going/O to/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O Mr./O Altman/PERSON ask/O you/O to/O come/O back/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
They/O would/O tell/O me-they/O called/O me/O and/O would/O say/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O there/O is/O a/O meeting/O at/O such/O and/O such/O an/O address/O ''/O :/O and/O I/O 'd/O say/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O I/O do/O n't/O think/O I/O can/O make/O it/O ''/O ;/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O ;/O and/O that/O was/O it/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
They/O must/O have/O given/O you/O a/O membership/O card/O if/O they/O considered/O you/O a/O member/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O never/O got/O a/O membership/O card/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O give/O you/O any/O name/O other/O than/O your/O own/O to/O use/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O the/O testimony/O here/O of/O the/O person/O who/O identified/O her/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O do/O not/O ./O 
It/O was/O transcribed/O by/O reporters/O from/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON ,/O and/O taken/O to/O Washington/LOCATION ,/O D./PERSON C./PERSON I/O night/O mention/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O that/O I/O have/O been/O advised/O that/O the/O records/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION disclose/O Miss/PERSON Poska/PERSON as/O a/O very/O unsatisfactory/O member/O ./O 
She/O was/O dropped/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Can/O you/O help/O us/O to/O understand/O what/O there/O was/O about/O the/O Communist/O group/O that/O constrained/O you/O to/O leave/O it/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O like/O regimentation/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O shape/O ,/O or/O form/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O like/O it/O and/O I/O wo/O n't/O have/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O free/O and/O I/O am/O going/O to/O stay/O that/O way/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O they/O discuss/O at/O any/O of/O the/O meetings/O at/O which/O you/O were/O present/O ,/O the/O matter/O of/O the/O relationship/O between/O our/O own/O Nation/O and/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
What/O was/O the/O discussion/O ?/O 
That/O is/O ,/O the/O different/O philosophies/O of/O govermnent/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
We/O were/O supposed/O to/O study/O Marx/PERSON ,/O and/O I/O was/O supposed/O to/O read/O it/O ,/O snd/O we/O were/O supposed/O to/O know/O our/O lessons/O when/O we/O went/O there/O ;/O but/O I/O never/O knew/O mine/O ,/O and/O it/O was-of/O course/O ,/O it/O was/O anti-/O capitalmst/O ,/O ad/O I/O could/O n't/O see/O anything/O wrong/O with/O our/O capitalistic/O so/O far/O ,/O is/O the/O best/O I/O know/O of/O ./O 
systein/O ./O 
I/O think/O it/O ,/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O you/O mentioned/O you/O never/O knew/O your/O lesson/O ./O 
Then/O you/O had/O a/O book/O on/O Marxism/O that/O you/O did/O n't/O study/O too/O much/O ./O 
You/O must/O have/O had/O a/O book/O for/O your/O lesson/O ./O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O buy/O that/O book/O ?/O 
Miss/O POsKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5781/O Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O books/O on/O Marxism/O were/O you/O supposed/O to/O read/O '/O Hiss/O PosKA/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ,/O but/O I/O never/O even/O got/O through/O that/O one/O because/O I/O was/O n't/O interested/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O wonder/O ,/O was/O there/O any/O discussion/O at/O all/O of/O our/O own/O Government/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O not/O to/O my/O knowledge/O ./O 
Mr/O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
As/O compared/O with/O the/O Marxist/O theory/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Any/O eriticii/O of/O our/O form/O of/O Government/O ?/O '/O 
1uss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O would/O n't/O say/O there/O was/O when/O I/O started-when/O I/O was/O going/O to/O the/O meetings/O ./O 
They/O always/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O stressed/O ,/O naturally/O ,/O that/O the/O workers/O should-in/O Russia/LOCATION what/O they/O are/O ,/O and/O we/O are/O a/O capitalistic/O system/O ;/O and/O that/O was/O better/O ,/O they/O thought/O ;/O and/O that/O is/O where/O I/O parted/O company/O also/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
On/O the/O matter/O of/O the/O literature/O ;/O you/O say/O you/O do/O not/O know/O how/O many/O books/O on/O Marxism/O you/O had/O ,/O but/O evidently/O you/O did/O not/O hia/O ve/O vour/O lesson/O in/O one/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosxA/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O have/O them/O in/O anything/O they/O gave/O me/O ./O 
After/O I/O quit/O going/O to/O meetings/O ,/O I/O threw/O them/O in/O the/O incinerator/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
But/O I/O am/O wondering/O ,/O did/O you/O get/O into/O the/O realm/O of/O helping/O them/O ;/O be/O the/O librarian/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosxA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Or/O distribute/O any/O of/O the/O literature/O ?/O 
Mbs/O POSIKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
By/O repute/O ,/O I/O know/O generally/O they/O do/O that/O with/O a/O begiinoer/O ./O 
lisc/O PosKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O neverMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Who/O was/O the/O treasurer/O of/O the/O group/O ?/O 
There/O must/O have/O been/O someone/O who/O was/O announced/O as/O treasurer/O ./O 
H1i/O -/O PosKa/O ./O 
Altman/PERSON ,/O he/O was/O collecting/O ./O 
When/O anybody/O gave/O money/O for/O anything/O ,/O why/O he/O collected/O it/O ./O 
They/O gave/O it/O to/O him/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O n't/O Mr./O and/O Mrs./O Altman/PERSON once/O in/O a/O while/O pick/O you/O up/O and/O go/O with/O you/O ?/O 
-/O MissPosxx/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Or/O you/O with/O him/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoswA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Who/O ,/O then/O ,/O was/O the/O chairman/O of/O the/O group/O if/O Altman/PERSON was/O the/O collector/O of/O dues/O ?/O 
Who/O was/O the/O chairman/O of/O it/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O he/O conducted/O the/O meetings/O ./O 
M/O -LSB-/O r./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Mischa/PERSON Altman/PERSON did/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
M1r/O ./O 
DoYLr/O ./O 
And/O he/O collected/O the/O money/O ,/O too/O ?/O 
Ji-s/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Air/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Generally/O w-ho/O phoned/O you/O as/O to/O where/O the/O meeting/O was/O to/O be/O held/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
It/O would/O be/O either/O Altman/PERSON or/O Christlieb/PERSON who/O would/O phone/O me/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Is/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON the/O one/O who/O identified/O the/O witness/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O WjhEELER/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O sir/O ./O 
5782/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O DoYL/O ./O 
Did/O you/O just/O drop/O out/O or/O did/O you/O send/O a/O written/O resignation/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O I/O just/O stopped/O ./O 
I/O just/O stopped/O going/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O see/O their/O filing/O system/O ,/O card/O index/O ,/O books/O ,/O or/O records/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSiKA/O ./O 
I/O never/O did/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O members/O were/O in/O your/O group/O ?/O 
MISS/O POSKA/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O know/O ./O 
At/O the/O meetings/O that/O I/O attended/O there/O would/O n't/O be/O more/O than/O 6/O or/O 7/O ./O 
They/O were/O small/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Did/O the/O members/O participate/O in/O the/O discussion/O ?/O 
You/O now/O were/O interested/O a/O little/O bit/O ,/O at/O least/O ./O 
For/O instance/O ,/O did/O you/O participate/O in/O the/O discussions/O ,/O too/O ,/O along/O with/O the/O rest/O of/O them/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O pretty/O good/O listener/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
You/O did/O not/O have/O your/O lesson/O ?/O 
MISS/O POSKA/PERSON ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
iMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
They/O criticized/O you/O because/O you/O did/O not/O have/O your/O lesson/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
So/O evidently/O you/O were/O expected/O to/O know/O your/O lesson/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKiA/O ./O 
I/O was/O ./O 
I/O was/O supposed/O to/O have/O my/O lesson/O and/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Were/O these/O meetings/O which/O you/O attended/O closed/O meetings/O ,/O or/O did/O you/O have/O the/O impression/O that/O you/O were/O free/O to/O bring/O with/O you/O anyone/O you/O AN-antedi/O to/O bring/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosiA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O was/O never/O told/O that/O I/O could/O bring/O anyone/O and/O I/O never/O did/O take/O anyone/O ;/O but/O I/O would-looking/O back/O on/O it/O ,/O I/O would/O think/O that/O they/O were/O closed/O meetings/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O not/O prompting/O you/O in/O this/O regard/O ,/O but/O was/O it/O your/O impression/O that/O you/O could/O not/O simply/O have/O taken/O a/O friend/O with/O you/O to/O the/O meeting/O ;/O is/O that/O a/O correct/O statement/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O that/O vas-that/O would/O be/O the/O impression/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O at/O no/O time/O were/O you/O asked/O to/O contribute/O or/O to/O pay/O dues/O or/O to/O make/O any/O contribution/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O yes/O ,/O I/O was/O expected/O to/O give/O a/O certain/O percentage/O of/O everything/O I/O made/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
And/O this/O you/O did/O not/O do/O ?/O 
MISS/O POSIrA/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O this/O remonstrated/O about/O by/O Mr./O Altman/PERSON or/O anyof/O the/O other/O members/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosRA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O when/O I/O inquired-you/O see/O ,/O I/O always/O like/O to/O know/O where/O my/O money/O is/O going/O ./O 
When/O I/O inquired/O where/O it/O was/O going/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O to/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O ''/O 
And/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O What/O for/O ?/O ''/O 
``/O Well/O ,/O ''/O he/O said/O ,/O ``/O you/O are/O not/O supposed/O to/O ask/O ./O ''/O 
I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O figure/O it/O is/O my/O money/O ,/O it/O is/O my/O privilege/O to/O know/O ./O ''/O 
So/O I/O said/O ,/O ``/O I/O do/O n't/O feel/O like/O it/O ./O ''/O 
Mr./O JAcKsoNe/O ./O 
Have/O you/O followed/O the/O course/O of/O the/O recent/O hearings/O of/O this/O committee/O in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Where/O the/O musicians/O were/O involved/O ,/O I/O did/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ,/O during/O the/O course/O of/O those/O hearings/O ,/O see/O the/O photograph/O or/O read/O the/O testimony/O of/O any/O person/O who/O was/O known/O to/O you/O either/O as/O a/O Communist/O or/O non/O -/O Communist/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O would/O n't/O say-I/O could/O n't/O say/O that/O an/O ,/O one/O except/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON was/O to/O my/O knowledge/O a/O Communist/O ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5783/O Mr./O JACRsON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Had/O you/O previously/O known/O any/O others/O who/O testified/O during/O the/O course/O of/O those/O hearings/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
There/O were/O a/O lot/O of/O musicians/O who/O testified/O that/O I/O know/O ;/O yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O know/O any/O of/O them/O to/O have/O been/O members/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
MIss/O PoSeA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
I/O was/O very/O amazed/O ./O 
I/O think/O I/O told/O you/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O that/O I/O was/O dumfounded/O at/O some/O of/O the/O names/O that/O I/O read/O ,/O completely/O dumfounded/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O inasmuch/O as/O the/O witness/O is/O not/O accompained/O by/O counsel/O ,/O I/O should/O like/O to/O ask/O one/O more/O question/O ./O 
Mr./O DOY-LE/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O J.kciiN/O ./O 
That/O is/O ,/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O feel/O that/O your/O rights/O have/O been/O in/O any/O way/O abused/O by/O the/O subcommittee/O ./O 
Miss/O PosirA/O ./O 
Here/O today/O ?/O 
Mfr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Here/O today/O ./O 
Miss/O PosrA/O ./O 
I/O should/O say/O not/O ./O 
Mr./O JAcKisox/PERSON ./O 
And/O whether/O you/O have/O been/O in/O any/O way/O intimidated/O ?/O 
MIss/O PosKx/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mfr/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Or/O anything/O of/O that/O sort/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKw/O ./O 
Oh/O ,/O no/O ./O 
Mr./O J/O CKsoN/O ./O 
We/O so/O frequently/O meet/O with/O that/O charge/O ./O 
We/O like/O to/O have/O it/O in/O the/O record/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O as/O a/O matter/O of/O fact/O ,/O you/O probably/O feel/O much/O better/O for/O having/O gotten/O it/O off/O your/O chest/O ./O 
Miss/O POsKA/O ./O 
I/O certainly/O do/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O happy/O to/O have/O come/O down/O here/O this/O morning/O ./O 
Mr./O ,/O J.AcKsoN/O ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O -RRB-/O ,/O ou/O feel/O that/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ,/O our/O investigator/O ,/O has/O been/O perfectly/O fair/O t/O o/O you/O in/O his/O dealings/O with/O you/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
He/O has/O been/O wonderful/O ,/O and/O I/O consider/O him/O my/O friend/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
We/O are/O glad/O to/O say/O that/O he/O is/O probably/O the/O man/O with/O the/O most/O ``/O former/O Communist/O ''/O friends/O of/O anyone/O we/O know/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELEr/PERSON ./O 
I/O would/O hke/O to/O ask/O if/O you/O have/O been/O to/O the/O Federal/ORGANIZATION Bureau/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Investigation/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O have/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O one/O more/O question/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O purposes/O of/O this/O committee/O under/O Public/O Law/O 601/O is/O to/O try/O to/O find/O ,/O from/O former/O Coimnunists/O especiallyMis/O PoSw/O N./O Oh/O ,/O that/O stigma/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O asked/O it/O that/O way/O in/O view/O of/O your/O testimony/O ,/O because/O you/O say/O vou/O must/O have/O been/O ,/O even/O though/O you/O do/O n't/O remember/O technically/O being/O a/O member/O ./O 
Have/O you/O any/O suggestion/O to/O make/O to/O the/O Congress/ORGANIZATION of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION in/O the/O field/O of/O how/O to/O get/O at/O the/O subversive/O activities/O ?/O 
Was/O there/O anything/O subversive/O discussed/O in/O your/O presence/O ?/O 
AliS/O POSKA/O ./O 
Never/O ./O 
MJr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Not/O in/O any/O way/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
there/O wasnt/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ,/O not/O a/O thing/O ;/O because/O had/O there/O been/O ,/O I/O would/O have/O been/O the/O first/O to/O go/O to/O the/O FBI/ORGANIZATION ,/O because/O we/O were/O at/O war/O and/O that/O was/O a/O very/O important/O thing/O to/O ine/O ./O 
I/O have/O con/O -/O sidered/O myself/O an/O American/O and/O a/O good/O one/O ,/O and/O I/O shall/O always/O be/O ;/O and/O anything/O subversive/O ,/O believe/O me/O ,/O I/O would/O be/O the/O first/O to-but/O nothing/O was/O ever/O subversive/O that/O was/O mentioned/O when/O I/O was/O going/O to/O matings/O ./O 
5784/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
The/O phrase/O ``/O former/O Communist/O ''/O has/O been/O mentioned/O ,/O and/O I/O think/O it/O should/O be/O on/O the/O record/O that/O the/O committee/O and/O the/O country/O owes/O a/O very/O great/O debt/O of/O gratitude/O to/O former/O Communists/O who/O have/O seen/O it/O as/O their/O duty/O to/O come/O forward/O and/O tell/O the/O committee/O and/O the/O country/O what/O they/O know/O about/O it/O ,/O having/O honestly/O and/O decisively/O broken/O with/O the/O Comiiist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
So/O I/O do/O not/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O consider/O that/O the/O term/O ``/O former/O Communist/O ''/O is/O anything/O but/O a/O term/O of/O approbation/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYE/O ./O 
I/O remember/O your/O testimony/O that/O at/O the/O time/O you/O were/O in/O that/O group/O we/O were/O at/O war/O ./O 
All/O of/O the/O time/O that/O you/O were/O in/O the/O group/O was/O Russia/LOCATION our/O ally/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSXA/O ./O 
Yes/O ,/O it/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
However/O at/O that/O same/O period/O of/O time/O the/O group/O was/O being/O instructed/O of/O the/O difference/O between/O the/O Soviet/O system/O of/O government/O and/O our/O system/O as/O you/O described/O ,/O capitalistic/O system/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O to/O make/O it/O clear/O in/O my/O own/O thinking/O ./O 
Russia/LOCATION was/O our/O ally/O ,/O but/O at/O that/O time/O the/O Communist/O leaders/O in/O your/O presence/O were/O contrasting/O the/O lSoviet/O system/O of/O government/O to/O ours/O ./O 
That/O leads/O me/O to/O think/O that/O there/O must/O have/O been/O a/O criticism/O of/O our/O form/O of/O ,/O government/O ,/O because/O at/O least/O they/O were/O contrasting/O our/O form/O of/O government/O with/O theirs/O ,/O with/O the/O Russian/O system/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O period/O during/O whsch/O we/O were/O allied/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O and/O I/O am/O wondering/O to/O what/O extent/O that/O was/O the/O subject/O of/O discussion/O during/O the/O time/O we/O were/O an/O ally/O of/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O to/O subsequent/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O I/O did/O n't/O go/O every/O single/O time/O there/O was/O a/O meeting/O ;/O and/O from/O what/O I/O learned-I/O mean/O ,/O there/O was-they/O advocated/O or/O they/O agreed/O with/O the/O Russian/O system/O that/O the/O government/O own/O everything/O ;/O and/O individual/O wealth/O or/O individual/O holdings/O was/O n't/O such/O in/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Otherwise/O ,/O I/O mean/O ,/O as/O far/O as/O anything/O subversiveMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
But/O it/O is/O interesting/O to/O me/O that/O during/O the/O time/O we/O were/O an/O ally/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ,/O that/O there/O was/O a/O group/O of/O people/O who/O were/O evidently/O comparing/O ,/O to/O the/O detriment/O of/O the/O capitalistic/O system/O which/O you/O have/O referred/O to-you/O said/O they/O used/O that/O term/O --/O evidently/O criticizing/O our/O form/O of/O government/O during/O the/O very/O time/O that/O they/O were/O an/O ally/O in/O a/O war/O against/O Mr./O Hitler/PERSON ./O 
Miss/O PosxA/O ./O 
I/O mean/O ,/O I/O never/O did/O see/O anything/O wrong/O with/O ourbest/O ./O 
system/O of/O government/O ./O 
I/O think/O ,/O as/O I/O said/O before/O ,/O I/O think/O it/O is/O the/O However/O ,/O they/O ,/O when/O there/O would/O be/O any/O discussion/O ,/O would/O compare/O them/O ./O 
I/O do/O n't/O say/O that/O they-well/O ,/O they/O would/O criticize/O to/O a/O certain/O extent/O ,/O but/O not/O to/O any/O great/O extent/O where/O I/O would/O consider/O it/O subversive/O insofar/O as/O tearing/O it/O down/O ,/O by/O any/O means/O whatsoever/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
Along/O what/O line/O did/O they/O discuss/O our/O being/O an/O ally/O of/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O they/O were/O for/O it/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O but/O did/O they/O seem/O to/O express/O an/O appreciation/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O we/O were/O joining/O with/O Russia/LOCATION and/O that/O we/O were/O an/O ally/O of/O Russia/LOCATION ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
They/O were/O very/O happy/O that/O we/O were/O allied/O with/O Russia/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
And/O yet/O they/O did/O compare/O to/O the/O detriment/O of/O our/O own/O country/O ,/O the/O capitalistic/O system/O ,/O as/O compared/O with/O the/O Soviet/O system/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSmA/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O that/O was/O the/O line/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O further/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5785/O Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Just/O one/O more/O thing/O ./O 
I/O should/O like/O to/O point/O out/O to/O the/O witness/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O my/O recollection/O she/O has/O identified/O four/O people/O ,/O and/O I/O say/O this/O in/O all/O good/O faith/O and/O for/O your/O own/O protection/O ./O 
You/O have/O already/O said/O under/O the/O compulsion/O of/O your/O oath/O that/O you/O can/O not/O identify/O any/O other/O person/O who/O was/O associated/O with/O you/O at/O your/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O point/O out/O that/O if/O ,/O subsequently/O ,/O future/O witnesses/O may/O testify/O to/O the/O contrary/O ,/O that/O a/O very/O real/O danger/O to/O you/O exists/O ./O 
I/O would/O not/O want/O you/O ,/O out/O of/O any/O moral/O compunctions/O or/O for/O any/O reasons/O ,/O to/O refrain/O from/O telling/O us/O if/O there/O are/O any/O more/O people/O with/O whom/O you/O were/O associated/O ./O 
I/O say/O that/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ;/O I/O say/O this/O for/O the/O protection/O of/O the/O witness/O ./O 
M1/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O J/O o/O noN/O ./O 
We/O have/O had/O circumstances/O in/O the/O past/O where/O witnesses/O for/O one/O reason/O or/O another/O felt/O that/O they/O should/O not/O disclose/O any/O names/O or/O some/O name/O ;/O where/O subsequently/O it/O has/O developed/O that/O they/O were/O not/O tetifying/O in/O full/O good/O faith/O ,/O which/O presents/O the/O committee/O with/O only/O one/O course/O of/O action/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O to/O refer/O the/O testimony/O to/O the/O Attorney/O General/O of/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
I/O simply/O ity/O that/O to/O you/O in/O order/O tl/O `/O it/O no/O ,1/O rDS/O out/O of/O the/O best/O of/O motives/O yoU/O mahr/O eonoeivably/O be/O withholding/O trom/O us/O the/O name/O or/O names/O of/O some/O ot/O the/O people/O with/O whom/O you/O were/O associated/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O am/O not/O ./O 
I/O think-I/O have/O been/O thinking/O about/O this/O ever/O since/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON first/O interviewed/O me/O ./O 
Aid/O I/O tried/O Lo/O think/O and/O tried/O to/O think/O ,/O and/O I/O just-if/O I/O knew/O or/O if/O I/O could/O think/O ,/O I/O would/O certainly/O tell/O you/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O :/O I/O am/O sure/O that/O is/O the/O case/O ./O 
But/O I/O felt/O that/O I/O should/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O place/O that/O in/O the/O record/O in/O order/O that/O it/O might/O be/O absolutely/O clear/O to/O her/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
As/O I/O say/O ,/O I/O have/O just/O told/O these/O gentlemen-I/O have/O been/O thinking/O ever/O since/O you/O first/O contacted/O me/O and/O we/O got/O together/O ,/O I/O have/O been/O thinking/O and/O thinking/O back-whom/O ,/O if/O anyone/O ,/O I/O could/O remember/O who/O were/O at/O those/O meetings/O ;/O and/O aside/O from/O the/O Altmans/O and/O the/O Christliebs/O ,/O I/O just/O ca/O n't/O remember/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Of/O course/O ,/O we/O do/O n't/O expect/O you/O ,/O nor/O do/O we/O want/O you/O ,/O to/O be/O at/O all/O uncertain/O or/O haphazard/O about/O it/O ./O 
We/O want/O the/O facts/O that/O are/O in/O your/O knowledge/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O all/O ./O 
I/O have/O nothing/O further/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O I/O recall/O in/O that/O connection/O ,/O Miss/PERSON Poska/PERSON ,/O your/O testimony/O is/O that/O there/O were/O only/O 6/O or/O 8/O people/O in/O the/O group/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O DornE/PERSON ./O 
You/O have/O named/O 4/O of/O them/O ,/O so/O it/O would/O only/O be/O a/O matter/O of/O your/O telling/O who/O the/O other/O 2/O or/O 3/O were/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoN/PERSON ./O 
Unless/O they/O were/O different/O people/O at/O different/O meetings/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
At/O different/O times/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Which/O would/O substantially/O increase/O the/O number/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O Dovax/PERSON ./O 
How/O many/O totally/O different/O people/O would/O you/O say/O were/O in/O the/O group/O during/O the/O 8/O or/O 10or/O 12/O meetings/O you/O attended/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Almost/O every/O time/O there/O would/O be/O a/O different/O conglomeration/O of/O people/O ./O 
Mr./O DomiE/PERSON ./O 
The/O Altmans/O and/O the/O Christliebs/O would/O make/O four/O ./O 
If/O the/O groups/O were/O not/O more/O numerous/O than/O 6/O or/O 8/O or/O 10/O ,/O then/O you/O would/O 5786/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O only/O have/O at/O most/O 4/O different/O people/O at/O each/O meeting/O ./O 
If/O these/O same/O four/O people/O attended/O ./O 
Miss/O PoSiKs/O ./O 
Now/O ,/O for/O instance/O ,/O I/O would/O n't/O say/O that/O they/O were/O all/O four/O there/O at/O tile/O Same/O time/O ,/O you/O see/O ./O 
Mr./O l/O -RRB-/O OYLE/O ./O 
I/O see/O ./O 
Miss/O PosK/O s./O They/O were/O n't/O always/O there/O together/O ./O 
M/O 1ILE/O ./O 
Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
,/O trying/O to/O be/O very/O fair/O and/O ver/O explicit/O with/O you/O ./O 
Miss/O POISKA/O ./O 
I/O understand/O that/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
But/O we/O are/O o/O anxious/O that/O you/O go/O out/O of/O the/O room/O feeling/O that/O you/O have/O given/O the/O best/O that/O you/O have/O according/O to/O Your/O recollection/O ,/O because/O we/O never/O know/O when/O some/O other/O witness/O is/O going/O to/O come/O forward/O and/O name/O other/O persons/O who/O might/O be/O in/O this/O same/O group/O ./O 
Miss/O PosE.s/O ./O 
That/O is/O true/O ./O 
I/O realize/O that/O ./O 
and/O if/O IMr/O ./O 
IACKSO/LOCATION ,/O ./O 
Even/O more/O than/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/PERSON ,/O if/O I/O maysomeone/O who/O ina/O ;/O have/O on/O a/O number/O of/O occasions/O accompanied/O you/O to/O the/O meeting-I/O do/O n't/O say/O that/O that/O occurred/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O that/O is/O what/O the/O chairman/O and/O I/O are/O trying/O to/O point/O out/O to/O you/O ,/O that/O we/O do/O not/O want/O you/O advertently/O or/O inadvertentlh/O to/O place/O yourself/O in/O a/O position/O where/O subsequent/O testimony/O may/O tend/O to/O incriminate/O you/O ./O 
We/O want/O to/O be/O fair/O ./O 
We/O are/O trying/O to/O be/O absolutely/O fair/O in/O this/O ./O 
Mi/O ,/O ./O 
Po/O ,/O ,/O x/O k./O Wait/O a/O minute/O ;/O to/O the/O best/O of/O nv/O knowledge/O I/O always/O went/O alone/O ./O 
I/O doi/O '/O t/O remember/O of/O having/O gone/O wlth/O anyone/O ./O 
I/O know/O I/O had/O my/O own/O car/O ,/O and/O I/O drove/O ;/O and/O I/O was/O living/O by/O myself/O at/O the/O time/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
So/O far/O as/O I/O know/O there/O is/O no/O testimony/O to/O the/O contrary/O ,/O but/O ,/O again/O ,/O I/O simply/O stores/O that/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O one/O question/O in/O conclusion/O ?/O 
Without/O preitice/O to/O the/O right/O of/O our/O committee/O to/O release/O tour/O testimon/O at/O any/O nine/O ,/O which/O ,/O of/O course/O ,/O is/O within/O the/O jurisdiction/O of/O the/O full/O committee/O ./O 
do/O you/O have/O any/O personal/O objection/O to/O the/O release/O of/O the/O testimony/O or/O to/O the/O fact/O of/O your/O testifying/O at/O this/O time-the/O fact/O of/O your/O cooperation/O with/O the/O coitnttee/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WsEsLER/O ./O 
I/O think/O she/O wants/O it/O released/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSO/PERSON ./O 
That/O is/O the/O point/O I/O wanted/O to/O make/O ./O 
MIss/O Posk/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSoN/PERSON ./O 
I/O say/O that/O I/O am/O not/O binding/O the/O committee/O to/O take/O action/O one/O way/O or/O the/O other/O ,/O but/O we/O should/O like/O to/O ,/O in/O light/O of/O the/O fact/O that/O you/O have/O cooperated-at/O least/O ,/O I/O should/O like/O to/O be/O able/O to/O say/O to/O the/O press/O that/O you/O tlid/O appear/O and/O cooperated/O fully/O with/O the/O committee/O ./O 
MlSS/O I/O `/O o/O ,1/O A./O It/O would/O make/O me/O very/O happy/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
What/O was/O your/O motive/O for/O coming/O forward/O and/O asking/O the/O hearing/O ?/O 
Miss/O PosK.s/O ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O did/O n'tMr/O ./O 
DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O ou/O do/O that/O ?/O 
Mink/O POSKA/O ./O 
Why/O did/O I/O ?/O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mi.ss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O was/O so/O stunned/O ,/O and/O I/O was/O so/O mad/O and/O surprised/O that/O I/O wanted/O to/O get/O the/O record/O straight/O that/O I/O am/O not/O a/O Comununist/O ;/O and/O to/O my/O knowledge-I/O mean/O ,/O I/O would/O n't/O have/O anything/O to/O do/O with/O them/O ,/O and/O to/O my/O knowledge/O I/O never/O was/O ./O 
But/O that/O is/O my/O only/O purpose/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
All/O right/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O ask/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON if/O he/O wants/O to/O ask/O any/O more/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKsoNs/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O I/O think/O in/O justice/O to/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON we/O should/O have/O it/O very/O clearly/O set/O forth/O in/O the/O record/O if/O the/O witness/O denies/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5787/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON has/O testified/O affirmatively/O that/O the/O witness/O was/O ,/O to/O the/O best/O of/O his/O knowledge/O ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O I/O do/O n't/O want/O to/O becloud/O his/O other/O identifications/O by/O any/O uncertainty/O in/O this/O case/O ./O 
It/O would/O seem/O to/O me/O from/O what/O has/O been/O adduced/O here/O today/O that/O the/O witness/O was/O indeed/O ,/O whether/O she/O realized/O it/O or/O not/O ,/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
I/O think/O you/O will/O appreciate/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O point/O I/O am/O making/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O that/O there/O are/O other/O identifications/O which/O I/O do/O not/O want/O to/O see/O beclouded/O unless/O they/O should/O be/O beclouded/O ,/O by/O any/O leaving/O of/O this/O in/O a/O cloud/O as/O to/O whether/O or/O not/O the/O witness/O was/O at/O one/O time/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
So/O far/O as/O I/O personally/O am/O concerned/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O the/O fact/O of/O attendance/O at/O what/O appear/O to/O have/O been/O closed/O meetings/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O the/O fact/O of/O what/O appears/O to/O be/O recruitment/O by/O Mr./O Altman/PERSON ,/O would/O lead/O me/O to/O believe/O that/O you/O had/O indeed-whether/O knowingly/O or/O not-become/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
I/O simply/O want/O to/O make/O the/O record/O clear/O and/O not/O have/O the/O final/O record/O appear/O as/O being/O clouded/O by/O the/O profession/O of/O the/O witness/O as/O not/O knowing/O whether/O or/O not/O she/O had/O been/O a/O member/O of/O the/O party/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Discussion/O off/O the/O record/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Let/O me/O go/O back/O on/O the/O record/O ./O 
Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O other/O individuals/O identified/O by/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON who/O were/O subsequently/O called/O before/O the/O committee/O to/O testify/O availed/O themselves/O of/O the/O privileges/O of/O the/O fifth/O amendment/O in/O refusing/O to/O answer/O any/O questions/O having/O to/O do/O with/O their/O alleged/O activities/O within/O the/O Communist/O Party/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Or/O affirm/O their/O membership/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Or/O conversely/O ,/O affirm/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON as/O to/O their/O membership/O and/O activities/O in/O and/O on/O behalf/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O DoYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O am/O glad/O you/O added/O that/O ,/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
I/O think/O to/O be/O perfectly/O fair/O with/O the/O witness/O ,/O I/O should/O add/O that/O ,/O too/O ./O 
As/O I/O hear/O your/O testimony/O ,/O you/O state/O you/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O ./O 
I/O think/O that/O is/O the/O essense/O of/O your/O testimony/O so/O far/O as/O membership/O is/O concerned/O ,/O you/O do/O n't/O know/O whether/O or/O not/O you/O were/O technically/O ;/O that/O fact/O as/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON has/O mentioned/O ,/O plus/O the/O fact/O that/O you/O refused/O to/O pay/O the/O dues/O they/O asked/O ,/O that/O they/O asked/O you/O apparently/O to/O pay/O a/O percentage/O of/O your/O income/O as/O dues/O ,/O and/O you/O say/O you/O never/O paid/O any/O of/O that/O percentage/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ,/O sir/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
But/O as/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON points/O out/O ,/O you/O have/O testified/O that/O these/O meetings/O were/O what/O you/O thought/O were/O closed/O meetings-you/O were/O not/O free/O to/O invite/O anyone/O to/O go/O with/O you/O ?/O 
In/O our/O experience/O that/O means/O that/O they/O are/O closed/O meetings/O ,/O that/O you/O considered/O them/O a/O closed/O arrangement/O ,/O not/O an/O invitational/O affair/O to/O which/O you/O could/O take/O another/O person/O ./O 
I/O want/O to/O be/O perfectly/O frank/O with/O you/O ./O 
From/O your/O testimony/O ,/O my/O own/O conclusion/O is/O that/O whether/O you/O knew/O it/O or/O not/O you/O were/O a/O member/O of/O that/O group/O ;/O I/O ca/O n't/O draw/O any/O other/O conclusion/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O obviously/O was/O ./O 
I/O very/O obviously/O was/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
That/O I/O think/O must/O be/O the/O conclusion/O of/O any/O objective/O person/O looking/O at/O it/O ./O 
I/O assure/O you/O we/O are/O not/O in/O any/O way/O trying/O ,/O nor/O 77486-es6/O --/O pt/O ./O 
11/O -/O 5788/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O am/O I/O trying/O ,/O to/O put/O any/O thoughts/O inyor/O mind/O or/O words/O in/O your/O mouth/O ,/O but/O I/O do/O want/O to/O protect/O the/O integrity/O of/O the/O testimony/O which/O we/O have/O received/O ./O 
Miss/O PosKa/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O DonL/O ./O 
That/O is/O right/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Which/O has/O proven/O itself/O so/O far/O as/O we/O have/O been/O able/O to/O explore/O it/O ./O 
I/O am/O sure/O you/O understand/O the/O situation/O in/O which/O the/O committee/O finds/O itself/O ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Surely/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Not/O to/O unduly/O embarrass/O you/O or/O not/O to/O question/O your/O word/O in/O any/O way/O ,/O but/O if/O there/O is/O any/O doubt/O in/O your/O mind/O on/O the/O score/O of/O membership/O ,/O I/O would/O feel/O ,/O Mr./O Chairman/O ,/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O comnittee/O ,/O that/O we/O should/O ask/O for/O a/O denial/O of/O membership/O in/O order/O that/O the/O situation/O might/O be/O perfectly/O clear-either/O something/O more/O perhaps/O than/O simply/O it/O might/O have/O been/O and/O it/O might/O not/O have/O been/O ,/O which/O tends/O to/O cloud/O the/O testimony/O of/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON ./O 
Perhaps/O I/O can/O simplify/O it/O by/O asking/O simply/O ,/O if/O you/O deny/O that/O you/O were/O ever/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O ca/O n't/O deny/O it/O when/O my/O name/O is/O on/O the/O record/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O JAcKsoN/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Your/O name/O might/O appear/O as/O mine/O might/O or/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON 's/O might/O ,/O by/O someone/O simply/O writing/O it/O down/O ,/O or/O the/O name/O of/O any/O other/O citizen/O whoin/O an/O official/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION might/O perhaps/O want/O to/O demean/O by/O writing/O it/O in/O ./O 
I/O think/O this/O is/O an/O important/O matter/O ,/O Mr./O Doyle/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
I/O do/O ,/O too/O ./O 
Mr./O J/O cxsoN/O ./O 
I/O can/O not/O be/O personally/O satisfied/O with/O an/O answer/O ,/O ``/O Well/O ,/O perhaps/O I/O was/O and/O perhaps/O I/O was/O not/O ./O ''/O 
We/O have/O had/O this/O heretofore/O ./O 
I/O personally/O would/O be/O unwilling/O to/O accept/O such/O an/O answer/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O supplement/O Mr./O Jackson/PERSON 's/O thought/O to/O you/O ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O you/O this/O :/O During/O the/O time/O you/O attended/O the/O meetings/O ,/O did/O you/O consider/O yourself/O in/O your/O own/O thinking/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
MIss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O ./O 
I/O did/O n't/O consider/O myself/O a/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Mir/O ./O 
Doyle/PERSON ,/O may/O I/O ask/O one/O further/O question/O ?/O 
You/O read/O the/O reports/O of/O Mr./O Christlieb/PERSON 's/O testimony/O ./O 
MIss/O POSKA/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
ir/O ./O 
JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Was/O that/O testimony/O in/O any/O respect/O ,/O so/O far/O as/O it/O pertaiied/O to/O you/O ,/O false/O ?/O 
Miss/O PoSKA/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Off/O the/O record/O ./O 
-LRB-/O Discussion/O off/O the/O record/O ./O -RRB-/O 
Mr./O JaCKSON/PERSON ./O 
I/O have/O no/O further/O questions/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Do/O you/O have/O anything/O further/O to/O add/O ,/O Miss/O Poska/PERSON ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
No/O ;/O I/O have/O n't/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O perfectly/O satisfied/O ?/O 
Miss/O POSKA/O ./O 
I/O am/O very/O happy/O to/O have/O had/O this/O opportunity/O of/O getting/O all/O this/O off/O my/O chest/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ./O 
Fine/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Is/O there/O anything/O else/O ,/O Mr./O Wheeler/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O WHELrR/O ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O JACKSON/PERSON ,/O ./O 
Thank/O you/O very/O much/O ./O 
We/O thank/O you/O for/O coming/O to/O this/O hearing/O ./O 
INVESTIGATION/O OF/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O THE/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA-Part/O 11/O WEDNESDAY/O ,/O JUNE/O 6/O ,/O 1956/O UNITED/O STATES/O HOUSE/O OF/O REPRESENT/O TIES/O ,/O SUBCOMMITTEE/O OP/O THE/O C0n3vITTE/O ON/O UN-AINERIC/O ./O 
AN/O AcTIvrrEms/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ./O 
EXECUTIVE/O SESSION/O '/O A/O subcommittee/O of/O the/O Committee/O on/O Un-American/O Activities/O met/O ,/O pursuant/O to/O call/O ,/O at/O 11/O :/O 45/O a./O m./O ,/O in/O room/O 484/O of/O the/O Statler/O Hotel/O ,/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O Calif./LOCATION ,/O Hon./O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON -LRB-/O chairman/O -RRB-/O presiding/O ./O 
Committee/O member/O present/O :/O Representative/O Clyde/PERSON Doyle/PERSON of/O California/LOCATION ./O 
Staff/O member/O present/O :/O William/PERSON A./PERSON Wheeler/PERSON ,/O investigator/O ./O 
Mr./O DoYLr/O ./O 
Mrs./O Viertel/PERSON ,/O will/O you/O rise/O ,/O please/O ,/O and/O be/O sworn/O ?/O 
Do/O you/O solemnly/O swear/O that/O the/O evidence/O you/O shall/O give/O to/O this/O subcommittee/O shall/O be/O the/O truth/O ,/O the/O whole/O truth/O ,/O and/O nothing/O but/O the/O truth/O ,/O so/O help/O you/O God/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VxERTEL/O ./O 
I/O do/O ./O 
TESTIMONY/O OF/O VIRGINIA/LOCATION VIERTEL/LOCATION ,/O ACCOMPANIED/O BY/O COUNSEL/O ,/O MARTIN/O GANG/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Will/O you/O state/O your/O full/O name/O ,/O please/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIETEL/PERSON ./O 
Virginia/PERSON Viertel/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Are/O you/O represented/O by/O counsel/O ?/O 
Misr/O ./O 
VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O Mr./O Martin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
Will/O counsel/O state/O his/O name/O for/O the/O record/O ?/O 
Mr./O GANG/O ./O 
Martin/PERSON Gang/PERSON ,/O 6400/O Sunset/LOCATION Boulevard/LOCATION ./O 
Mr./O WREELER/PERSON ./O 
Where/O were/O you/O born/O ,/O Mrs./O Viertel/PERSON ?/O 
Mr./O VCERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Beaver/PERSON ,/O Pa./LOCATION ,/O September/O 3/O ,/O 1915/O ./O 
you/O relate/O your/O educational/O background/O ?/O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
I/O went/O to/O Fairfax/ORGANIZATION High/ORGANIZATION School/ORGANIZATION in/O Los/LOCATION Angeles/LOCATION ,/O and/O then/O years/O later/O I/O went/O 1/O year/O at/O USC/ORGANIZATION and/O 1/O year/O at/O UCLA/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
What/O is/O your/O occupation/O ?/O 
right/O now/O ./O 
Mrs./O VTTRTEL/PERSON ./O 
Editor/O it/O has/O been/O ./O 
Nothing/O the/O motion/O picture/O Mr./O ``/O HEELER/O ./O 
Are/O you/O referring/O to/O an/O editor/O in/O industry/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VSEERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Mostly/O not/O ./O 
released/O by/O the/O committee/O August/O 7/O ,/O 1956/O ./O 
,/O Odered/O 5789/O 5790/O COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Mostly/O not/O ?/O 
Then/O in/O what/O field/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTs/O ./O 
In/O books/O ./O 
Book/O publishing/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O appearing/O before/O the/O subcommittee/O at/O your/O own/O request/O ;/O is/O that/O correct/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O know/O that/O you/O have/O been/O identified/O as/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION by/O witnesses/O before/O the/O committee/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O a/O member/O of/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O was/O ./O 
Mrs./O ViERT/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O please/O state/O when/O you/O first/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O VrsRTEL/O ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
It/O is/O n't/O entirely/O easy/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O it/O was/O 1936/O or/O thereabouts/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O terminate/O that/O membership/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
That/O ,/O too/O ,/O is/O not/O exactly/O a/O definite/O date/O ,/O but/O it/O was/O certainly/O erratic/O after/O 1940/O ;/O but/O I/O know/O that/O after-during/O 1945/O I/O never/O saw/O anybody/O again/O ./O 
That/O was/O the/O final/O end/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O previously/O married/O to/O Budd/PERSON Schulberg/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O the/O marriage/O terminate/O in/O divorce/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
In/O 1944/O ,/O 1/O think/O ./O 
Is/O that/O right/O ?/O 
Mr./O GANe/O ./O 
You/O separated/O in/O 1942/O ./O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O believe/O you/O said/O you/O separated/O in/O 1942/O ,/O were/O di/O -/O vorced/O in/O 1944/O ./O 
Mrs./O VIsRTEL/O ./O 
1944/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
I/O want/O the/O record/O clear/O ./O 
Mr./O GAN/O ./O 
Make/O the/O record/O clear/O ,/O would/O you/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O yes/O ./O 
We/O separated/O in/O 1942/O and/O were/O divorced/O in/O 1944/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
May/O the/O record/O show/O that/O you/O were/O divorced/O in/O January/O of/O 1944/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Was/O your/O membership/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION during/O the/O entire/O period/O of/O your/O marriage/O to/O Mr./O Schulberg/PERSON ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O was/O a/O member/O the/O whole/O time/O ;/O but/O ,/O as/O I/O say/O ,/O we/O often/O went/O away/O and/O we/O were/O n't/O in/O constant/O attendance/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O state/O your/O constant/O attendance/O ,/O then/O ,/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ,/O if/O you/O possibly/O can/O ?/O 
When/O did/O you/O start/O to/O draw/O away/O from/O membership-become/O disinterested/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Oh/O ,/O I/O should/O say/O in/O 1939/O ./O 
We/O had/O some/O small/O quarrels/O and/O things/O in/O 1938/O and/O 1939/O ,/O really/O ,/O but/O I/O guess/O in/O 1940/O ,/O that/O wasI/O do/O n't/O think/O we/O attended/O meetings/O regularly/O ever/O again/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
After/O 1940/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VirRan/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
But/O you/O still/O retained/O your/O membership/O to/O a/O later/O date/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ,/O but/O it/O really/O did/O n't/O matter/O ./O 
It/O is/O hard/O ;/O I/O know/O it/O seems/O strange/O ,/O but/O membership/O one/O did/O n't/O think/O about/O ./O 
That/O was/O a/O rather/O loose-it/O was/O unimportant/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O pay/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION dues/O during/O the/O entire/O time/O of/O your/O membership/O ?/O 
COMMUNIST/O ACTIVITIES/O IN/O LOS/LOCATION ANGELES/LOCATION ,/O CALIF./LOCATION ,/O AREA/O 5791/O Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
Mine/O were/O nominal/O dues/O ./O 
Housewife/O dues/O ./O 
Fifty/O cents/O or/O a/O dollar/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
When/O did/O you/O completely/O divorce/O yourself/O from/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O VIRa'I/O `/O L./O Well/O ,/O completely/O in/O 1945/O ./O 
Mr./O DOYLE/PERSON ./O 
May/O I/O ask/O ,/O up/O until/O what/O time/O did/O you/O pay/O dues/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Well/O ,/O I/O imagine/O until/O 1940/O ,/O because/O after/O that/O I/O did/O not/O go/O to/O regular/O meetings/O ./O 
I/O was/O not/O a/O regular/O member/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Would/O you/O tell/O the/O subcommittee/O ,/O please/O ,/O the/O reasons/O you/O joined/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
It/O is/O really/O very/O simple/O ,/O because/O we/O had/O just/O been/O through/O the/O depression/O and/O it/O hit/O most/O of/O us/O quite/O hard-if/O not/O us/O ,/O because/O we/O were/O so/O young/O ,/O we/O saw/O what/O happened/O ,/O and/O we/O thought/O there/O must/O be/O economic/O reasons/O for/O this/O ,/O and/O we/O all/O wanted/O to/O study/O and/O find/O out/O about/O it/O ./O 
It/O was/O bewildering/O to/O young/O people/O to/O have/O suddenly/O the/O whole/O world/O that/O we/O knew/O sort/O of/O crash/O ,/O and/O then/O just/O on/O the/O humanitarian/O level/O ,/O the/O unemployed/O ,/O and/O the/O people/O were/O going/O through/O such/O hardships/O ./O 
That/O marks/O young/O people/O ,/O I/O think/O ,/O very/O much/O ./O 
It/O would/O take/O a/O very/O calloused/O young/O person/O not/O to/O respond/O some/O way/O ./O 
Then/O we/O were/O --/O and/O we/O responded/O in/O the/O only/O way/O we/O knew/O how/O ,/O because/O we/O were/O intellectuals/O ,/O so/O we/O studied/O and/O tried/O to/O find/O out/O about/O it/O ./O 
Then/O we/O were/O certainly/O anti-Fascist/O ,/O and/O no/O other/O organization/O or/O group/O seemed/O to/O be/O doing/O anything/O about/O this/O at/O that/O time/O ./O 
There/O was/O nothing/O that/O one/O could-a/O young/O person/O could/O go/O to/O say/O ,/O at/O least/O for/O guidance/O ./O 
Not/O even/O church/O groups/O ./O 
The/O Communist/O Party/O held/O out/O the/O only/O knowledge-when/O up/O in/O Imperial/LOCATION Valley/LOCATION ,/O for/O example/O ,/O where/O the/O poor/O were/O starving/O ./O 
Nobody/O helped/O except/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O went/O in/O and/O raised/O money/O ;/O for/O floods/O ,/O for/O disasters/O of/O all/O kinds/O ;/O and/O they/O seemed/O like/O a/O great/O humanitarian/O to/O be/O noticed/O group/O ./O 
I/O think/O most/O of/O the/O young/O people/O were/O pleased/O by/O them/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Did/O you/O ever/O hold/O any/O office/O in/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O VERTL/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Neither/O on/O the/O county/O level/O nor/O on/O a/O club/O level/O ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
No/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Were/O you/O assigned/O to/O a/O club/O by/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mr./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ;/O I/O guess/O so/O ./O 
I/O must/O have/O been/O assigned/O ,/O but/O I/O think/O I/O either-I/O must/O have/O started/O just/O with/O Budd/PERSON ,/O and/O then/O just/O continued/O with/O the/O writers/O '/O group/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
You/O are/O referring/O to/O Budd/PERSON Schulberg/PERSON ?/O 
Airs/O ./O 
VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
Yes/O ./O 
I/O am/O sorry/O ./O 
Mr./O WHEELER/PERSON ./O 
Why/O did/O you/O leave/O the/O Communist/ORGANIZATION Party/ORGANIZATION ?/O 
Mrs./O VIERTEL/PERSON ./O 
For/O many/O years/O ,/O after/O 1940/O ,/O really/O ,/O there/O was/O no/O reason/O for/O me/O to/O be/O in/O it/O ./O 
I/O had/O sort/O of/O completed/O my/O study/O course/O ,/O and/O that/O was/O the/O main/O reason/O I/O was/O in/O there/O ,/O and/O that/O is/O why/O I/O returned/O a/O few/O times/O after/O 1940/O ,/O just/O because/O they/O were/O discussing/O something/O I/O wanted/O to/O hear/O ;/O and/O they/O were/O friends/O also/O ./O 
